Healing the Fragmented Selves of Trauma Survivors

治愈创伤幸存者碎裂的自我

Healing the Fragmented Selves of Trauma Survivors integrates a neurobiologically informed understanding of trauma, dissociation, and attachment with a practical approach to treatment, all communicated in straightforward language accessible to both client and therapist. Readers will be exposed to a model that emphasizes "resolution"—a transformation in the relationship to one's self, replacing shame, self-loathing, and assumptions of guilt with compassionate acceptance. Its unique interventions have been adapted from a number of cutting-edge therapeutic approaches, including Sensorimotor Psychotherapy, Internal Family Systems, mindfulness-based therapies, and clinical hypnosis. Readers will close the pages of Healing the Fragmented Selves of Trauma Survivors with a solid grasp of therapeutic approaches to traumatic attachment, working with undiagnosed dissociative symptoms and disorders, integrating "right brain-to-right brain" treatment methods, and much more. Most of all, they will come away with tools for helping clients create an internal sense of safety and compassionate connection to even their most disowned selves.

《治愈创伤幸存者碎裂的自我》将神经生物学视角下对创伤、解离与依恋的深刻理解，与切实可行的治疗方法融为一体，以来访者和治疗师均能理解的平实语言加以呈现。读者将接触到一种强调"解决"的模型——即对自我关系的根本转化，以慈悲接纳取代羞耻感、自我厌恶和自我归咎。书中独特的干预方法汇集了多种前沿治疗取向，包括感觉运动心理治疗、内部家庭系统（IFS）、正念疗法及临床催眠。读者读完本书后，将对创伤性依恋的治疗方法、处理未确诊的解离症状与障碍、整合"右脑对右脑"治疗方式等内容有扎实的把握。最重要的是，他们将获得帮助来访者建立内在安全感、与最疏离的自我部分建立慈悲连结的实用工具。

Janina Fisher, PhD, is assistant education director of the Sensorimotor Psychotherapy Institute, an EMDR International Association (EMDRIA) consultant, and a former instructor at the Trauma Center, a clinic and research center founded by Bessel van der Kolk. Known for her expertise as a clinician, author, and presenter, she is also past president of the New England Society for the Treatment of Trauma and Dissociation, a former instructor at Harvard Medical School, and coauthor (with Pat Ogden) of Sensorimotor Psychotherapy: Interventions for Trauma and Attachment.

贾尼娜·费舍尔（Janina Fisher），博士，感觉运动心理治疗研究所助理教育主任，眼动脱敏与再处理国际协会（EMDRIA）认证顾问，贝塞尔·范德科尔克创办的创伤中心前任讲师。她以临床工作者、作者和演讲者的身份享有盛誉，曾任新英格兰创伤与解离治疗协会主席、哈佛医学院前任讲师，并与帕特·奥格登合著《感觉运动心理治疗：创伤与依恋干预》。

Acknowledgments

致谢

As a child, my ambition in life was to become a writer, a life goal I quickly gave up when I got to college and began to see what it might actually entail in terms of blood, sweat, and tears. The invitation to write this book for Routledge gave that young part of me satisfaction in finally becoming an author, but I must confess that the process was just as difficult as other parts told me it would be decades ago!

童年时，我的人生志向是成为一名作家，但上了大学、真正看清写作所需付出的心血之后，我很快就放弃了这个目标。受邀为Routledge撰写本书，让我内心那个年少的部分终于感受到了成为作者的满足，但我必须坦承，这个过程确实如几十年前另一些部分所预言的那样艰难！

The inspiration behind the ideas presented in this book comes directly from my patients who, over the years, taught me everything I understand today about the impact of trauma from "inside the volcano." They helped me to understand the experience of living with the enduring threat of annihilation, of hating themselves when they could not risk hating those who harmed them. They helped me to see that the deepest pain of all is connected to the failure of those they loved to cherish them and, for that reason, provide them safety and care. No arms reached out to break their fall, dry their tears, or comfort the ache of loneliness. There was no balm for the shame. When I finally understood that, to find peace, they needed a way to love the wounded children inside them, an insight came to me: it is the quality of our internal attachments that determines how safe we feel "inside," how easy or difficult it is to be "me." When we ignore, despise, or disown out littlest selves, we can't help but feel their pain: once again, they are not welcome. And when we learn how to offer them and ourselves an unconditionally "loving presence," wounds can heal and hope is renewed.

本书思想的灵感，直接源自多年来我的来访者——他们从"火山内部"教会了我今日所理解的关于创伤影响的一切。他们让我理解，活在长期被湮灭的威胁之中是怎样的体验：当无法承受憎恨那些伤害自己的人时，只能转而憎恨自己。他们让我看到，最深的痛苦，来自于所爱之人未能珍视他们、因而也未能给予他们安全与关怀。没有人伸出双臂接住他们的跌落，擦干他们的泪水，抚慰孤独的酸楚。羞耻感无处得到抚慰。当我终于明白，他们若要寻得平静，需要找到一种爱护自己内心受伤孩童的方式，一个领悟降临于我：正是内在依恋的质量，决定了我们在"内心"感到多么安全，以及做"我自己"有多容易或多困难。当我们忽视、鄙视或抛弃最幼小的自我时，我们不由自主地感受着他们的痛苦——他们再一次不被欢迎。而当我们学会向他们和自己给予无条件的"爱的临在"时，创伤得以愈合，希望得以更新。

To get from an idea to a finished manuscript, though, takes a cast of thousands, to all of whom I am indebted. I would not have written a book at all if it were not for my longtime friends and chosen family, Stephanie Ross, and Deborah Spragg, who first had the thought, "You should write a book!" And then never, ever let me forget it—for years. They became a Greek chorus that would not stop reminding me of what I "had" to do. Thank goodness for the wind at my back!

然而，将一个想法变成完整的书稿，需要无数人的帮助，我对他们都深怀感激。如果不是我的老朋友、我所选择的家人Stephanie Ross和Deborah Spragg，我根本不会写成这本书。正是她们最先萌生了"你应该写本书！"的想法，然后多年来从不让我忘记这件事。她们如同希腊合唱队，不断提醒我"必须"去做的事。感谢她们成为我背后的推动力！

Every new writer also needs guides who have traveled the same journey and know the way. My dear friend, Lisa Ferentz, would not let me off the hook either, encouraging and supporting me over years now. Having already published her first two books, Lisa was not only my cheerleader but could give me wise advice, emotional "chicken soup," and a map to guide me along the way.

每位初出茅庐的作者也都需要走过相同旅程、熟悉路途的引导者。我亲爱的朋友Lisa Ferentz多年来也从未放过我，一直鼓励和支持着我。已出版两本著作的她不仅是我的拉拉队长，还能给予我睿智的建议、情感上的"心灵鸡汤"，以及一张指引前行的地图。

Thanks to Bessel van der Kolk, my friend and mentor, I have been able to fulfill a professional mission first inspired when I heard Judith Herman speak about trauma 27 years ago. In that moment, my course was set. I am eternally grateful for my years as a supervisor and instructor at Bessel's Trauma Center, for the opportunity to learn from him as he led the neurobiological revolution in psychotherapy, and for his mentoring of my teaching and writing career. The understanding of trauma described in this book comes directly from his contributions to the field and is inspired by his belief that "the body keeps the score."

感谢我的朋友兼导师Bessel van der Kolk，正因为有他，我才能完成一项专业使命——这一使命最初源于27年前听到Judith Herman谈论创伤时的那个瞬间。那一刻，我的方向由此确立。我永远感激在贝塞尔创伤中心担任督导和讲师的那些岁月，感激在他引领心理治疗神经生物学革命期间向他学习的机会，以及他对我教学和写作生涯的悉心指导。本书对创伤的理解，直接来源于他对该领域的贡献，并受到他"身体铭记着一切"这一信念的启发。

My thanks, too, to Pat Ogden for her friendship, professional and personal support, and for the gift of Sensorimotor Psychotherapy. From Pat, I have learned how to use the resources of the body as a vehicle for communication that goes "beyond words." The therapist's own self is always the instrument in psychotherapy, and it behooves us to learn how to use our own internal states, body language, and tone of voice (the way mothers do with babies) to induce states of comfort, curiosity, and excitement that transform the client's state of distress. I also want to thank my Sensorimotor Institute "family" for their support—even when this book meant that I didn't have time for them!

我也要感谢Pat Ogden，感谢她的友谊、专业与个人层面的支持，以及感觉运动心理治疗这份礼物。从Pat那里，我学会了如何将身体资源作为"超越言语"的沟通媒介。治疗师自身始终是心理治疗的工具，我们有必要学会运用自己的内在状态、肢体语言和语调（就像母亲对待婴儿那样），来引发安慰、好奇与兴奋的状态，从而转化来访者的痛苦状态。我也要感谢感觉运动研究所"大家庭"的支持——尽管写这本书意味着我没有时间陪伴他们！

I have appreciated Dick Schwartz's generosity and supportive presence since we first met as faculty at Bessel van der Kolk's annual trauma conference, and my gratitude for his IFS model goes back even further. When I discovered IFS 20 years ago, I was overwhelmed by the responsibility for a caseload of clients with dissociative disorders—all of whom were in crisis. The discovery of Dick's concept of "self"-leadership allowed me to step back and allow the inherent strengths in each of them to come to the rescue. In this field, experts and founders can be territorial and self-protective. But Dick is welcoming of all parts of each person he encounters, and I thank him for trusting me to honor his work—as I hope I have done with the affection and respect he has earned.

自从我们在贝塞尔·范德科尔克年度创伤会议上作为同事初次相识，Dick Schwartz的慷慨与支持一直令我深为感激，而我对他的内部家庭系统（IFS）模型的感激则更为久远。20年前当我发现IFS时，我正被一大批解离性障碍来访者的责任所压垮——他们全都处于危机之中。Dick提出的"自我"领导力概念让我得以退后一步，让每位来访者自身内在的力量出来解围。在这个领域，专家和创始人往往具有领地意识和自我保护倾向。而Dick却对他所遇到的每个人的所有部分都热忱相迎，我感谢他信任我能尊重他的工作——我希望我确实以他所赢得的深情与敬意做到了这一点。

I am blessed also to have a family of colleagues around the world who have sent me their support, implored me to finish the book (at least for their sakes), or given me feedback when I've needed it. I want to thank Licia Sky, Carol Japha, Gil Levin, Benjamin Fry, and Sally LoGrasso for their willingness to read chapters in progress. Their insightful suggestions and encouragement helped enormously. In Norway, I am grateful to my dear friends, Kirsten Benum and Trine Anstorp, who always inspire me to dream bigger and then ply me with food and wine to entice me into our next project! In the United Kingdom, Benjamin Fry has given me the opportunity to translate my vision of "trauma treatment" into the ongoing work of Khiron House's clinical programs, while the uniquely talented staff inspire me in a different way: by speaking on behalf of the complex needs of their traumatized clients. In Italy, Giovanni Tagliavini and Paola Boldrini have generously offered me a stage from which to share my work. Their equally passionate devotion to serving the needs of traumatized clients (and their parts) makes them "family." A special thanks to Giovanni for his offer to translate this book into Italian, and thanks to Julian Baillet for offering to do the French translation. In Spain, I have "true believers" in this way of working, Dolores Mosquera and Esther Perez, whose encouragement was important to remember each time I questioned what I was doing. Thanks, too, to my wonderful UK colleagues and friends: Catherine Cox, Helen-Jane Ridgeway, Sally-Anne Bubbers, Linda Beton, and Liz Hall, among others. In Boston, my dear friend, Lana Epstein, contributed the gift of laughter—endless laughter—the perfect antidote to the stress of an author's journey. In New York, I want to give special thanks to Ken Frank, Sandy Shapiro, and Ken's study group for their enthusiastic reading of early chapters. I've found that a writer needs every crumb of that enthusiasm to keep going through such a long, often agonizing process.

我也很幸运，拥有一个遍布世界各地的同仁大家庭——他们向我传递支持，恳请我尽快完成这本书（至少是为了他们自己），或在我需要时给予反馈。我要感谢Licia Sky、Carol Japha、Gil Levin、Benjamin Fry和Sally LoGrasso，感谢他们愿意阅读尚未完成的章节。他们富有洞见的建议和鼓励助益良多。在挪威，我感谢我亲爱的朋友Kirsten Benum和Trine Anstorp，她们总是激励我怀揣更宏大的梦想，然后用美食与美酒诱惑我投入下一个项目！在英国，Benjamin Fry给了我机会，将我对"创伤治疗"的愿景转化为Khiron House临床项目的日常工作，而那里才华横溢的工作人员则以另一种方式激励着我：他们代表着受创来访者复杂的需求发声。在意大利，Giovanni Tagliavini和Paola Boldrini慷慨地为我提供了分享工作的舞台。他们同样炽热地投身于服务受创来访者（及其各部分）的事业，使他们成为"家人"。特别感谢Giovanni主动提出将本书译成意大利语，也感谢Julian Baillet主动承担法语翻译。在西班牙，我有Dolores Mosquera和Esther Perez这样对这种工作方式的"真诚信徒"，每当我质疑自己所做的事情时，他们的鼓励都是重要的支撑。也要感谢我出色的英国同事和朋友：Catherine Cox、Helen-Jane Ridgeway、Sally-Anne Bubbers、Linda Beton和Liz Hall等人。在波士顿，我亲爱的朋友Lana Epstein贡献了笑声的礼物——无尽的笑声——这是应对作者旅程中压力的最佳解药。在纽约，我要特别感谢Ken Frank、Sandy Shapiro以及Ken的学习小组，感谢他们热情地阅读早期章节。我发现，一位作者需要每一粒热情的碎屑，才能在这漫长而常常令人痛苦的过程中坚持下去。

My gratitude, too, to Dan Brockett, Steve Pierce, and the dedicated State of Connecticut Young Adult Services staff who participated in "test-driving" this model with their very traumatized, high-risk clients. The response we got from our clients affirmed that even severely suicidal and self-harming clients could benefit from understanding their fragmentation and learning to work with it.

我也要感谢Dan Brockett、Steve Pierce以及康涅狄格州青年成人服务机构敬业的工作人员，他们与严重受创的高危来访者一起"试驾"了这一模型。我们从来访者身上得到的回应证明，即便是严重的自杀和自伤来访者，也能从理解自身的碎裂并学会与之共处中获益。

There are so many more friends and colleagues and fellow travelers that I could thank, and I hope you will consider yourself thanked even if I have neglected to mention you by name.

还有更多的朋友、同仁和同路人值得我感谢，如果我疏于提及您的名字，希望您仍能感受到我的感激之情。

Last, but surely not least, I want to thank my children and grandchildren for their love, support, and patience. No one can appreciate what they have sacrificed for "the book": weekends, evenings, vacations, outings, family dinners—for months at a time. On top of that, they have had to be supportive! And they have been. To Jadu, Jason and Kelli, Ruby, and Nika, I am so grateful! I don't know what I would do without your smiling faces and the best hugs ever. You have my heartfelt love and gratitude.

最后，也同样重要的是，我要感谢我的子女和孙辈们给予的爱、支持与耐心。没有人能真正体会他们为"这本书"所做出的牺牲：周末、夜晚、假期、郊游、家庭晚餐——一次就是数月之久。除此之外，他们还必须给予支持！而他们也真的做到了。向Jadu、Jason与Kelli、Ruby和Nika，我深怀感激！没有你们的笑脸和最温暖的拥抱，我不知道该如何是好。你们拥有我由衷的爱与感激。

Introduction

引言

How This Book Came To Be

本书的诞生

Having no way to understand the entrenched self-alienation or intense self-hatred of their traumatized clients, therapists often feel frustrated, baffled, and inadequate to the task of trying to help. Why do they seem to be at war with themselves? Or with us? Although the client has come seeking relief from a burden of trauma-related symptoms and issues, the task of exchanging self-alienation for self-compassion can feel overwhelming or distasteful. Neither client nor therapist has a language with which to explain the internal struggles being played out inside the client’s mind and body. In a mental health world that rejects the notion that personality and identity can be fragmented and compartmentalized, therapists are rarely trained to see the splits, much less the life-or-death battle for control being waged by “selves” with opposite aims and instincts.

面对来访者根深蒂固的自我疏离或强烈的自我憎恨，治疗师往往感到沮丧、困惑，觉得自己无力胜任帮助他人的工作。为什么他们似乎总是在与自己交战？或是与我们交战？尽管来访者带着创伤相关症状和困扰的重担前来寻求解脱，但将自我疏离转化为自我慈悲的任务，却可能让人感到不堪重负或难以接受。来访者和治疗师都没有一套语言，能够解释在来访者心智与身体内部上演的内在挣扎。在一个拒绝承认人格与身份可以碎裂化、分隔化的心理健康世界里，治疗师鲜少受过识别这些分裂的训练，更遑论看见那些目标与本能截然相反的"自我"之间你死我活的控制权争夺。

My intention in writing this book was to share a way of conceptualizing the most complex and challenging clients who come to us, often carrying “terminal” diagnoses, such as personality disorder, bipolar II, even schizophrenia. Over three decades in the trauma treatment field, my compatriots and I have learned about trauma “the hard way,” by letting the clients teach us about their inner worlds, their intrusive, overwhelming symptoms, what it is like to live in a body organized to expect annihilation or abandonment. Lacking approaches specifically tailored to the needs of traumatized clients, all of us “winged it,” creating new techniques and interventions, seeing what “worked,” and retaining what did—either because the interventions were effective or because the clients liked how they felt.

写作本书的初衷，是分享一种概念化框架，用以理解那些来到我们面前、最为复杂且最具挑战性的来访者——他们往往背负着"终极性"诊断，如人格障碍、双相II型障碍，甚至精神分裂症。在创伤治疗领域浸润三十余年，我与同仁们以最艰难的方式学习创伤——让来访者教导我们他们的内心世界、那些侵入性的、排山倒海的症状，以及活在一个预设着毁灭或遗弃的身体里究竟是怎样一种体验。由于缺乏专门针对创伤来访者需求的方法，我们所有人都只能"摸索前行"，创造新的技术与干预手段，观察什么"有效"，并保留那些有效的——无论是因为干预本身起效，还是因为来访者喜欢它所带来的感受。

In the 1990s, as an instructor and supervisor at Bessel van der Kolk’s Trauma Center, I was profoundly influenced by the neuroscience research that began to revolutionize our way of understanding trauma and by Bessel’s belief that “the body keeps the score” (Van der Kolk, 2014). We began then to see trauma-related disorders not as disorders of events but as disorders of the body, brain, and nervous system. The neurobiological lens also resulted in another paradigm shift: if the brain and body are inherently adaptive, then the legacy of trauma responses must also reflect an attempt at adaptation, rather than evidence of pathology.

20世纪90年代，作为Bessel van der Kolk创伤中心的讲师和督导，我深受那场开始颠覆我们创伤理解方式的神经科学研究的影响，也深受Bessel"身体铭记着一切"这一信念的熏陶（Van der Kolk，2014）。我们由此开始将创伤相关障碍视为身体、大脑和神经系统的障碍，而非事件本身的障碍。神经生物学视角也催生了另一次范式转变：如果大脑和身体本质上具有适应性，那么创伤反应的遗留必定也反映着一种适应的尝试，而非病理的证据。

Through that neurobiological lens, what appears clinically as stuckness and resistance, untreatable diagnoses, or character-disordered behavior simply represent how an individual’s mind and body adapted to a dangerous world in which the only “protection” was the very same caretaker who endangered him or her. Each symptom was an ingenious solution by the body to create some semblance of safety for the developing child or endangered adult. The trauma-related issues with which the client presents for help, I now believe, are in truth a “red badge of courage” that tell the story of what happened even more eloquently than the events each individual consciously remembers.

透过神经生物学的视角，那些在临床上表现为停滞和阻抗、难以治疗的诊断或人格障碍行为的现象，不过是个体的心智与身体在一个危险世界中适应的方式——在那个世界里，唯一的"保护"恰恰来自同一个使他或她身陷险境的照料者。每一个症状，都是身体为正在发展中的孩子或身处险境的成人创造某种安全感的精妙解决方案。我现在相信，来访者带来求助的创伤相关问题，实则是一枚"勇敢的红色徽章"，它们讲述所发生之事的方式，比每个人有意识记忆中的事件更加雄辩。

As I came to be known as an expert in treating trauma, increasing numbers of clients sought me out for consultation, asking, “Why am I not getting better? My therapist and I have a wonderful relationship, but none of my symptoms are diminishing. Am I doing the wrong kind of therapy? Or is there something wrong with me?” Time after time, as I heard from clients and therapists what had been tried and failed, I could not find a “mistake” or misguided choice of treatment. More often, what could be seen from the consultant’s perspective was something both therapist and client could not see: the client was fragmented. What it had taken to adapt was a splitting of self and identity sufficiently severe that the individual’s inner world had become a war zone. What I also noticed was the relief these clients experienced as I educated them about dissociative splitting as a normal adaptation to trauma. First describing to them the theory of Structural Dissociation (Van der Hart, Nijenhuis & Steele, 2006), I would then translate their struggles using the language of parts and the language of animal defense survival responses, the cornerstone of the Structural Dissociation theory. Often, as I spoke, I observed a look of recognition on their faces, as if I were telling them nothing new but simply giving them a language to describe at long last what they already recognized but had no words to explain. Rather than feeling stigmatized or “crazier,” the Structural Dissociation model seemed to be reassuring to them. Its central principle, that splitting had simply allowed them to adapt and survive more successfully in an unsafe world, helped even very proud, narcissistic individuals to experience the fragmentation as a validation of their survival, not further proof of their defectiveness.

随着我在创伤治疗领域的专家声誉日渐建立，越来越多的来访者找到我寻求咨询，他们问道："为什么我没有好转？我和治疗师的关系很好，但我的症状没有一点减轻。我是在做错误的治疗吗？还是我本身有什么问题？"一次又一次，当我从来访者和治疗师那里听到已经尝试过但失败了的一切时，我找不到任何"错误"或治疗选择上的失误。更多时候，从咨询师的视角可以看到一些治疗师和来访者都无法看见的东西：来访者是碎裂的。这种适应所需要的，是一种严重到足以让个体内心世界变成战场的自我与身份分裂。我还注意到，当我向这些来访者介绍解离性分裂是对创伤的正常适应时，他们所体验到的释然。首先向他们描述结构性解离理论（Van der Hart, Nijenhuis和Steele，2006），我随后用"部分"的语言和动物防御生存反应的语言——结构性解离理论的基石——来诠释他们的挣扎。往往，在我讲述的过程中，我观察到他们脸上浮现出一种认出的神情，仿佛我所说的并非什么新鲜事，只是给了他们一种语言，终于能够描述他们早已认出却无言以名的东西。结构性解离模型非但没有让他们感到被污名化或"更疯狂"，反而似乎给了他们安慰。其核心原则——分裂只是让他们能够在不安全的世界中更成功地适应和生存——甚至帮助那些非常自尊、自恋的个体，将碎裂化体验为对其生存的认可，而非对其缺陷性的进一步证明。

As I worked in this way with a range of clients, it became increasingly clear that when they “adopted” or came to love their hurt, lost, and lonely parts, something remarkable happened. Their self-disparagement, self-hatred, and disconnection began spontaneously to yield to self-compassion. Whereas the idea of being “nice,” “taking care of” or being “compassionate” to themselves was met with disgust and avoidance, every client could be helped to “see” his or her child parts and to extend kindness and care. And as they developed internal attachment relationships to these young selves, I could see them healing.

当我以这种方式与各类来访者工作时，越来越清晰地看到：当他们"收养"或开始爱上自己受伤、迷失和孤独的部分时，某种非凡的事情发生了。他们的自我贬低、自我憎恨和断离感，开始自发地向自我慈悲让步。尽管对自己"好"、"照顾"自己或对自己"充满慈悲"的想法往往引发厌恶和回避，但每一位来访者都能被引导去"看见"自己的儿童部分，并向其延伸善意与关怀。而随着他们与这些年幼的自我发展出内在依恋关系，我能看见他们在愈合。

What it means to “heal” is subjective, of course: for some clients, it implies the ability to function again, to simply reclaim their lives. But, as I observed the clients who began forming loving attachment bonds to their young selves, I could see healing at a much deeper level. Seeing them “bond” with the child they had once been and feeling their shame and self-hatred melt away convinced me that the left brain “adult” side of each one was capable of relating to the right brain “child” side, experiencing him or her as innocent and little, spontaneously evoking warmth and protectiveness. By bonding to the lost children inside, their internal states transformed, creating a warm, loving environment that felt safe at last. Best of all, it was evident that this work was not only transformative but also easy for the clients once they learned the basic skills needed to form internal attachment relationships to their parts.

"愈合"意味着什么，当然是主观的：对某些来访者而言，它意味着重新能够正常运作，简单地夺回自己的生活。但当我观察那些开始与年幼自我建立爱的依恋纽带的来访者时，我看到了更深层次的愈合。看见他们与曾经的那个孩子"联结"，感受到他们的羞耻感和自我憎恨渐渐消融，这让我确信：每个人左脑的"成人"一侧，都有能力与右脑的"儿童"一侧建立关系，将其体验为无辜而幼小，自发地唤起温暖与保护欲。通过与内在那些迷失的孩子建立联结，他们的内在状态发生了转化，创造出一个温暖、充满爱的环境，终于让人感到安全。最重要的是，显而易见的是，一旦来访者学会了与自己的部分建立内在依恋关系所需的基本技能，这项工作不仅具有转化性，而且对他们来说也是轻松可及的。

The book is intended for use by a wide range of therapists and for an even wider range of clients. In writing it, I hoped particularly to address the challenges faced by chronically traumatized individuals much like those who have sought me out for consultations. These are clients young and old who battle to recover from their legacies of trauma, confused that these have not resolved despite good therapy, effective treatments, supportive relationships, or even rich full lives in the present. I also wanted to describe an effective and respectful way of working with traumatized clients who have lost their hope and ability to function or who depend upon hospitals, families, and loved ones to care for them as they struggle with self-destructive impulses driving suicidal, self-harming, addicted, or eating disordered behavior. Despite decades of research attesting to the relationship between early abuse and a later diagnosis of borderline personality disorder, it is rare for clients with borderline diagnoses to be treated as trauma patients or to be recognized as individuals whose “borderline” symptoms stem logically and tragically from the unsafe environments of their early lives. Thanks to enlightened Departments of Mental Health in the states of Massachusetts and Connecticut, I have had the invaluable opportunity to try out the treatment model described in this book with some of their most high-risk patients and to find that, with a treatment model organized around trauma-related splitting and compartmentalization, these patients could begin to stabilize, to live outside of institutional walls, and to understand their attacks on the body as a valiant attempt by one part to gain quick short-term relief from the painful implicit memories of other parts. This book is also meant for traumatized clients who have “overcome,” who have prestigious jobs and loving families of choice, whose lives are rich and full, but who still struggle to enjoy the quality of life they have fought to create. And the book is also intended to offer hope to individuals who may be stable but whose internal quality of life is still as dark and painful as the traumatic past despite the safety, support, and meaningful work in their external lives.

本书旨在供各类治疗师及更广泛的来访者群体使用。在撰写过程中，我特别希望回应那些慢性创伤个体所面临的挑战——他们与那些来找我咨询的来访者颇为相似。这些来访者无论老幼，都在艰难挣扎，试图从创伤的遗留中恢复，却困惑于为何即便经历了良好的治疗、有效的疗法、支持性的关系，甚至目前生活富足充实，这些创伤仍未消解。我也想描述一种有效且尊重来访者的工作方式，用于那些已失去希望与功能能力的创伤来访者，或那些在与驱动自杀、自伤、成瘾或进食障碍行为的自毁冲动抗争时，依赖医院、家人和爱人照料的来访者。尽管数十年的研究证实了早期虐待与日后边缘型人格障碍诊断之间的关系，但被诊断为边缘型人格障碍的来访者却鲜少被当作创伤患者对待，也鲜少被视为那些"边缘型"症状在逻辑上、悲剧性地源于其早期不安全环境的个体。感谢马萨诸塞州和康涅狄格州开明的心理健康部门，我获得了宝贵的机会，将本书所描述的治疗模式在一些高风险患者身上加以实践，并发现：以创伤相关分裂和分隔化为核心组织的治疗模式，能够帮助这些患者开始趋于稳定，在机构围墙之外生活，并将对身体的攻击理解为某一部分试图从其他部分痛苦的内隐记忆中获得快速短期解脱的英勇尝试。本书也是为那些已经"克服困难"的创伤来访者而写——他们有着令人瞩目的工作和自己选择的充满爱的家庭，生活丰富而充实，却仍在努力享受他们拼搏所创造的生活品质。本书同样旨在为那些虽然稳定，但其内在生活品质依然与外部生活的安全、支持和有意义的工作相悖、仍像创伤过去一样黑暗痛苦的个体提供希望。

The treatment paradigm described in this book is not intended for the treatment of any one particular diagnosis. It is meant to be used with and on behalf of all survivors of trauma, whether the client carries a diagnosis of post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD), has been given a common trauma-related diagnosis such as ADHD, bipolar disorder, borderline personality, or a dissociative disorder, or has never met a mental health professional. If you, the reader, have been failed, attacked, threatened, abandoned, terrorized, or abused by other human beings, and if you still carry with you the emotional and physical legacy of those experiences, or if you work to help those who do, I believe this book will speak to you.

本书所描述的治疗范式，并非针对任何特定诊断的治疗。它旨在被用于所有创伤幸存者及为他们服务——无论来访者是否携带创伤后应激障碍（PTSD）的诊断，是否被给予常见的创伤相关诊断如ADHD、双相障碍、边缘型人格或解离障碍，或者是否从未接触过心理健康专业人员。如果您，读者，曾被他人辜负、攻击、威胁、遗弃、恐吓或虐待，而您仍然带着那些经历的情感与身体遗留，或者您正在帮助那些有此经历的人，我相信这本书会与您产生共鸣。

Fragmentation and Internal Struggles

碎裂化与内在挣扎

Ten years ago, in the context of consulting with traumatized clients who came to me as an “expert,” seeking to understand why they were not making progress in treatment, I began to observe a very characteristic pattern: these clients had something unique in common. Each was superficially an integrated whole person but also manifested clear-cut signs of being internally fragmented. They experienced intense conflicts between trauma-related perceptions and impulses (for example, “the worst is going to happen,” “I will be abandoned if I don’t get out first”) versus here-and-now assessments of danger: “I know I’m safe here. I wouldn’t let my children live in this house if it were not safe.” They suffered from paradoxical symptoms: the desire to be kind and compassionate toward others or to live a spiritual life, on the one hand, and intense rage or even impulses to violence, on the other. Once their conflicts were described, the patterns became more easily observable and meaningful. Each side of the conflict spoke to a different way of surviving the unsurvivable, of reconciling the opposites that are so often part and parcel of traumatic experience. With an explanatory model that described each reaction as logical and necessary in the face of threat or abandonment and that reframed them as the survival responses of different parts of the self, to which the individual could relate, each client started to make faster, more sustainable progress. The theoretical model that best explained the phenomena they described was the Structural Dissociation model of Onno van der Hart, Ellert Nijenhuis, and Kathy Steele (2004). Rooted in a neuroscience perspective and well-accepted throughout Europe as a trauma model, it was a good fit for me as a firm believer and spokesperson for a neurobiologically informed approach to trauma and trauma treatment. The theory describes (Van der Hart, Nijenhuis & Steele, 2006) how the brain’s innate physical structure and two separate, specialized hemispheres facilitate left brain-right brain disconnection under conditions of threat. Capitalizing on the tendency of the left brain to remain positive, task-oriented, and logical under stress, these writers hypothesized that the disconnected left brain side of the personality stays focused on the tasks of daily living, while the other hemisphere fosters an implicit right brain self that remains in survival mode, braced for danger, ready to run, frozen in fear, praying for rescue, or too ashamed to do anything but submit. In each individual client, I could see that some parts were easier to identify with or “own” and some parts were easier to ignore or dismiss as “not me.” Internally, the parts were also in conflict: was it safer to freeze or fight? To cry for help? Or to be seen and not heard? What I also noticed was that the internal relationships between these fragmented aspects of self reflected the traumatic environments for which they had once been solutions. The left-brain-dominant present-oriented self avoids the right-brain-dominant survival-oriented parts or judges them as bad qualities to be modified, while the right brain implicit selves of the parts are equally alienated from what they perceive as a “weak” or absent other half. The functioning self carries on, trying desperately to be “normal”—at the cost of feeling alienated from or invaded by the intrusive communications of the parts.

十年前，在与创伤来访者的咨询过程中——他们将我视为"专家"寻求帮助，试图理解为何在治疗中毫无进展——我开始观察到一种极具特征性的模式：这些来访者有一种独特的共同之处。每个人表面上都是一个完整的整体，但同时也表现出内在碎裂化的明确迹象。他们经历着创伤相关感知和冲动（例如，"最坏的情况即将发生"，"如果我不先逃走，我会被遗弃"）与对当下危险的现实评估之间的激烈冲突："我知道我在这里是安全的。如果这所房子不安全，我不会让我的孩子住在这里。"他们承受着悖论性的症状：一方面渴望对他人仁慈、充满慈悲，或过一种精神性的生活，另一方面却有着强烈的愤怒，甚至暴力冲动。一旦他们的冲突被描述出来，这些模式就变得更容易观察和理解。冲突的每一方，都讲述着一种在无法生存中生存下来的不同方式，一种调和那些往往是创伤体验一部分的对立面的方式。有了一个能够将每种反应描述为在威胁或遗弃面前合乎逻辑且必要的解释性模型，并将其重构为个体可以认同的自我不同部分的生存反应，每位来访者都开始取得更快、更可持续的进展。最能解释他们所描述现象的理论模型，是Onno van der Hart、Ellert Nijenhuis和Kathy Steele（2004）的结构性解离模型。这一模型植根于神经科学视角，在欧洲作为创伤模型被广泛接受，对于我这位神经生物学知情创伤治疗方法的坚定信奉者和倡导者而言，它非常契合。该理论描述了（Van der Hart, Nijenhuis和Steele，2006）大脑固有的物理结构和两个独立的专业化半球如何在威胁条件下促进左脑-右脑的断联。利用左脑在压力下保持积极、任务导向和逻辑性的倾向，这些作者假设，断联的人格左脑一侧始终专注于日常生活的任务，而另一半球则滋养着一个内隐的右脑自我，它停留在生存模式中，为危险做好准备，随时准备逃跑，冻结在恐惧中，祈求救援，或因太过羞耻而只能顺从。在每位来访者身上，我都能看到某些部分更容易被认同或"认领"，而另一些部分则更容易被忽视或否定为"不是我"。在内部，各部分之间也存在冲突：冻结还是战斗，哪个更安全？哭泣求助吗？还是被看见却不被倾听？我还注意到，这些碎裂化的自我方面之间的内在关系，反映了它们曾经作为解决方案的那个创伤性环境。左脑主导的面向当下的自我，回避或将右脑主导的生存导向部分评判为需要改变的不良品质，而各部分的右脑内隐自我，同样疏离于它们所感知到的"软弱"或缺席的另一半。功能性自我继续前行，拼命试图"正常"——代价是感到被疏离，或被各部分的侵入性沟通所入侵。

The Price of Self-Alienation: A “False Self”

自我疏离的代价："虚假自我"

Survivors of abuse, neglect, and other traumatic experiences often report functioning better as a result of their compartmentalization but then suffer from feelings of fraudulence or “pretending.” Not realizing that each side of the personality is equally “real” and necessary from an evolutionary standpoint, clients easily misinterpret the intense, palpable feeling memories of the “not me” child as more “real” than the experience of the “going on with normal life self,” doggedly “putting one foot in front of the other,” or “keeping on keeping on” even in the face of overwhelming pain. Without an explanatory paradigm that makes sense of these contradictions, there is no way for individuals to know that their intense feelings and distorted perceptions are evidence of fragmentation, not proof of internal defectiveness or fraudulence masked by the ability to function.

遭受虐待、忽视和其他创伤性体验的幸存者，往往报告说由于自己的分隔化而功能运作得更好，但随后却遭受着欺诈感或"假装"感的折磨。由于没有意识到人格的每一面从进化角度来说都同样是"真实"且必要的，来访者容易将"非我"的儿童那些强烈、可感知的感受记忆，误读为比"正常生活中的自我"的体验更加"真实"——那个倔强地"一步一步向前走"、或即使面对排山倒海的痛苦也"坚持下去"的自我。如果没有一个能够解释这些矛盾的解释性范式，个体就无从知晓，他们强烈的感受和扭曲的感知是碎裂化的证据，而非由功能运作能力所掩盖的内在缺陷性或欺诈性的证明。

Over time, self-alienation can only be maintained by most individuals at the cost of increasingly greater self-loathing, disconnection from emotion, addictive or self-destructive behavior, and internal struggles between vulnerability and control, love and hate, closeness and distance, shame and pride. While longing to be loved, safe, and welcome, many traumatized clients find themselves alternating between anxious clinging and pushing others away, hating themselves or having little patience with the flaws of others, yearning to be seen and yearning to be invisible. Years later, they present in therapy with symptoms of anxiety, chronic depression, low self-esteem, stuckness in life, or diagnoses such as PTSD, bipolar disorder, borderline personality disorder, even dissociative disorders. Unaware that their symptoms are being driven not just by the traumatic events but by an internal attachment disorder mirroring the traumatic attachment of early childhood, therapist and client have no framework for understanding the chaos and/or stuckness that may soon elude their best efforts at treatment.

随着时间推移，对大多数个体而言，维持自我疏离只能以越来越强烈的自我厌恶、与情绪的断联、成瘾或自毁行为，以及脆弱与控制、爱与恨、亲近与距离、羞耻与自尊之间的内在挣扎为代价。尽管渴望被爱、安全和被接纳，许多受创伤的来访者却发现自己在焦虑地依附他人与推开他人之间交替摇摆，对自己充满憎恨或对他人的缺陷缺乏耐心，既渴望被看见又渴望隐于无形。多年以后，他们带着焦虑症状、慢性抑郁、低自尊、生活停滞，或PTSD、双相障碍、边缘型人格障碍甚至解离障碍等诊断出现在治疗中。治疗师和来访者都没有意识到，症状不仅仅被创伤事件驱动，还被一种内在依恋障碍所驱动——这种障碍映射着早期童年的创伤性依恋——因而对于可能很快超出他们最佳治疗努力的混乱和/或停滞，他们没有任何理解框架。

Traumatic Attachment as a Complication in Trauma Therapy

创伤性依恋作为创伤治疗中的复杂因素

In the trauma treatment world in which I have practiced professionally over the past 25 years, generations of “best treatment” models have been repeatedly challenged by client vulnerability to being triggered by apparently innocuous stimuli, swept into the “trauma vortex,” and overwhelmed with painful emotions and physiological responses. For some clients, the present feels little better than the past. Since my postdoctoral fellowship in Judith Herman’s clinic in 1991 and arrival at Bessel van der Kolk’s Trauma Center in 1995 as a supervisor and instructor, my colleagues and I, led by Bessel van der Kolk, have been on a quest to find new methods or interventions that might help free our clients from the insidious impact of the traumatic past—but, even as each is an improvement on the last, we always come up somewhat short. Each new understanding or sophisticated treatment method helps some clients we haven’t before been able to reach, but it doesn’t bring resolution for all—or each brings relief in some symptoms while not alleviating others. And for some traumatized clients, the course of treatment even over the long term seems to consist of two effortful steps forward followed by a slide backward—pushing the proverbial boulder up a steep hill this week only to find by the next session that it is right back at the bottom again. Even more challenging, some clients find that their trauma-related wishes and fears of relationship are so equally intense that therapy and the therapist evoke painful yearning, mistrust, hypervigilance, and anger, or fear and shame, rather than feelings of safety and comfort. It was my hope in writing this book that the treatment approach described here would create a way for these clients and their therapists to navigate these challenges and resolve them.

在我执业二十五年的创伤治疗世界里，一代又一代的"最佳治疗"模式被反复挑战——来访者极易被表面上看似无害的刺激触发，被卷入"创伤漩涡"，被痛苦的情绪和生理反应所淹没。对某些来访者而言，当下的感受与过去相比好不了多少。自1991年在Judith Herman诊所完成博士后研究，以及1995年以督导和讲师身份加入Bessel van der Kolk的创伤中心以来，我和同事们在Bessel van der Kolk的带领下，一直在寻求能够帮助来访者从创伤过去的潜移默化影响中解脱出来的新方法或干预手段——但即便每一种都是对上一种的改进，我们总还是有所欠缺。每一种新的理解或精密的治疗方法，都能帮助我们以前无法触及的一些来访者，但并不能为所有人带来解决——或者每一种都能缓解某些症状，却无法减轻其他症状。对某些受创伤的来访者而言，即便是长期的治疗过程，似乎也只是由两步艰难的前进接着一次滑落所构成——本周费尽力气将那块众所周知的巨石推上陡峭的山坡，下一次治疗却发现它又滚回了底部。更具挑战性的是，一些来访者发现他们与关系有关的愿望和恐惧同样强烈，以至于治疗和治疗师唤起的是痛苦的渴望、不信任、高度警觉和愤怒，或恐惧和羞耻，而非安全与舒适的感觉。撰写本书时，我的希望是，书中描述的治疗方法能为这些来访者及其治疗师提供一条应对并化解这些挑战的路径。

Stuckness: Trauma-Related Internal Conflicts

停滞：创伤相关的内在冲突

Often, at this point, the client reports feeling worse instead of better, and the therapist begins to question his or her ability. Each wonders, “Am I doing something wrong?” What neither client nor therapist realizes is that stuckness in treatment reflects trauma-related internal conflicts between fragmented selves being played out on the stage of the psychotherapy. In questioning our ability as therapists or generalizing client behavior as “transference” or “resistance,” we miss the opportunity to become witnesses to the reenactment occurring inside the client’s fragmented inner world. Not understanding that fragmentation of the personality can result in simultaneous, strongly held opposing goals, such as “I want to die” and “I am determined to live,” or “I want to be connected, but I don’t want anyone to know I care.” Or “I loathe and despise myself, I look up to others above me, and then I loathe and despise them when I see that they’re not better than any other authority figure.”

往往到了这个时刻，来访者报告感觉更糟而非更好，治疗师开始怀疑自己的能力。双方都在疑惑："是我做错了什么吗？"然而，来访者和治疗师都没有意识到的是，治疗中的停滞反映了碎裂化自我之间创伤相关的内在冲突，正在心理治疗的舞台上上演。当我们质疑自己作为治疗师的能力，或将来访者的行为笼统地归结为"移情"或"阻抗"时，我们错过了成为来访者碎裂化内心世界中重演现象的见证者的机会。我们没有理解到，人格的碎裂化可能导致同时并存且强烈持有的对立目标，例如"我想死"与"我决心活下去"，或"我想有连接，但我不想让任何人知道我在乎"，又或"我憎恨和鄙视自己，我仰望高于我的他人，然后当我发现他们并不比任何其他权威人物更好时，我又憎恨和鄙视他们"。

Although written for the therapist committed to finding ways to better help clients for whom other methods haven’t been quite right or complete, this book is also written on behalf of the trauma survivor who comes to therapy as a client. Since the early 1990s, I have been looking for gentler, less retraumatizing ways of treating the effects of traumatic experience. It never made sense to me that a therapy for those who have been badly hurt should have to cause the same intensity of pain. I have always believed that it was bad enough for my clients to have lost their childhoods or adolescence, but it was absolutely unacceptable to allow the legacy of trauma to deprive them of their adult lives, too. And it has equally felt unacceptable that processing trauma should be as frightening and overwhelming as the early experiences themselves, that all subsequent relationships, even the therapeutic ones, should feel as threatening as those in childhood. When we are young, our caregivers have almost total control over our inner worlds and the power to evoke in us both painful and pleasurable emotions as well as lay down expectancies for how relationships work. When we have survived to adulthood with its promise of autonomy, we finally have the ability to move away from painful experiences, to choose how much or how little to trust, to negotiate boundaries and intimacy—but that’s not how survivors of trauma feel. Their bodies still remember the experience of “no control” over pleasure or pain. My purpose in developing this approach was to describe a way of coming to terms with trauma that felt healing; that spoke to survival, not victimization; that created warm and pleasurable feelings in the body rather than terrifying ones.

虽然本书主要是为那些致力于寻找更好方法来帮助那些其他方法还不够恰当或完整的来访者的治疗师所写，但它同时也是代表以来访者身份前来接受治疗的创伤幸存者而写。自20世纪90年代初以来，我一直在寻找更温和、更少造成再创伤的方式来治疗创伤体验的影响。对我来说，为那些曾经受到严重伤害的人提供的治疗，必须引发同等强度的痛苦，这一逻辑从来就说不通。我一直认为，我的来访者已经因失去童年或青少年时期而蒙受了足够大的损失，但允许创伤的遗留再剥夺他们的成年生活，是绝对无法接受的。同样无法接受的是，加工创伤应该像早期创伤体验本身一样令人恐惧和不堪重负，所有后续关系，甚至是治疗关系，应该感觉和童年时期的关系一样充满威胁。当我们年幼时，照料者对我们的内心世界拥有近乎完全的控制权，以及在我们内心唤起既痛苦又愉悦情绪的力量，并为关系如何运作奠定期望。当我们成年并拥有自主权的承诺时，我们终于有了远离痛苦体验的能力，有了选择信任多少或多少的能力，有了协商边界和亲密度的能力——但这不是创伤幸存者的感受。他们的身体仍然记得在快乐或痛苦面前"没有控制权"的体验。我发展这种方法的目的，是描述一种与创伤和解的方式——它感觉像是愈合；它诉说的是生存，而非受害；它在身体中创造温暖和愉悦的感受，而非令人恐惧的感受。

This book is intended to appeal to clients and therapists working with trauma, attachment disorders, and dissociation as these manifest in complex and paradoxical symptoms, alienation from self, internal conflicts, and troubled therapeutic relationships or impasses. Therapists routinely are stymied by the effects of self-alienation on the therapy: shame, punitive self-hatred, separation anxiety and fear of abandonment, self-destructive behavior, inability to self-soothe or self-care, fears of hope, happiness, and compassion for self. Psychotherapist training programs provide little information on traumatic attachment, or on how undiagnosed trauma-related fragmentation or splitting can complicate straightforward resolution of trauma, or on the treatment of dissociative disorders as one of a constellation of trauma-related disorders. Healing traumatic wounds and trauma-related fragmentation is ultimately dependent upon the individual’s relationship to self—or to his or her “selves.” Self-alienation will always impede resolution of the past by creating an internal Berlin Wall standing in the way of acceptance that “it” happened and an ability to welcome home the child who endured and survived it.

本书旨在引起那些与创伤、依恋障碍和解离共同工作的来访者和治疗师的共鸣——这些问题以复杂且悖论性的症状、自我疏离、内在冲突以及困难的治疗关系或僵局的形式呈现。治疗师经常受到自我疏离对治疗的影响所困扰：羞耻感、惩罚性的自我憎恨、分离焦虑和对遗弃的恐惧、自毁行为、无法自我安抚或自我照料、对希望、幸福和自我慈悲的恐惧。心理治疗师培训项目很少提供关于创伤性依恋的信息，或关于未被诊断的创伤相关碎裂化或分裂如何复杂化创伤的直接解决，或关于解离障碍作为创伤相关障碍群之一的治疗信息。创伤伤口和创伤相关碎裂化的愈合，最终依赖于个体与自我——或与其"众多自我"的关系。自我疏离将始终阻碍对过去的解决，它在内心竖起一道柏林墙，妨碍接受"它"确实发生过，以及欢迎那个忍受并幸存下来的孩子回家的能力。

How This Book Is Organized

本书的结构安排

Like all books, this one reflects its author’s experience and theoretical paradigms. For me, as a practicing clinician whose professional homes have been Bessel van der Kolk’s Trauma Center (since 1996) and Pat Ogden’s Sensorimotor Psychotherapy Institute (since 2003), the theoretical models for understanding trauma to which I am committed have their origins in neuroscience and attachment research. It is important to me that we as therapists understand why we are choosing one treatment or intervention over another. Even when the interventions I choose are not immediately “successful,” I can still look to the theory to help me understand why—so that my next intervention can be informed by what was missing in the last. In the chapters that follow, I will be integrating a theoretical understanding of trauma, dissociation, neurobiology, and attachment with a practical, “hand’s on” approach to the treatment of these issues that is intended to be accessible to both client and therapist. To help clients reach below the level of “talking about,” interventions drawn from a number of therapeutic approaches were integrated into this way of working, including Sensorimotor Psychotherapy (Ogden et al., 2006), Internal Family Systems (Schwartz, 2001), mindfulness-based approaches (Pollack, Pedulla & Siegel, 2014), and clinical hypnosis.

如同所有书籍一样，这本书也反映了作者的经验和理论范式。对我而言，作为一名执业临床工作者，我的专业归属地一直是Bessel van der Kolk的创伤中心（自1996年起）和Pat Ogden的感觉运动心理治疗研究所（自2003年起），我所信奉的理解创伤的理论模型，其根源在于神经科学和依恋研究。对我而言，重要的是我们作为治疗师理解为什么在各种治疗和干预手段之间做出某种选择。即使我所选择的干预手段没有立竿见影地"成功"，我仍然可以借助理论来理解原因——这样我的下一个干预手段就能从上一个所缺少的东西中获得启示。在接下来的章节中，我将把对创伤、解离、神经生物学和依恋的理论理解，与一种旨在对来访者和治疗师都易于获取的、处理这些问题的实践性、"动手"方法相整合。为了帮助来访者触及"谈论"层面以下的内容，来自多种治疗方法的干预手段被整合进这种工作方式，包括感觉运动心理治疗（Ogden等，2006）、内在家庭系统（Schwartz，2001）、正念为基础的方法（Pollack, Pedulla和Siegel，2014）以及临床催眠。

As I set out to create a way of working clinically with the Structural Dissociation model, being a practitioner and teacher of Sensorimotor Psychotherapy (Ogden & Fisher, 2015; Ogden et al., 2006), it was only natural to start by integrating my understanding of the body and nervous system with what I knew about parts from working with clients with dissociative identity disorder (DID). Because each part in Structural Dissociation theory is driven by an animal defense response (i.e., fight, flight, etc.), the connection to the body was easy to make. How the body organizes to flee is distinctly different than how it organizes to fight or feign death. But Sensorimotor Psychotherapy speaks the language of the body, so I still needed a language of parts. Richard Schwartz’ (1995) Internal Family Systems (IFS) approach, upon which I had drawn heavily in my work with DID clients years earlier, teaches therapists to become fluent in speaking the language of parts. Not only are they asked to speak the language with their clients, but they are also expected to become mindful of their own parts. Because both IFS and Sensorimotor Psychotherapy are mindfulness-based treatment models, they also fit perfectly with my “mindfulness of parts” approach in which I help clients learn at first just to mindfully scan their bodies and feeling states for the communications from their fragmented selves.

当我着手构建在临床上运用结构性解离模型的工作方式时，作为感觉运动心理治疗的实践者和教师（Ogden和Fisher，2015；Ogden等，2006），从整合我对身体和神经系统的理解与我从与解离性身份障碍（DID）来访者工作中所了解的关于"部分"的知识出发，是再自然不过的了。由于结构性解离理论中每个部分都由动物防御反应（即战斗、逃跑等）所驱动，与身体的联系是容易建立的。身体组织逃跑的方式，与其组织战斗或装死的方式截然不同。但感觉运动心理治疗使用的是身体的语言，所以我仍然需要一套关于"部分"的语言。Richard Schwartz（1995）的内在家庭系统（IFS）方法——我多年前在与DID来访者工作时曾大量借鉴——教导治疗师流利地使用"部分"的语言。他们不仅被要求在与来访者交流时使用这种语言，还被期待对自己的部分保持正念觉察。由于IFS和感觉运动心理治疗都是以正念为基础的治疗模型，它们也完美地契合了我的"对部分的正念"方法——在这种方法中，我帮助来访者首先学会正念地扫描自己的身体和感受状态，寻找来自碎裂化自我的沟通。

What had drawn me originally to IFS for help in working with DID was the concept of “self” and “self”-leadership. (Schwartz, 2001) “Self” refers to innate qualities possessed by all human beings in undamaged form, no matter how much abuse and trauma they have experienced. These qualities include curiosity, clarity (the ability for meta-awareness or perspective), creativity, calm, courage, confidence, and commitment. Healing in IFS is the outcome of providing these qualities as an antidote to the painful experiences suffered by exiled child parts. With my DID clients, I had found it immensely stabilizing to help their adult selves grow these “C” qualities and to help the child parts learn to turn to a “self-led” wise adult self who could reassure their fears and loneliness. As I began to see that fragmentation was not limited just to clients with dissociative disorders, the Structural Dissociation model and IFS provided some welcome support. Structural Dissociation theory is a trauma theory, applying equally to clients with PTSD, complex PTSD, and borderline personality disorder. IFS is a parts theory, applying equally to all human beings, not just traumatized individuals with dissociative disorders. Feeling supported by these ideas, I began to use my “blend” of sensorimotor and IFS interventions and techniques with complex PTSD clients, with clients who came for consultations and were willing to try out different approaches. I also increasingly used it whenever I encountered a client who was stuck, in crisis, in turmoil or “terminal ambivalence.” Just as with borderline clients, the mindfulness approach and the attribution of each and every symptom to parts (drawn from IFS) created “breathing space” that allowed clients to be curious about these parts, less afraid, even to feel empathy for them.

最初吸引我转向IFS以帮助处理DID工作的，是"自我"（Self）和"自我"领导力的概念（Schwartz，2001）。"自我"指的是所有人类在未受损状态下所拥有的内在品质，无论他们经历过多少虐待和创伤。这些品质包括好奇心、清晰度（元意识或视角的能力）、创造力、平静、勇气、自信和承诺。IFS中的愈合，是将这些品质作为解药提供给被流放的儿童部分所遭受的痛苦体验的结果。在与DID来访者的工作中，我发现帮助他们的成人自我培育这些"C"品质，并帮助儿童部分学会转向一个能够安抚其恐惧和孤独感的"自我主导"的智慧成人自我，具有极大的稳定作用。当我开始意识到碎裂化并不仅限于有解离障碍的来访者时，结构性解离模型和IFS提供了一些受欢迎的支持。结构性解离理论是一种创伤理论，同样适用于PTSD、复杂性PTSD和边缘型人格障碍的来访者。IFS是一种关于"部分"的理论，同样适用于所有人类，而不仅仅是有解离障碍的受创伤个体。在这些理念的支持下，我开始将感觉运动和IFS干预技术的"混合"用于复杂性PTSD来访者，用于那些前来咨询且愿意尝试不同方法的来访者。我也越来越多地在遇到陷入停滞、危机、混乱或"终极矛盾心理"的来访者时使用它。就像与边缘型来访者一样，正念方法和将每一个症状都归因于部分（源自IFS）创造了"喘息空间"，使来访者能够对这些部分感到好奇，不那么害怕，甚至对它们产生共情。

Chapter 1, Alienation from Self: How We Survive Overwhelming Experience, sets the stage by describing dissociative splitting and fragmentation as an adaptive response to abnormal experience. To create distance from overwhelming events and preserve a sense of “a good me,” individuals must disown the self-states of which they are ashamed, intimidated, or experience as “not-me,” allowing them to also disown the trauma (Bromberg, 2011). The ability to encode two parallel sets of experiences in one brain and body is supported by the “split-brain research” in the 1970s and 1980s (Gazzaniga, 1985) and by the neuroscience brain scan research in the late 1990s and 2000s demonstrating how traumatic events come to be encoded as implicit emotional and physical states, rather than being encoded in the form of chronological narrative. The introduction of the Structural Dissociation model in 2000 provided the first neuroscientific understanding of dissociative splitting and compartmentalization (Van der Hart et al., 2000). Unlike earlier models of dissociative fragmentation, this theory does not emphasize the compartmentalization of memory. Instead, its central tenet is that structural dissociation is a survival-oriented adaptive response to the specific demands of traumatic environments, facilitating a left brain-right brain split that supports the disowning of “not me” or trauma-related parts and the ability to function without awareness of having been traumatized. The splitting also supports development of parts driven by animal defenses that serve the cause of survival in the face of danger. Chapter 1 provides a theoretical foundation for understanding both neurobiologically informed trauma work and the need for a parts approach to treatment. Working with a parts approach allows therapists to work more effectively with complex and personality disorder clients. In this model, these clients are not “acting out,” “manipulative,” “resistant,” or “unmotivated.” Their trauma-related parts, activated by normal life stimuli, driven by implicit trauma responses, experience the sense of threat and automatically engage instinctive responses: fight, flight, cry for help, freeze, or “feign death” (Porges, 2011).

第1章《与自我疏离：我们如何在排山倒海的体验中生存》，以将解离性分裂和碎裂化描述为对异常体验的适应性反应为开场，奠定基础。为了与排山倒海的事件保持距离，并保留对"一个好我"的感知，个体必须否认那些让自己感到羞耻、恐惧或体验为"非我"的自我状态，从而也能否认创伤本身（Bromberg，2011）。在一个大脑和身体中对两套平行体验进行编码的能力，得到了20世纪70至80年代"裂脑研究"（Gazzaniga，1985）以及20世纪90年代末和21世纪初神经科学脑扫描研究的支持，后者证明创伤事件是如何以内隐的情绪和身体状态形式被编码，而非以时间顺序叙事的形式。2000年结构性解离模型的引入，提供了对解离性分裂和分隔化的第一个神经科学理解（Van der Hart等，2000）。与早期解离性碎裂化模型不同，该理论并不强调记忆的分隔化。相反，其核心主张是，结构性解离是对创伤性环境特定需求的一种生存导向的适应性反应，它促进了左脑-右脑的分裂，支持了对"非我"或创伤相关部分的否认，以及在没有意识到自己曾受创伤的情况下维持功能的能力。这种分裂也支持了由动物防御驱动的、在危险面前服务于生存目的的部分的发展。第1章为理解神经生物学知情创伤工作和部分治疗方法的必要性提供了理论基础。以部分方法工作，使治疗师能够更有效地与复杂和人格障碍来访者共事。在这一模型中，这些来访者不是在"付诸行动"、"操纵性"、"阻抗"或"缺乏动机"。他们与创伤相关的部分，被日常生活刺激激活，由内隐创伤反应驱动，体验到威胁感，并自动启动本能反应：战斗、逃跑、哭泣求援、冻结或"装死"（Porges，2011）。

In Chapter 2, Understanding Parts, Understanding Traumatic Responses, we explore the implications of the neuroscience research on traumatic memory as a basis for understanding and recognizing the signs of fragmented parts as they will appear in client presentations. A simplified understanding of the emergency stress response to threat is presented and how the legacy of trauma becomes encoded in the body. It is important to know how body-based trauma responses drive animal defense impulses to unsafe behavior, why the left-brain-related “normal life” self may observe helplessly but cannot hold back the impulses to action. Underlying automatic hypervigilance, reactivity, suspiciousness, and impulsive action-taking is the body’s autonomic nervous system, which governs action and inaction, strong emotions and numbing. In the wake of trauma, the nervous system adapts to a threatening world, conditioned to be “at the ready” for impending danger and therefore biased to mobilize sympathetic hyperarousal or parasympathetic hypoarousal or both, depending on the environment in which these responses were conditioned (Ogden et al., 2006). This chapter asks therapists to make a paradigm shift from a focus on traumatic events to prioritizing attention to the role of implicit memory in trauma treatment. In order to recognize, understand, and help clients work with their trauma-related parts, the therapist must help clients understand their responses to triggering so that they can accurately identify triggered, implicitly remembered feelings, beliefs, and survival responses. Lastly, this chapter addresses the question: What does it mean to “process memory”? When the memories are implicit feelings, body sensations, changes in activation, and disregulated impulsive behavior held by young parts, “what” gets processed? Modern views on memory emphasize its unstable nature: that is, the brain seems to be organized to update and rewrite past experiences, integrating them with prior and subsequent events. Rather than focusing on desensitizing the event memories, experts now advise prioritizing transformation or repair of trauma-related states through the cultivation of new experiences. Instead of focusing on developing a trauma narrative, clients are instead advised to rewrite their “self-defeating” stories and create a healing story that allows them to make meaning of what happened (Michenbaum, 2012).

在第2章《理解各部分，理解创伤性反应》中，我们探讨了神经科学关于创伤记忆研究的启示，以此作为理解和识别碎裂化部分在来访者呈现中出现迹象的基础。对紧急应激反应的简化理解及创伤遗留如何在身体中被编码得到呈现。重要的是要了解，基于身体的创伤反应如何驱动动物防御冲动至不安全行为，以及为什么与左脑相关的"正常生活"自我可能只能无助地旁观，却无法抑制行动的冲动。潜在的自动化高度警觉、反应性、多疑和冲动性行动背后，是支配行动与不行动、强烈情绪与麻木的身体自主神经系统。在创伤的余波中，神经系统适应了一个充满威胁的世界，被条件化地处于"随时准备"迎接即将来临的危险的状态，因而偏向于动员交感神经的高度唤醒或副交感神经的低度唤醒，或两者兼有，具体取决于这些反应被条件化的环境（Ogden等，2006）。本章要求治疗师完成一次范式转变——从聚焦于创伤事件转向优先关注内隐记忆在创伤治疗中的作用。为了识别、理解并帮助来访者处理其创伤相关部分，治疗师必须帮助来访者理解他们对触发因素的反应，以便他们能够准确识别被触发的、以内隐方式记忆的感受、信念和生存反应。最后，本章探讨了这个问题：什么是"加工记忆"？当记忆是年幼部分持有的内隐感受、身体感觉、激活状态的变化和失调性冲动行为时，"什么"被加工了？现代记忆观强调其不稳定的本质：大脑似乎以更新和重写过去体验的方式组织起来，将它们与之前和之后的事件整合。专家们现在建议不是聚焦于对事件记忆的去敏感化，而是优先考虑通过培育新体验来转化或修复创伤相关状态。来访者不是被建议聚焦于发展创伤叙事，而是被建议重写他们"自我挫败"的故事，创造一个允许他们赋予所发生之事以意义的愈合故事（Meichenbaum，2012）。

Chapter 3, Working with Changing Roles for Client and Therapist, begins with a discussion of fundamental shifts in perspective and approach necessitated by a neuroscientifically informed view of traumatized clients. The treatment begins with education for the therapist on the nature of trauma and dissociation, geared to explain the symptoms with which a client struggles and to provide information to reassure him or her that these are normal, logical responses to trauma. Additionally, psychoeducation helps to equalize the inherent power differential by “making public” the knowledge base that will be used in the therapy, empowering clients to become educated consumers in their own treatments (Herman, 1992).

第3章《与来访者和治疗师角色转变共同工作》，以讨论神经科学知情的创伤来访者视角所必然带来的视角和方法的根本性转变为开篇。治疗从为治疗师提供关于创伤和解离本质的心理教育开始，旨在解释来访者所挣扎的症状，并提供信息以向他或她保证这些都是对创伤的正常、合乎逻辑的反应。此外，心理教育通过将治疗中将使用的知识基础"公之于众"来均衡固有的权力差异，使来访者有能力成为自己治疗中受过教育的消费者（Herman，1992）。

Most therapists have been trained in “uni-consciousness” models of personality and are less familiar with working in a “multi-consciousness” paradigm. Psychodynamically trained therapists have been trained to play a less directive, educational role than required in trauma treatment; cognitive-behavioral therapists may not have been trained in the skills of attunement and resonance. Both are critically important in the context of trauma and in a parts approach. The client’s instinctive avoidance of the trauma and trauma-related parts will continue to re-enact the behavior of non-protective bystanders if not guided to a different way of working.

大多数治疗师在"单一意识"人格模型中接受训练，对在"多元意识"范式中工作不那么熟悉。接受心理动力学训练的治疗师被训练成扮演比创伤治疗所需更少指导性、教育性的角色；认知行为治疗师可能没有接受过协调性和共鸣技能的训练。两者在创伤的情境中以及部分方法中都至关重要。来访者对创伤及创伤相关部分的本能回避，如果没有被引导向不同的工作方式，将继续重演非保护性旁观者的行为。

Mindfulness skills must be explicitly taught, along with the language of parts necessary for identifying them. The beginning stages of the therapy involve the therapist’s attuned building of a collaboration based on what the client needs, not just on what he or she wants. To create a new story about whom he or she is in the aftermath of the painful and traumatic events requires learning new habits of observation and discovery: the “op-ed” stories clients have been writing about themselves have been biased, not in their favor. They need help in acquiring the skills of mindful observation of both positive and negative feelings and sensations without interpretation or judgment. Next, they learn to use the language of parts or “selves” to describe their often confusing or paradoxical actions and reactions as they happen moment-to-moment clients but without “identifying with them,” or interpreting them as data about the immediate present. Identification invariably intensifies any emotion or evokes shame. Learning to describe an experience without “identifying with it” allows clients to notice its “building blocks” (Ogden & Fisher, 2015): “As I talk about my father, I’m noticing a tightness in my chest and my heart beating fast” or “I’m noticing that a part of me is anxious.” Learning to dispassionately notice allows for the next steps in this approach to unfold: increased ability to hold a curious or even compassionate attitude toward whatever feelings or reactions are observed and, following that, an ability to “befriend” the emotion. In Buddhism, acceptance, welcoming, avoiding “attachment or aversion” (identifying with the feeling or fighting/judging it) are an essential part of finding equanimity, a state of calm, peacefulness, and composure. Translated into psychotherapy, this practice helps clients learn to tolerate and accept even the most painful, humiliating, or frightening emotions and sensations.

正念技能必须被明确教授，以及识别各部分所需的"部分"语言。治疗的开始阶段，涉及治疗师基于来访者的需要（而非仅仅是他或她的愿望）进行协调性合作关系的建立。要创造一个关于在痛苦和创伤性事件之后"我是谁"的新故事，需要学习新的观察和发现习惯：来访者一直在写关于自己的"社论"故事，这些故事是有偏见的，对他们不利。他们需要帮助来获得对正面和负面感受和感觉进行正念观察（不加诠释或评判）的技能。接下来，他们学习使用"部分"或"自我"的语言来描述他们时刻发生的往往令人困惑或悖论性的行为和反应，但不"认同它们"，也不将其解读为关于即时当下的数据。认同总是会强化任何情绪或唤起羞耻感。学会描述体验而不"认同它"，使来访者能够注意到其"构成要素"（Ogden和Fisher，2015）："当我谈到我父亲时，我注意到胸口有一种紧绷感，心跳加速"，或"我注意到我的一部分感到焦虑。"学会冷静地观察，使得这种方法的下一步得以展开：对所观察到的任何感受或反应持有好奇心甚至慈悲态度的能力增强，继而产生"与情绪交友"的能力。在佛教中，接纳、欢迎、避免"执著或厌恶"（认同感受或与其战斗/评判它），是找到平静——一种平静、安宁和沉着的状态——的基本部分。转化为心理治疗，这种实践帮助来访者学会容忍和接受甚至是最痛苦、最屈辱或最令人恐惧的情绪和感觉。

Rather than beginning with an exploration of the “old world” of painful, humiliating experiences and overwhelming feelings, the therapist is encouraged to focus on increasing the client’s curiosity and interest in feeling states, parts, thoughts, and body responses. The goal of this approach is not remembering: it is repair of the injuries suffered as a result of the traumatic events, whether remembered explicitly as narrative or implicitly as feelings and reactions.

治疗师被鼓励不要以探索痛苦、屈辱的体验和排山倒海的感受的"旧世界"为开始，而是聚焦于增加来访者对感受状态、部分、思想和身体反应的好奇心和兴趣。这种方法的目标不是记忆：而是对创伤性事件所造成伤害的修复，无论是以叙事形式显性地记住，还是以感受和反应形式隐性地记住。

In Chapter 4, Learning to See Our “Selves”: An Introduction to Working with Parts, therapist and client are taught the fundamental skills necessary for working in a parts paradigm. This early stage of the treatment is intended to help clients learn the basic skills necessary for working in a parts paradigm. First and foremost, clients are introduced to the Structural Dissociation model and asked to describe what resonates with their experiences and difficulties. How do they recognize themselves in the model? The Structural Dissociation model also offers a client-friendly entrée into identifying the signs of parts. Each animal defense survival response is associated with certain behaviors frequently associated with trauma. These are introduced to clients in diagram form to help them focus attention and take in this new information with greater interest and curiosity. Another approach to increasing awareness of parts activity is to ask clients to “assume” that all distressing thoughts, feelings, and body responses are communications from trauma-related parts. (This assumption is consistent with split-brain neuroscience findings on the activity and abilities associated with each of the two hemispheres.) Teaching schemas that facilitate ready identification of parts activity allows clients easier access to their internal experience, enabling them to differentiate “their feelings,” rather than identify with all emotions as “mine.” Clients are also taught to be mindful of internal conflicts, ambivalence, or confusion as manifestations of struggles between parts triggered by each other as well as by trauma-related stimuli.

在第4章《学会看见我们的"自我"：部分工作导论》中，治疗师和来访者学习在部分范式中工作所必需的基本技能。治疗的这一早期阶段旨在帮助来访者学习在部分范式中工作所必需的基本技能。首先，来访者被介绍结构性解离模型，并被要求描述哪些内容与他们的体验和困难产生共鸣。他们如何在模型中认出自己？结构性解离模型也为来访者提供了一个友好的入口，用以识别各部分的迹象。每种动物防御生存反应都与某些常与创伤相关的行为相关联。这些内容以图表形式向来访者介绍，帮助他们集中注意力，以更大的兴趣和好奇心接收这些新信息。增加对部分活动意识的另一种方法是要求来访者"假设"所有令人痛苦的想法、感受和身体反应都是来自创伤相关部分的沟通。（这一假设与两个半球各自活动和能力的裂脑神经科学研究发现相一致。）教导有助于即时识别部分活动的图式，使来访者更容易进入其内在体验，从而能够区分"他们的感受"，而非将所有情绪都认同为"我的"。来访者还被教导对内在冲突、矛盾心理或困惑保持正念觉察，将其视为各部分之间相互触发以及被创伤相关刺激触发的挣扎的表现。

Chapter 5, Befriending Our Parts: Sowing the Seeds of Compassion, focuses on interventions that begin a process of fostering the increased self-understanding and self-compassion so necessary for healing. Asked to have compassion for themselves or to better care for themselves, most traumatized clients have a strong negative reaction. But when an emotion such as fear or shame is connected to the felt sense of a young child, the same client can often feel empathy or even indignation for that child. In mindfulness-based treatment, it is not necessary that we differentiate between compassion “for ourselves” versus compassion “for the child.” The felt emotional and somatic sensations of compassion are the same, no matter who is the intended receiver, and it is those sensations of compassion that help to soothe and heal traumatic and attachment wounding. It is also not necessary to have detailed narrative memory of the client’s traumatic experience: it is only necessary for the client to have a felt sense of what the child part has been through. Having a “sense” or a synopsis of the client’s trauma history allows the therapist and client to acknowledge what younger selves have been through without overwhelming the client’s nervous system or capacity for affect tolerance. Acknowledging the parts’ traumatic experiences feels validating without triggering traumatic reactions. At this stage of the work, the emphasis is on cultivating compassion for the parts, one by one. Compassion is challenged by overwhelming emotions or disturbing body responses. The goal is to help the client feel “just enough” of the part’s suffering that empathy is evoked. It is important for the therapist to remember that, in trauma treatment, feeling too much interferes with empathy and compassion as much as feeling too little. At this stage, clients are also taught to recognize “blending” (Schwartz, 2001) or identifying with their parts, making them vulnerable to being flooded or acting out the impulse of some part, and to practice “unblending” and dis-identifying.

第5章《与我们的部分交友：播种慈悲的种子》，聚焦于开启一个培育对愈合如此必要的自我理解和自我慈悲增长过程的干预手段。当被要求对自己充满慈悲或更好地照顾自己时，大多数受创伤的来访者会有强烈的负面反应。但当恐惧或羞耻等情绪与一个幼小孩子的体感相连接时，同一位来访者往往能对那个孩子产生共情甚至愤慨。在正念为基础的治疗中，我们不必区分"对自己"的慈悲与"对孩子"的慈悲。慈悲的情感和躯体感受是相同的，无论预期的接受者是谁，正是这些慈悲的感受有助于抚慰和愈合创伤性和依恋性的伤痛。也不必拥有来访者创伤体验的详细叙事记忆：来访者只需对儿童部分所经历的事情有一种体感即可。拥有来访者创伤史的"感知"或概要，使治疗师和来访者能够承认年幼自我所经历的一切，而不至于压垮来访者的神经系统或情感耐受能力。承认各部分的创伤体验感觉具有确认性，而不会触发创伤反应。在这一工作阶段，重点是逐一培育对各部分的慈悲。慈悲受到排山倒海的情绪或令人不安的身体反应的挑战。目标是帮助来访者感受到部分痛苦的"恰到好处"，从而唤起共情。治疗师要记住，在创伤治疗中，感受太多与感受太少一样，都会妨碍共情和慈悲。在这一阶段，来访者还被教导识别"融合"（Schwartz，2001）或与其部分认同，这使他们容易被淹没或付诸行动于某个部分的冲动，并练习"解除融合"和去认同。

In Chapter 6, Complications of Treatment: Traumatic Attachment, we address the internal conflicts and struggles created by a history of traumatic attachment. If the hallmark of traumatic attachment is a reversal of roles in which the object of safety (the parent figure) becomes the object of fear and life threat, any intimate relationship thereafter, even the therapy, evokes danger signals. Growing closeness in relationship can convey threat or a promise of comfort and connection, evoking emotional memories of the longing for an attachment figure that never came alongside implicit memories of the abandonment and betrayal that did happen. Because attachment and fear have become intertwined in the client’s experience, a therapy focused on the narrative memories or on the transference is likely to ignite an internal struggle between the hunger for closeness in young attachment-seeking parts and their fear of abandonment versus the defensive responses of fight, flight, and total submission. In dissociative disorder clients with parts that are more disconnected and autonomous, this internal struggle becomes even more easily activated in personal relationships or in the therapy, harder to decode or deconstruct, and more difficult to manage behaviorally.

在第6章《治疗的复杂因素：创伤性依恋》中，我们探讨了由创伤性依恋史所造成的内在冲突和挣扎。如果创伤性依恋的标志是角色颠倒——安全的对象（父母形象）成为恐惧和生命威胁的对象——那么此后的任何亲密关系，甚至是治疗关系，都会唤起危险信号。关系中日益增长的亲密感可以传递威胁或舒适与联结的承诺，唤起对那个从未出现的依恋对象的渴望的情感记忆，以及对确实发生过的遗弃和背叛的内隐记忆。由于依恋和恐惧在来访者的体验中已经交织在一起，聚焦于叙事记忆或移情的治疗很可能点燃年幼寻求依恋部分对亲密的渴望与其对遗弃的恐惧，与战斗、逃跑和完全顺从的防御反应之间的内在挣扎。在有更多断联和自主部分的解离障碍来访者中，这种内在挣扎在个人关系或治疗中变得更加容易被激活，更难被解码或解构，行为管理也更加困难。

How therapists anticipate this phenomenon and how they help their clients accept and work with it can lead either to deeper healing or to a reopening of attachment wounds in the therapy itself. If either clinging or devaluing is interpreted as an interpersonal issue between client and therapist, they are often exacerbated. If we understand them as “intra-personal,” indicators of an internal attachment disorder still operating within the client, then the therapist can become an ally for both sides of the struggle and a facilitator of “earned secure attachment” (Siegel, 1999). In “earned” secure attachment, the insecure or disorganized attachment of childhood and/or adulthood is resolved to the point that individuals can reflect back on their early attachment relationships without becoming disregulated, without idealizing or demonizing their attachment figures, and feel a sense of acceptance. In this model, earned secure attachment is the outcome of the clients’ growing ability to bond with their own young wounded selves as innocent children who deserved the loving care of a compassionate adult but never received it. Rather than the therapeutic focus being centered on attachment to the therapist, the emphasis is consistently on building empathy and attunement to the parts.

治疗师如何预见这一现象，以及如何帮助来访者接受并处理它，可能导向更深的愈合，也可能导致治疗本身重新开启依恋伤口。如果依附或贬低被解读为来访者与治疗师之间的人际问题，它们往往会被加剧。如果我们将其理解为"个体内部"的问题——仍在来访者内部运作的内在依恋障碍的指标——那么治疗师便能成为挣扎双方的盟友，以及"赢得的安全型依恋"（Siegel，1999）的促进者。在"赢得的"安全型依恋中，童年和/或成年期的不安全或紊乱型依恋得到解决，达到个体能够回顾早期依恋关系而不失调、不理想化或魔鬼化其依恋对象，并感受到一种接纳感的程度。在这一模型中，赢得的安全型依恋是来访者日益增长的能力——即与自己年幼受伤的自我建立联结，将其视为本应得到一位慈悲成人的爱护照料却从未得到的无辜孩子——的结果。治疗的焦点不是集中于对治疗师的依恋，而是始终强调对各部分建立共情和协调。

In Chapter 7, Working with Suicidal, Self-Destructive, Eating Disordered, and Addicted Parts, unsafe and high-risk behaviors are recontextualized as manifestations of parts-related animal defense survival responses. Addictive, eating disordered, suicidal, and self-injurious behaviors are all reinterpreted through a neurobiological lens. The neurobiological premise assumes that human bodies have the same self-righting, self-healing tendencies as do the bodies of other mammalian species. If that is so, then self-destructive behavior must also have a self-righting intention. Viewed in this way, unsafe behavior historically labeled “self-destructive” can be better understood as a desperate attempt to survive, a way to tolerate shame, rage, and fear, to inhibit flashbacks and nightmares, or to use endogenous or exogenous substances to regulate a traumatized nervous system. As part of an informal, clinically oriented pilot project offering new forms of treatment to trauma patients in a Connecticut Department of Mental Health system, participating clinicians have been gathering informal data on what precedes and follows episodes of unsafe behavior. They have observed that episodes of self-harm or suicide attempts most commonly follow relational disappointments, separations or ending of relationships, preoccupation with shame and self-loathing, and intrusive memories or flashbacks. This finding implies that such events evoke the experience of threat and generate trauma-related emotional responses that feel unbearable until some impulsive behavior diminishes their intensity or creates emotional and bodily numbing. After these episodes, there is a corresponding tendency for patients to report exhaustion, loss of energy, and intense feelings of needing rest—the same indicators characteristic of parasympathetic responses following a fight or flight response. Historically, this classic post-traumatic unsafe behavior has been interpreted clinically as attention-seeking, manipulation, or avoidance. With the implementation of this neurobiologically informed approach, in which patients are helped to reframe impulsive or unsafe behavior as communications from a part driven by the animal defense of fight, the frequency of unsafe behavior has diminished. By externalizing the impulses and assigning them to a defensive part, the patients are able to keep an observing prefrontal cortex available to help them manage the impulses as “not mine—it’s the fight part.” Better yet, when these patients are taught the Structural Dissociation model, there appears to be a decrease in negative self-judgment and an increase in their curiosity, both of which are antidotes to impulsive behavior. Teaching these clients the basic skills outlined in Chapters 4 and 5 and asking them to practice their use seems to have a stabilizing effect in and of itself. In addition, clients are given psychoeducation about the biological effects of their unsafe behavior and how it “works” to regulate the nervous system, helping them to gain a perspective on the body’s role in these issues. As their ability to “unblend” from impulsive parts increases, and there is more access to an uninhibited prefrontal cortex, these clients are better able to notice the parts’ distressing emotions and unsafe impulses and regulate them, rather than react to them.

在第7章《与自杀、自毁、进食障碍和成瘾部分共同工作》中，不安全和高风险行为被重新情境化为与部分相关的动物防御生存反应的表现。成瘾、进食障碍、自杀和自伤行为都通过神经生物学视角重新得到诠释。神经生物学前提假设人类身体具有与其他哺乳动物物种身体相同的自我纠正、自我愈合倾向。如果是这样，那么自毁行为也必定具有自我纠正的意图。以这种方式来看，历史上被标记为"自毁"的不安全行为，可以更好地理解为一种绝望的生存尝试，一种容忍羞耻、愤怒和恐惧的方式，一种抑制闪回和噩梦的方式，或一种使用内源性或外源性物质来调节创伤化神经系统的方式。作为康涅狄格州心理健康部门系统中为创伤患者提供新型治疗的非正式临床导向试点项目的一部分，参与临床医生一直在收集关于不安全行为发作前后情况的非正式数据。他们观察到，自我伤害或自杀未遂发作最常发生在关系失望、分离或关系结束、对羞耻和自我厌恶的沉迷，以及侵入性记忆或闪回之后。这一发现意味着，这类事件唤起了威胁体验，并产生了创伤相关的情感反应，这些反应在某种冲动行为降低其强度或造成情感和身体麻木之前感觉难以忍受。在这些发作之后，患者往往倾向于报告精疲力竭、精力丧失以及强烈的需要休息的感觉——与战斗或逃跑反应后副交感神经反应特征相同的指标。从历史上看，这种经典的创伤后不安全行为在临床上被解读为寻求关注、操纵或回避。随着这种神经生物学知情方法的实施——帮助患者将冲动或不安全行为重构为来自由战斗动物防御驱动的部分的沟通——不安全行为的频率已经减少。通过将冲动外化并将其归因于一个防御部分，患者能够保持一个观察性的前额叶皮层可用，以帮助他们将冲动管理为"不是我的——是战斗部分"。更好的是，当这些患者被教授结构性解离模型时，负面自我评判似乎减少，好奇心增加，两者都是冲动行为的解药。向这些来访者教授第4章和第5章所概述的基本技能，并要求他们练习运用，似乎本身就具有稳定效果。此外，来访者接受关于其不安全行为的生物学影响以及它如何"起作用"来调节神经系统的心理教育，帮助他们对身体在这些问题中的作用获得视角。随着他们从冲动部分"解除融合"的能力增加，以及对未受抑制的前额叶皮层的更多获取，这些来访者能够更好地注意到各部分令人痛苦的情绪和不安全冲动并调节它们，而非对其做出反应。

In Chapter 8, Treatment Challenges: Dissociative Systems and Disorders, we address the unique issues posed by clients who have diagnosable dissociative disorders (DID, DDNOS, depersonalization disorder). A dissociative disorder diagnosis reflects a more extreme degree of compartmentalization, affecting the ability for continuous consciousness, the ability to know moment-to-moment “who I am,” to make coherent choices and decisions and carry them through to completion, to manage impulses, to have accurate perceptions of cause-effect or time and space, and to integrate the traumatic past and normal, safe present. Clients with dissociative disorders are often underdiagnosed or misdiagnosed despite their statistically significant dissociative symptomatology (Korzekwa et al., 2009a). Most often, they present with diagnoses of borderline personality disorder, bipolar disorder II, and ADD or ADHD. This chapter reviews the diagnostic signs indicating a possible DID diagnosis, discusses assessment approaches, and suggests criteria for making a formal diagnosis. The same treatment approach outlined in Chapters 3–5 is very effective for DID and DDNOS clients, with adjustments to how the therapist works to account for the failures of memory and continuity.

在第8章《治疗挑战：解离系统与解离障碍》中，我们探讨了那些有可诊断解离障碍（DID、DDNOS、人格解体障碍）的来访者所提出的独特问题。解离障碍诊断反映了更极端程度的分隔化，影响连续意识的能力、时刻知道"我是谁"的能力、做出连贯选择和决定并将其贯彻到底的能力、管理冲动的能力、对因果或时间空间的准确感知能力，以及整合创伤过去与正常、安全的现在的能力。尽管有统计学上显著的解离症状学，有解离障碍的来访者往往被漏诊或误诊（Korzekwa等，2009a）。最常见的情况是，他们带着边缘型人格障碍、双相障碍II型和ADD或ADHD的诊断出现。本章回顾了表明可能有DID诊断的诊断迹象，讨论了评估方法，并建议了做出正式诊断的标准。第3至5章所概述的相同治疗方法对DID和DDNOS来访者非常有效，只需对治疗师的工作方式做出调整，以适应记忆和连续性方面的缺失。

Because the approach described in this book is mindfulness-based, it tends to be stabilizing for clients and to facilitate deconstructing problems encountered in normal life, as well as trauma-related issues. The language of parts allows both client and therapist to keep in mind the central challenge of working with dissociative disorders: holding in mind that the client is still one physical individual with one body and one brain, while equally appreciating that this one brain and body are fragmented and hold many parts of different ages, stages, attachment styles, and defensive responses. To feel empathy for each part’s plight, while not losing sight of the fact that the client is an adult with functional capabilities is a mental ability that often has to be practiced before it becomes second nature. With dissociative disorders, the therapist is working with clients who are not an integrated “she” or “he.” Viewing them as such is often confusing, rather than helpful, just as viewing clients as inner children without adult resources equally causes confusion.

由于本书所描述的方法以正念为基础，它往往对来访者具有稳定作用，并有助于解构在正常生活中遇到的问题，以及创伤相关问题。"部分"的语言使来访者和治疗师都能牢记与解离障碍工作的核心挑战：记住来访者仍然是一个有一个身体和一个大脑的物理个体，同时同等地意识到这一个大脑和身体是碎裂化的，持有许多不同年龄、阶段、依恋风格和防御反应的部分。对每个部分的困境感到共情，同时不失去对来访者是一个有功能能力的成人这一事实的关注，是一种往往需要练习才能成为第二本能的心理能力。在解离障碍中，治疗师正在与那些不是整合的"她"或"他"的来访者一起工作。将他们视为如此往往令人困惑，而非有帮助，就像将来访者视为没有成人资源的内在孩子同样造成困惑一样。

The duality of whole and part, or a whole with parts, is always front and center in DID treatment. When the therapist asks the client to distinguish the parts responsible for a problem behavior and then becomes curious about their emotions, beliefs, motives, and defensive responses, he or she engages the left brain-driven part of the personality to “help” solve the issues and challenges raised by right brain-driven trauma-related parts. This skill is even more crucial in the treatment of clients with dissociative disorders than it is in work with fragmented individuals without DID. When right brain dominant parts can act independently outside the conscious awareness of the client, the need to have the balancing, stabilizing presence of a left brain self is especially crucial.

整体与部分，或一个有部分的整体的双重性，在DID治疗中始终处于最前沿和中心位置。当治疗师要求来访者区分负责问题行为的各部分，然后对其情绪、信念、动机和防御反应产生好奇时，他或她参与了人格中左脑驱动的部分来"帮助"解决右脑驱动的创伤相关部分所提出的问题和挑战。这种技能在解离障碍来访者的治疗中甚至比在没有DID的碎裂化个体工作中更为关键。当右脑主导的部分能够在来访者有意识意识之外独立行动时，拥有左脑自我的平衡、稳定存在的需要就显得尤为重要。

In Chapter 9, Repairing the Past: Embracing Our Selves, the premise is that resolution of traumatic experience is dependent upon overcoming survival-related self-alienation. By cultivating the growing attunement between child selves and grownup normal life self, each aspect of self feels an increasing comfort in the other’s presence, greater safety, and a warmth in connection. But in order to foster attachment bonds between traumatized individuals and their young selves, the therapist first must help clients acknowledge, connect, and identify with the normal life adult inside themselves—the self that has the ability to care for and express caring, that has always been instinctively driven to seek safety, normality, and stability, that can “be here now” for a small child in need of safe attachment.

在第9章《修复过去：拥抱我们的自我》中，前提是创伤体验的解决依赖于克服与生存相关的自我疏离。通过培育儿童自我与成年正常生活自我之间日益增长的协调，自我的每个方面在对方的存在中感到越来越多的舒适感、更大的安全感和联结中的温暖。但为了在受创伤个体和其年幼自我之间培育依恋纽带，治疗师首先必须帮助来访者承认、联结并认同内在的正常生活成人——那个有能力关怀和表达关怀的自我，那个始终本能地被驱动去寻求安全、正常和稳定的自我，那个能够为一个需要安全依恋的小孩"活在当下"的自我。

Distorted cognitions associated with shame and self-loathing often interfere with clients’ ability to feel connected even to strengths they are aware they possess. Perhaps it was unsafe as a child to have strengths or a desire for mastery without traumatic consequences. The parts may be triggered by normal life activities (such as a job, a partner relationship, responsibilities, or simply having to be visible), undermining the client’s ability to handle them. Internal conflicts between parts may debilitate or destabilize the normal life self or block attempts at developing a life after trauma.

与羞耻和自我厌恶相关的扭曲认知，往往干扰来访者感受到与他们意识到自己拥有的优势相连接的能力。也许作为孩子，拥有优势或对掌控欲而不产生创伤性后果是不安全的。各部分可能被正常生活活动（如工作、伴侣关系、责任，或仅仅是必须被看见）所触发，破坏来访者处理这些活动的能力。各部分之间的内在冲突可能使正常生活自我虚弱或失稳，或阻碍在创伤后发展生活的尝试。

Using clinical examples to illustrate in detail how the therapist can foster the innate compassion of the normal life self on behalf of wounded child parts, the reader is given a template for how internal acceptance is built by drawing on the client’s strengths and life experiences as resources for the young child selves. While the left brain self has been learning and storing competencies, these abilities have not been available to the right brain selves. This chapter illustrates interventions that bring the two sides into contact and evoke pleasurable moments of attunement and togetherness that become the building blocks of internal secure attachment. The human brain’s complexity allows us to heal ourselves: it endows upon us the unique ability to access acquired capacities and engage them on behalf of other parts sharing the same brain and body.

通过临床案例详细说明治疗师如何代表受伤儿童部分培育正常生活自我的内在慈悲，读者被给予一个关于内在接纳如何通过将来访者的优势和生活经历作为年幼儿童自我的资源来构建的模板。虽然左脑自我一直在学习和储存能力，但这些能力对右脑自我并不可用。本章说明了使双方进入接触并唤起愉快的协调和在一起时刻——这些时刻成为内在安全型依恋的构建模块——的干预手段。人类大脑的复杂性允许我们自我愈合：它赋予我们独特的能力，能够获取习得的能力，并代表共享同一大脑和身体的其他部分来参与这些能力。

In Chapter 10, Restoring What Was Lost: Deepening the Connection to Our Young Selves, the healing work takes another step forward. First, clients must earn the parts’ trust, made challenging by their implicit memories of inadequate bonding and failed trust that both increase the yearning to trust but also increase hypervigilant resistance to trusting. The therapist consistently asks the client, on behalf of the parts, to communicate, collaborate, and extend compassion to them, slowly building up a felt sense of an internal attachment figure, one who shares the same brain and body, one who might have once been the age of the parts but now is a strong, caring adult committed to creating a life different from the past: safe, nourishing, and relational.

在第10章《恢复失去的：深化与年幼自我的联结》中，愈合工作又向前迈进了一步。首先，来访者必须赢得各部分的信任，这因各部分对不充分联结和信任失败的内隐记忆而具有挑战性——这些记忆既增加了信任的渴望，又增加了对信任的高度警觉性抵抗。治疗师始终代表各部分要求来访者与它们沟通、合作并延伸慈悲，慢慢建立起一种内在依恋对象的体感——一个共享同一大脑和身体的对象，一个可能曾经与各部分同龄但现在已经是一个致力于创造与过去不同的生活（安全、滋养和关系性的）的强大、关怀的成人。

In Chapter 11, Safety and Welcome: The Experience of Earned Secure Attachment, we address “integration” not as a goal of treatment but as a process that occurs organically when we use mindfulness-based techniques to bring awareness and compassion to the system of traumatized parts. As defined by Daniel Siegel (2010), “Integration results from differentiation coupled with linkage.” Asked to bring focused attention to a young part in distress, the client is asked to imagine a young child of the same age with the same emotions in the room, “standing right there before you.” By bringing the child part inside “alive,” the therapist facilitates the client’s access to right brain-based inherently compassionate intuitive responses. Using guided visualization, the therapist evokes images of the child’s face, body language, and plight to increase the sense of connection or empathy between child and normal life adult and the latter is asked to notice, “And how do you feel toward that part now?” Repeatedly, client and part are asked to mentalize the other’s mentalization, to notice how one impacts the other, stimulating a felt sense of connection, then enhancing the bond by sharing their responses again and again: “Ask the little girl how it feels to hear you say, ‘I’m glad I’m here—I want her to feel safe’.” While internal bonds of secure attachment are built through the dyadic interchanges between adult and part, the normal life self of the client is also asked to repair the distressed state of the child or create a new ending to the story of distress, just as secure attachment figures do. Imaginal experiences of healthy, safe attachment can generate the same feelings and sensations and evoke the same “attunement bliss” that babies and mothers enjoy, and, by simply focusing mindfully on these moments, they can be encoded as readily as a concrete, physical experience of safety and attunement (Hanson, 2014).

在第11章《安全与欢迎：赢得的安全型依恋的体验》中，我们将"整合"不是作为治疗目标，而是作为当我们使用正念为基础的技术将意识和慈悲带入受创伤部分系统时有机发生的过程来探讨。正如Daniel Siegel（2010）所定义的，"整合是分化与联结相结合的结果。"被要求将专注注意力带向一个处于痛苦中的年幼部分，来访者被要求想象一个同龄且有同样情绪的小孩在房间里，"就站在你面前"。通过将儿童部分"活"带入内在，治疗师促进来访者获取以右脑为基础的内在慈悲直觉性反应。利用引导性可视化，治疗师唤起孩子的面孔、身体语言和困境的意象，以增加孩子与正常生活成人之间的联结感或共情，后者被要求注意，"现在你对那个部分有什么感受？"反复地，来访者和部分被要求心智化对方的心智化，注意一方如何影响另一方，激发联结的体感，然后通过一次又一次分享他们的反应来增强纽带："问问小女孩，听到你说'我很高兴我在这里——我希望她感到安全'，是什么感觉。"虽然安全型依恋的内在纽带是通过成人与部分之间的二元交流建立的，来访者的正常生活自我也被要求修复孩子的痛苦状态或为痛苦的故事创造新的结局，就像安全型依恋对象所做的那样。健康、安全依恋的想象性体验可以产生与婴儿和母亲享受的相同感受和感觉，并唤起相同的"协调幸福感"，通过简单地正念地专注于这些时刻，它们可以像安全和协调的具体、物理体验一样容易地被编码（Hanson，2014）。

Chapter 11 stresses again that emotional healing of traumatic wounds has to be attachment-based. Like long-lost young relatives, the alienated disowned parts must be invited to the table and welcomed into the heart and mind and arms of the client. This process can be very moving for both client and therapist but is not without its challenges. The trauma-related fear of self-compassion is strong and unbending, leaving the therapist with the job of holding a calm, clear, courageous stance that alienation from or rejection of any part leaves us less than whole. Without welcoming each and every part “home” and offering safe, unconditional acceptance, survivors can’t fully heal the wounds left by the failed empathy of the caretakers who harmed them or allowed them to be harmed when they were too little, too alone, and too vulnerable to defend themselves. For those clients traumatized as adults, the therapist has to be absolutely clear that resolution still depends upon all parts finding safety after trauma: young parts whose needs were not reliably met in childhood or who interpreted the traumatic events in the light of insecure attachment, adolescent parts whose fight and flight responses have been reactivated, despairing submissive parts who “took the fall” in an inescapable situation, even suicidal parts who would rather turn their swords on themselves rather than be humiliated or abandoned.

第11章再次强调，创伤伤口的情感愈合必须以依恋为基础。就像久别的年幼亲属一样，被疏离和否认的部分必须被邀请到桌前，被欢迎进入来访者的心灵、思想和怀抱。这个过程对来访者和治疗师都可能非常感人，但并非没有挑战。与创伤相关的对自我慈悲的恐惧是强烈且不屈的，这给治疗师留下了持有一种平静、清晰、勇敢的立场的工作——疏离或拒绝任何部分使我们不够完整。如果不欢迎每一个部分"回家"并提供安全、无条件的接纳，幸存者就无法完全愈合那些当他们太小、太孤独、太脆弱而无法保护自己时伤害或允许他们被伤害的照料者的同理心失败所留下的伤口。对于那些作为成人被创伤的来访者，治疗师必须绝对清楚，解决方案仍然依赖于所有部分在创伤后找到安全：那些童年需求未被可靠满足或以不安全依恋的视角解读创伤事件的年幼部分，那些战斗和逃跑反应被重新激活的青少年部分，那些在无法逃脱的情境中"承担后果"的绝望顺从部分，甚至是那些宁愿将剑对准自己也不愿被羞辱或遗弃的自杀部分。

Dan Siegel’s conceptualization of “earned secure attachment” reflects the belief of many in the attachment field (Main, Schore, Lyons-Ruth) that childhood attachment wounds can be modified through life experiences that “grow” states of secure attachment, even in adulthood. These experiences might include raising one’s own children, healthy friendships and intimate relationships, or creating secure attachment relationships with one’s parts. Each of these avenues for earned security capitalizes on the brain’s ability to grow new neural networks and encode new, pleasurable feeling states. By imaginally evoking new implicit memories of safety and attunement, parts feel the inner sensate experience of healthy attachment, moments that can be encoded alongside the painful memories of failed or frightening attachments, changing the ending of the story. “Earned security” is measured by the degree of “coherence” exhibited by individuals reflecting on their early attachment relationships on the Adult Attachment Inventory, that is, the degree to which they have integrated the bitter and the sweet of their lives, the pain then and the pleasure in relationships now.

Dan Siegel对"赢得的安全型依恋"的概念化，反映了依恋领域许多人（Main、Schore、Lyons-Ruth）的信念：童年依恋伤口可以通过"培育"安全型依恋状态的生活体验来修改，即使在成年期也是如此。这些体验可能包括抚养自己的孩子、健康的友谊和亲密关系，或与自己的部分创建安全型依恋关系。这些赢得安全感的途径中，每一条都利用了大脑生长新神经网络和编码新的愉悦感受状态的能力。通过想象性地唤起关于安全和协调的新内隐记忆，各部分感受到健康依恋的内在感觉体验，这些时刻可以与失败或令人恐惧的依恋的痛苦记忆并排编码，改变故事的结局。"赢得的安全感"通过个体在成人依恋量表中反思其早期依恋关系时所表现出的"连贯性"程度来衡量，即他们整合生活中苦与甜的程度——那时的痛苦与现在关系中的愉悦。

Only the human brain can create a new story of safety, closeness, and compassion by evoking states of well-being connected either to imagined or remembered experiences. For neuroplastic brain change to occur, only three ingredients are needed: first, clients have to be helped to inhibit their habitual emotional, physical, and cognitive patterns. Next, they have to practice a new pattern with which they’d like to replace the old—and then practice the new pattern over and over again without losing the felt connection to the child and to their own bodies. It could be as simple as bringing the right hand over the heart to communicate calm or repeating the words, “It’s okay now” or “I’m here now.”

只有人类大脑能够通过唤起与想象或记忆体验相连接的幸福感状态，创造一个关于安全、亲密和慈悲的新故事。要使神经可塑性大脑变化发生，只需要三个要素：首先，来访者必须被帮助抑制其习惯性的情感、身体和认知模式。其次，他们必须练习一种他们想用来替代旧模式的新模式——然后一遍又一遍地练习新模式，而不失去与孩子和自己身体的体感联结。它可以像将右手放在心脏上传递平静，或重复说"现在没事了"或"我现在在这里"一样简单。

A client’s new “healing story” might sound a bit like this: “Once upon a time, my parts felt as unsafe and unlovable as I did as a child. Now I don’t feel anxious that I’ll be rejected and abandoned, and neither do they. I know I’m OK, and I know they’re OK—I feel connected to my parts and to myself, and I’ll always be here to keep them safe. They are special to me and always will be.”

来访者的新"愈合故事"可能听起来有点像这样："很久很久以前，我的各部分像我童年时感受到的一样不安全，不值得被爱。现在我不再焦虑于被拒绝和遗弃，它们也不再如此。我知道我没事，我知道它们没事——我感到与我的各部分和我自己相连，我将永远在这里保护它们的安全。它们对我来说是特别的，永远都是。"

In the appendices that follow Chapter 11, therapists and clients will find some additional tools to help them with the tasks presented throughout the book. Appendix A consists of a simple protocol for learning how to unblend from parts, especially parts with intense feelings that hijack the prefrontal cortex and destabilize the client. Appendix B consists of a meditation circle practice for parts. Appendix C presents the Internal Dialogue protocol that, practiced over and over again, builds the ability to communicate internally, calm and comfort distressed parts, and grow the bonds of compassion. Appendix D presents a treatment paradigm for internal attachment repair. Appendix E consists of a worksheet, the Dissociative Experiences Log, for helping clients increase the ability to track and differentiate the signs of parts’ activity and communication. And Appendix F provides a script for the Four Befriending Questions, a technique that builds inner communication and bonds of love and trust.

在第11章之后的附录中，治疗师和来访者将找到一些额外工具，帮助他们完成本书各处呈现的任务。附录A包含一个学习如何从部分解除融合的简单协议，特别是那些有强烈感受、会劫持前额叶皮层并使来访者失稳的部分。附录B包含一个针对各部分的冥想圆圈练习。附录C呈现了内在对话协议，经过反复练习，它建立内在沟通的能力、安抚和慰藉受困部分，并增长慈悲的纽带。附录D呈现了内在依恋修复的治疗范式。附录E包含一个工作表，即解离体验日志，帮助来访者增加跟踪和区分部分活动和沟通迹象的能力。附录F提供了四个交友问题的脚本，这是一种建立内在沟通以及爱与信任纽带的技术。

Psychotherapists have wondered and worried and philosophized for hundreds of years about the nature of healing. This book describes one theory about healing the effects of trauma and traumatic attachment that emerged from my clinical observations: healing is the outcome of reversing long-standing patterns of self-alienation and building the capacity to love and accept our “selves.” When we reclaim our lost souls and wounded children, befriend them, and allow ourselves to trust deeply felt compassionate impulses to reach out to them and build bonds of secure attachment, they feel safe and welcome at long last. And we feel whole.

几百年来，心理治疗师们一直对愈合的本质感到疑惑、担忧和哲学思考。本书描述了一个关于愈合创伤和创伤性依恋影响的理论，这一理论源于我的临床观察：愈合是逆转长期自我疏离模式、建立爱与接纳我们"众多自我"的能力的结果。当我们找回迷失的灵魂和受伤的孩子，与他们交友，并允许自己信任深深感受到的慈悲冲动，向他们伸出手，建立安全型依恋的纽带时，他们终于感到安全和被欢迎。而我们也感到完整。

References

Bromberg, P. (2011). The shadow of the tsunami and the growth of the relational mind. New York: Taylor & Francis.

Gazzaniga, M. S. (1985). The social brain: discovering the networks of the mind. New York: Basic Books.

Hanson, R. (2014). Hardwiring happiness: the new brain science of contentment, calm, and confidence. New York: Harmony Publications.

Herman, J. L. (1992) Trauma and recovery. New York: Basic Books.

Ogden, P. & Fisher, J. (2015). Sensorimotor psychotherapy: interventions for trauma and attachment. New York: W.W. Norton.

Ogden, P., Minton, K. & Pain, C. (2006). Trauma and the body: a sensorimotor approach to psychotherapy. New York: W.W. Norton.

Pollack, S.M., Padulla, T., & Seigel, R.D. (2014). Sitting together: essential skills for mindfulness-based psychotherapy. New York: Guilford Press.

Porges, S.W. (2011). The Polyvagal theory: neurophysiological foundations of emotions, attachment, communication, and self-regulation. New York: W.W. Norton.

Schwartz, R. (1995). Internal family systems therapy. New York: Guilford Press.

Schwartz, R. (2001). Introduction to the internal family systems model. Oak Park, IL: Trailhead Publications.

Siegel, D.J. (1999). The developing mind: toward a neurobiology of interpersonal experience. New York: Guilford Press.

Siegel, D. J. (2010). The neurobiology of ‘we.’ Keynote address, Psychotherapy Networker Symposium, Washington, D.C., March 2010.

Van der Hart, O., Nijenhuis, E.R.S., & Steele, K. (2006). The haunted self: structural dissociation and the treatment of chronic traumatization. New York: W.W. Norton.

Van der Hart, O., Nijenhuis, E.R.S., Steele, K., & Brown, D. (2004). Trauma-related dissociation: conceptual clarity lost and found. Australian and New Zealand Journal of Psychiatry, 38, 906–914.

Van der Hart, O., van Dijke, A., van Son, M., and Steele, K. (2000). Somatoform dissociation in traumatized World War I combat soldiers: a neglected clinical heritage. Journal of Trauma and Dissociation, 1(4), 33–66.

Van der Kolk, B.A. (2014). The body keeps the score: brain, mind and body in the healing of trauma. New York: Viking Press.

CHAPTER 1
The Neurobiological Legacy of Trauma: How We Become Fragmented

第1章
创伤的神经生物学遗产：我们如何走向碎裂

"If the elements of the trauma are replayed again and again, the accompanying stress hormones engrave those memories even more deeply into the mind. Ordinary, day-to-day events become less and less compelling. Not being able to deeply take in what is going on around [us] makes it impossible to feel fully alive. It becomes harder to feel the joys and aggravations of ordinary life, harder to concentrate on the tasks at hand. Not being fully alive in the present keeps [us] more firmly imprisoned in the past."

"如果创伤的各个元素被一遍遍地重演，伴随而来的应激激素会将那些记忆更深地刻入大脑。日常生活中的普通事件变得越来越无法引起共鸣。无法深深吸收周围发生的一切，使人不可能感到真正的活着。越来越难以感受日常生活的喜悦与烦恼，越来越难以专注于手头的任务。不能真正活在当下，使我们更紧地被囚禁在过去。"

(Van der Kolk, 2014, p. 67)

（Van der Kolk，2014年，第67页）

In the face of abuse and neglect, especially at the hands of those they love, children need enough psychological distance from what is happening to avoid being overwhelmed and survive psychologically intact. Preserving some modicum of self-esteem, attachment to family, and hope for the future requires victims to disconnect from what has happened, doubt or disremember their experience, and disown the "bad [victim] child" to whom it happened as "not me." By holding out some sense of themselves as "good" disconnected from how they have been exploited, abused children capitalize on the human brain's innate capacity to split or compartmentalize. That "good child" might be precociously mature, sweet and helpful, perfectionistic, self-critical, or quiet and shy, but, most importantly, he or she has a way to be acceptable and safer in an unsafe world. Splitting or fragmenting in this way is an ingenious and adaptive survival strategy—but one with a steep price. To ensure that the rejected "not me" child is kept out of the way (i.e., out of consciousness) requires that, long after the traumatic events are over, individuals must continue to rely on dissociation, denial, and/or self-hatred for enforcing the disconnection. In the end, they have survived the failure of safety, the abuse, and betrayal at the cost of disowning their most vulnerable and most wounded selves. Aware that their self-presentation and ability to function is only one piece of who they really are, they now feel fraudulent. Struggling to stay away from the "bad" side and identify with the good side, they have a felt sense of "faking it," "pretending," or of being what others want them to be. For some, this conviction of fraudulence engenders resentment; for some, shame and self-doubt. For both groups, the legacy of the trauma remains alive rather than resolved.

面对虐待和忽视，尤其是来自他们所爱之人的伤害，孩子需要与正在发生的事情保持足够的心理距离，以避免被淹没、在心理上完好无损地存活下来。为了维持一点点自尊、对家庭的依恋和对未来的希望，受害者需要与已发生的事情断开联系，对自己的经历产生怀疑或遗忘，并将那个"坏的（受害）孩子"认定为"非我"而加以抛弃。通过维持某种与被剥削方式相分离的"好"的自我感，受虐待的孩子利用了人类大脑天生的分裂或分隔化能力。那个"好孩子"可能表现得早熟、温顺乐于助人、完美主义、自我批评，或安静内向，但最重要的是，他/她有一种方式在不安全的世界中显得可被接受、相对安全。以这种方式分裂或碎裂是一种巧妙而适应性的生存策略——但代价高昂。为了确保被排斥的"非我"孩子被挡在意识之外，在创伤事件结束很久之后，个体仍必须继续依赖解离、否认和/或自我憎恨来强化这种断裂。最终，他们以抛弃最脆弱、最受伤的自我为代价，存活于安全的失败、虐待和背叛之中。意识到自己展现给他人的形象和功能运转只是真实自我的一部分，他们如今感到虚假。在努力远离"坏"的一面并认同好的一面的过程中，他们有一种"装腔作势"、"假装"或成为别人想要他们成为的样子的体感。对某些人而言，这种虚伪感带来了怨恨；对另一些人而言，则是羞耻和自我怀疑。对这两个群体而言，创伤的遗产依然鲜活，而非得到化解。

As children of abuse continue to grow through latency into adolescence and subsequently adulthood, this splitting of the self supports another important aspect of surviving trauma: mastering normal developmental tasks, such as learning in school, developing peer relationships, finding interests on which to focus and even enjoy. The "good" part of the child is free to develop normally while that other part of the child bears the emotional and physical imprint of the past, scans for signs of danger, and braces for the next set of threats and abandonments. To make the individual's situation more complicated, neither the "me" nor the "not me" self is likely to have well-developed chronological memories of the traumatic events that could provide a context for self-understanding. Due to the nature of traumatic memory, what can be "recalled" tends to appear in the form of intrusive images, emotions, and physical reactions (Van der Kolk, 2006; 2014) that occur spontaneously without warning, not a sequence of narrative memories that make a clear-cut case for what happened "beyond a reasonable doubt."

随着受虐待孩子从潜伏期成长经过青春期、最终进入成年，这种自我的分裂支撑着存活于创伤的另一个重要方面：掌握正常的发展任务，例如在学校学习、发展同伴关系、找到可以专注甚至享受的兴趣。孩子的"好"的部分可以自由地正常发展，而孩子另一部分则承载着过去的情感与身体印记，扫描危险的迹象，为下一轮威胁和遗弃做好准备。使个体处境更为复杂的是，"我"和"非我"的自我都不太可能对创伤事件拥有发展良好的时序记忆，而这种时序记忆本可以为自我理解提供背景。由于创伤记忆的本质，能够被"回忆"的内容往往以侵入性画面、情绪和身体反应（Van der Kolk，2006；2014）的形式出现，这些都是自发地、毫无预兆地发生的，而非能够"排除合理怀疑地"说明发生了什么的叙事性记忆序列。

The "Living Legacy" of the Past

过去的"活的遗产"

Without a clear chronological record of what happened but vulnerable to the uninvited activation of trauma-related feeling and body memories, individuals are left with a legacy of symptoms and reactions with no context that identifies them as memory. Survivors of trauma later present in therapy with descriptions of their anxiety, depression, shame, low self-esteem, loneliness and alienation, problems with anger, and impulsivity or acting out. They might be troubled by chronic expectations of danger: intrusive fear and dread, hypervigilance ("eyes in the back of my head"), chronic shame and self-hatred, a conviction that the worst is about to happen, hopelessness and helplessness, fear of abandonment, numbing and disconnection from emotions. Or they may come to therapy as a last resort because they are fighting a losing battle against addiction, self-harming impulses, eating disorders, or a longing or even determination to die. Often, they can tell us very little about what evokes these self-destructive impulses that bring quick short-term relief at great risk to their safety: "I do it to punish myself," "I hate myself," "I don't deserve to live," "I'm disgusting—I wish I were dead." They sometimes struggle with how to connect these patterns to the past—but, more often, they prefer not to think about what happened then or minimize it: "It wasn't that bad."

在没有清晰的时序记录的情况下，个体却又容易被创伤相关的情感和身体记忆所不请自来地激活，留下的是没有任何背景将其识别为记忆的症状和反应的遗产。创伤幸存者随后在治疗中呈现出对焦虑、抑郁、羞耻、低自尊、孤独和疏离、愤怒问题以及冲动或行动化的描述。他们可能受到慢性危险预期的困扰：侵入性的恐惧和忧虑、过度警觉（"脑后长眼"）、慢性羞耻和自我憎恨、最坏的事情即将发生的确信、无望和无助、被遗弃的恐惧、情绪麻木和断联。或者他们可能将治疗作为最后的手段，因为他们在与成瘾、自伤冲动、饮食障碍或渴望甚至决心去死的斗争中节节败退。通常，他们几乎无法告诉我们是什么引发了这些自我毁灭的冲动——这些冲动以巨大的安全风险为代价带来快速的短期解脱："我这样做是为了惩罚自己"，"我恨我自己"，"我不值得活着"，"我令人厌恶——我希望我死了"。他们有时挣扎于如何将这些模式与过去联系起来——但更常见的是，他们宁愿不去想那时发生了什么，或将其最小化："那没那么糟糕。"

In the early history of trauma treatment, therapists relied on the "talking cure," the most commonly accepted practice in psychotherapy from the time of Freud to the present day (Rothschild, in press), to address the strong emotional reactivity of traumatized clients coupled with their lack of clarity for the traumatic events. Clients were generally encouraged to keep retrieving the memories of "what happened" until they had established a detailed narrative of the chronological events. But, when therapists adopted this approach, rather than resolving the traumatic past, clients became flooded with overwhelming implicit memories and traumatic reactions, increasingly symptomatic rather than at peace (Herman, 1992; Van der Kolk, 2014). Talking about the events of the past, therapists discovered, led to more implicit "reliving" of it. Unwittingly, the therapist and the "good child," now a grown-up client, were at long last validating the events experienced by the disowned "not me" child—while at the same time, activating the trauma-related parts and triggering their implicit memories. Feeling endangered yet again, the "not me" children were crying for help, still without being heard.

在创伤治疗的早期历史中，治疗师依赖"谈话疗法"——从弗洛伊德时代到今天，这是心理治疗中最被广泛接受的实践（Rothschild，待出版）——来处理创伤来访者强烈的情绪反应与对创伤事件缺乏清晰认识的问题。来访者通常被鼓励不断检索"发生了什么"的记忆，直到他们建立起对时序事件的详细叙述。但当治疗师采用这种方法时，来访者不仅没有化解创伤性过去，反而被大量的内隐记忆和创伤反应所淹没，变得愈加有症状而非获得平静（Herman，1992；Van der Kolk，2014）。治疗师发现，谈论过去的事件导致了更多内隐性的"重温"。在不知不觉中，治疗师和那个"好孩子"（现在已成为成年来访者）终于确认了被抛弃的"非我"孩子所经历的事件——同时激活了创伤相关部分并触发了它们的内隐记忆。再次感到危险，"非我"孩子们在呼救，依然没有被听见。

I have long believed that trauma treatment must address the effects of the traumatic past, not its events. Being able to tolerate remembering a horrific experience is not as important a goal as feeling safe right here, right now—or being able to reassure oneself that the racing of the heart is just a triggered response, not a sign of danger—or being able to relate to shame, grief, and anger as the feeling memories of child selves too young to comfort themselves. In my view, resolution of painful past events cannot truly be achieved without reclaiming the lost children and disowned parts of ourselves, extending to them a helping hand, welcoming them "home" at long last, creating safety for them, and making them feel wanted, needed, and valued. It took many decades of scientific research for the clinical world to accept that child abuse constituted an epidemic, not a rare occurrence, and that untreated post-traumatic stress resulted in tremendous social costs, not just individual suffering. Only in the last ten years have the concepts of implicit memory and bodily-driven responses to trauma become increasingly widespread (Ogden et al., 2006; Van der Kolk, 2014), but, even now, theoretical ideas about splitting, parts of the self, and dissociation are still controversial and often avoided. We as a field have not yet accepted that compartmentalization is normal under stress and much more common than we generally recognize. In a parallel process, the mental health world has had a history of disowning the prevalence of child abuse, dissociation, and fragmentation of the personality, either by ignoring its manifestations or by invalidating it as "factitious" or "malingering." To be the "good child" in the psychiatric treatment world, therapists have been under pressure to "un-see" signs of dissociation, to diagnose voices as a psychotic symptom, and to treat fragmented clients "as if" they were whole integrated human beings. To be an integrated human, as Dan Siegel (2010) insists, requires "differentiation—with linkage," that is, it necessitates the ability to make distinctions between different parts of the self, to name them as parts, but also to link them to other parts and to the whole of which they are a part. Disowning parts of one's self and over-identifying with other parts does not facilitate integration and a sense of being whole, nor does it engender an internal sense of safety that could counteract the after-effects of an unsafe, unwelcoming hostile world.

我长期以来坚信，创伤治疗必须处理创伤性过去的影响，而非其事件本身。能够忍受对可怕经历的回忆，并不如现在此刻此地感到安全那么重要——也不如能够自我安慰"心跳加速只是一种被触发的反应，不是危险的信号"那么重要——也不如能够将羞耻、悲痛和愤怒理解为年幼自我太小而无法自我安慰的情感记忆那么重要。在我看来，如果不重新找回那些失落的孩子和被抛弃的自我部分、向他们伸出援手、最终欢迎他们"回家"、为他们创造安全感，并让他们感到被需要、被珍视，那么对痛苦过去事件的真正化解就无从实现。临床世界花了数十年的科学研究才接受儿童虐待是一种流行病而非罕见事件，以及未经治疗的创伤后应激会造成巨大的社会代价，而不仅仅是个体痛苦。内隐记忆和创伤躯体反应的概念只是在过去十年才变得越来越普遍（Ogden等，2006；Van der Kolk，2014），但即便如此，关于分裂、自我各部分和解离的理论思想仍然存在争议并常被回避。我们作为一个领域，尚未接受分隔化在压力下是正常的，且比我们通常认识到的更为普遍。在一个平行的过程中，精神健康世界有着否认儿童虐待、解离和人格碎裂普遍性的历史，要么忽视其表现，要么将其定性为"人为的"或"装病"而加以否定。为了成为精神病学治疗世界中的"好孩子"，治疗师被迫"看不见"解离的迹象，将幻听诊断为精神病症状，并将碎裂的来访者"当作"完整整合的人来治疗。正如Dan Siegel（2010年）所坚持的，成为一个整合的人需要"区分与连结"，即需要能够区分自我的不同部分、将它们命名为部分，同时也将它们连结到其他部分以及它们所属的整体。抛弃自我的各部分并过度认同其他部分，既不能促进整合和完整感，也不能在内心产生可以抵消不安全、不欢迎的敌对世界后遗症的安全感。

Parallel Lives: The Disowning of Dissociation

平行的生命：解离的否认

In the history of the trauma field, the concepts of dissociation and splitting have been repeatedly observed as complications of trauma but consistently rejected as "not me," that is, as not valid or believable within the prevailing diagnostic systems and therefore to be avoided. One of the difficulties with gaining acceptance for the existence of dissociative splitting and especially dissociative disorders has been an absence of studies demonstrating a scientific basis for such dramatic, difficult-to-treat symptoms. Theories of parts tend to be metaphorical rather than biologically or brain-based. In the dissociative disorders world, the explanatory hypothesis has historically been stress-related: when events are traumatic, the theory asserts, they exceed the brain's capacity to tolerate or process them as wholes. Therefore, they must be split or compartmentalized so that overwhelming event memories are shared by dissociated parts of the same age, each carrying some portion of the memory. In this model, each part is viewed as a repository of memory, representing the history of the client at a specific time. In treatment, the parts are encouraged to "download" or disclose their memories so that the "host" can share their pain and accept their shared past. Only then could the parts begin fusing into one homogenized whole (Putnam, 1989). Although this hypothesis makes intuitive sense to many clinicians and clients, it lacks the scientific validity necessary to overcome the skepticism and disowning of dissociation by the mental health world.

在创伤领域的历史中，解离和分裂的概念被反复观察为创伤的并发症，但一再被以"非我"的方式拒绝，即在主流诊断系统中被视为无效或不可信，因而应加以回避。获得对解离性分裂尤其是解离性障碍存在的认可，困难之一在于缺乏证明此类戏剧性、难以治疗的症状具有科学基础的研究。关于各部分的理论往往是隐喻性的，而非以生物学或大脑为基础。在解离性障碍领域，历史上的解释性假说与压力相关：当事件是创伤性的时，该理论主张，它们超过了大脑作为一个整体加以耐受或处理的能力。因此，它们必须被分裂或分隔化，以便不堪重负的事件记忆由同龄的解离部分共同承担，每个部分携带记忆的某个部分。在这个模型中，每个部分被视为记忆的储存库，代表着来访者在特定时期的历史。在治疗中，各部分被鼓励"下载"或披露它们的记忆，以便"主人格"能够分担它们的痛苦并接受共同的过去。只有这样，各部分才能开始融合成一个同质化的整体（Putnam，1989年）。虽然这一假说对许多临床医生和来访者来说具有直觉上的合理性，但它缺乏克服精神健康世界对解离的怀疑和否认所需的科学效度。

Another theory is that multiplicity is normal, that all human beings have multi-consciousness rather than uni-consciousness. A mindfulness-based approach to understanding parts based on this hypothesis is Internal Family Systems or IFS (Schwartz, 1995; 2001). Known for its compassionate tone and cultivation of mindful awareness, IFS also depends upon a metaphorical theory, this one based on intrapsychic defenses: the "not-me" child is termed an "exile," hidden from conscious awareness by the activity of "managers." When the manager parts do not offer enough protection to keep exiles out of awareness, acting out by another set of parts, the "firefighters," creates distraction and crisis. Healing occurs in the IFS model when the exiled parts are reclaimed, can feel safe enough with "self," the higher self of the client, to share the disowned memories and be "unburdened" of the painful emotions and beliefs connected to the trauma.

另一种理论认为多元性是正常的，所有人类都拥有多重意识而非单一意识。基于这一假说的正念导向的部分理解方法是内部家庭系统（IFS）（Schwartz，1995；2001年）。以其富有慈悲的基调和培养正念意识而著称，IFS同样依赖于一种隐喻性理论，这个理论基于内心防御：那个"非我"孩子被称为"流放部分"，被"管理部分"的活动藏匿于有意识的意识之外。当管理部分提供的保护不足以将流放部分挡在意识之外时，另一组部分——"救火部分"——的行动化制造了分心和危机。在IFS模型中，当流放部分被重新找回，能够在来访者的更高自我——"自我"——面前感到足够安全，愿意分享被抛弃的记忆，并从与创伤相关的痛苦情绪和信念中得到"减负"时，愈合就会发生。

But to bring credibility to such a controversial "not us" topic as dissociation, good clinical models without a theoretical basis are not sufficient. It took the neuroscience revolution to provide a scientific explanation for the concept of "splitting" and even to the terminology of "parts of the self." It has taken years of research to challenge the fixed negative beliefs about dissociation and dissociative disorders so prevalent in the field (Brand et al., 2016).

但要为解离这样一个颇具争议的"非我们"话题带来可信度，没有理论基础的优秀临床模型是不够的。正是神经科学革命为"分裂"的概念甚至"自我各部分"的术语提供了科学解释。研究人员花了多年时间来挑战该领域中关于解离和解离性障碍的根深蒂固的负面信念（Brand等，2016年）。

Compartmentalization under Stress: Exploiting the Fault Lines

压力下的分隔化：利用断层线

A biological basis for understanding compartmentalization under stress lies in the brain's innate "fault lines," the fact that its functions are tied to and governed by different regions and differentiated structures within each region (Van der Hart et al., 2004). One "fault line" for splitting available even at birth is the right hemisphere-left hemisphere split. Though children are born with both left and right hemispheres, they are right brain dominant for most of childhood (Cozolino, 2002; Schore, 2001). The slower developing left brain has spurts of growth around the age of language development and again at adolescence, but the development of left brain dominance is only achieved very gradually over the course of the first eighteen years of life. In addition, the corpus callosum, the part of the brain that makes possible right brain-left brain communication, also develops slowly and only becomes fully elaborated around the age of twelve (Cozolino, 2002; Teicher, 2004). Thus, in the early years of childhood, right brain experience is relatively independent of left brain experience, lending itself to splitting should the need arise. Studying brain development in children and adolescents, Martin Teicher has observed a correlation between a history of abuse and/or neglect and under-development of the corpus callosum compared to normal controls (2004), which would also support the hypothesis that trauma is associated with independent development of right and left hemispheres and that deficits in communication between the two brains may hinder right-left integration, leaving clients with "two brains" (Gazzaniga, 2015) instead of one integrated brain.

理解压力下分隔化的生物学基础在于大脑固有的"断层线"——即其功能与不同区域及每个区域内分化的结构相关联并受其支配这一事实（Van der Hart等，2004年）。甚至在出生时就已存在的一条分裂"断层线"是右半球与左半球的分裂。尽管孩子出生时左右半球都有，但他们在大部分童年期都是右脑主导的（Cozolino，2002；Schore，2001年）。发展较慢的左脑在语言发展年龄前后以及青春期出现增长高峰，但左脑优势的发展只是在人生最初十八年中逐渐实现的。此外，胼胝体——使右脑-左脑沟通成为可能的大脑部分——也发展缓慢，直到大约十二岁才完全发育（Cozolino，2002；Teicher，2004年）。因此，在童年早期，右脑体验与左脑体验相对独立，一旦需要就容易发生分裂。在研究儿童和青少年大脑发育时，Martin Teicher观察到虐待和/或忽视史与胼胝体欠发育之间存在相关性（2004年），这也支持了创伤与右脑和左脑独立发育相关的假说，以及两脑之间沟通的缺陷可能阻碍左右整合，使来访者拥有"两个大脑"（Gazzaniga，2015年）而非一个整合大脑的假说。

The "split-brain research" of the 1970s (Gazzaniga, 2015) was the first research to show the degree to which left and right hemispheres of the brain operate independently and quite differently. "Split-brain" research refers to studying patients whose right and left hemispheres have been separated by injury or surgery or who have suffered damage to the corpus callosum. Although these patients demonstrate that there seems to be some shared knowledge available to both hemispheres, only the left hemisphere uses language to describe experience and information, while the right hemisphere is more visual, better able to recognize differences and similarities between stimuli but lacking words to describe it. The right hemisphere tends to remember episodically and implicitly, whereas the left is specialized for autobiographical memory and acquired knowledge. But the left hemisphere's ability to encode information verbally does not imply that its recollection of events is more "accurate." "The left hemisphere has a tendency to grasp the gist of a situation, make an inference that fits in well with the general schema of the event, and toss out anything that does not. This elaboration has a deleterious effect on accuracy but usually makes it easier to process new information. The right hemisphere does not do this. It is totally truthful and only identifies the original [information]" (Gazzaniga, 2015, p. 152); that is, the right hemisphere does not "forget" the nonverbal aspects of experience and does not interpret it. Emotions, these researchers discovered, are experienced on both sides of the brain but can only be verbalized by the left hemisphere; the right hemisphere might act on the emotion but could not describe it in words. And without an exchange of information via the corpus callosum, researchers observed that the left hemisphere might have no memory of the right hemisphere's emotion-driven actions and reactions.

1970年代的"裂脑研究"（Gazzaniga，2015年）是第一个揭示大脑左右半球在多大程度上独立且截然不同地运作的研究。"裂脑"研究是指对因伤或手术导致左右半球被分离，或遭受胼胝体损伤的患者的研究。尽管这些患者表明两个半球似乎共享一些知识，但只有左半球使用语言来描述体验和信息，而右半球更具视觉性，更善于识别刺激之间的差异和相似性，但缺乏言词来描述它。右半球倾向于以情节性和内隐性方式记忆，而左半球则专门处理自传体记忆和习得知识。但左半球以语言形式编码信息的能力并不意味着其对事件的回忆更加"准确"。"左半球有一种倾向，抓住情境的要旨，做出符合事件总体图式的推断，并丢弃任何不符合的内容。这种精加工对准确性有有害影响，但通常使处理新信息更容易。右半球不这样做。它完全忠实，只识别原始信息"（Gazzaniga，2015年，第152页）；即右半球不会"忘记"体验的非言语方面，也不会对其进行诠释。研究人员发现，情绪在大脑两侧都有体验，但只能由左半球言语化；右半球可能基于情绪采取行动，但无法用语言描述它。在没有通过胼胝体进行信息交换的情况下，研究人员观察到左半球可能对右半球的情绪驱动的行动和反应毫无记忆。

Attachment research has also contributed to the literature supporting the concept of an innate tendency to compartmentalize under stress. In longitudinal studies of attachment behavior (Lyons-Ruth et al., 2006; Solomon & George, 1999; Solomon & Siegel, 2003), researchers have demonstrated that children with disorganized attachment status at age one are significantly more likely to exhibit dissociative symptoms by age 19 and/or to be diagnosed with borderline personality disorder or dissociative identity disorder in adulthood. When attachment figures are abusive, the child's only source of safety and protection becomes simultaneously the source of immediate danger, leaving the child caught between two conflicting sets of instincts. On the one hand, they are driven by the attachment instinct to seek proximity, comfort, and protection from attachment figures. On the other, they are driven by equally strong animal defense instincts to freeze, fight, flee, or submit or dissociate before they get too close to the frightening parent. Liotti (1999) hypothesizes that dissociative splitting is necessitated to manage this irresolvable struggle between two such strong emotional and physical drives and two very different internal working models: biologically, the attachment figure automatically elicits the cry for help response or proximity-seeking drive, yet approaching abusive or threatening adults also elicits fear and fight and flight responses.

依恋研究也为支持压力下固有分隔化倾向的文献做出了贡献。在依恋行为的纵向研究中（Lyons-Ruth等，2006；Solomon & George，1999；Solomon & Siegel，2003），研究人员证明，一岁时具有紊乱型依恋状态的儿童，到19岁时出现解离症状的可能性显著更高，和/或成年后被诊断为边缘性人格障碍或解离性身份障碍的可能性也显著更高。当依恋人物具有虐待性时，孩子唯一的安全和保护来源同时成为直接危险的来源，使孩子被两组相互冲突的本能所困。一方面，他们受依恋本能驱使，向依恋人物寻求亲近、安慰和保护。另一方面，他们受同样强烈的动物防御本能驱使，在接近令人恐惧的父母之前冻结、战斗、逃跑、顺从或解离。Liotti（1999年）假设，解离性分裂是管理这两种强烈的情绪和身体驱力之间以及两种截然不同的内部工作模型之间无法解决的斗争所必需的：在生物学上，依恋人物自动引发求救反应或寻求亲近的驱力，然而接近具有虐待性或威胁性的成人也引发恐惧、战斗和逃跑反应。

Van der Hart, Nijenhuis, and Steele (2004; 2006) cite yet another set of fault lines along which dissociative compartmentalization can occur: the "action systems" or drives that propel the stages of child development and adaptation to the environment. One set of drives can be seen in children's innate propensity to attach, explore, play, and develop social engagement and collaboration skills and then, as older children and adults, learn to regulate their bodily needs, mate and reproduce, and care for the next generation (Panksepp, 1998; Van der Hart et al., 2006). Equally, though, children have to depend upon their instinctive animal defenses (hypervigilance, cry for help, fight and flight, freeze, collapse and submission) to quickly inhibit exploration, social engagement, and regulating functions to ensure automatic self-protective behavior. For children raised in unsafe environments, both types of action system are necessary in response to changing internal and external demands: for example, going to school requires a part of the personality that can explore, pay attention in class, learn, and socially engage with peers and teachers. At home, with parents who may be withdrawn or neglectful at some times and violent at others, the ability to rapidly shift from state to state as needed to deal with different threats could be essential: for example, in response to the sound of the abuser's voice or footsteps, panic or fear could alert the individual to danger. Playfulness might lift the parent's irritable mood and facilitate a positive connection by making him or her laugh (social engagement). At times, it might be helpful to capitalize on the submission response to become the precociously responsible child who tries to protect younger siblings in the face of the violent behavior, but at other times, it could be safer to rely on hypervigilance, staying "on guard," carefully observing the parents' mood, and reacting in whatever ways best defend against their "frightened or frightening" behavior. These patterns of compartmentalization can be conceptualized as trauma-related procedural learning: it is safer to adapt using a system of selves rather than becoming a fully integrated "self."

Van der Hart、Nijenhuis和Steele（2004；2006年）还引用了另一组解离性分隔化可能发生的断层线：驱动儿童发展阶段和适应环境的"行动系统"或驱力。一组驱力体现在儿童固有的依恋、探索、游戏以及发展社交参与和协作技能的倾向，以及后来作为年长儿童和成人学会调节身体需求、交配繁殖和照顾下一代（Panksepp，1998；Van der Hart等，2006年）。然而同样地，儿童必须依赖其本能的动物防御（过度警觉、求救、战斗和逃跑、冻结、崩溃和顺从）来迅速抑制探索、社交参与和调节功能，以确保自动的自我保护行为。对于在不安全环境中成长的儿童，两种类型的行动系统都是回应不断变化的内外部需求所必需的：例如，上学需要一个能够探索、在课堂上专注、学习以及与同伴和老师社交参与的人格部分。在家里，与有时退缩或疏于照顾、有时又具有暴力倾向的父母在一起，根据需要迅速从一种状态转换到另一种状态以应对不同威胁的能力可能至关重要：例如，对施虐者的声音或脚步声做出反应，恐慌或恐惧可以警示个体危险的存在。嬉戏玩耍可能能够提振父母的烦躁情绪，通过逗他/她笑来促进正面的连结（社交参与）。有时，利用顺从反应成为在暴力行为面前试图保护年幼兄弟姐妹的早熟负责任孩子可能是有帮助的，但有时候，依赖过度警觉、保持"戒备"、仔细观察父母的情绪并以最能抵御其"受惊吓或令人恐惧"行为的方式做出反应，可能更为安全。这些分隔化模式可以被概念化为创伤相关的程序性学习：使用一个自我系统来适应，比成为一个完全整合的"自我"更为安全。

Extrapolating from the observations by Charles Myers of "shell-shocked" World War I veterans, Van der Hart and colleagues (2004) labeled these different drives or systems "part(s) of the personality." Although "part of the personality" remains a very controversial term in the mental health world, it has certain advantages: first, use of the word "part" clearly suggests that there is a whole person and personality—of which we are studying just one piece. Secondly, it is a word so commonly used to describe normal ambivalence or inner conflicts (e.g., "Part of me wants to eat that piece of cake so badly, but another part won't let me") that it is easily adopted by clients. And lastly, research has demonstrated the propensity of the brain to develop neural networks holding related neural pathways that consistently "fire" together, and these neural systems often encode complex systems of traits or systems (Schore, 2001) that represent aspects of our personalities or ways of being. For example, if neural pathways activating the proximity drive fire consistently in the presence of the attachment figure, along with neural pathway holding feelings of loneliness and yearning for comfort and a neural network holding the tendency to believe that "she loves me—she would never hurt me," the result might be a neural system representing a young child part of the personality with a toddler's yearning for comfort and closeness along with the magical thinking that the attachment figure will be safe and loving, yet also the uneasy feeling that something is not right. Such neural systems can be complex with a subjective sense of identity or can be a simpler collection of traits associated with different roles played by the individual.

从Charles Myers对一战"炮弹休克"退伍军人的观察推断，Van der Hart和同事们（2004年）将这些不同的驱力或系统称为"人格的部分"。尽管"人格的部分"在精神健康世界中仍是一个极具争议的术语，但它有某些优势：首先，使用"部分"一词清楚地表明存在一个完整的人和人格——我们只是在研究其中的一个部分。其次，这个词在描述正常的矛盾心理或内部冲突时极为常用（例如，"我的一部分非常想吃那块蛋糕，但另一部分不允许我"），因此很容易被来访者采纳。最后，研究表明，大脑有发展保持相关神经通路的神经网络并使其持续"一起激发"的倾向，这些神经系统往往编码了代表我们人格方面或存在方式的特质或系统的复杂系统（Schore，2001年）。例如，如果在依恋人物存在时激活亲近驱力的神经通路持续激发，连同保持孤独感和渴望安慰的神经通路以及保持相信"她爱我——她绝不会伤害我"倾向的神经网络，结果可能是一个代表人格年幼孩子部分的神经系统，带着幼儿对安慰和亲密的渴望，以及依恋人物会是安全和充满爱的魔幻思维，但同时也有事情不对劲的不安感。这样的神经系统可以是带有主观身份认同感的复杂系统，也可以是与个体扮演的不同角色相关的更简单的特质集合。

Van der Hart et al. (2006) borrowed the language of Myers in describing the aspect of self driven by daily life priorities as the "apparently normal part of the personality" and parts driven by animal defense responses as the "emotional parts of the personality," or, individually, the fight, flight, freeze, submit, or attach for survival parts. In this book, I will use terms that I have found more useful in clinical practice: the "going on with normal life part" and the "trauma-related parts" of the personality. In avoiding the words, "apparently normal," my goal is to emphasize the positive evolutionary function of parts of us driven to survive or persevere and to challenge clients' tendencies to see their ability to function as a "false self" and their trauma-related responses as the "true self." In addition, emphasizing the positive aims and goals of the "normal life" part encourages clients to strengthen their ability to regulate the tumultuous emotions and autonomic dysregulation of the animal defense-related parts, rather than either trying to ignore them or interpreting them as "the true self." Connecting different parts to the survival responses that drive their actions and reactions challenges the client's automatic shame and self-doubt: experiences of feeling rage make more sense when tied to a "fight part" triggered by an act of unfairness; automatic passivity and the inability to say "no" feels less shameful when connected to a young child submit part whose sense of safety is tied to pleasing others or feeling "less than." The concept that each part represents a way of surviving dangerous conditions, that each represents a different approach to self-protection, gives meaning and dignity to the fragmentation. The parts in this view are not repositories of memory; they were a means of surviving the 'worst of the worst,' not a means of remembering it. As I often say to my clients, "We wouldn't be sitting here together today if each part had not done its job well, if each hadn't helped you to survive." But as carriers of our instinctive survival responses, the parts remain poised for the next threat or the next trauma-related trigger for decades after "it" is over.

Van der Hart等人（2006年）借用了Myers的语言，将由日常生活优先事项驱动的自我方面描述为"人格的表观正常部分"，将由动物防御反应驱动的部分描述为"人格的情绪部分"，或单独称为战斗、逃跑、冻结、顺从或为生存而依恋的部分。在本书中，我将使用我发现在临床实践中更为有用的术语："正常生活的持续部分"和人格的"创伤相关部分"。通过避免"表观正常"这个词，我的目标是强调我们中受驱动去存活或坚持的部分的正面进化功能，并挑战来访者将其功能运转能力视为"虚假自我"、将其创伤相关反应视为"真实自我"的倾向。此外，强调"正常生活"部分的正面目标和目的，鼓励来访者加强其调节动物防御相关部分混乱情绪和自主神经失调的能力，而不是试图忽略它们或将它们解读为"真实自我"。将不同的部分与驱动其行动和反应的生存反应联系起来，挑战了来访者自动的羞耻和自我怀疑：当愤怒感与被不公正行为触发的"战斗部分"相联系时，愤怒体验变得更有意义；当与其安全感依赖于取悦他人或感到"低人一等"的年幼孩子顺从部分相联系时，自动被动和无法说"不"的感觉就不那么令人羞耻了。每个部分代表一种在危险条件下生存的方式、每个部分代表一种不同的自我保护方式这一概念，赋予了碎裂意义和尊严。在这种观点中，各部分不是记忆的储存库；它们是在"最糟中的最糟"中存活的手段，而不是记忆它的手段。正如我经常对来访者说的："如果每个部分没有做好它的工作，如果每个部分没有帮助你存活，我们今天就不会坐在这里了。"但作为我们本能生存反应的携带者，各部分在"那件事"结束后数十年内仍随时准备迎接下一个威胁或下一个创伤相关触发因素。

Recognizing the Signs of Structurally Dissociated Parts

识别结构性解离部分的迹象

Just as each individual responds to trauma differently, we would expect each client's structurally dissociated personality system to be unique. Clients whose histories of chronic trauma and/or multiple types of abuse and/or neglect necessitated more complex structural dissociation are likely to have a well-developed going on with normal life self and several different parts driven by the survival responses of fight, flight, freeze, submission, or cry for help. But even in these clients, fragmentation can be more subtle and permeable or more dramatic and rigid: some clients (e.g., those carrying PTSD or bipolar II diagnoses) might shift between clear-cut states (sometimes irritable, sometimes depressed, at other times anxious). Clients with borderline personality disorder might present at times as regressed and clinging; at other times, cold and angry; then, at still other times, hopeless and passively suicidal, while all the while functioning fairly well at work. With mild to moderate dissociative disorder not otherwise specified (DDNOS), the therapist might encounter clearly observable compartmentalization and some difficulty with memory (e.g., not clearly recalling the intense anger and aggressive behavior of their fight parts or the neediness of a young child part with separation anxiety). In clients with dissociative identity disorder (DID), not only will the number of trauma-related parts tend to be greater overall, but these clients are more likely to have other subparts serving the priorities associated with the going on with normal life self, for example, a professional self, a parenting part, or a part with special talents or social skills. In addition, as the neural systems governing each part become more elaborated and autonomous, DID clients start to exhibit switching and time loss as they are "hijacked" by parts who, when triggered, act outside the conscious awareness of the going on with normal life self.

正如每个人对创伤的反应不同，我们可以预期每位来访者的结构性解离人格系统都是独特的。那些慢性创伤和/或多种类型虐待和/或忽视的历史使他们需要更复杂的结构性解离的来访者，可能拥有发展良好的正常生活持续自我和几个由战斗、逃跑、冻结、顺从或求救等生存反应驱动的不同部分。但即使在这些来访者中，碎裂也可能更为微妙和可渗透，或更为戏剧性和刚性：一些来访者（例如，那些携带创伤后应激障碍或双相情感障碍II型诊断的人）可能在清晰的状态之间转换（有时烦躁，有时抑郁，另一些时候焦虑）。边缘性人格障碍来访者有时可能表现为退行和依附；另一些时候，冷漠和愤怒；然后，又在另一些时候，无望和被动性自杀，而始终在工作中运转得相当好。在轻至中度的其他未特指的解离障碍（DDNOS）中，治疗师可能遇到清晰可观察的分隔化以及一些记忆困难（例如，不能清楚回忆其战斗部分的强烈愤怒和攻击性行为，或具有分离焦虑的年幼孩子部分的需求性）。在解离性身份障碍（DID）来访者中，创伤相关部分的数量总体上往往更多，而且这些来访者更有可能拥有服务于正常生活持续自我相关优先事项的其他子部分，例如职业自我、父母角色部分或具有特殊才能或社交技能的部分。此外，随着支配每个部分的神经系统变得更加精细和自主，DID来访者开始表现出人格转换和时间失去，因为他们被那些在被触发时在正常生活持续自我有意识意识之外行动的部分所"劫持"。

While updating her curriculum vita, Celia, a successful organizational consultant, was surprised to discover that she had won an award in 1990 for which she had no memory. Not only could she not recall winning it, she couldn't recall what she had done to deserve it! Annie also discovered disturbing evidence of missing time and dissociative hijacking when she received a letter from her oldest friend asking her never to contact him again under any circumstances. "I will never forgive you for what you said to me last week—it was cruel, and I don't want to be hurt anymore." Lacking a memory of having spoken to him recently, she could not imagine why 'she' had been angry at him and what 'she' could have said that upset him so much.

在更新简历时，成功的组织顾问Celia惊讶地发现她在1990年获得了一个奖项，而对此她毫无记忆。她不仅不记得获奖，还不记得自己做了什么值得这个奖！Annie也发现了令人不安的时间缺失和解离性劫持证据，当她收到最老朋友的来信，要求她在任何情况下都不要再联系他时。"我永远不会原谅你上周对我说的话——那很残忍，我不想再受伤了。"由于没有最近与他交谈过的记忆，她无法想象为什么"她"对他生气了，以及"她"说了什么让他如此不安。

Characteristically, while the going on with normal life part tries to carry on (functioning at a job, raising the children, organizing home life, even taking up meaningful personal and professional goals), other parts serving the animal defense functions of fight, flight, freeze, submit, and "cling" or attach for survival continue to be activated by trauma-related stimuli, resulting in hypervigilance and mistrust, overwhelming emotions, incapacitating depression or anxiety, self-destructive behavior, and fear or hopelessness about the future, that is, the difficulties that often lead clients to seek psychotherapy.

典型地，当正常生活的持续部分试图继续运作（在工作中运转、抚养孩子、组织家庭生活，甚至承担有意义的个人和职业目标）时，其他服务于战斗、逃跑、冻结、顺从和为生存而"依附"或依恋等动物防御功能的部分，继续被创伤相关刺激激活，导致过度警觉和不信任、难以承受的情绪、使人丧失能力的抑郁或焦虑、自我毁灭行为以及对未来的恐惧或无望——即那些经常促使来访者寻求心理治疗的困难。

Symptoms as Communications from Parts

症状作为来自各部分的沟通

Many clients come for treatment after being flooded or "hijacked" by the trauma responses and implicit memories of the animal defense-related parts; others come when their attempts to disconnect or deny these trauma responses lead to chronic depression or depersonalization. Although some clients may present with diagnosable dissociative disorders, many more will come to therapy with trauma-related symptoms that appear initially straightforward, such as PTSD, anxiety and mood disorders, or personality disorders. However, certain symptoms can alert us to the presence of underlying structural dissociation: for example, see the following.

许多来访者在被动物防御相关部分的创伤反应和内隐记忆所淹没或"劫持"后前来接受治疗；另一些来访者则是当他们试图断开或否认这些创伤反应的努力导致慢性抑郁或人格解体时才来。尽管某些来访者可能表现出可诊断的解离性障碍，但更多人会带着最初看起来较为直接的创伤相关症状前来治疗，如创伤后应激障碍、焦虑和情绪障碍或人格障碍。然而，某些症状可以提醒我们注意潜在结构性解离的存在，例如以下这些。

Signs of Internal Splitting

内在分裂的迹象

The client functions highly at work when stimulated by "positive triggers" (work assignments, collaboration with peers, responsibilities) while regressing at home or in personal relationships because of the trauma triggers associated with those environments. Or the client might report alternating fears of abandonment followed by pushing away those who try to get close or a tendency to initially idealize others followed by disillusionment and anger when they fail the client in some way. The fears of abandonment represent communications of the attach or cry for help part as closeness to others exacerbates that part's separation anxiety; the pushing away is the response of a fight part activated by the risk of vulnerability or hurt. Splitting often manifests in paradoxical behavior: fears of triggers might be intense, while the client lacks appropriate fears for real threats; the client plans a family vacation for the following summer while simultaneously ruminating on her determination to suicide; or he describes himself as "enlightened," kind, and reasonable, while family and friends portray the client as typically angry, arrogant, and demanding.

来访者在被"正面触发因素"（工作任务、与同事的合作、责任）刺激时在工作中高效运转，而在家里或个人关系中由于与那些环境相关的创伤触发因素而出现退行。或者来访者可能报告交替出现的被遗弃恐惧，随后是推开试图亲近的人，或最初将他人理想化，随后当他们以某种方式让来访者失望时出现幻灭和愤怒的倾向。被遗弃的恐惧代表了与他人亲近加剧其分离焦虑时，依恋或求救部分的沟通；推开是由脆弱或受伤风险激活的战斗部分的反应。分裂常常以矛盾行为表现出来：对触发因素的恐惧可能很强烈，而来访者对真实威胁缺乏适当的恐惧；来访者计划明年夏天的家庭度假，同时又沉浸在自杀决心的反刍中；或者他将自己描述为"开悟的"、善良的和理性的，而家人和朋友却将来访者描述为通常愤怒、傲慢和苛求的。

Treatment History

治疗史

The client reports a number of previous treatments that have resulted in little progress or clarity, or describes those treatments as rocky and tumultuous or having ended in some unusually dramatic way. The therapist or previous therapists report feeling "in over my head," "inadequate for what he or she needs," "don't have the skills," while the client reports fearing therapist abandonment more than therapeutic inadequacy.

来访者报告了若干没有带来多少进展或清晰认识的既往治疗，或将那些治疗描述为曲折动荡的，或以某种异常戏剧性的方式结束的。治疗师或既往治疗师报告感到"深不可测"、"无法胜任他/她的需求"、"没有相关技能"，而来访者报告对治疗师被遗弃的恐惧多于对治疗本身不足的担忧。

Somatic Symptoms

躯体症状

Unusual pain sensitivity or uncharacteristically high pain tolerance, stress-related headaches, eye blinking or drooping, narcoleptic symptoms, even physical symptoms with no diagnosable medical cause can be trauma-related or a symptom of dissociative activity. One of the most common indicators of structural dissociation is atypical or non-responsiveness to psychopharmacological medications (Anderson, 2014). In these instances, parts are communicating somatically: blinking or drooping of the eyelids often signals dissociative switching; a collapsed left shoulder and a tense, raised right shoulder might be evidence of a submissive part on the non-dominant side of the body and a part ready to fight connected to the physically stronger dominant side of the body.

不寻常的痛觉敏感或非典型性的高痛耐受性、与压力相关的头痛、眼睑眨动或下垂、发作性睡病症状，甚至没有可诊断医学原因的躯体症状，都可能与创伤相关或是解离活动的症状。结构性解离最常见的指标之一是对精神药物的非典型或无反应性（Anderson，2014年）。在这些情况下，各部分正在以躯体方式进行沟通：眼睑眨动或下垂通常预示着解离性转换；左肩塌陷而右肩紧绷抬高，可能是身体非主导侧顺从部分的证据，以及与身体更强壮的主导侧相连的准备战斗部分的证据。

"Regressive" Behavior or Thinking

“退行性”行为或思维

Sometimes, the client's body language seems more typical of a young child than an adult of his or her chronological age: he or she might appear shy, collapsed, fearful, unable to tolerate being seen, or unable to make eye contact. The message might be: "I'm scared—don't hurt me" or "Please notice me—please like me" or "Please don't leave me." Verbal and cognitive style can also reveal the presence of younger parts of the self: concrete or black/white thinking, words or style of expression more typical of a child than an adult. Children use shorter sentences, express themes related to separation, caring, and fairness, and are more likely to feel empathically failed when not well understood.

有时，来访者的肢体语言似乎更像是一个年幼孩子而非其实际年龄的成人：他/她可能看起来羞怯、蜷缩、充满恐惧、无法忍受被看见，或无法进行目光接触。信息可能是："我害怕——不要伤害我"或"请注意我——请喜欢我"或"请不要离开我"。语言和认知风格也可以揭示自我较年幼部分的存在：具体或非黑即白的思维，更像孩子而非成人的词语或表达方式。儿童使用较短的句子，表达与分离、关怀和公平相关的主题，并且在没有被充分理解时更容易感到共情的失败。

Patterns of Indecision or Self-Sabotage

优柔寡断或自我破坏的模式

Often misinterpreted as "ambivalence," a client's inability to make small everyday decisions or problems with carrying out his or her expressed intentions can reflect conflicts between parts with opposite aims. Often this phenomenon manifests in frequent changes of job, career, or relationship, or a history of success in life alternating with self-sabotage or inexplicable failure, high functioning alternating with decompensation, hard work being suddenly undone by self-destructive actions. Very crucial life decisions can be involved, but often this pattern appears in difficulties in daily living such as an inability to choose what to wear in the morning, what to eat for breakfast, or whether to keep a date with a friend for lunch.

通常被误解为"矛盾心理"，来访者无法做出日常小决策或难以执行其明确表达的意图，可能反映了目标相反的各部分之间的冲突。这一现象通常表现为频繁更换工作、职业或关系，或生活中成功史与自我破坏或莫名其妙的失败交替出现，高效运转与失代偿交替，辛苦工作突然被自我毁灭性行动所撤销。可能涉及非常重要的人生决策，但这种模式往往出现在日常生活困难中，例如早上无法选择穿什么、吃什么早餐，或是否去赴与朋友的午餐约会。

Memory Symptoms

记忆症状

While memory gaps and "time loss" are cardinal symptoms of dissociative disorders, more subtle memory problems can be indicative of structural dissociation. For example, all of the following memory issues are common manifestations of parts activity: difficulty remembering how time was spent in a day, difficulty remembering conversations or the focus of therapy sessions, "black outs," getting lost while driving somewhere familiar (such as going home from work), forgetting well-learned skills (such as how to drive), or engaging in behavior one does not recall.

虽然记忆空白和"时间失去"是解离性障碍的主要症状，但更细微的记忆问题可能表明结构性解离的存在。例如，以下所有记忆问题都是各部分活动的常见表现：难以记住一天中时间是如何度过的，难以记住对话或治疗会谈的重点，"黑暗时刻"，在驾车前往熟悉地点时迷路（例如从工作返回家中），忘记已熟练掌握的技能（例如如何驾驶），或做出自己不记得的行为。

Patterns of Self-Destructive and Addictive Behavior

自我毁灭与成瘾行为的模式

Many studies have demonstrated correlations between suicidality and self-harm and addictive behavior with a history of trauma, so it should not be surprising that therapists encounter traumatized clients who struggle against their own self-destructive behavior. My assumption is that unsafe behavior consistently reflects the activation of fight and flight-driven parts by trauma-related triggers. While the going on with normal life self of the client seeks therapy because he or she is committed to life, to wanting "all the things everyone wants," fight parts engage in high-risk behavior or attempt to harm the body or end life in the effort to get relief from the implicit memories at any cost. Parts driven by the flight response tend to engage in eating disorders that result in numbing or addictive behavior that alters consciousness, allowing distance from unbearable feelings and flashbacks. Fight-related parts are prone to more violent actions, whether aggression toward others or self-harm and suicidal behavior. In a pilot study using the structural dissociation model with a group of severely symptomatic inpatients hospitalized for 2–10 years to prevent intentional or unintentional suicide, six of the eight subjects demonstrated marked improvement after a year of psychoeducationally based treatment focused on identifying the parts connected to the unsafe behavior and strengthening the ability of the going on with normal life self to identify and separate from the impulses of self-destructive parts (Fisher, in press).

许多研究已经证明了自杀倾向和自伤及成瘾行为与创伤史之间的相关性，因此治疗师遇到与自身自我毁灭行为抗争的创伤来访者应该不足为奇。我的假设是，不安全行为始终反映了创伤相关触发因素对战斗和逃跑驱动部分的激活。当来访者的正常生活持续自我因其致力于生命、渴望"每个人都想要的一切"而寻求治疗时，战斗部分从事高风险行为或试图伤害身体或结束生命，不惜一切代价从内隐记忆中获得解脱。受逃跑反应驱动的部分倾向于从事导致麻木的饮食障碍或改变意识的成瘾行为，以便远离难以承受的感受和闪回。战斗相关部分倾向于更多的暴力行动，无论是对他人的攻击还是自伤和自杀行为。在一项使用结构性解离模型对一组因防止有意或无意自杀而住院2-10年的严重症状性住院患者进行的试验研究中，八名受试者中有六名在以识别与不安全行为相关的部分为重点并加强正常生活持续自我识别和分离自我毁灭部分冲动能力的心理教育为基础的治疗一年后显示出显著改善（Fisher，待出版）。

By the time the trauma survivor appears at our doorstep, the neurobiological and psychological effects of a dysregulated autonomic nervous system, disorganized attachment patterns, and structurally dissociated parts will have become a set of well-entrenched, familiar, habitual responses. He or she will be unconsciously driven by post-traumatic implicit procedural learning activated by trauma-related triggers. The symptoms and triggered reactions now will be so familiar and automatic that, subjectively, they feel like "just who I am." Although apparently unrelated to the past, these "just who I am" responses are the conveyors of a narrative that cannot be fully remembered or put into words, a history held by different parts of the personality with different perspectives, triggers, and survival responses.

当创伤幸存者出现在我们门口时，失调的自主神经系统、紊乱的依恋模式和结构性解离部分的神经生物学和心理影响，已经成为一套根深蒂固的、熟悉的、习惯性的反应。他/她将被创伤相关触发因素激活的创伤后内隐程序性学习无意识地驱动。当前的症状和被触发的反应现在是如此熟悉和自动，以至于从主观上感觉像是"就是我这个人"。尽管表面上与过去无关，这些"就是我这个人"的反应是一个无法被充分记忆或付诸语言的叙事的传递者，是由人格的不同部分以不同视角、触发因素和生存反应所承载的历史。

For Gillian, the anger, shame, and hopelessness she felt at age 26 had that quality: she didn't have to account for why she felt those feelings because they were so familiar, so much a part of her. She didn't think to be curious about how fearless she could become when angry or how quickly shame and hopelessness could take over her body and stop her words in mid-sentence. Nor was she curious about how confident she was in her ability as an artist, unafraid to market her work yet so afraid of displeasing people in personal relationships. Gillian didn't even feel alarmed by what her therapist called the "suicidal part"; she simply accepted as normal her strong wish not to live. Normal life was a distant memory—something that had once been important to her—but now long gone. She didn't see the subtle but meaningful signs that her going on with normal life part was still alive and well and had always been, even during the worst of times. She was still a wise, mature mother figure for her little sister and the emotional support of her mother—a role that gave her a sense of control over the chaos in the family. Secondly, she had used her aesthetic and creative abilities as a safe haven as a child—that was the side of her with which she identified as "the good side," leading her to become a professional ceramicist in her early twenties. She minimized it: "Hey, if I didn't have an alcoholic mother, I'd probably go in for drugs, so I'm addicted to making things—so what?"

对于Gillian来说，她26岁时感受到的愤怒、羞耻和无望正具有这种特质：她不必解释为什么会有这些感受，因为它们是如此熟悉，如此成为她的一部分。她没有想到要对愤怒时自己会变得多么无所畏惧感到好奇，也没有想到羞耻和无望会多迅速地接管她的身体并让话语在句中停止。她也没有对自己作为艺术家的能力有多自信感到好奇——她不惧推销自己的作品，却在个人关系中如此害怕令人不悦。Gillian甚至没有对治疗师所称的"自杀部分"感到警觉；她只是将自己强烈的不想活着的愿望当作正常接受。正常生活是遥远的记忆——曾经对她很重要的东西——但现在早已消逝。她没有看到她的正常生活持续部分仍然活着且运转良好，并且即使在最糟糕的时候也一直如此的那些微妙但有意义的迹象。她仍然是妹妹的智慧成熟的母亲式人物和她母亲的情感支撑——这个角色给了她对家庭混乱的控制感。其次，她从小就将她的审美和创造能力用作避风港——那是她认同为"好的一面"的部分，使她在二十多岁时成为了一名职业陶艺师。她将其最小化："嘿，如果我没有一个酗酒的母亲，我可能会染上毒品，所以我沉迷于制作东西——那又怎样？"

As Gillian attests, trauma survivors all too often develop other symptoms that represent neurobiologically regulating attempts to cope with the trauma: self-injury and suicidality, risk-taking, re-enactment behavior, caretaking and self-sacrifice, revictimization, and addictive behavior. All of these behaviors represent different ways of modulating a dysregulated nervous system and preparing for the next threat: self-injury and planning suicide induce adrenaline-related responses of power, icy calm, control, and physical strength but also a relaxation effect from increased production of endorphins; restricting, binging and purging, and overeating all induce emotional and bodily numbing; and addictive behaviors can be tailored to evoke either numbing or increased arousal or a combination of both. Historically, in the mental health field, we have addressed these issues first by stabilizing unsafe behavior and then treating the traumatic events. But narrative memories are connected to intense states of autonomic arousal. Because the activation "readies" us for danger, remembering is likely to reactivate self-destructive impulses. Even "thinking about thinking about" the memories (Ogden et al., 2016) is often enough to cause a reactivation of the nervous system as if the events were recurring in the here-and-now. The neurobiological research and a better understanding of the somatic legacy of trauma advise us to take a new and different course in treatment (Van der Kolk, 2014; Ogden et al., 2006). (See Chapter 2 on Understanding Parts, Understanding Traumatic Responses and Chapter 7 on Working with Suicidal, Self-Destructive, Eating Disordered, and Addicted Parts.)

正如Gillian所证实的，创伤幸存者常常发展出其他代表着神经生物学上调节性的应对创伤尝试的症状：自伤和自杀倾向、冒险、重演行为、照顾他人和自我牺牲、再次受害以及成瘾行为。所有这些行为代表了调节失调的神经系统并为下一个威胁做好准备的不同方式：自伤和计划自杀诱发与肾上腺素相关的力量感、冷静、控制和身体力量反应，但也有内啡肽分泌增加的放松效果；限制饮食、暴饮暴食和清除以及过度饮食都诱发情绪和身体麻木；成瘾行为可以被定制为引发麻木或增加唤醒或两者的组合。历史上，在精神健康领域，我们首先通过稳定不安全行为然后处理创伤事件来解决这些问题。但叙事记忆与自主神经唤醒的强烈状态相连。因为激活使我们为危险做好"准备"，记忆可能会重新激活自我毁灭的冲动。甚至"思考关于思考"记忆（Ogden等，2016年）往往足以导致神经系统的重新激活，仿佛事件在此时此地再次发生。神经生物学研究和对创伤躯体遗产的更好理解建议我们在治疗中采取新的不同路线（Van der Kolk，2014；Ogden等，2006年）。（参见第2章理解各部分、理解创伤性反应，以及第7章与自杀、自我毁灭、饮食障碍及成瘾部分工作。）

Helping Clients and Their Parts "Be Here" Now

帮助来访者及其各部分"活在当下"

When their symptoms represent implicit memories held by trauma-related parts expressing emergency and survival responses, individuals continue to feel unsafe, and their parts continue to defend, as if threatened now. When trauma responses are misinterpreted in these ways, it threatens the parts: it feels like proof that they are endangered, defective, or trapped in a hopeless situation. Once again, the felt sense is that they are in danger, alone, without protection. Our first priority in treatment must be to challenge this subjective perception that their symptoms are indicative of current danger or proof of their defectiveness or "just who they are." Therapists need to counteract the habitually triggered danger signals and trauma responses by calling attention to these reactions as communications from parts. When clients are provided with psychoeducation about structural dissociation, encouraged to become mindful and curious instead of reactive, helped to develop new responses to triggers, they begin to build the capacity to self-regulate and to "be here now." Then, by pacing the exploration of the past in such a way that the autonomic nervous system gets a chance to experience regulation instead of dysregulation, clients can experience moments of what I call "being present in the present," moments of feeling calm in the body, being able to think clearly, knowing they are safe.

当他们的症状代表着由表达紧急和生存反应的创伤相关部分所持有的内隐记忆时，个体继续感到不安全，他们的各部分继续防御，仿佛当前正受到威胁。当创伤反应被这样误解时，它威胁到各部分：感觉就像是他们处于危险中、有缺陷或被困在无望处境中的证明。再一次，体感是他们处于危险中，孤独，没有保护。我们在治疗中的首要任务必须是挑战他们的症状表明当前危险或其缺陷性或"就是他们这个人"的主观感知。治疗师需要通过将这些反应作为来自各部分的沟通加以关注，来抵消习惯性触发的危险信号和创伤反应。当来访者获得关于结构性解离的心理教育，被鼓励变得正念和好奇而非反应性，被帮助对触发因素发展出新的反应时，他们开始建立自我调节和"活在当下"的能力。然后，通过以自主神经系统有机会体验调节而非失调的方式引导对过去的探索，来访者可以体验我所称的"当下在场"的时刻，感到身体平静、能够清晰思考、知道自己是安全的片刻。

In the next chapter, we will explore how to understand the issues and symptoms described by our clients as manifestations of the "living legacy" of trauma. Without an understanding of post-traumatic implicit memory or structural dissociation, not knowing they have been triggered by some cue reminiscent of the past, they interpret fear, shame, and anger as signs of imminent danger or deep-seated inadequacy. It can be a relief to discover that their stuckness, resistance, chronic depression, fear of change, entrenched fear and self-hatred, crisis and conflict, even suicidality all can be communications from parts who fear for their lives, unaware that the dangers they are bracing against are now in the past. Disappointment, criticism, closeness, or distance, even authority figures, may no longer be life-threatening, but each nonetheless evokes trauma-related implicit memories and the parts that hold them. Helping clients learn to become curious and interested in their symptoms and able to identify the voices that speak through their reactions can change their relationship to themselves and to the past from one of shame and dread to one of compassion. Knowing that each part is charged with the mission to survive, each in its own way, helps clients to see that how they survived was more crucial than how they were victimized. Understanding how each part participated in survival increases the sense of "we, together" and challenges the sense of being abandoned and alone. Feeling warmth and empathy for young wounded selves feels healing and comforting.

在下一章中，我们将探讨如何将来访者所描述的问题和症状理解为创伤"活的遗产"的表现。在没有对创伤后内隐记忆或结构性解离的理解的情况下，不知道自己已被过去的某些线索触发，他们将恐惧、羞耻和愤怒解释为迫在眉睫的危险或根深蒂固的不足的迹象。发现他们的停滞、抵抗、慢性抑郁、对变化的恐惧、根深蒂固的恐惧和自我憎恨、危机和冲突，甚至自杀倾向，都可能是那些为生命担忧、不知道他们戒备的危险现在已成为过去的各部分发出的沟通，这可能会带来宽慰。失望、批评、亲近或距离，甚至权威人物，可能不再是危及生命的，但每一个仍然唤起创伤相关的内隐记忆和承载它们的各部分。帮助来访者学会对自己的症状感到好奇和感兴趣，并能够识别通过其反应说话的声音，可以将他们与自己和过去的关系从羞耻和恐惧转变为慈悲的关系。知道每个部分都被赋予了以自己的方式存活的使命，帮助来访者看到他们如何存活比他们如何被害更为重要。理解每个部分如何参与了存活，增强了"我们，在一起"的感觉，挑战了被遗弃和孤独的感觉。对年轻受伤的自我感到温暖和共情，感觉是愈合的和令人安慰的。

References

Brand, B.L., Sar, V., Stavropoulos, P., Kruger, C., Korzekwa, M., Martinez-Taboas, A., & Middleton, W. (2016). Separating fact from fiction: an empirical examination of six myths about dissociative identity disorder. Harvard Review of Psychiatry, 24(4), 257–270.

Cozolino, L. (2002). The neuroscience of psychotherapy: building and rebuilding the human brain. New York: W.W. Norton.

Gazzaniga, M. S. (1985). The social brain: discovering the networks of the mind. New York: Harper-Collins.

Gazzaniga, M. S. (2015). Tales from both sides of the brain: a life of neuroscience. New York: Harper-Collins.

Herman, J. L. (1992) Trauma and recovery. New York: Basic Books.

Liotti, G. (1999). Disorganization of attachment as a model for understanding dissociative psychopathology. In J. Solomon and C. George (Eds.). Attachment disorganization. New York: Guilford Press.

Lyons-Ruth, K. et al. (2006). From infant attachment disorganization to adult dissociation: relational adaptations or traumatic experiences? Psychiatric Clinics of North America, 29(1).

Ogden, P., Minton, K., & Pain, C. (2006). Trauma and the body: a sensorimotor approach to psychotherapy. New York: W.W. Norton.

Panksepp J. (1998). Affective neuroscience: the foundations of human and animal emotions. New York: Oxford University Press.

Putnam, F.W. (1989). Diagnosis and treatment of multiple personality disorder. New York: Guilford Press.

Schore, A.N. (2001). The effects of early relational trauma on right brain development, affect regulation, and infant mental health. Infant Mental Health Journal, 22, 201–269.

Schore, A.N. (2010). Relational trauma and the developing right brain: the neurobiology of broken attachment bonds. In T. Bardon, Relational trauma in infancy: psychoanalytic, attachment and neuropsychological contributions to parent-infant attachment. London: Routledge.

Schwartz, R. (1995). Internal family systems therapy. New York: Guilford Press.

Schwartz, R. (2001). Introduction to the internal family systems model. Oak Park, IL: Trailhead Publications.

Siegel, D. J. (2010). The neurobiology of 'we.' Keynote address, Psychotherapy Networker Symposium, Washington, D.C.

Solomon, J. & George, C. (1999). Attachment disorganization. New York: Guilford Press.

Solomon, M.F. & Siegel, D.J., Eds. (2003). Healing trauma: attachment, mind, body and brain. New York: W.W. Norton.

Teicher, M.H. et al. (2004). Childhood neglect is associated with reduced corpus callosum area. Biological Psychiatry, 56(2), 80–85.

Van der Hart, O., Nijenhuis, E.R.S., Steele, K., & Brown, D. (2004). Trauma-related dissociation: conceptual clarity lost and found. Australian and New Zealand Journal of Psychiatry, 38, 906–914.

Van der Hart, O., Nijenhuis, E.R.S., & Steele, K. (2006). The haunted self: structural dissociation and the treatment of chronic traumatization. New York: W. W. Norton.

Van der Kolk, B. A. (2006). Clinical implications of neuroscience research in PTSD. Annals NY Academy of Sciences, 1–17.

Van der Kolk, B.A. (2014). The body keeps the score: brain, mind and body in the healing of trauma. New York: Viking Press.

CHAPTER 2
Understanding Parts, Understanding Traumatic Responses

第2章
理解各部分，理解创伤性反应

"When the images and sensations of experience remain in 'implicit-only' form …, they remain in unassembled neural disarray, not tagged as representations derived from the past … Such implicit-only memories continue to shape the subjective feeling we have of our here-and-now realities, the sense of who we are moment to moment, but this influence is not accessible to our awareness."

「当体验的意象与感觉仅以'内隐'形式存在……它们仍处于尚未整合的神经混乱之中，未被标注为源自过去的表征……这类纯内隐记忆持续塑造着我们对当下现实的主观感受，以及我们时时刻刻对自我身份的感知，但这种影响并不在我们的意识可及范围之内。」

(Siegel, 2010, p. 154)

Trauma often leaves its legacy in ways that don't fit traditional diagnostic or treatment molds. Rather than finding relief in disclosing their secrets, clients feel ashamed, mistrustful, or exposed. Instead of feeling better, they experience difficulty remembering or generalizing their new learning outside of therapy and return like Winnie the Pooh to the very same place over and over. Or there is no one "she" or "he" with whom the therapist can work. The agitated, angry client of last week is often replaced by someone who is depressed, shut down, unable to say more than a few dark words. Then, the next week, plans for the future are the subject of discussion rather than despair and suicide. When we mention last week's disclosure of sexual abuse, the client is surprised; the disclosure has been forgotten as if it hadn't occurred. Whereas, last week, therapy was the client's only safe place, today it feels unsafe and threatening. Worse yet, the determination to change has given way to the fear of change. Not only is the therapist confused by these shifting states of mind, so too is the client.

创伤留下的印记，往往不符合传统的诊断或治疗框架。来访者非但没有从倾诉秘密中得到宽慰，反而感到羞耻、不信任或暴露无遗。他们不仅没有好转，还难以记住或将在治疗中获得的新认知迁移到治疗室以外，像小熊维尼一样一次又一次回到同一个地方。抑或治疗师根本找不到一个稳定的"她"或"他"可以合作。上周那个焦躁易怒的来访者，这周往往换成了一个抑郁、关闭、只能吐出几句灰暗言词的人。而到了下一周，话题又变成了对未来的规划，而非绝望与自杀。当治疗师提及上周吐露的性虐待经历时，来访者却大感意外；那次披露仿佛从未发生过，已经被遗忘了。上周，治疗室是来访者唯一的安全之地；今天，它却令人感到危险和恐惧。更糟的是，改变的决心已让位于对改变本身的恐惧。不仅治疗师被这些变幻莫测的心理状态搞得困惑，来访者自己也是如此。

In the context of life threat, survival is a necessity. Being able to consciously witness the experience, preserve a sense of time, place, and identity, and clearly encode a memory of what happened frame-by-frame is an unnecessary luxury when human beings are in immediate danger. Faced with potential threat, the brain and body instinctively mobilize the emergency stress response, preparing the individual to take action: fleeing, fighting, ducking, and hiding. As danger cues are perceived by the sensory system, a chain reaction of neurochemical events is set in motion. The amygdala (a structure that serves as the brain's smoke detector and fire alarm) begins to "fire" more rapidly, activating another limbic system structure, the hypothalamus, to initiate an adrenaline release to "turn on" the sympathetic nervous system. As the adrenaline release speeds up heart rate and respiration to increase oxygen flow to muscle tissue, the body prepares to engage fight-flight impulses. The individual feels braced and strong; the events unfold in slow motion; an icy calm replaces fear; the eyes narrow; and the body prepares for action, clenching fists, engaging the leg muscles, biceps, and shoulders. As fight and flight responses unfold, release of another neurochemical, cortisol, begins to activate reciprocal activity in the parasympathetic nervous system. The parasympathetic system is best known for its role in recuperation, rest, and states of calm and is often referred to as an "energy conservation system" in contrast to the "energy expending" sympathetic system (Ogden et al., 2006). As the body mobilizes for fight and flight, the parasympathetic system prepares the body to freeze (like a deer in the headlights) to avoid exposure or to submit or "feign death" (Porges, 2011) if the individual is trapped with no way out, no way to defend. The parasympathetic system also helps the body recover from the massive expenditure of energy involved in fighting and fleeing, facilitating feelings of depletion, exhaustion, "just need to sleep," or numbing.

在生命受到威胁的情境下，生存是必然的选择。当人类处于即时危险之中，能够有意识地见证体验、保持对时间、地点和身份的感知，并逐帧清晰地编码所发生的记忆，不过是一种无谓的奢侈。面对潜在威胁，大脑和身体本能地启动紧急应激反应，为个体做好采取行动的准备：逃跑、战斗、躲闪与藏匿。当感官系统感知到危险信号时，一系列神经化学反应链便被触发。杏仁核（大脑的烟雾探测器兼火灾警报器）开始更加迅速地"放电"，激活另一个边缘系统结构——下丘脑，启动肾上腺素释放，从而"开启"交感神经系统。肾上腺素释放加速心率与呼吸，以增加肌肉组织的氧气供应，使身体准备好投入战斗或逃跑冲动。个体感到紧绷而有力；事件以慢动作展开；一种冰冷的平静取代了恐惧；眼睛微眯；身体准备行动，握紧拳头，收紧腿部肌肉、二头肌和肩膀。随着战斗和逃跑反应的展开，另一种神经化学物质——皮质醇——的释放开始在副交感神经系统中激活对应活动。副交感神经系统以其在恢复、休息和平静状态中的作用而闻名，通常被称为"能量储存系统"，以区别于"能量消耗"的交感神经系统（Ogden等，2006）。当身体为战斗和逃跑做好动员时，副交感神经系统会让身体进入冻结状态（如路灯前的鹿），以避免暴露；或者，当个体陷入无路可逃、无法防御的困境时，副交感神经系统会让其顺从或"装死"（Porges，2011）。副交感神经系统还帮助身体从战斗和逃跑所消耗的大量能量中恢复，带来精疲力竭、"只想睡觉"或麻木的感觉。

In traumatogenic environments where the threat of danger is ever-present, it is more adaptive for both children and adults when their bodies are conditioned to maintain a readiness for potential danger. These automatic patterns of response may be sympathetically activated (biased toward hypervigilance, high arousal, readiness to take action, impulsivity) or parasympathetically dominant (without energy, exhausted, slowed, numb, disconnected, hopeless and helpless). For children or victims of domestic violence who endure day-in-day-out conditions of threat or for whom being seen and not heard is the safest adaptation, it is common to see parasympathetic patterns of passivity, slowed thinking, and depression or shame dominating the individual's experience. In sympathetically dominant clients, it is more typical to see hyperactivity, reactivity, feelings of anger or fear, a readiness to act first and think later, and mistrust or hypervigilance.

在危险威胁无处不在的创伤性环境中，儿童和成人的身体被条件化地保持对潜在危险的警觉状态，这具有更强的适应性。这些自动反应模式可能是交感神经激活的（偏向于高度警惕、高度唤醒、随时准备行动、冲动性），也可能是副交感神经主导的（无精打采、精疲力竭、行动迟缓、麻木、断离感、绝望和无助）。对于那些日复一日承受威胁状态的儿童或家庭暴力受害者，或那些以"看得见但不能发声"作为最安全适应策略的人而言，常见的是副交感神经模式的被动性、思维迟缓以及抑郁或羞耻主导个体体验。而在交感神经主导的来访者中，更典型的表现是过度活跃、反应激烈、愤怒或恐惧感、先行动后思考的冲动，以及不信任或高度警惕。

Because survival depends upon sympathetic highs and parasympathetic lows to drive animal defense responses, these clients' nervous systems have been conditioned to dysregulate under stress. The parts connected to sympathetic arousal (fight and flight parts, the attach part, and the freeze part) and those connected to parasympathetic arousal (submit, the going on with normal life self) are primed for activation as the nervous system responds to triggers. Under traumatic conditions, individuals fail to develop or lose the capacity for a "window of tolerance" (Ogden et al., 2006; Siegel, 1999). The "window of tolerance" refers to the individual's bandwidth or capacity to tolerate intense emotions at the sympathetic end and bored, numb, or "low" feelings at the parasympathetic end. Because most threatening conditions for traumatized children are recurrent or "enduring" (Saakvitne, 2000), there is generally very little opportunity to develop a window of tolerance. To adapt, their bodies have had to be on high alert, ready for action, or to be disconnected, numb, passive, and able to endure whatever comes. When they are triggered later in childhood or as adults, their nervous systems are already conditioned to activate the same autonomic responses and animal defenses that served them best as children (Ogden et al., 2006). As Grigsby and Stevens (2000) stress, "An activity that previously has been adaptive is likely to recur because the brain functions automatically, but probabilistically, to produce that [same] behavior in similar circumstances" (p. 51). The body's instinct to prepare for the next threat, while ensuring survival, is inconsistent with the opportunity to recover from what has just happened, to feel a sense of "it's over now," or to reset the nervous system to a calm, resting state. Years later, clients often report a feeling of anxiety when they begin to access feelings of calm: "It feels so weird," they complain, "I'm not comfortable with it."

由于生存依赖于交感神经的高度唤醒和副交感神经的低落状态来驱动动物防御反应，这些来访者的神经系统已被条件化地在压力下失调。与交感神经唤醒相连的部分（战斗部分、逃跑部分、依恋部分和冻结部分）以及与副交感神经唤醒相连的部分（顺从部分、正常生活自我部分），在神经系统对触发因素做出反应时，均处于随时激活的备战状态。在创伤条件下，个体未能发展出或已失去了"耐受之窗"的能力（Ogden等，2006；Siegel，1999）。"耐受之窗"是指个体在交感神经端容忍强烈情绪、在副交感神经端容忍无聊、麻木或"低落"感受的带宽或能力。由于大多数受创伤儿童所面临的威胁性情境是反复发生或"持续性的"（Saakvitne，2000），发展耐受之窗的机会通常极为有限。为了适应，他们的身体不得不始终保持高度警觉、随时备战，或者处于断离、麻木、被动的状态，能够忍受任何降临的事情。当他们在童年后期或成年后被触发时，其神经系统已被条件化地激活与童年时期最有效的相同自主神经反应和动物防御（Ogden等，2006）。正如Grigsby和Stevens（2000）所强调的："曾经具有适应性的活动可能会重复发生，因为大脑以自动的、但有概率性的方式，在类似情境中产生[相同的]行为"（第51页）。身体为下一次威胁做好准备的本能，虽然保证了生存，却与从刚刚发生的事情中恢复、感受到"现在已经结束了"或将神经系统重置为平静安息状态的机会相悖。多年以后，来访者常常报告，当他们开始触及平静的感觉时会产生焦虑："感觉太奇怪了，"他们抱怨道，"我对此感到不舒服。"

In addition, when the autonomic nervous system is repeatedly activated, the hippocampus (the part of the brain responsible for putting experience into chronological order and perspective preparatory to being transferred to verbal memory areas) is suppressed (Van der Kolk, 2014). Without a functioning hippocampus or prefrontal cortex, the individual is deprived of an opportunity to witness what happened or to process it and is left instead with only the "sensory elements [of the experience] … unintegrated and unattached" (Van der Kolk, Hopper, & Osterman, 2001). For the very worst of human experiences, the body's survival responses have impeded the mind and body from making meaning of what has happened. Survivors are left with a confusing array of unfinished neurobiological responses and "raw data," i.e., the overwhelming feelings, physical reactions, intrusive images, sounds, and smells associated with the event encoded as implicit memories and therefore unrecognizable as "memory."

此外，当自主神经系统被反复激活时，海马体（大脑中负责将体验按时间顺序排列并进行整合、为转移至言语记忆区域做准备的部分）会受到抑制（Van der Kolk，2014）。在缺乏正常运作的海马体或前额叶皮层的情况下，个体被剥夺了见证所发生之事或对其进行加工的机会，只剩下体验中那些"感官元素……未经整合、悬而未决"（Van der Kolk, Hopper和Osterman，2001）。面对最为惨烈的人类遭遇，身体的生存反应阻碍了心智与身体对所发生之事赋予意义的能力。幸存者只剩下一堆令人困惑的、未完成的神经生物学反应和"原始数据"——即与事件相关的排山倒海的感受、身体反应、侵入性意象、声音和气味，这些都以内隐记忆的形式编码，因此无法被辨识为"记忆"。

With the advent of brain scan technology in the mid-1990s, it became possible to study traumatic memory by observing the brain's response to "script-driven provocation," a type of research in which subjects recall the details of a specific trauma while their brain activity is scanned and recorded. Bessel van der Kolk (2014; 1994) had been arguing for years that "the body keeps the score:" that traumatic memories did not resolve as did ordinary memories because they were physiologically driven rather than subject to deliberate recall. He believed that this underlying physiology accounted for the occurrence of "re-enactment behavior" in trauma patients and a host of other symptoms we associate with post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD). In addition, most trauma survivors tended to have either too many unbidden intrusive memories or "not enough" memory to feel certain of what happened, very different from their memories of ordinary events that could be willingly recalled.

随着20世纪90年代中期脑扫描技术的出现，通过观察大脑对"脚本驱动诱发"的反应来研究创伤记忆成为可能——这是一种让受试者回忆特定创伤细节、同时对大脑活动进行扫描记录的研究方法。Bessel van der Kolk（2014；1994）多年来一直主张"身体铭记着一切"：创伤记忆之所以无法像普通记忆那样消解，是因为它们由生理驱动，而非受有意识回忆的支配。他认为，这种潜在的生理机制解释了创伤患者中出现的"重演行为"以及我们与创伤后应激障碍（PTSD）相关的一系列其他症状。此外，大多数创伤幸存者倾向于拥有过多不请自来的侵入性记忆，或对所发生之事"记忆不足"而难以确定，这与他们可以主动回忆的普通事件记忆截然不同。

The brain scan research slowly but surely revealed the causes of these unique characteristics of traumatic memory: when research subjects recalled a traumatic event in their own words, the language and narrative areas of the prefrontal cortex became inactive, while emotional memory centers in the right hemisphere limbic system, especially the amygdala, became highly activated. With the left hemisphere language centers inhibited, these subjects were speechless, leaving the amygdala to "fire" (i.e., stimulate an emergency stress response) unchecked—as if the event were happening all over again. This research thus confirmed another characteristic of traumatic memory: even if it could not be deliberately retrieved and verbalized, it could be activated by triggers (i.e., stimuli in some direct or indirect way connected to traumatic events), even decades after the events were over. Gillian provides us with a good example of these characteristics of traumatic memory.

脑扫描研究缓慢而确定地揭示了创伤记忆这些独特特征的成因：当研究受试者用自己的语言回忆一个创伤事件时，前额叶皮层的语言和叙事区域变得不活跃，而右半球边缘系统的情绪记忆中枢，尤其是杏仁核，则变得高度激活。随着左半球语言中枢受到抑制，这些受试者陷入失语状态，任由杏仁核不受约束地"放电"（即刺激紧急应激反应）——仿佛事件正在重新发生一般。这项研究因此证实了创伤记忆的另一个特征：即便无法被有意识地提取和用语言表达，它也可以被触发因素（即以某种直接或间接方式与创伤事件相关联的刺激）激活，甚至在事件结束数十年后仍然如此。Gillian为我们提供了这些创伤记忆特征的一个典型案例。

Gillian's traumatic experiences of 10 years before were reflected in triggered implicit memory states: swings from anger to numbing, shame and self-doubt, difficulty attaching to others but also difficulty tolerating aloneness or separation, feeling overwhelmed and wanting to die "to get it over with." She didn't remember clearly her mother's neglect or older brother's incestuous behavior, and she would never have thought to connect her extreme feelings to the events she could recall, but as a 26-year-old still living in her parents' home, she was constantly triggered by apparently benign stimuli. Though her mother was now less depressed and her brother was an adult and out of the home, the house was full of "landmines." The most innocuous stimuli (e.g., being alone in the house, not being "heard" when she tried to express her feelings, disappointment that no one understood her) evoked strong feelings that she still wasn't "safe."

Gillian十年前的创伤经历，以被触发的内隐记忆状态呈现出来：从愤怒到麻木的剧烈摇摆、羞耻与自我怀疑、难以与他人建立依恋关系，同时又难以忍受孤独或分离，感到被压垮，想要死去"一了百了"。她对母亲的忽视或哥哥的乱伦行为没有清晰的记忆，也从未想过将自己的极端感受与能够回忆起的事件相联系。然而，作为一个26岁仍住在父母家中的年轻人，她不断被表面上看似无害的刺激所触发。尽管母亲现在不那么抑郁了，哥哥也已成年离家，但这栋房子里却到处是"地雷"。最无害的刺激（例如独自一人在家、试图表达感受时不被"倾听"、没有人理解自己的失望感）都会激发强烈的感受——她仍然不"安全"。

Uninvited Remembering

不请自来的记忆

As difficult as it can be to deliberately recall traumatic experiences as a past event, the brain's "negativity bias" (Hanson, 2014), its tendency to perceive and prioritize negative stimuli more quickly than positive stimuli, results in long-term sensitivity to all cues related to previous danger. Even very subtle cues (e.g., Gillian's being alone at home or feeling disappointed) can stimulate the implicit memories and inadvertent uninvited "remembering." Without stimulus discrimination, unavailable when the prefrontal cortex is inhibited, the body responds as if the individual was facing life-or-death threat now. It instinctively mobilizes the same survival defense responses as if the client were in immediate danger. For survivors of trauma now in their 40s, 50s, and 60s, this reactivation of memory via triggers has been especially costly. Many have been victims of triggering for many more years than they were exposed to the actual traumatic events. Without awareness that their triggered responses are evidence of body and emotional memory, they "believe" the pounding heartbeat, burning shame, braced muscles, inability to breathe, numbing, and/or explosive rage are signs that they are in danger. When it becomes clear that they are not at risk, other fears arise: maybe they are going crazy, or have proof they are defective, or maybe they are just going through the motions of life "pretending." On the basis of this "evidence," many traumatized individuals isolate and withdraw, end healthy relationships prematurely or explosively, or can't end unhealthy ones. Many function but avoid living life fully to reduce their exposure to triggers, and others engage in self-destructive behavior to manage the overwhelming feelings and activation, only to feel more damaged and defective.

尽管有意识地将创伤经历作为过去事件加以回忆本已相当困难，但大脑的"负性偏向"（Hanson，2014）——即比正性刺激更快地感知并优先处理负性刺激的倾向——会导致个体对所有与既往危险相关的线索产生长期敏感性。即便是极其细微的线索（例如Gillian独自一人在家，或感到失望），也能激活内隐记忆，引发无意间不请自来的"记忆"。在前额叶皮层受到抑制而无法进行刺激辨别的情况下，身体的反应仿佛个体此刻正面临生死威胁，本能地动员起与来访者处于即时危险时相同的生存防御反应。对于如今年届四五六十岁的创伤幸存者而言，这种通过触发因素重新激活记忆的过程尤为代价高昂。许多人遭受触发的年数，远远超过他们实际暴露于创伤事件的年数。由于不了解自己被触发的反应是身体记忆和情绪记忆的证据，他们"相信"那砰砰直跳的心跳、灼烧般的羞耻感、绷紧的肌肉、无法呼吸、麻木和/或爆发性的愤怒，是自己正处于危险中的迹象。当明显不处于危险之中时，新的恐惧又随之而来：也许他们快要精神失常了，或者这是自己有缺陷的证明，抑或他们只是在"假装"度日。基于这些"证据"，许多受创伤的个体变得孤立和退缩，过早或激烈地结束健康的关系，或者无法结束不健康的关系。许多人虽能维持基本功能，却为了减少接触触发因素而回避充分地生活，另一些人则通过自我毁灭性行为来管理排山倒海的感受和激活状态，结果只是感到更加受损和有缺陷。

"Remembering" Actions and Reactions

"记忆"行为与反应

With a more scientific understanding of the neurobiology of trauma, traumatic memory can now be understood as a highly complex phenomenon. How each individual encodes memories of the traumatic past is unique and different, but what each has in common is the way in which memory is fragmented and unintegrated. Some trauma survivors have more explicit memories for events; some have little to none. All have a host of implicit memories, including trauma-related emotions, autonomic arousal responses, muscle and body memories, cognitive distortions, and visceral memories, as well as tactile-olfactory-visual and auditory memories.

随着对创伤神经生物学的科学认识不断深入，创伤记忆现在可以被理解为一种高度复杂的现象。每个人对创伤过去的记忆编码方式都是独特而各异的，但所有人的共同之处在于记忆的碎片化和未整合状态。一些创伤幸存者对事件有较多的外显记忆；另一些则几乎没有。所有人都拥有大量内隐记忆，包括与创伤相关的情绪、自主神经唤醒反应、肌肉和身体记忆、认知扭曲以及内脏记忆，以及触觉-嗅觉-视觉和听觉记忆。

And to a greater or lesser degree, all "remember" via trauma-related procedural or conditioned learning (Grigsby & Stevens, 2000), too. The procedural memory system is a subset of implicit or nonverbal memory that encodes function, action, and habit: that is, riding a bike, driving a car, social behavior like shaking hands or smiling on greeting others, and well-learned abilities from playing the piano to playing golf or tennis. Survival "habits" are also encoded as procedurally learned behavior—for example, tendencies to automatically disconnect from strong emotion or to feel overwhelmed by it, difficulty making eye contact, need for a certain physical proximity or distance from others, withdrawal or isolation, difficulty asking for help or disclosing feelings and personal information, a tendency to say "too much" or "too little," phobias of emotions or emotional expression, avoidance of having one's back to others or to doors and windows, habits of freezing, fighting or fleeing in response to stress or triggers.

而且，所有人在程度不一的情况下，都会通过创伤相关的程序性或条件化学习来"记忆"（Grigsby和Stevens，2000）。程序性记忆系统是内隐记忆或非言语记忆的一个子集，它编码功能、行为和习惯：例如骑自行车、驾驶汽车、握手或见人微笑等社交行为，以及从弹钢琴到打高尔夫或网球等习得性技能。生存"习惯"也以程序性学习行为的形式被编码——例如，自动与强烈情绪断开联系或被其淹没的倾向，难以进行眼神接触，对与他人保持特定身体距离或亲近感的需要，退缩或孤立，难以寻求帮助或披露感受和个人信息，倾向于说"太多"或"太少"，对情绪或情绪表达的恐惧，回避背对他人或门窗，以及在压力或触发因素面前习惯性地冻结、战斗或逃跑。

To the extent that the individual has difficulty identifying implicit emotional, physical, or procedural memories as "memory," reality-testing can become compromised, creating a kind of self-triggering. When particular people or situations are experienced as unsafe, there is a tendency for them to become "demonized," that is, to become associated with danger or menace. Once the trigger is also a trigger, the body responds to it as a danger signal in its own right; the prefrontal cortex shuts down; and there is no witnessing brain to discriminate memory from present reality. Gillian's fear of helping professionals illustrates how innocuous or even positive stimuli can become associated with a sense of threat and thereafter experienced as dangerous. It also demonstrates that if the implicit memories and trauma responses are associated with a child part, reality-testing will be even more challenging because a child part's cognitive style, limited by the age or developmental stage of that part, is likely to be more concrete.

在个体难以将内隐情绪记忆、身体记忆或程序性记忆识别为"记忆"的程度上，现实检验能力可能受损，从而产生一种自我触发。当特定的人或情境被体验为不安全时，就会产生将其"魔鬼化"的倾向，即将其与危险或威胁相关联。一旦触发因素本身也成为触发因素，身体就会将其作为危险信号做出反应；前额叶皮层关闭；没有见证性的大脑来区分记忆与当下现实。Gillian对助人专业人员的恐惧，说明了无害甚至正面的刺激如何能够与威胁感相关联，继而被体验为危险。这也表明，如果内隐记忆和创伤反应与一个儿童部分相关联，现实检验将更具挑战性，因为儿童部分的认知风格受限于该部分的年龄或发展阶段，往往更为具体化。

Gillian developed a fear of therapy and therapists in her early teens: as the family's identified patient, she was sent to one therapist after another to be "fixed." None of them "got" what her behavior was communicating about her mother's alcoholism or her brother's abuse and focused on strengthening her relationship with her family by getting her to be more compliant. "Not being understood," "not being heard," or "no one getting it" are all very powerful triggers for traumatized individuals. Without realizing it, the therapists' automatic assumption that this was a healthy but overly permissive family with a challenging child made them triggering stimuli and therefore dangerous. Isolated from her peers, the "best friend" of her fragile mother, dependent on her father's financial assistance, and triggered by the helping professionals, Gillian regarded therapy as a dangerous place she had to navigate rather than as a source of help and safety. Had she known that her fear was a communication from a young child part that longed for help but was triggered by the failure of former therapists to "believe her," Gillian would have been able to make a connection between the past and present. She might even have felt protective of this little girl and tried to stand up for "her." She might have been able to reassure the child that, even if no one else did, Gillian believed her unquestionably. Gillian knew what had happened. She might even have been able to tell the little girl that not being understood or believed was hurtful but it wasn't dangerous—as long as she was in Gillian's care.

Gillian在十几岁初期就对治疗和治疗师产生了恐惧：作为家庭中被认定的"病人"，她被一个接一个地送去治疗师那里，希望被"修复"。没有一位治疗师能"读懂"她的行为所传达的信息——那些关于母亲酗酒和哥哥虐待的信息——而是将重心放在通过让她变得更顺从来强化她与家人的关系。"不被理解"、"不被倾听"或"没有人懂我"，对受创伤的个体来说都是极为强烈的触发因素。治疗师们在不自觉中做出了自动化假设——认为这是一个健康但过于宽松的家庭，有个难以管教的孩子——这使他们自身成为触发因素，因而变得危险。Gillian与同龄人相互隔绝，是脆弱母亲的"最好的朋友"，依赖父亲的经济资助，又被助人专业人员所触发，她将治疗视为一个必须小心应对的危险场所，而非帮助与安全的来源。如果她知道自己的恐惧是来自一个渴望帮助却因前任治疗师未能"相信她"而被触发的幼小儿童部分的信息，Gillian便能在过去与现在之间建立起联系。她甚至可能对这个小女孩产生保护欲，试图为"她"站出来发声。她或许能够安抚这个孩子——即使没有其他人相信她，Gillian也毫无疑问地相信她。Gillian知道发生了什么。她甚至可能告诉这个小女孩，不被理解或相信是痛苦的，但并不危险——只要她在Gillian的照顾之中。

For trauma treatment to be effective, no matter what methods we employ, survivors have to be able to integrate past and present. Concretely, this step requires education: about what traumatic memory is and is not, about triggers and triggering stimuli, about learning to accurately label triggered states ("this is a feeling memory"—"a body memory"), and cultivating the ability to trust that triggered states "tell the story" of the past without the necessity to either recall or avoid recalling specific incidents. When the therapist can also help clients connect implicit memory states to young parts of the self, it is easier to address them as a record of old dangers instead of signs of current threat. Also, when the triggered sensations, emotions, and images are reframed as "the child part's feelings," clients are better able to tolerate their intensity. Feeling compassion or protectiveness for younger selves also helps the clients to feel their "big-ness," to appreciate the physical size differences, the adult capabilities and resources, and the greater respect which individuals are accorded as adults and the greater safety it enables them to count on.

无论采用何种方法，要使创伤治疗有效，幸存者必须能够整合过去与现在。具体而言，这一步骤需要心理教育：关于创伤记忆是什么、不是什么，关于触发因素和触发刺激，关于学会准确标注被触发状态（"这是一种感受记忆"——"一种身体记忆"），以及培养相信被触发的状态"讲述着"过去的故事、无需回忆或刻意回避特定事件的能力。当治疗师能够帮助来访者将内隐记忆状态与自我的年幼部分相连接时，将其作为旧有危险的记录而非当下威胁的迹象来处理，就会变得更容易。同样，当被触发的感觉、情绪和意象被重构为"儿童部分的感受"时，来访者也能更好地承受其强度。对年幼自我感到慈悲或保护欲，也有助于来访者感受到自己的"宏大感"，意识到身体尺寸上的差异、成人的能力和资源，以及成年后所获得的更多尊重，以及这种尊重使他们能够依靠的更大安全感。

Finding "Now," Not "Then"

找到"现在"，而非"过去"

It is not difficult for traumatized individuals to re-experience the past, explicitly or implicitly. What is more challenging is how to "be here now" when one's body is communicating "danger, danger—red alert!" We now know that, as important as it is to acknowledge the past, it is even more crucial for traumatized individuals to stay connected to present time: "Right now, I can feel my feet—I can see where I am—this is just a moment—it will pass." The past does not have to be denied or avoided. It simply is (Rothschild, in press). Acknowledging the past without exploring it or observing the past intruding into present experience is very validating for traumatized clients: "Of course you are sensitive to disappointment! After a childhood of neglect and false promises, who wouldn't be sensitive to disappointment?" Acknowledgment of the past while lingering in the awareness of the present is much more helpful to clients in the early stages of therapy than exploring the past in detail and inadvertently evoking its implicit components.

对于受创伤的个体而言，以显性或隐性的方式重新体验过去并不困难。更具挑战性的是，当身体传递着"危险，危险——红色警报！"的信息时，如何"活在当下"。我们现在知道，尽管承认过去至关重要，但对于受创伤的个体而言，保持与当下时刻的连接更为关键："此刻，我能感受到我的双脚——我能看见自己身处何地——这只是一个当下时刻——它会过去的。"过去无需被否认或回避，它只是存在着（Rothschild，即将出版）。在不深入探索的情况下承认过去，或者观察过去侵入当下体验，对受创伤的来访者来说极具肯定意义："当然，你对失望很敏感！经历了一个充满忽视和虚假承诺的童年，谁不会对失望敏感呢？"在停留于当下意识的同时承认过去，对于处于治疗早期阶段的来访者而言，远比详细探索过去、无意中唤起其内隐成分更有帮助。

When the implicit aspects of memory reactivate the sense of danger "now" instead of conveying that we are remembering dangers that are over, we can't look back on the past. There is no vantage point in the here-and-now from which to look back and view what happened "then." Rather than remembering what happened, once thought to be the goal of trauma treatment, we know now that resolution of the past requires transforming the memories. As Bessel van der Kolk wrote over 20 years ago, "[The] goal of treatment is to find a way in which people can acknowledge the reality of what has happened without having to re-experience the trauma all over again. For this to occur, merely uncovering memories is not enough: they need to be modified and transformed, i.e., placed in their proper context and reconstructed into neutral or meaningful narratives. Thus, in therapy, memory paradoxically becomes an act of creation, rather than the static recording of events …" (Van der Kolk, Van der Hart, & Burbridge, 1995, p. 2).

当记忆的内隐方面在"现在"重新激活危险感，而非传递我们正在回忆已经过去的危险时，我们便无法回望过去。在此时此地，没有一个制高点可以让我们回望并审视"那时"所发生的事情。与其说记住发生了什么——这曾被认为是创伤治疗的目标——我们现在知道，解决过去需要转化记忆。正如Bessel van der Kolk二十多年前所写的："治疗的目标是找到一种方式，让人们能够承认所发生之事的现实，而无需重新完整地体验创伤。要实现这一点，仅仅揭露记忆是不够的：它们需要被修正和转化，即被置于适当的情境中，并重构为中性的或有意义的叙事。因此，在治疗中，记忆以一种悖论性的方式成为一种创造行为，而非事件的静态记录……"（Van der Kolk, Van der Hart和Burbridge，1995，第2页）。

"Transformation" or "reconstruction" of traumatic memory occurs as the individual's relationship to both the implicit and explicit memories undergoes change, as tolerance for triggered or dysregulated states expands so that he or she can "be here now," live more fully in the present, and slowly reorganize the unprocessed implicit elements into a new narrative that, as Donald Meichenbaum (2012) says, tells a "healing story."

创伤记忆的"转化"或"重构"，发生于个体与内隐记忆和外显记忆的关系双双发生变化之时：随着对被触发或失调状态的耐受力扩展，个体得以"活在当下"，更充分地生活于现在，并缓慢地将未经加工的内隐元素重组为一个新的叙事——正如Donald Meichenbaum（2012）所说，讲述一个"疗愈的故事"。

References

Gazzaniga, M. S. (2015). Tales from both sides of the brain: a life of neuroscience. New York: Harper-Collins.

Grigsby, J. & Stevens, D. (2000). Neurodynamics of personality. 1st Edition. New York: Guilford Press.

Hanson, R. (2014). Hardwiring happiness: the new brain science of contentment, calm, and confidence. New York: Harmony Publications.

Meichenbaum, D. (2012). Roadmap to resilience: a guide for military, trauma victims and their families. Clearwater, FL: Institute Press.

Ogden, P., Minton, K. & Pain, C. (2006). Trauma and the body: a sensorimotor approach to psychotherapy. New York: W.W. Norton.

Porges S. W. (2011). The Polyvagal theory: neurophysiological foundations of emotions, attachment, communication, and self-regulation. New York: W.W. Norton.

Rothschild, B. (in press). The body remembers, volume 2: revolutionizing trauma treatment. New York: W.W. Norton.

Saakvitne, K.W., Gamble, S.J., Pearlman, L.A., & Lev, B.T. (2000) Risking connection: a training curriculum for work with survivors of childhood abuse. Baltimore, MD: Sidran Institute Press.

Siegel, D.J. (1999). The developing mind: toward a neurobiology of interpersonal experience. New York: Guilford Press.

Siegel, D. J. (2010). The neurobiology of 'we.' Keynote address, Psychotherapy Networker Symposium, Washington, D.C.

Van der Kolk, B. A. (1994). The body keeps the score: memory & the evolving psychobiology of post-traumatic stress. Harvard Review of Psychiatry, 1(5), 253–265.

Van der Kolk, B.A. (2014). The body keeps the score: brain, mind and body in the healing of trauma. New York: Viking Press.

Van der Kolk, B.A., Hopper, J., & Osterman, J. (2001). Exploring the nature of traumatic memory: combining clinical knowledge with laboratory methods. Journal of Aggression, Maltreatment & Trauma, 4(2), 9–31.

Van der Kolk, B. A., van der Hart, O., & Burbridge, J. (1995). Approaches to the treatment of PTSD. In S. Hobfoll & M. de Vries (Eds.), Extreme stress and communities: impact and intervention. NATO Asi Series. Series D, Behavioural and Social Sciences, Vol 80. Norwell, MA: Kluwer Academic.

CHAPTER 3
Changing Roles for Client and Therapist

第3章
来访者与治疗师的角色转变

"We think that by protecting ourselves from suffering we are being kind to ourselves. The truth is, we only become more fearful, more hardened, and more alienated. We experience ourselves as being separate from the whole. This separateness becomes like a prison for us, a prison that restricts us to our personal hopes and fears and to caring only for the people nearest to us. Curiously enough, if we primarily try to shield ourselves from discomfort, we suffer. Yet when we don't close off and we let our hearts break, we discover our kinship with all beings."

「我们以为，通过保护自己免受苦难，是在善待自己。然而真相是，我们只会变得更加恐惧、更加冷硬、更加疏离。我们感到自己与整体分离。这种分离感如同一座囚笼，把我们局限在个人的希冀与恐惧之中，只关心最亲近的人。奇怪的是，若我们主要致力于屏蔽不适，我们反而会受苦。然而当我们不再封闭自己，当我们让内心碎裂，我们便发现了自己与所有众生的亲缘关系。」

(Pema Chodren, 2008, p. xxxx)

In the aftermath of trauma, individuals' symptoms and difficulties reflect how their minds and bodies once tried to adapt to circumstances beyond their control. "Not feeling alive in the present" might have once served as an antidote to the threat of annihilation: if we don't feel alive, the threat loses its power to terrify us. Depression might once have provided a cushion against disappointment and being overwhelmed. Hypervigilance enables even children to stand guard over themselves. Numbing and loss of interest allow the individual protection against grief and disappointment: if you don't care, it doesn't matter anymore. Anger pushes others away before they cause harm or, worse yet, before the survivor develops an attachment to them. It would be rare in the mental health treatment world to think of these symptoms as adaptive strategies made possible by the body's instinctive survival defenses. But from a neurobiologically informed perspective, they are "survival resources" (Ogden et al., 2006), ways that the body and mind adapted for optimal survival in a dangerous world. In the worst of circumstances, our survival resources save us—at a cost. By disowning the trauma, or the anger, or the need for contact with others, we lose or deny important aspects of ourselves. By over-identifying with the trauma-related shame, hopelessness, and fear of being seen, we constrict our lives and make ourselves smaller than we need to be. Both strategies, adaptive in a time of danger, become liabilities when the individual is ready to live a "life after trauma," free of the constrictions and restrictions needed for living in a traumatogenic environment.

在创伤发生之后，个体的症状与困境反映的是他们的身心曾经如何试图适应那些超出其掌控的处境。"感受不到当下的活着"曾经可能是对抗毁灭威胁的解药：如果我们感受不到活着，那个威胁便失去了令我们恐惧的力量。抑郁曾经可能是抵御失望与不堪重负的缓冲。过度警觉甚至让儿童也能自我守护。麻木与失去兴趣保护个体免受悲伤与失望之苦：如果你不在乎，一切便不再重要。愤怒在他人造成伤害之前将其推开，或者更糟的是，在幸存者对他们产生依恋之前便推开他们。在心理健康治疗领域，很少有人会将这些症状视为由身体本能生存防御所促成的适应性策略。然而，从神经生物学的视角来看，它们是"生存资源"（Ogden等，2006），是身心为了在危险世界中实现最优生存而形成的适应方式。在最糟糕的处境中，我们的生存资源以某种代价拯救了我们。通过否认创伤、愤怒，或与他人接触的需求，我们失去或拒绝了自身重要的面向。通过过度认同与创伤相关的羞耻、绝望以及对被看见的恐惧，我们收窄了自己的生活，让自己比本来所需的更加渺小。这两种策略在危险时期都具有适应性，但当个体准备好过一种"创伤之后"的生活——从容于创伤性环境中生存所需的种种束缚与限制之外——它们便成了负担。

In the absence of a context of meaning (i.e., a narrative) to explain their bewildering reactions, afraid to be curious or even more afraid to face the events that created a need for these responses, clients assume the worst: they are crazy or damaged or inadequate. Without specialized training in trauma, most therapists would not know to be curious about differentiating normal emotional responses from traumatic reactions, desperate communications from parts, ingenious survival strategies, or implicit memories. Because the client presents in crisis or chaos with emotional pain or signs of a "mental disorder," we feel a responsibility to diminish or alleviate the symptoms—curious about their origin in the childhood past perhaps but not necessarily curious about their role or their original purpose.

在缺乏意义脉络（即叙事框架）来解释其令人困惑的反应的情况下，来访者因害怕好奇、甚至更害怕面对那些催生这些反应的事件，而倾向于作出最坏的假设：自己是疯了，或是受损的，或是不够好的。若没有经过专门的创伤培训，大多数治疗师不会想到去好奇地区分：正常的情绪反应与创伤性反应、来自各部分的迫切沟通、巧妙的生存策略，还是内隐记忆。由于来访者以危机或混乱的状态呈现，伴随情绪痛苦或"精神障碍"的迹象，我们感到有责任减轻或缓解这些症状——也许会对其童年过去的源头感到好奇，但未必会对它们的作用或最初目的感到好奇。

When the therapist subsequently encounters "resistance" or trauma treatments become "stuck," our theoretical models make meaning of it, but rarely do these theories assume a creative, adaptive explanation. When clients continue to live from crisis to crisis or complain that they are not improving in therapy nor have energy for change, one hypothesis might be that they are "help-rejecting complainers" or "passive-aggressive." Or the therapist might theorize that these clients are "borderline," "attention-seeking," or manipulative, "acting out" for some secondary gain. The ashamed, chronically depressed client might be described as having "low self-esteem." Whether objectively accurate or not, these types of interpretations have gained clinicians little in terms of practical or successful client interventions for trauma.

当治疗师随后遭遇"阻抗"或创伤治疗陷入"停滞"时，我们的理论模型会为此赋予意义，但这些理论鲜少采取一种富有创造性、适应性的解读。当来访者持续在一次又一次的危机中度日，或抱怨自己在治疗中没有进步、也没有改变的能量时，一种假设可能是他们是"拒绝帮助的抱怨者"或"被动攻击型"的人。治疗师也可能理论化地认为这些来访者是"边缘型"、"寻求关注"或带有操控性，为某种次要获益而"付诸行动"。那个充满羞耻感、长期抑郁的来访者，可能被描述为"自尊心低"。无论客观上是否准确，这类解读在针对创伤的实际有效干预方面，给临床工作者带来的益处都寥寥无几。

Working with the Neurobiological Legacy of Trauma

与创伤的神经生物学遗产共事

In a neurobiologically informed treatment, a different set of theoretical principles guides our thinking. The root causes of the client's difficulty, we now know, is not just the original event but the reactivation of implicit memories by trauma-related stimuli that mobilize the emergency stress response as if the individual were in danger again (Van der Kolk, 2014). A trauma-informed treatment therefore focuses on recognizing and working in present time with the spontaneous evoking of implicit memory and animal defense survival responses rather than on creating a verbal narrative of past experiences. But since implicit memories encoded in nonverbal areas of the brain are subjectively experienced as emotional and physical reactions not distinguishable as "memory," the first task of therapy is often to help clients recognize and "befriend" their triggered reactions, rather than react to them with alarm, avoidance, or negative interpretations.

在以神经生物学为基础的治疗中，一套不同的理论原则引导着我们的思考。我们现在知道，来访者困境的根本原因，不仅仅是最初的事件本身，更是创伤相关刺激对内隐记忆的再激活——这些刺激动员了紧急应激反应，仿佛个体再度身处危险之中（Van der Kolk，2014）。因此，创伤知情的治疗聚焦于在当下识别并处理内隐记忆和动物防御性生存反应的自发唤起，而非创建关于过去经历的言语叙事。然而，由于编码在大脑非语言区域的内隐记忆，在主观上体验为情绪和躯体反应，无法辨识为"记忆"，治疗的首要任务往往是帮助来访者识别并"与之为友"其被触发的反应，而非以警觉、回避或负面诠释来回应它们。

Many traumatized clients come to therapy with unusually difficult, painful histories: severe childhood physical, emotional and/or sexual abuse, neglect, abandonment at an early age, abuse/neglect coupled with other types of trauma, multiple perpetrators, or sadistic and malevolent abuse accompanied by mind control practices, child pornography, or forced witnessing of violence. These complex histories often are accompanied by "borderline" presentations, more severe compartmentalization, and dissociative disorders or by more severe self-destructive, suicidal, and addictive behavior—or both. For over twenty years, the "gold standard" of trauma therapy has been the Phase-Oriented Treatment Model (Ogden & Fisher, 2015; Van der Hart, Nijenhuis, & Steele, 2006; Herman, 1992), a sequential approach in which the consequences of autonomic dysregulation are treated first and then, only after a period of symptom stabilization, the traumatic memories and their implicit components are addressed. Only when the past is no longer "alive" in the client's body can integration of past and present, child and adult, part and whole be completed. But for clients with chronic, multi-layered trauma histories and severe dissociative symptoms, dysregulated unsafe behavior, or chronic stuckness, the goal of stabilization can be elusive. Years of treatment focused on self-regulation and avoidance of traumatic content sometimes leads only to small steps forward—or bigger steps forward followed by setback after setback. For fear of exacerbating the dysregulation, the therapist might inadvertently collude with the client's tendencies to ignore the trauma; or fearing empathic failure, the therapist might make the opposite mistake: allowing clients to say too much and, then having triggered themselves, become overwhelmed or unsafe. Often, the therapist comes to feel equally overwhelmed by the conflicting challenges of helping the client stabilize while also feeling heard and validated and to resolve the past.

许多受创伤的来访者带着异常艰难、痛苦的历史走进治疗：严重的童年躯体、情绪和/或性虐待、忽视、早年被遗弃、虐待/忽视叠加其他类型的创伤、多名施害者，或伴随精神控制、儿童色情或被迫目睹暴力的施虐性、恶意性虐待。这些复杂的历史往往伴随着"边缘型"呈现、更严重的区隔化与解离性障碍，或更严重的自我毁灭、自杀及成瘾行为——抑或两者兼而有之。二十余年来，创伤治疗的"金标准"一直是阶段性治疗模型（Ogden和Fisher，2015；Van der Hart, Nijenhuis和Steele，2006；Herman，1992），这是一种序贯性方法，首先处理自主神经失调的后果，然后仅在症状稳定一段时间后，才着手处理创伤记忆及其内隐成分。只有当过去不再在来访者的身体中"存活"，过去与现在、儿童与成人、部分与整体的整合才能完成。但对于有慢性、多层次创伤史以及严重解离症状、失调的不安全行为或长期停滞的来访者而言，稳定化的目标可能难以企及。多年来聚焦于自我调节和回避创伤内容的治疗，有时只能带来一小步的进展——或者迈出更大的步伐后，随之而来的是一次又一次的挫折。出于对加剧失调的恐惧，治疗师可能不经意间与来访者忽视创伤的倾向共谋；或者出于对共情失败的担忧，治疗师可能犯了相反的错误：允许来访者说得太多，结果触发了自身，变得不堪重负或不安全。治疗师往往同样感到不堪重负——一方面要帮助来访者稳定，另一方面又要让其感到被倾听和被认可，同时还要化解过去，这些相互矛盾的挑战令人倍感艰难。

A Multi-Consciousness Approach to Treatment

多重意识的治疗取向

A parts approach offers some new possibilities for addressing these challenges. First and foremost, working with symptoms as manifestations of parts allows the therapist to incorporate mindfulness-based practices: helping clients "notice" their experience rather than "get in touch with it." In traumatized clients, the heightened intensity (or numbing) caused by autonomic dysregulation makes "getting in touch with feelings" either overwhelming or deadening, either of which can evoke anxiety, depression, or impulsive behavior. "Noticing" as in mindful awareness allows the client to achieve "dual awareness," the ability to stay connected to the emotional or somatic experience while also observing it from a very slight mindful distance. Secondly, a parts approach allows us to titrate emotions or memories: if one part is overwhelmed by emotional pain, other parts of the mind and body can be calm, curious, or even empathic. If one part is remembering something alarming or devastating, other parts can offer support, validation, or comfort. As meditation practices, clinical hypnosis, and other uses of mindfulness attest, the human brain is capable of holding multiple states of consciousness "in mind" simultaneously, and this ability has important therapeutic uses. The left hemisphere is associated with more positive moods and the right hemisphere with more negative states (Hanson, 2014); the medial prefrontal cortex supports an observing consciousness that enables us to "hover above" whatever we are feeling so it can be experienced as a feeling in the body rather than lead to retraumatization (Van der Kolk, 2014). Using "dual awareness," we have the capacity to fully inhabit the present moment: to feel our feet on the ground through awareness of body sensation while our visual perception takes in details of the room in which we are sitting—while, in the same moment, we can evoke an image from an earlier time in our lives that takes us "back there" to a state-specific memory.

部分取向为应对这些挑战提供了一些新的可能性。首先也是最重要的是，将症状作为各部分的表达来处理，使治疗师得以融入以正念为基础的实践：帮助来访者"注意到"自己的体验，而非"接触"它。在受创伤的来访者身上，自主神经失调所造成的强度升高（或麻木），使得"接触感受"要么令人不堪重负，要么令人死气沉沉，两者都可能引发焦虑、抑郁或冲动行为。正念觉察意义上的"注意"，让来访者得以实现"双重觉知"——即一边与情绪或躯体体验保持连接，一边从轻微的正念距离观察它的能力。其次，部分取向让我们能够滴定情绪或记忆：如果一个部分被情绪痛苦所淹没，心身的其他部分可以保持平静、好奇，甚至具有共情能力。如果一个部分正在回忆某件令人警觉或毁灭性的事情，其他部分可以提供支持、认可或安慰。正如冥想练习、临床催眠以及其他正念运用所证实的，人类大脑能够同时在"心中"持有多种意识状态，这一能力具有重要的治疗用途。左半球与更积极的情绪相关，右半球则与更消极的状态相关（Hanson，2014）；内侧前额叶皮层支持一种观察性意识，使我们能够"盘旋于"自身感受之上，让它得以作为身体中的一种感觉被体验，而非导致再创伤化（Van der Kolk，2014）。借助"双重觉知"，我们有能力完全栖居于当下：通过身体感觉的觉知感受双脚踩在地面，同时视觉感知着我们所处房间的细节——与此同时，我们又能在同一瞬间唤起生命早期的某个意象，将我们带"回到那里"，进入一段状态特异性记忆。

Describing these phenomena using the language of the brain, however, would not have the same result as does using the language of parts. To say, "I can sense my medial prefrontal cortex is curious about the negative mood state connected to the right subcortical areas of my brain" does not evoke interest, emotional connection, or self-compassion. When the therapist teaches clients to observe, "I can sense in myself some curiosity about the depressed part's sadness," they are more connected and attuned to their emotions and sensations—the first step toward achieving the ability to have compassion for themselves. Research shows that when the medial prefrontal cortex is activated, there is a decrease in activity in the right hemisphere amygdala (Van der Kolk, 2014). It is most likely activation of the amygdala by trauma-related triggers that results in flashbacks, intrusive implicit memories, automatic animal defense responses, or parasympathetic responses of disconnection, numbing, or spacing out.

然而，用大脑的语言描述这些现象，与用部分的语言描述，效果截然不同。说"我能感觉到我的内侧前额叶皮层对与大脑右侧皮层下区域相连的消极情绪状态感到好奇"，并不能唤起兴趣、情感连接或自我慈悲。当治疗师教导来访者观察"我能感受到自己对那个抑郁部分的悲伤有些好奇"时，他们与自己的情绪和感觉更加连接和协调——这是走向自我慈悲能力的第一步。研究显示，当内侧前额叶皮层被激活时，右半球杏仁核的活动会减少（Van der Kolk，2014）。创伤相关触发因素对杏仁核的激活，很可能正是导致闪回、侵入性内隐记忆、自动化动物防御反应，或解离、麻木、恍惚等副交感神经反应的原因。

Pathogenic Kernels of Memory

记忆的致病核心

If the purpose of modern trauma therapy is no longer to treat traumatic events, what should be the focus?

如果现代创伤治疗的目的不再是处理创伤事件本身，那么焦点应该放在哪里？

Van der Hart, Nijenhuis, and Steele (2006) have suggested that trauma treatment prioritize the effects or "pathogenic kernels" of the trauma, that is, those aspects of the post-traumatic legacy that still exert a traumatic effect on the client or constrict full participation in normal life even to this day. For example,

Van der Hart、Nijenhuis和Steele（2006）建议，创伤治疗应优先关注创伤的影响或"致病核心"，即创伤后遗症中那些直至今日仍对来访者施加创伤性影响、或限制其充分参与正常生活的面向。例如，

Even after years of therapy, Annie was still afraid to leave the house, resulting in a pattern of isolation—even though she hated feeling alone and lonely and stuck in the house. Although Annie was aware that it was safe in her small rural town, the shaking and trembling she experienced each time she tried to go out seemed more "real" than her factually based appraisal of her environment.
When I asked her, "What would have happened if you walked out the door in the home you grew up in?" she replied, "Anyone could get me—anyone." There was a long pause. "No wonder I can't even open the front door now—it wasn't safe even to peek out my mother's door back then!"
Though differentiating the implicit memory from factual reality gave her insight, it did not change her ability to leave the house—because the implicit memory was held not by Annie but by a structurally dissociated young part of her. Once we identified the part "who is afraid to leave the house," I asked Annie to inquire of the part, "Ask her if she'd be willing to show you a picture that would help you understand what she's afraid will happen if you walk out this door …" An image immediately came up connected to the experience of having been kidnapped at the age of seven. "Is that what you're afraid of?" she asked the child part. She could feel her head wanting to nod. "Did you think it could happen again?" Another nod. Spontaneously, Annie said to the part, "Did you know that can't happen at my house?" She felt her head nodding again. "Do you know why? Because I'm too big now, and no one can see you because you're inside me." She could feel a sense of relief and tension relaxing in her body each time she said again, "No one can see you—they only see me because you're safe inside."

尽管经过多年治疗，Annie仍然害怕出门，形成了一种孤立的模式——尽管她憎恨那种独自一人、孤独、被困在家里的感觉。Annie意识到她所在的小农村是安全的，但每当她试图出门时所经历的颤抖和发抖，似乎比她基于事实对环境的评估更加"真实"。
当我问她："如果你走出你成长的家的大门，会发生什么？"她回答说："任何人都能抓到我——任何人。"沉默了很长时间。"难怪我现在甚至无法打开前门——那时候，就连偷偷往妈妈的门外看一眼都是不安全的！"
尽管将内隐记忆与事实现实区分开来给了她洞察，但这并没有改变她出门的能力——因为这个内隐记忆并不是Annie本人所持有的，而是由她的一个结构性解离的年幼部分所持有。一旦我们识别出那个"害怕出门的部分"，我便请Annie向那个部分询问："问问她，她是否愿意给你看一幅画面，帮助你理解如果你走出这扇门她会害怕发生什么……"脑海中立刻浮现出一个与七岁时被绑架的经历相关的意象。"那是你所害怕的吗？"她问那个儿童部分。她能感觉到自己的头想要点头。"你以为这件事还会再发生吗？"又是一次点头。Annie自发地对那个部分说："你知道那件事不会发生在我家吗？"她感到自己的头再次点头。"你知道为什么吗？因为我现在太大了，没有人能看见你，因为你在我的身体里面。"每当她再次说"没有人能看见你——他们只能看见我，因为你在里面，你是安全的"，她都能感受到身体中一种如释重负、紧张舒缓的感觉。

Although there were many different traumatic events connected to the kidnapping, the "pathogenic kernel" that continued to affect her life and distort her reality was the experience of being away from home and alone—that is, what led up to the kidnapping. As we worked on ways of demonstrating to the part that Annie was too big to be kidnapped, such as measuring Annie's height on the door jam and asking the little girl to show us how tall she was, the words that consistently regulated the little part were the words, "They can't see you because you're inside me! All they can see is my big, tall body."

尽管与绑架事件相关的创伤性事件有很多，但持续影响她生活并扭曲她现实的"致病核心"，是离家在外、孤身一人的体验——也就是导致绑架发生的那段经历。当我们致力于向那个部分证明Annie已经大到不会被绑架了——例如在门框上量Annie的身高，并请那个小女孩告诉我们她有多高——能够持续安抚那个小部分的话语，始终是这些话："他们看不见你，因为你在我身体里面！他们只能看见我高大的身体。"

Another pathogenic kernel was the absence of a protective adult who would have supervised a seven-year-old that night and made sure no one would take her. That also needed to be addressed.

另一个致病核心，是那晚本应监护一个七岁孩子、确保没有人能带走她的保护性成人的缺席。这也需要被处理。

Unless her parts felt that someone cared about her/them, Annie disclosed, she had trouble feeling any safety even in her home—or in her body—because their fears were so intense. As the parts explained to her, "If someone cares about you, they watch over you to make sure nothing happens." In her previous therapy, Annie had complied with the therapist's insistence that she repeatedly recall and re-experience the traumatic events, stimulating recurrent flashbacks in and out of therapy. She remembered wanting to tell the therapist that the excavation of memory was making her worse. But, under the influence of young "attach for survival" parts wanting the therapist to care about them, she just did as the therapist said.

Annie透露，除非她的各个部分感受到有人在乎她/她们，否则即便在家里——或在自己身体里——她也难以感受到任何安全感，因为她们的恐惧是如此强烈。正如那些部分向她解释的："如果有人在乎你，他们就会守护你，确保什么事都不会发生。"在以前的治疗中，Annie顺从了治疗师的坚持，反复回忆和重新体验那些创伤性事件，在治疗内外不断刺激出反复发作的闪回。她记得自己曾想告诉治疗师，对记忆的挖掘正在让她的状态越来越差。但在那些渴望治疗师关心自己的年幼"为生存而依恋"部分的影响下，她只是照治疗师说的做了。

Influenced by widespread belief in the "talking cure," the pioneers in the trauma field initially assumed that creation of a narrative and being able to "tell the story" to a witness were sufficient to process "what happened" and resolve the symptoms (Rothschild, in press). A corollary assumption was that the worst effects on the individual would be dictated by the worst aspects or details of the trauma. Therefore, one might think it important to process those "worst" memories.

在"谈话疗法"这一广泛信念的影响下，创伤领域的先驱者最初假设，创建叙事并能够向见证者"讲述故事"，足以处理"所发生的事情"并化解症状（Rothschild，待出版）。一个相关假设是，对个体影响最深的，将由创伤中最糟糕的面向或细节所决定。因此，人们可能认为处理那些"最糟糕"的记忆是重要的。

These assumptions leave therapists trained to use the phase-oriented treatment model in a quandary: while it does not feel empathically attuned to ask clients to avoid telling their stories, the prioritizing of stabilization requires focusing away from traumatic events. On the other hand, meeting the client's "need to 'get it out'" is also risky. The former risks empathic failure; the latter risks destabilization. What does the therapist do when caught between "a rock and a hard place?"

这些假设让接受了阶段性治疗模型训练的治疗师陷入两难：一方面，要求来访者避免讲述自己的故事，感觉上并不符合共情协调；另一方面，优先考虑稳定化又要求将焦点从创伤事件上移开。而另一面，满足来访者"需要'把它说出来'"的需求同样有风险。前者冒着共情失败的风险，后者则冒着去稳定化的风险。当治疗师被夹在"进退两难"之间，该怎么办？

Acknowledging the Past Without Exploring It

承认过去而不深入探究它

When we start to understand traumatic memory from a neurobiological perspective, client memories do not have to be avoided or discharged. We simply have to help clients develop a different relationship to both their explicit and implicit memories. It is the details of memory and chronological scene-by-scene retelling that activates associated implicit memories, dysregulates the nervous system, and can have a retraumatizing effect on the client. Acknowledging the trauma or implicit triggered memories is never unsafe, especially when we allude to the "bad things that happened" in a more general way without vivifying the details of them or using triggering language, such as "rape," "incest," or "penetration." When the therapist alludes to the "unsafe world you grew up in," or "the years when nowhere was safe," most clients feel validated and supported. This kind of matter-of-fact acknowledgment of the past often calms the traumatized nervous system rather than activating it: it conveys, "Someone knows how it was."

当我们开始从神经生物学的角度理解创伤记忆时，来访者的记忆既不必被回避，也不必被宣泄。我们只需帮助来访者对其外显记忆和内隐记忆都发展出一种不同的关系。正是记忆的细节以及按时间顺序逐幕讲述，激活了相关的内隐记忆，使神经系统失调，并可能对来访者产生再创伤的效果。承认创伤或内隐的被触发记忆从来都不是不安全的，尤其是当我们以更笼统的方式暗示"曾经发生的坏事"，而不渲染其细节，也不使用触发性语言（如"强奸"、"乱伦"或"插入"）时。当治疗师提及"你成长其中的那个不安全的世界"，或"任何地方都不安全的那些年"，大多数来访者都会感到被认可和支持。这种对过去实事求是的承认，往往能平息受创伤的神经系统，而非激活它：它传达了"有人知道那是怎样的。"

In addition, when they talk about a traumatic event, therapist and client have a choice of focus: they can concentrate on the experience of horror (most likely to trigger implicit memories), or on the victimization and objectification (most likely to trigger shame), or they can bring attention to how the individual survived. How did he adapt to a traumatogenic environment? How did she "fight" or "flee" without incurring more punishment? How did he get up and go to school the next morning?

此外，当他们谈论某个创伤性事件时，治疗师和来访者有选择焦点的自由：可以聚焦于恐惧的体验（最可能触发内隐记忆），或聚焦于受害化和物化（最可能触发羞耻感），也可以将注意力引向个体如何生存下来。他是如何适应创伤性环境的？她是如何在不招致更多惩罚的情况下"战斗"或"逃跑"的？他是如何在第二天早晨起床去上学的？

Annie's fear of leaving the house and the need to have proximity to a protective figure were reflections of how she survived: via hypervigilant anticipation of danger, constriction of her activities to what was safe, and a focus on pleasing people and gaining their loyalty. Though other parts longed to be a part of "normal life" and yearned for closer connections to others, the fearful agoraphobic 7-year-old had been dictating defensive avoidance for many years. As Annie learned to correctly interpret "her" fear of leaving the house as a communication from a frightened little girl, she could more easily work with her "agoraphobia." She began by bringing up images of the door the little part was afraid to open (i.e., the door of her childhood home) and praising the seven-year-old for figuring out that she should never, ever, ever open that door. Then Annie would call up images of the door in her own home that she wanted to open to a safe neighborhood and community. She visualized taking hold of the seven-year-old's hand, somatically communicating that she was there and would not let anyone harm her. Over many weeks of Annie's patient reassurance and help in orienting her to the present by focusing on the images, this young child part was increasingly able to trust that the door she and Annie opened was not the same door that had once led to a dangerous world.

Annie对出门的恐惧以及需要靠近一个保护性人物，是她如何生存下来的反映：通过对危险的过度警觉性预期、将活动收缩到安全的范围内，以及专注于取悦他人、赢得他们的忠诚。尽管其他部分渴望融入"正常生活"、渴望与他人建立更亲密的联系，但那个充满恐惧的广场恐惧症式的7岁孩子，多年来一直在主导着防御性的回避。当Annie学会将"她"对出门的恐惧正确诠释为一个受惊小女孩的沟通时，她便能更轻松地与自己的"广场恐惧症"共事了。她从唤起那个小部分害怕打开的门的意象开始（即她童年家园的那扇门），称赞那个七岁孩子想明白了她永远、永远、永远不应该打开那扇门。然后Annie会唤起她自己家里那扇她想要打开、通向安全街区和社区的门的意象。她在脑海中握住那个七岁孩子的手，以躯体的方式传达她在场、不会让任何人伤害她。经过Annie耐心地一周又一周地安抚，并通过专注于意象帮助她定向于当下，这个年幼的儿童部分越来越能够相信，她和Annie所打开的那扇门，并不是那扇曾经通向危险世界的门。

A Different Approach to Traumatic Memory

处理创伤记忆的另一种取向

In today's trauma treatment world, therapist and client have many more choices when it comes to treating traumatic memory. We can choose what kind of memory to treat: implicit or explicit memory? Memories of dehumanizing events or memories of ingenious survival? Memories as held by parts? Cognitive schemas? Incomplete actions? Or procedural memories of habitual actions and reactions? We can touch on memory by acknowledging it, naming it as a part's memory or as an implicit feeling or body memory. The therapist can help the client observe how it continues to exert its effects through pathogenic kernels that may or may not have any obvious connection to narrative. What is different is that the therapist no longer has to be focused preferentially on becoming a witness to the client's narrative regardless of its effects on his or her symptoms and stability. Instead, the trauma therapist's job is to create in the therapy hour a neurobiologically regulating environment that enables the client's nervous system to experience greater safety and therefore an expanded capacity for tolerating both past and present experience (Ogden et al., 2006).

在今天的创伤治疗世界中，治疗师和来访者在处理创伤记忆方面有了更多的选择。我们可以选择处理哪类记忆：内隐记忆还是外显记忆？非人性化事件的记忆，还是巧妙生存的记忆？由各部分所持有的记忆？认知图式？未完成的行动？还是习惯性行为和反应的程序记忆？我们可以通过承认记忆、将其命名为某个部分的记忆、或作为一种内隐的感受或身体记忆来触及它。治疗师可以帮助来访者观察，记忆如何通过致病核心持续发挥其影响——这些核心可能与叙事有明显的关联，也可能没有。不同之处在于，治疗师不再需要优先专注于成为来访者叙事的见证者，无论其对症状和稳定性产生何种影响。相反，创伤治疗师的工作，是在治疗时段内创造一个神经生物学意义上的调节性环境，使来访者的神经系统得以体验更大的安全感，从而扩展对过去和当下体验的耐受能力（Ogden等，2006）。

A Different Kind of Witness

另一种见证方式

Although many clients are relieved to know that "telling the story" is a choice but not a requirement of the therapy, some profess a longing or intense feeling of need to tell someone "what happened." A neurobiologically informed therapist can also bear witness to the individual's story but in a different way than in traditional models. As witness in a psychodynamic approach, the therapist is a receptive listener who can tolerate hearing the story, even its horrifying details, and still "be there" for the storyteller. A good witness in this approach never interrupts even when the client becomes autonomically activated or makes meaning of the events by constructing a "self-defeating narrative" (Meichenbaum, 2012), such as "it was my fault." In a neurobiologically oriented world, this approach raises concerns: a story told chronologically and in detail to a silent witness is more likely to trigger trauma-related autonomic responses and implicit memories, reactivating the neural networks as if the client were again in danger. As a silent listener without a way to keep track of the client's autonomic dysregulation or cortical activity, we have no way to know: is the client overwhelmed? Is the client able to mentalize and thereby witness being witnessed? Or is the prefrontal cortex shut down? If clients are dysregulated and cortically inhibited, they cannot take away a corrective memory or coherent narrative of having been heard.

尽管许多来访者得知"讲述故事"是一种选择而非治疗的要求后感到如释重负，但仍有一些人表达了渴望，或强烈感到需要告诉某人"发生了什么"。以神经生物学为导向的治疗师同样可以见证个体的故事，但方式与传统模型有所不同。在心理动力学取向中，作为见证者的治疗师是一位接受性的聆听者，能够忍受听到故事——甚至是其骇人的细节——同时仍然为讲述者"在场"。这一取向中一位好的见证者从不打断，即便来访者自主神经被激活，或通过构建"自我挫败叙事"（Meichenbaum，2012）——例如"这是我的错"——来对事件赋予意义。在以神经生物学为导向的视角中，这一做法引发了担忧：按时间顺序详细地向一位沉默见证者讲述的故事，更有可能触发创伤相关的自主神经反应和内隐记忆，重新激活神经网络，仿佛来访者再度身处危险之中。作为一个沉默的聆听者，无法追踪来访者的自主神经失调或皮层活动，我们无从得知：来访者是否被压垮了？来访者是否能够心智化，从而见证被见证的体验？还是前额叶皮层已经关闭？如果来访者失调且皮层受到抑制，他们便无法带走一段被倾听的矫正性记忆或连贯叙事。

Differentiating Past from Present

区分过去与现在

The ability to differentiate being triggered and being threatened is key to trauma treatment. We have to know we are safe now in order to effectively process how unsafe it was then. The therapist has to be curious: can this client differentiate objectively between a trauma and a trigger? Or does he interpret the triggering as "danger now"? Without education about the phenomenon of implicit memory and a prefrontal cortex capable of taking in this new information, post-traumatic dysregulation, hypervigilance, impulsivity, and/or shutdown will be repeatedly reinforced by the simple phenomenon of triggering. In the example below, Sheila insisted that telling her story was the only way she could resolve the intense pressure she felt inside that kept communicating to her: "I have to tell someone."

区分被触发和被威胁的能力，是创伤治疗的关键。我们必须知道自己现在是安全的，才能有效地处理那时是多么不安全。治疗师必须保持好奇：这位来访者能否客观地区分创伤与触发因素？还是他将被触发诠释为"现在有危险"？如果没有关于内隐记忆现象的心理教育，以及一个能够吸收这一新信息的前额叶皮层，创伤后失调、过度警觉、冲动性和/或关闭，将会被简单的触发现象一再强化。在下面的例子中，Sheila坚持认为，讲述自己的故事是她化解内心那种持续向她传达"我必须告诉某人"的强烈压力的唯一方式。

After setting a particular appointment time for this important moment of "telling," Sheila arrived a few minutes late, a little breathless. First, I invited her to take a moment to let her breath settle: "We have all the time we need—all the time in the world," I said slowly and gently (a technique drawn from Sensorimotor Psychotherapy [Ogden & Fisher, 2015]). "Take your time … and while you're getting your breath back, let's talk for a few minutes about this important process you want to have today. I know it's something you've felt an intense need for … to be heard and believed. But it is also going to bring up a lot. I just want to be sure that it's OK if I interrupt you from time to time—to ask how you're doing, check on how your nervous system is coping, or slow things down so you can settle. It's my philosophy: on my watch, I don't want the telling of your story to be retraumatizing, so I might be annoying from time to time because I am going to interrupt to make sure that doesn't happen. Is that OK?" (Getting the client's explicit permission for an intervention is another important principle of treatment in Sensorimotor Psychotherapy.)
Sheila begins to describe the environment in which the abuse took place: "My mother was not the right match for my super-intellectual father—she wanted nice clothes and pretty things—he was frugal and worried about money. He didn't like conflict or emotionality; she was always highly emotional. It was hard to be around her because she'd suddenly go into a rage." Seeing her activation rising as she recalled her mother's rages, and noticing how little she was breathing, I interrupted.

为这个重要的"讲述"时刻专门预约了一个特定的时间后，Sheila迟到了几分钟，略显气喘。首先，我邀请她花一点时间让呼吸平稳下来："我们有充裕的时间——世界上所有的时间，"我缓慢而轻柔地说（这是一种源自感觉运动心理治疗的技术[Ogden和Fisher，2015]）。"慢慢来……在你恢复呼吸的同时，让我们先谈几分钟你今天想要进行的这个重要过程。我知道这是你强烈渴望的事情……被倾听和被相信。但这也会带出很多东西。我只是想确认，如果我不时打断你——询问你的感受、检查你的神经系统如何应对，或者放慢节奏让你能够安定下来——这样可以吗？这是我的信念：在我的关照下，我不希望讲述你的故事成为再创伤的经历，所以我可能会时不时地令你烦恼，因为我会打断你，以确保那种情况不会发生。这样可以吗？"（获得来访者对干预的明确许可，是感觉运动心理治疗中另一条重要的治疗原则。）
Sheila开始描述虐待发生的环境："我母亲与我那超级学术型的父亲不是合适的搭配——她想要漂亮的衣服和精致的东西——而他节俭，总在担心钱的问题。他不喜欢冲突或情绪化；而她总是情绪化得厉害。和她在一起很难，因为她会突然暴怒。"看到她在回忆母亲的暴怒时激活程度不断上升，注意到她的呼吸多么浅短，我打断了她。

ME: "How are you doing right now, Sheila? That's a lot to remember."

我：「Sheila，你现在感觉怎么样？这要回忆的东西太多了。」

SHEILA: "I'm a little overwhelmed but managing OK—when I was talking about my mother and her anger, I suddenly remembered something: she used to beat me when I was 'too emotional,' especially if I cried or I got angry … She could cry and scream at me, but I couldn't scream back."

SHEILA：「我有点不堪重负，但还在应对——当我在说到我母亲和她的愤怒时，我突然想起了什么：她过去会在我'太情绪化'的时候打我，尤其是当我哭或者我生气的时候……她可以对我哭叫和尖叫，但我不能叫回去。」

ME: "She could yell, but you couldn't … [I mirrored her words so she could hear them and take them in.] And you were just a little girl …"

我：「她可以叫，但你不能……〔我镜映了她的话语，让她能够听到并吸收进去。〕而你只是一个小女孩……」

SHEILA: [begins to cry]

SHEILA：〔开始哭泣〕

ME: [speaking as she is crying]: "Yes, lots of feelings coming up—painful feelings?" [She nods] "Of course … You were just a little girl, and you couldn't get mad and you couldn't cry … lots of feelings there. … Just notice, though: right here, right now, that little girl inside is crying, and no one is getting mad at her … You and I are hearing her cry and hearing her feelings, and we're not mad … we feel for her … Ask her to notice that it's different here—it's different with you and me. Right this minute, she's being heard and we are feeling for her."

我：〔在她哭泣时说话〕「是的，涌现出了很多感受——痛苦的感受？」〔她点头〕「当然……你只是一个小女孩，你不能生气，你也不能哭……那里有那么多感受。……不过，请注意：就在此处，就在此刻，里面的那个小女孩在哭泣，没有人在对她生气……你和我都在听她哭泣，听她的感受，我们没有生气……我们心疼她……请让她注意到，这里是不同的——和你、和我在一起是不同的。就在这一刻，她被倾听了，我们都心疼她。」

In a more traditional psychodynamic approach, the therapist would most likely have spoken less and certainly interrupted less. But all of the "interruptions" had a purpose: to help Sheila stay "here" instead of going "there," to help her slow down and pay attention to her breathing and activation, to keep her prefrontal cortex online to make sure she could witness being witnessed, and to provide a different experience, an antidote, for her young child self.

在更为传统的心理动力学取向中，治疗师很可能会说得更少，打断的次数也肯定会更少。但所有这些"打断"都有其目的：帮助Sheila留在"这里"而不是去到"那里"，帮助她放慢节奏、注意自己的呼吸和激活状态，保持前额叶皮层在线以确保她能够见证被见证的体验，并为她幼小的儿童自我提供一种不同的体验——一种解药。

Witnessing Being Witnessed

见证被见证的体验

To achieve the purpose of witnessing, it is of crucial importance to remember that the longing to be heard may be a natural human response to having to keep terrible secrets, but it is also an implicit memory. Few children "tell their stories" to someone at the time of the abuse, leaving a feeling memory of the longing or impulse to tell that was never satisfied. Often, the clients who are desperate "to tell" are being driven by that implicit memory. In addition, the wish to tell or be heard does not guarantee that client can remain fully present in the moment when activated by the details of the narrative. The syndrome of "post-traumatic stress disorder" reflects the degree to which traumatic reactions can intrude upon and "upstage" the experience of "being here now." The research (Van der Kolk, 2014) is clear that trauma-related stimuli, including one's own narrative, stimulates the body to alarm responses, animal defense reactions, and inhibition of prefrontal activity—all of which prevent witnessing the therapist's attentive presence. In Sensorimotor Psychotherapy (Ogden & Fisher, 2015), the therapist periodically directs the client's attention back to the present moment by asking clients to: "Pause for a moment and just notice what's happening right now: you are telling your story … and I'm hearing you … I'm hearing you and I believe you … Notice what that's like to feel me here with you, listening to you … and believing you." In a parts approach, I might ask: "What's it like for the parts to hear those words, 'I believe you'?" In Sensorimotor Psychotherapy, the therapist would next ask, "What happens in your body when you notice that?" Or "What happens inside when I say the words, 'I hear you, and I believe you'?"

要实现见证的目的，至关重要的是要记住：渴望被倾听，可能是不得不保守可怕秘密的自然人类反应，但它同时也是一种内隐记忆。很少有儿童会在受虐时向某人"讲述自己的故事"，由此留下了对那种从未得到满足的倾诉渴望或冲动的感受记忆。那些拼命想"讲述"的来访者，往往正是被这种内隐记忆所驱动。此外，想要倾诉或被倾听的愿望，并不保证来访者在被叙事细节所激活时能够完全保持临在。"创伤后应激障碍"这一综合征，反映了创伤性反应入侵并"盖过""此刻在场"体验的程度。研究（Van der Kolk，2014）清楚地表明，创伤相关刺激——包括自己的叙事——会刺激身体产生警报反应、动物防御反应以及前额叶活动的抑制——所有这些都阻碍了见证治疗师专注临在的体验。在感觉运动心理治疗中（Ogden和Fisher，2015），治疗师会定期将来访者的注意力引回当下，请他们："暂停一下，只是注意此刻正在发生的事情：你在讲述你的故事……我在听你……我在听你，我相信你……注意感受到我在这里陪着你、倾听你……相信你，是什么感觉。"在部分取向中，我可能会问："各个部分听到'我相信你'这些话，是什么感受？"在感觉运动心理治疗中，治疗师接下来会问："当你注意到这些时，你的身体里发生了什么？"或者"当我说'我听到你了，我相信你'这些话时，内心深处发生了什么？"

I can also bring the client's attention to the difference between now and then: "I am hearing you, and … I believe you," "I'm hearing you, and I'm not angry," "I'm hearing you and I'm not going away," "I hear you, and I am not shocked, not horrified … Just notice that. What's it like to have someone hear you without shock or horror?" At these moments of recognition (when the client can experience how different "now" is, how attentively someone listens now, how it feels to be believed), the old experience is changed: there is a different ending to the story now—and that changes the feelings inside.

我也可以将来访者的注意力引向现在与过去的不同："我在听你，而且……我相信你，""我在听你，我没有生气，""我在听你，我不会离开，""我听到你了，我没有震惊，没有恐惧……只是注意到这一点。有人能够在没有震惊或恐惧的情况下听你说话，这是什么感觉？"在这些认识的时刻（当来访者能够体验到"现在"有多么不同、有人多么专注地倾听、被相信是什么感觉），旧有的体验被改变了：故事现在有了一个不同的结局——这也改变了内心深处的感受。

The Therapist as "Auxiliary Cortex" and Educator

治疗师作为"辅助皮层"与教育者

In a neurobiologically informed treatment approach, the issues presented by traumatized clients are seen as stemming from dysregulated autonomic arousal, implicit memories, disorganized attachment, and structural dissociation, requiring that the therapist play a somewhat different role in the treatment. In traditional models, it has always been assumed that individuals had access to words that could describe the traumatic experiences but without the opportunity to express them.

在以神经生物学为基础的治疗取向中，受创伤来访者所呈现的问题，被视为源于失调的自主神经唤醒、内隐记忆、混乱型依恋和结构性解离，这要求治疗师在治疗中扮演一种略有不同的角色。在传统模型中，人们一直假设个体能够获取可以描述创伤体验的语言，只是没有机会将其表达出来。

In the light of the neuroscience research, however, that assumption has to be re-examined. Brain scan evidence on traumatic recall of events is clear that traumatic memory evokes "speechless terror" and experiences "beyond words" (Ogden & Fisher, 2015; Van der Kolk, 2014), not a clear-cut narrative that can be verbalized. In brain scan studies, narrative recall resulted in inhibited cortical activity, including inhibition of expressive language centers in the left brain, leaving the subjects "speechless," while the limbic system, especially the right hemisphere amygdala, became highly active (Van der Kolk & Fisler, 1995). These findings describe what therapists often observe in traumatized clients: when the prefrontal cortex, inhibited by autonomic responses to traumatic memory, cuts them off from language areas of the brain, their ability to observe even their own experience verbally and sequentially is lost. The overwhelming emotions and physical impact are too big to be captured by language. After the events are over, many victims attempt to put words to what has happened but can only approximate a "feeling of what happened" biased by whatever meaning-making they have attached to the event (Damasio, 1999). Often these stories are distorted by the experience of degradation, humiliation, terror, and abandonment: they do not capture the event itself but rather how the victims experienced themselves as a result of it. Shame, feeling dirty or disgusting, or painfully exposed is not a description of an event. They are the implicit memories of the effects of that event on them.

然而，在神经科学研究的光照下，这一假设必须被重新审视。脑扫描对创伤性事件回忆的证据清楚地表明，创伤记忆唤起的是"无言的恐惧"和"超越言语"的体验（Ogden和Fisher，2015；Van der Kolk，2014），而非可以被言语化的清晰叙事。在脑扫描研究中，叙事性回忆导致皮层活动受到抑制——包括左脑表达性语言中枢的抑制，使受试者"失语"——而边缘系统，尤其是右半球杏仁核，变得高度活跃（Van der Kolk和Fisler，1995）。这些发现描述了治疗师在受创伤来访者身上常常观察到的现象：当前额叶皮层因对创伤记忆的自主神经反应而受到抑制，将他们与大脑语言区切断时，他们甚至无法用语言和序列性方式观察自己的体验。那排山倒海的情绪和躯体冲击太过巨大，无法被语言所捕捉。事件结束后，许多受害者试图为所发生的事情赋予词语，却只能近似地描述一种"对所发生之事的感受"——这种感受被他们附着在事件上的任何意义建构所偏移（Damasio，1999）。这些故事往往被降格、羞辱、恐惧和被遗弃的体验所扭曲：它们捕捉的不是事件本身，而是受害者作为其后果如何体验自身。羞耻感、感到肮脏或令人厌恶、或痛苦地暴露无遗——这些不是对一个事件的描述，而是那个事件对他们所产生的影响的内隐记忆。

A neurobiologically informed therapist is aware that clients do not know these facts about traumatic remembering. They have not read the brain scan research, and do not know why they can't remember at all or why they remember only in fragments that feel "unreal," or why they feel so much shame or are afraid of remembering at all. They experience themselves as crazy or inadequate or damaged without understanding the role of the trauma in biasing their interpretations. Without the words and without a template to make meaning of what has happened, let alone understand the resulting symptoms, our clients will not be able to make headway in therapy or in their normal lives. It therefore becomes imperative for the therapist to act as an educator and temporary "auxiliary cortex" (Diamond, Balvin, & Diamond, 1963, p. 46). When the therapist is willing to reinterpret the client's "self-defeating story" and give it psychoeducationally informed meaning, it has a different effect than providing empathy or challenging distorted cognitions. When the therapist provides a template for understanding the trauma-related symptoms or the phenomenon of triggering, and makes sense of their prefrontal shutdown and animal defenses, clients are reassured that there is logic to their actions and reactions: what I call "trauma logic." Lillian provides us with an illustration of these issues and how I dealt with them on the occasion of our first meeting.

以神经生物学为基础的治疗师意识到，来访者并不了解这些关于创伤记忆的事实。他们没有读过脑扫描研究，不知道为什么他们完全记不住，或为什么只能以感觉"不真实"的碎片形式记起，或为什么会有那么强烈的羞耻感，或为什么对记忆本身感到恐惧。他们体验到自己是疯了、不够好、或是受损的，却不理解创伤在偏移他们诠释方式中所扮演的角色。若没有语言，没有一个对所发生之事赋予意义的模板，更遑论理解由此产生的症状，我们的来访者将无法在治疗中或在正常生活中取得进展。因此，对治疗师而言，充当教育者和临时"辅助皮层"（Diamond, Balvin和Diamond，1963，第46页）变得至关重要。当治疗师愿意重新诠释来访者的"自我挫败故事"，并赋予其经过心理教育启发的意义时，效果不同于单纯提供共情或挑战扭曲认知。当治疗师提供一个用于理解创伤相关症状或触发现象的模板，并使其前额叶关闭和动物防御反应变得合理时，来访者会感到欣慰：他们的行为和反应是有其逻辑的——我称之为"创伤逻辑"。Lillian为我们提供了这些议题的一个例证，以及我在我们第一次会面时是如何处理它们的。

Seventy years old and a recently retired pediatrician, Lillian appeared barely able to walk, even with the help of her son who had set up a consultation to "find out what's wrong with my mother." Shaking, trembling, her head hanging, she made her way into the office and sat on the couch, rocking back and forth like a small child. "All I can say is I feel like a frightened child, and I don't know why," she said. "I'm afraid of my own shadow—I can't look at you—I can't go out of the house by myself."
I asked, "When did this frightened child appear? When did the fear begin?"
After a terrifying childhood, Lillian described herself as having become a headstrong, independent young adult, determined to become a doctor and help children around the world. That fearlessness persisted for many decades: in her pediatric career, raising her children as a single mother, and then volunteering for Doctors Without Borders after retirement. Then she came home from Africa at the age of 70 without a job, structure, or a cause. "I was just alone in the house all day—I felt lonely and useless and of no value—and then the fear started."
I said excitedly, "I just realized what must have happened, Lillian—can I tell you the story about what is going on right now?"
She nodded.
"A very brave young woman left home fifty years ago, walked away from the trauma and the intimidation, and she never looked back. There was a lot of trauma in her body—a lot of traumatized young parts—but she had a strong drive to build a normal life, and she did! With that strong, determined normal life self, she created a family, chose a career, and even fulfilled her goal of helping children just as afraid as she was once. She never looked back—even once. But after the return from Africa, there were no more goals for the normal life part to pursue, no more people to help or kids to raise—nothing to keep her going. The empty house and the loneliness triggered the young traumatized parts she'd been able to ignore for so many years. Triggered by being alone in the house, they began to have intense feeling and body memories of feeling hopeless, unlovable, alone, and, most of all, scared out of their minds. This fear you are having is a memory, their feeling memory of what it was like to be in their home—in your family's home."
"What do I do?" she asked.

Lillian七十岁，是一位近期退休的儿科医生。她的儿子为她预约了会诊，想"弄清楚我母亲怎么了"。即便有儿子搀扶，Lillian看起来几乎无法行走。她颤抖着、摇晃着，低垂着头走进诊室，坐在沙发上，像个小孩一样前后摇晃。"我只能说我感觉自己像一个受惊吓的孩子，我不知道为什么，"她说。"我连自己的影子都怕——我没办法看你——我没法独自出门。"
我问："这个受惊吓的孩子是什么时候出现的？恐惧是什么时候开始的？"
经历了可怕的童年之后，Lillian描述自己成长为一个倔强、独立的年轻成人，下定决心要成为一名医生，帮助世界各地的孩子。这种无所畏惧持续了数十年：在她的儿科职业生涯中，作为单身母亲抚养孩子，然后在退休后志愿参与无国界医生组织。然后，她70岁时从非洲回到家，没有工作、没有结构、没有事业。"我整天一个人待在家里——我感到孤独、无用、毫无价值——然后恐惧就开始了。"
我兴奋地说："我刚刚意识到一定发生了什么，Lillian——我可以告诉你此刻正在发生的事情吗？"
她点了点头。
"一个非常勇敢的年轻女性在五十年前离开了家，离开了创伤和恐吓，她从未回头。她的身体里有很多创伤——很多受创伤的年幼部分——但她有强烈的驱力去建立正常的生活，而且她做到了！凭借着那个强大、坚定的正常生活的持续自我，她组建了家庭，选择了职业，甚至实现了帮助那些曾经和她一样恐惧的孩子们的目标。她从未回头——一次都没有。但是从非洲回来后，那个正常生活部分没有了更多可以追求的目标，没有了更多需要帮助的人或需要抚养的孩子——没有任何东西能让她继续前行。空荡荡的房子和孤独感，触发了那些她多年来一直能够忽视的年幼受创伤部分。被独自待在家中所触发，她们开始有强烈的感受和身体记忆——感到无望、不值得被爱、孤独，最重要的是，惊恐万状。你正在经历的这种恐惧是一种记忆，是她们对在那个家里——在你的原生家庭里——是什么感觉的感受记忆。"
"我该怎么办？"她问道。

ME: "Think as a mother and a pediatrician for a moment: what do we do when a child is feeling scared and doesn't know she's safe? When the scary feeling is a memory?"

我：「作为一个母亲和儿科医生想一想：当一个孩子感到害怕、不知道自己是安全的时候，我们会怎么做？当那种恐惧的感觉是一种记忆时？」

LILLIAN: "We'd reassure her that she's safe …"

LILLIAN：「我们会安抚她，告诉她她是安全的……」

ME: "OK, and what would you do if she didn't believe you right away?"

我：「好的，如果她不立刻相信你，你会怎么做？」

LILLIAN: "We'd have to tell her over and over again—tell her that we're there, that nothing can hurt her now."

LILLIAN：「我们得一遍又一遍地告诉她——告诉她我们在这里，现在没有什么能伤害她了。」

ME: "You know children well, don't you? Yes, you'd have to tell her over and over, wouldn't you? Can you start now? Just tell her with your feelings and your body that you're here."

我：「你很了解孩子，不是吗？是的，你得一遍又一遍地告诉她，不是吗？你能现在就开始吗？只是用你的感受和你的身体告诉她，你在这里。」

Lillian was quiet for a moment, then she chuckled: "Smart kid—she says if there's nothing scary happening, why am I so scared?"

Lillian沉默了片刻，然后轻笑道：「聪明的孩子——她说如果没有发生什么可怕的事，为什么我这么害怕？」

ME: "Explain to her that you did get scared—you got frightened when she got scared—always tell the truth to her because no one ever did that before."

我：「向她解释，你确实感到了害怕——当她害怕时你也感到害怕——永远向她说实话，因为以前从来没有人这样做过。」

Lillian was quiet again, her attention inside: "She likes me admitting that I got scared, too, but then I told her that I looked around, and nothing bad was happening. And that is why I came here today even though I was scared."

Lillian再次沉默，注意力转向内心：「她喜欢我承认我也害怕了，但我告诉她我环顾四周，没有什么坏事正在发生。这就是为什么今天我尽管害怕还是来了这里。」

ME: "Right—it isn't that grownups never get scared, but they do something different with their fear than kids do."

我：「对——不是说大人从不害怕，而是他们对待恐惧的方式和孩子不同。」

LILLIAN: "Yeah, and now I have to remember not to get scared when she gets scared."

LILLIAN：「是的，现在我必须记住，当她害怕时，我不要跟着害怕。」

ME: "That's right—you don't want to blend with her fear—because then she has no one. You want her to have access to your confidence and courage so it will be there for her, too."

我：「没错——你不想与她的恐惧融合——因为那样她就没有人了。你希望她能够获取你的信心和勇气，这样它也会在那里陪伴她。」

In this single session, it was immediately clear to me that Lillian's return from Africa had stimulated a flooding of implicit memories of terror, loneliness, shame, and fears of abandonment. She had neither the knowledge base nor the words to explain her sudden transformation from confident globe-trotter to quivering child other than "I feel like a frightened child." Notice that the therapist/educator does not hesitate to make psychoeducational meaning of the client's symptoms and story, to introduce words like "trigger," "part," "feeling memory," "dysregulation." A therapist/educator does not deflect or interpret a question such as, "What do I do?" Knowing that the question is a request from the normal life self for a roadmap, the therapist provides both concrete information and the opportunity to experiment with using it.

在这次单次会谈中，我立刻清楚地看到，Lillian从非洲的归来激发了恐惧、孤独、羞耻和被遗弃恐惧等内隐记忆的泛滥。除了"我感觉自己像一个受惊吓的孩子"之外，她既没有知识基础，也没有语言来解释自己从自信的环球旅行者到颤抖儿童的突然转变。请注意，治疗师/教育者毫不犹豫地对来访者的症状和故事赋予心理教育性的意义，引入"触发因素"、"部分"、"感受记忆"、"失调"等词汇。治疗师/教育者不会回避或解读诸如"我该怎么办？"这样的问题。知道这个问题是正常生活自我对路线图的请求，治疗师既提供了具体的信息，也提供了尝试运用它的机会。

Clearly, Lillian's frightened part had "hijacked the body" (Ogden & Fisher, 2015), inhibiting her prefrontal cortex from being able to conceptualize an answer to the question, "What is wrong with me?" If the therapist's role is to educate, rather than elicit the client's interpretation of what is wrong, then this question provides an opportunity to teach the client about autonomic dysregulation, implicit memory, and structural dissociation. Lillian's description, "I've turned into a frightened child," immediately opened the door to the discussion of child parts, and although it was only the second or third sentence she uttered, I did not hesitate to say, "Yes, you have. You've been hijacked by a very young, very scared little girl." Another client might have described it as, "My body is running amuck—I can't sleep, I can't stop shaking, I am paralyzed," calling for psychoeducation about the body's participation in trauma-related symptoms. Some narratives might have emphasized deficiencies: "I've fallen apart—I'm so ashamed—I don't want anyone to see me like this—I'll never be the person I used to be." For clients with shame-related cognitive schemas, psychoeducation becomes imperative to help them disidentify from the self-defeating story of failure and inadequacy. They will need education about their symptoms: "Yes, it feels as if you've fallen apart, and you don't want anyone to see you. The good news is that you haven't fallen apart—your body is just remembering feeling broken, shattered. The shame is a feeling memory, too, that often helps keep children safer." When clients lament that they'll never "be the person I used to be," they can often be reassured that the "person I used to be" is alive and well in their left hemispheres. They are experiencing "limbic hijacking," which inhibits cortical functioning and thereby disconnects them from the "person I used to be."

显然，Lillian受惊吓的部分已经"劫持了身体"（Ogden和Fisher，2015），抑制了她的前额叶皮层，使其无法为"我怎么了？"这个问题构建出答案。如果治疗师的角色是教育，而非引发来访者对问题所在的自我诠释，那么这个问题就提供了一个机会，向来访者讲授自主神经失调、内隐记忆和结构性解离。Lillian的描述"我变成了一个受惊吓的孩子"，立刻打开了讨论儿童部分的大门，尽管这只是她说的第二或第三句话，我毫不犹豫地说："是的，你确实是。你被一个非常年幼、非常恐惧的小女孩劫持了。"另一位来访者可能会这样描述："我的身体失控了——我睡不着，我无法停止颤抖，我瘫痪了"——这呼唤的是关于身体参与创伤相关症状的心理教育。某些叙事可能会强调缺陷："我崩溃了——我非常羞耻——我不想让任何人看到我这个样子——我再也不会成为我曾经的那个人了。"对于有与羞耻相关认知图式的来访者，心理教育变得不可或缺，帮助他们从关于失败和不足的自我挫败故事中去认同。他们需要关于症状的教育："是的，感觉好像你崩溃了，你不想让任何人看见你。好消息是你并没有崩溃——你的身体只是在记忆那种破碎、粉碎的感觉。羞耻感也是一种感受记忆，它往往帮助孩子保持更安全。"当来访者哀叹自己再也不会"成为我曾经的那个人"时，往往可以向他们保证，"我曾经的那个人"在他们的左半球活得好好的。他们正在经历"边缘系统劫持"，这抑制了皮层功能，从而将他们与"我曾经的那个人"切断。

As illustrated in the session with Lillian, another important part of the therapist/educator's role is to help clients connect not only to their vulnerability but also to their strengths. Historically, trauma treatment has emphasized helping clients get in touch with vulnerable emotions of fear, grief, and shame and with their rage—with the expectation that grief and anger will empower, dissipate shame, and free them to let go of the past. However, clients often get stymied when the anger and grief are overwhelming rather than empowering or when shame is exacerbated rather than relieved by access to grief. In addition, focus primarily on trauma-related emotions creates a bias in the treatment by leaving out a very important aspect of any traumatic experience: how the child's survival resources and animal defenses enabled him or her to remain intact, to "keep on keeping on."

正如与Lillian的会谈所示，治疗师/教育者角色的另一个重要部分，是帮助来访者不仅与自己的脆弱性建立连接，也与自身的力量建立连接。历史上，创伤治疗一直强调帮助来访者接触脆弱的情绪——恐惧、悲伤和羞耻——以及他们的愤怒，期待悲伤和愤怒能够赋权、消散羞耻感，并释放他们放下过去。然而，当愤怒和悲伤是压倒性的而非赋权的，或当羞耻感因接触悲伤而加剧而非缓解时，来访者往往会陷入困境。此外，主要聚焦于创伤相关情绪，会在治疗中造成一种偏差，遗漏了任何创伤体验中一个非常重要的面向：儿童的生存资源和动物防御如何使他或她保持完整，"坚持，继续坚持"。

A Creative Adaptation to Abnormal Experience

对异常经历的创造性适应

Even when the only option is to "feign death" (go numb, pretend to be asleep, float up to the ceiling, or go unconscious), the body instinctively chooses the defensive response most likely to succeed in limiting the injury, shock, or pain. When we freeze, inhibit active defenses, and can't speak, it is also adaptive: what could we say that wouldn't provoke the aggressor? When children fight back, even if it's a losing battle, their animal defense systems may instinctively assess that, in this situation, it is safer to fight than to submit—even though it might result in punishment. It seemed important to emphasize the strengths connected to Lillian's going on with her normal life self, to reassure her that we can temporarily lose access to a part of the brain, but, unless we sustain a brain injury, those strengths are still encoded and potentially accessible. The intrepid, determined woman she had been most of her adult life was still intact and available for reconnection.

即便唯一的选择是"装死"（变得麻木、假装睡着、飘离到天花板上，或失去意识），身体也会本能地选择最有可能限制伤害、休克或痛苦的防御反应。当我们冻结、抑制主动防御、无法开口说话时，这同样是适应性的：我们能说出什么而不激怒攻击者呢？当孩子反抗时，即使这是一场必败之仗，他们的动物防御系统可能也会本能地评估，在这种情况下，战斗比顺从更安全——尽管这可能导致惩罚。强调与Lillian继续正常生活自我相关的力量，向她保证我们可以暂时失去对大脑某部分的访问，但除非我们遭受脑损伤，这些力量仍然被编码，并可能重新获得，这似乎非常重要。她大部分成年生活中所展现的那个无畏、坚定的女性依然完整，可以重新连接。

At the moment a trigger precipitates flooding of implicit memories held by structurally dissociated parts, the client frequently loses access to verbal information or conceptual thinking. For the time being, Lillian was going to need her therapist to be an auxiliary cortex, providing psychoeducation about trauma and parts, helping her "test-drive" different interventions and practice those that worked, and mapping out step by step how to stop the flooding and access her normal life self once again. Her biggest risks were going to be regression and avoidance. Without a therapy that emphasized the importance of using mindful observation, curiosity, and psychoeducation to gain access to her normal life self, Lillian would be at risk to "blend" with the parts (Schwartz, 2001) and become a frightened child rather than building relationships with them. Or, having reconnected to her going on with her normal life self, she might feel so much relief that it might be tempting to ignore and suppress the trauma-related parts again. In the initial consultation session, it was important to establish a way of working that emphasized that she could heal and go on with her life—if she were willing to build a protective, caring relationship with her young parts by calling upon the same determination to help suffering children that had been her strength and motivation since her twenties.

当触发因素引发结构性解离部分所持有的内隐记忆泛滥的那一刻，来访者往往失去对语言信息或概念思维的访问。就目前而言，Lillian将需要她的治疗师担任辅助皮层，提供关于创伤和部分的心理教育，帮助她"试驾"不同的干预措施并练习那些有效的方法，并逐步规划如何停止泛滥并再次访问她的正常生活自我。她最大的风险将是退行和回避。没有一种强调运用正念观察、好奇心和心理教育来访问正常生活自我的治疗，Lillian将有"融合"（Schwartz，2001年）于各部分的风险，变成一个受惊吓的孩子，而不是与它们建立关系。或者，在重新连接到她继续正常生活的自我之后，她可能感到如此释然，以至于可能忍不住再次忽视和压制那些创伤相关部分。在初次咨询会谈中，建立一种强调她可以愈合并继续生活的工作方式至关重要——前提是她愿意建立对年幼部分的保护性、关爱性关系，调用自二十多岁以来便是她力量与动力的、帮助受苦儿童的那种坚定信念。

A New Role for the Therapist: Neurobiological Regulator

治疗师的新角色：神经生物调节者

In early attachment relationships, parent figures provide not only an auxiliary cortex for their infants but also externally mediated neurobiological regulation or soothing. Successfully regulating a child's immature nervous system is necessary not only for his or her sense of attunement and well-being but also critical for growing affect tolerance via an expanding "window of tolerance" (Ogden et al., 2006; Siegel, 1999) that allows children to increasingly regulate and tolerate a range of emotions. Childhood neglect, trauma, early loss, witnessing of violence, or "frightened and frightening" caregiving (Liotti, 2004; Lyons-Ruth, 2006) all interfere with attachment formation and therefore with developing a spacious and flexible window of tolerance that fosters resilience. With or without childhood trauma, adult traumatic experiences, such as combat, assaults, rape, and domestic violence, disrupt previously established autonomic patterns and prime the nervous system to respond to environmental stressors with over- or under-activity.

在早期依恋关系中，父母人物不仅为其婴儿提供辅助皮层，还提供外部介导的神经生物调节或安抚。成功调节儿童不成熟的神经系统，不仅是其协调感和幸福感的必要条件，而且对于通过扩展的"耐受窗"（Ogden et al.，2006年；Siegel，1999年）培养情感耐受性至关重要，这使儿童能够日益调节和容纳各种情绪。童年忽视、创伤、早期失去、目睹暴力，或"恐惧性且令人恐惧的"养育（Liotti，2004年；Lyons-Ruth，2006年），都会干扰依恋形成，因此也会干扰培养促进韧性的宽广灵活耐受窗的发展。无论有无童年创伤，战斗、攻击、强奸和家庭暴力等成人创伤经历，都会破坏先前建立的自主神经模式，使神经系统在面对环境压力时以过度或不足的活动来响应。

The result is a client who enters therapy with a dysregulated nervous system and a truncated window of tolerance, with a brain conditioned to activate the emergency stress response in the presence of trauma-related stimuli. Unless the therapist is prepared to offer interactive neurobiological regulation, a dysregulated client will encounter difficulty with some of the basic aspects of traditional psychotherapy: the request to "free-associate" or say what comes to mind, the ability to connect to affect, to trust the therapist's good intentions, to focus, conceptualize (why he or she is there, what hopes or goals bring the client to therapy), connect past/present, and "sit with" whatever emotions and physical reactions are activated in the course of the therapeutic hour without hyper- or hypoarousal, dissociation, or impulsive responses. This is a challenging expectation, one for which a window of tolerance and a prefrontal cortex are necessary prerequisites.

结果是，来访者带着失调的神经系统和狭窄的耐受窗进入治疗，大脑已被条件化为在创伤相关刺激存在时激活紧急应激反应。除非治疗师准备好提供互动性神经生物调节，否则失调的来访者将在传统心理治疗的某些基本方面遇到困难："自由联想"或说出脑海中浮现内容的要求、连接情感的能力、信任治疗师良好意图的能力、专注和概念化的能力（他或她为何来此、什么希望或目标带来访者接受治疗）、连接过去与现在，以及在治疗时间内"容纳"任何被激活的情绪和身体反应，而不出现过度或低度唤醒、解离或冲动反应。这是一个具有挑战性的期望，而耐受窗和前额叶皮层是其必要的先决条件。

At her first visit, Carla, a 45-year-old attorney, was visibly shaking as she described why she was there. Her speech pressured, she leaned forward as if ready to leap out of her chair at a moment's notice. "I haven't been able to eat or sleep in months. My last therapist said she couldn't help me, and this new one lets me out early each week because I get too overwhelmed to do 'the work,' as she calls it." Holding out her shaking hands for me to see, she asked, "Why isn't 'the work' helping me with all this? Why does the work have to be about the abuse? I don't know how I'm managing at my job, but it's the only place I almost feel like my old self."
Talking very slowly and calmly to slow the pace of conversation, but with a smile to signal that things were not so bad as she felt, I said, "I have good news and bad news for you—which do you want first?" [More smiling.]
"The bad news," Carla said, "Better to get it over with."
"The bad news is you are flooded with trauma-related feelings and body memories, and your nervous system has gone through the roof into extreme hyperarousal. Want to hear the good news? The good news is that you are not going crazy! [The therapist laughs and smiles, and Carla does, too.] In fact, there is a very simple remedy for this! Would you like to hear it?
"Yes!"
"To help your nervous system and stop the flooding of feeling memories, we need to get your frontal lobes back online. That's why you feel better at work: your job requires you to think—it 'pulls' your prefrontal cortex to do what it does so well."

在她第一次访问时，Carla，一位45岁的律师，明显地颤抖着描述她来这里的原因。她的语速紧迫，身体前倾，好像随时准备从椅子上跳起来。"我几个月来一直无法进食或睡觉。我上一个治疗师说她帮不了我，而这个新治疗师每周都让我提前离开，因为我太不堪重负了，无法做'那项工作'，她是这么称呼的。"她把颤抖的双手伸出来让我看，问道："为什么'那项工作'对这一切没有帮助？为什么那项工作必须关乎虐待？我不知道我是如何在工作中撑下来的，但那是唯一一个我几乎感觉像旧日自己的地方。"
我说话非常缓慢平静以减慢对话的节奏，但带着微笑示意事情并没有她感觉的那么糟糕，我说："我有好消息和坏消息要告诉你——你想先听哪个？"[更多微笑。]
"坏消息，"Carla说，"最好先解决它。"
"坏消息是你被创伤相关的感受和身体记忆所淹没，你的神经系统已经冲到天花板，进入极度过度唤醒状态。想听好消息吗？好消息是你没有发疯！[治疗师笑着，Carla也笑了。]事实上，有一个非常简单的解决方法！你想听听吗？
"想！"
"为了帮助你的神经系统并停止感受记忆的泛滥，我们需要让你的额叶重新上线。这就是为什么你在工作时感觉更好：你的工作要求你思考——它把你的前额叶皮层'拉'去做它擅长的事情。"

In this vignette, I use a number of "tools" available to all therapists: my tone of voice, pacing of speech, smiling and laughing versus a serious facial expression, choice of focus (beliefs, affect, body, vulnerability, strength, parts), projecting a confident energy versus a questioning, more tentative energy. Focusing attention on the client's strengths often elicits a moment of recognition and reconnection to resources long forgotten; reframing negative interpretations or providing corrective information helps to change the story, elicit curiosity, and even regulate the nervous system.

在这个片段中，我使用了所有治疗师都能使用的许多"工具"：我的语调、说话节奏、微笑和笑声对比严肃的面部表情、焦点的选择（信念、情感、身体、脆弱性、力量、各部分）、投射自信的能量对比疑问性、更加试探性的能量。将注意力聚焦于来访者的力量，通常会引发一个认知和重新连接长久被遗忘资源的瞬间；重新框架负面诠释或提供纠正性信息，有助于改变故事、引发好奇心，甚至调节神经系统。

To help facilitate getting her prefrontal cortex back online, I next provide some psychoeducation by reinterpreting Carla's difficulties as dysregulation: "No one can think clearly or manage intense feelings when the nervous system is in a state of traumatic activation—it's too overwhelming. So, let's go very slowly and stay curious. I'm going to ask you to pause and just notice what your body is doing right now."
"The shaking has gone down," she observed in a less pressured tone. "I feel less speedy and on edge—actually, as soon as you said, 'we just need to get your frontal lobes back online,' I felt better."
"Great! Your body really responds to those words: 'all we have to do is get your frontal lobes back online.' Now, let's be curious about what else gets your frontal lobes back online other than going to work. Over the years, has your prefrontal cortex been a resource for you?"
"Oh yes! I'm a civil rights attorney. I have to inspire people, challenge them, out-argue them, make them see what needs to be done."
"Wonderful—your prefrontal cortex is a resource, and so is your sense of purpose, being more determined than the other side. Now we need to focus your determination on getting your frontal lobes back online. Here's what I want you to do: I want you to notice when you're speeding up and starting to feel more shaky and overwhelmed, then pause and just keep saying to yourself, 'I'm just triggered—these are feeling memories'—or body memories—which do you prefer? Feeling memory? Or body memory?"
"Body memory—it feels like my whole body, not just my feelings."
"Wonderful—then remind yourself that it's just your body being triggered, just body memory, and then become interested and curious in what's happening rather than panicking." As the session continued, the therapist kept watching for the signs that Carla was getting hyperaroused again, asked her to pause periodically and then use her frontal lobes to be curious and interested in these body memories without trying to figure out to what event they were best matched. Each time, the observing and curiosity slowed her down, increased activity in the prefrontal cortex, settled her nervous system a bit, and allowed her to think more clearly.

为了帮助使她的前额叶皮层重新上线，我接下来通过将Carla的困难重新诠释为失调来提供一些心理教育："当神经系统处于创伤激活状态时，没有人能清晰思考或处理强烈感受——那太不堪重负了。所以，让我们走得非常慢，保持好奇。我要请你暂停，只是注意一下你的身体现在在做什么。"
"颤抖已经减轻了，"她用不那么急促的语调观察道。"我感觉不那么快速和紧张了——实际上，当你说'我们只需要让你的额叶重新上线'时，我就感觉好多了。"
"太好了！你的身体真的对这些话有反应：'我们所要做的就是让你的额叶重新上线。'现在，让我们好奇地看看，除了去上班之外，还有什么能让你的额叶重新上线。这些年来，你的前额叶皮层是否是你的一个资源？"
"哦，是的！我是一名民权律师。我必须激励人们、挑战他们、在辩论中胜过他们、让他们看到需要做什么。"
"太好了——你的前额叶皮层是一个资源，你的目标感、比对方更坚定的决心也是。现在我们需要把你的决心集中在让你的额叶重新上线上。这是我要你做的：我想让你注意到什么时候你在加速、开始感到更颤抖和不堪重负，然后暂停，对自己反复说，'我只是被触发了——这些是感受记忆'——还是身体记忆——你更喜欢哪个？感受记忆？还是身体记忆？"
"身体记忆——感觉像是我整个身体，不只是我的感受。"
"太好了——然后提醒自己这只是你的身体被触发了，只是身体记忆，然后对正在发生的事情变得感兴趣和好奇，而不是恐慌。"随着会谈的继续，治疗师不断注意Carla再次进入过度唤醒的迹象，定期请她暂停，然后用她的额叶对这些身体记忆保持好奇和感兴趣，而不试图弄清楚它们最匹配哪个事件。每一次，观察和好奇都让她放慢了速度，增加了前额叶皮层的活动，稍微安定了她的神经系统，并让她能够更清晰地思考。

The neurobiologically astute therapist has one primary goal: to ensure that each intervention, including even the physical presence of the therapist, has a regulating effect on the client's nervous system. We can be confident that trauma-related material will be dysregulating and that trusting the therapist, being the center of attention, revealing avoided emotions or secrets, feeling too close or not close enough will all be triggering. Even the proximity to another human being in a small, enclosed space may be activating for some clients. Once committed to therapy, the potential triggers keep multiplying: changes in schedule, not feeling "gotten," inadequate time or words to express all one wants to say, disappointed hopes for some particular response, separation between sessions, distorted beliefs, and projections.

具有神经生物学洞察力的治疗师有一个首要目标：确保每次干预——甚至包括治疗师的身体存在——都对来访者的神经系统具有调节效果。我们可以确信，创伤相关材料将会引起失调，信任治疗师、成为关注的中心、揭示被回避的情绪或秘密、感觉太近或不够近，都将是触发因素。即使是在小型封闭空间中与另一个人的接近，对某些来访者来说也可能是激活的。一旦投入治疗，潜在的触发因素不断增加：日程变化、感觉不被"理解"、时间或语言不足以表达所有想说的、对某种特定回应的希望落空、会谈之间的分离、扭曲的信念和投射。

Unlike traditional models of treatment, the assumption in neurobiologically informed trauma treatment is that clients are just as likely to be dysregulated by therapy than to feel "safe," more likely to come to therapy with limitations imposed by trauma-related hypo- or hyperarousal, sensitivity to triggering, and some degree of structural dissociation. The most complex regulating challenges are posed by clients with dissociative disorders and more severe structural dissociation (see Chapter 8 on Treatment Challenges: Dissociative Systems and Disorders).

与传统治疗模式不同，神经生物学知情的创伤治疗中的假设是，来访者与其说感到"安全"，不如说同样可能被治疗所引起失调；他们更有可能带着创伤相关的低度或过度唤醒、对触发的敏感性以及某种程度的结构性解离所带来的局限来接受治疗。最复杂的调节挑战由患有解离障碍和更严重结构性解离的来访者提出（参见第8章治疗挑战：解离系统与障碍）。

Tessa came to her first therapy session with a very sophisticated question, "How does one deal with the effects of attachment trauma in personal relationships?" But as she talked about her new dating relationship, it became increasingly clear that she was describing structural dissociation: "I really like him, but when we're together, I start feeling very ambivalent. I begin questioning: should I have come on this date? Should I let him hold my hand? What if he becomes sexual?" The picture she described suggested conflicts between several parts: a part that liked him and longed to be his girlfriend, a part that pulled away and began questioning as soon as things got closer, a part that wanted sex, and a part disgusted and frightened by the thought. "So I keep my distance when we're out taking a walk, but then I get home to an empty apartment, and I feel a longing for him, and I wish I'd let him take my hand. I hate this—I can't think about anything else at home, but then I get ambivalent in his presence."

Tessa来到她第一次治疗会谈时带着一个非常复杂的问题："一个人如何处理人际关系中依恋创伤的影响？"但当她谈及她新的约会关系时，越来越清楚地发现，她描述的是结构性解离："我真的很喜欢他，但当我们在一起时，我开始感到非常矛盾。我开始质疑：我应该来这次约会吗？我应该让他牵我的手吗？如果他变得性化怎么办？"她所描述的画面暗示了几个部分之间的冲突：一个喜欢他并渴望成为他女朋友的部分，一个一旦事情变得更亲近就退缩并开始质疑的部分，一个想要性的部分，以及一个对这个念头感到厌恶和恐惧的部分。"所以当我们出去散步时，我保持距离，但当我回到空荡荡的公寓后，我感到对他的渴望，希望我让他牵我的手。我讨厌这个——在家里我只能想到他，但在他面前我却变得矛盾。"

ME: "Of course it's a battle …" I knew that validating the normality of her internal conflicts would help her feel understood. "How could it not be? This is what relational trauma leaves as a legacy: the terrible longing when you're not together and a 'yuck, don't get too close' feeling in his presence."

我：「当然是一场战斗……」我知道认可她内部冲突的正常性会让她感到被理解。「怎么可能不是呢？这就是关系创伤留下的遗产：不在一起时强烈的渴望，以及他在场时那种'哇，别靠太近'的感觉。」

The "of course" is said with conviction but also a softness and sadness. "How could it not be?" is said with a smile that normalizes and lightens it. "Terrible longing" conveys the yearning in its tone; "yuck" is equally spoken with conviction but also toughness. Both are expressed as if each is entirely normal and to be expected.
"What generally happens next?" I ask.

"当然"是带着信念说的，但也带着柔软和悲伤。"怎么可能不是呢？"是带着使其正常化和减轻重量的微笑说的。"强烈的渴望"在语调上传达出渴望；"哇"同样带着信念但也带着坚硬说出。两者都像完全正常和理所当然一样被表达。
"接下来通常会发生什么？"我问。

TESSA: "I don't know … I try to be honest about my ambivalence but at the same time, he's all I ever think about … Usually, these guys stop returning my texts and emails, and I don't know why, so I get very upset and keep texting to explain myself. And then I get brushed off. He isn't ready for commitment either, he'll say. But what's the 'either'? What makes him think I'm not ready for commitment?" [Note that she is out of touch in this moment with the part of her that speaks openly to her dates about feeling ambivalent.]

TESSA：「我不知道……我试着对我的矛盾诚实，但同时，他是我唯一想到的……通常，这些男人停止回复我的短信和电子邮件，我不知道为什么，所以我变得非常不安，继续发短信解释自己。然后我被冷落了。他也还没准备好承诺，他会说。但"也"是什么意思？是什么让他认为我没准备好承诺？」[请注意，此刻她与那个曾公开向约会对象讲述感到矛盾的自我部分失去了联系。]

ME: [Again, I mirror her words so she can hear herself better:] "So the ambivalent part discourages him, and then the part that yearns for connection encourages him—the guy must get very, very confused!" [Laughs softly.]

我：「[我再次用她的话镜射，让她能更好地听到自己：]「所以矛盾的部分让他退缩，而渴望连接的部分鼓励他——这个男人一定非常非常困惑！」[轻声笑。]

TESSA: "Why do you keep talking to me like I'm some multiple personality?" she suddenly says in a new gruff, irritated tone.

TESSA：「你为什么一直用多重人格的方式和我说话？」她突然用一种新的粗糙、恼怒的语调说道。

I use an authoritative but empathic tone: "Because I can hear both sides in your story, Tessa. Both sides of you are there. This is what happens when we have relational trauma when we're young: a battle starts up inside whenever we might possibly, maybe get close to someone." [The last few words are said with a tone of regret or sadness.]

我用权威但富有同理心的语调："因为我能在你的故事中听到两面，Tessa。你的两面都在那里。这就是当我们年幼时经历关系创伤会发生的事：每当我们可能、也许、有可能靠近某人时，内部就开始了一场战斗。"[最后几个词带着遗憾或悲伤的语调说出。]

If clients like Tessa are willing to embrace the structural dissociation model, learn to consciously and voluntarily "split off" the intense affects and assign them to younger, more vulnerable parts, they can achieve the necessary mindful distance to feel some relief without having to resort to denial or disconnection. Only when they are able to "see" the parts in these paradoxical responses will they be able to begin healing their wounds. But they cannot successfully learn the abilities needed without help and direction from the therapist.

如果像Tessa这样的来访者愿意接受结构性解离模型，学习有意识地自愿"分离"强烈情感并将其归因于更年轻、更脆弱的部分，他们就能达到必要的正念距离，感受到一些解脱，而不必诉诸否认或断联。只有当他们能够"看见"这些悖论性反应中的部分时，他们才能开始愈合伤口。但如果没有治疗师的帮助和指导，他们无法成功学到所需的能力。

The Therapist as Director, Coach, and Pace-Setter

治疗师作为导演、教练和节奏调控者

Many therapists have been carefully trained to avoid directing the treatment for fear that clients will become automatically compliant and lose an opportunity to get "in touch" with an inner sense of direction. But because dissociative fragmentation results in multiple senses of direction and an inhibited prefrontal cortex, because of the risks of retraumatization or stuckness and avoidance, the therapist has to be unafraid to gently direct the focus and pacing of treatment.

许多治疗师被仔细训练去避免引导治疗，担心来访者会自动顺从，失去"接触"内在方向感的机会。但因为解离性碎片化导致多种方向感和被抑制的前额叶皮层，由于再创伤或陷入停滞与回避的风险，治疗师必须毫不畏惧地温和引导治疗的焦点和节奏。

One way of conceptualizing this aspect of the therapist's role is to think of it as providing a roadmap for clients whose traumatic reactions inhibit consistent access to the prefrontal cortex, leaving them confused and overwhelmed with no sense of direction. Or, because we are working with fragmented systems of parts, the more active role of family therapist is also a good model for trauma therapists, especially in the face of the need to prevent chaos and crisis. As family members engage in old, unhealthy patterns of behavior in the session, the family therapist has no choice but to guide and direct the session to prevent increased conflict and help family members begin to develop increasing acceptance of and compassion for each other. The therapist working with a fragmented client is in the same role—made more challenging by the fact that he or she can't actually see the other family members!

将治疗师角色的这一方面概念化的一种方式是，将其视为为那些创伤反应阻碍持续访问前额叶皮层的来访者提供路线图，使他们困惑和不堪重负、没有方向感。或者，因为我们正在处理碎片化的部分系统，家庭治疗师更积极的角色也是创伤治疗师的良好模型，特别是在需要防止混乱和危机的情况下。当家庭成员在会谈中重复旧的、不健康的行为模式时，家庭治疗师别无选择，只能引导和指导会谈以防止冲突加剧，并帮助家庭成员开始对彼此发展出越来越多的接纳和慈悲。与碎片化来访者工作的治疗师处于同样的角色——因为他或她实际上看不到其他家庭成员而更具挑战性！

As clients are taught by the therapist to mindfully notice the child parts' distress and understand it as "her" or "his" pain, they are next encouraged to empathize with "the child part's feelings." This is not always an easy step for clients whose way of distancing the "not me" parts has been to loathe and despise their feelings. But the therapist whose compassion for the parts is genuine and spontaneous can create a contagion effect, evoking compassion even in the client who resists. To evoke empathy for the child, the therapist has to ask the client to pause and be curious about this child part that is afraid, ashamed, or hurt and lonely. How old is he or she? Can the client see the part? What does he or she look like? What expression does the client see on that little face? Acknowledging the enormity of what this child part has experienced can also evoke compassion, as long as the therapist is clearly asking, "What kinds of things has this child experienced?" rather than "What happened to you at this age?" The latter is more likely to trigger implicit reliving, while the former helps the client "see" the child as a helpless, innocent victim. Lastly, the client is next taught to use the resources characteristic of the normal life self to "help" the child parts that are so frightened and in so much distress.

当治疗师教导来访者正念地注意儿童部分的痛苦并将其理解为"她"或"他"的痛苦时，接下来鼓励他们对"儿童部分的感受"产生共情。对于那些通过厌恶和鄙视感受来疏远"非我"部分的来访者来说，这并不总是一个容易的步骤。但对各部分怀有真诚自发慈悲的治疗师可以产生感染效应，即使在抵抗的来访者中也能唤起慈悲。为了唤起对孩子的共情，治疗师必须请来访者暂停，对这个感到恐惧、羞耻或受伤、孤独的儿童部分保持好奇。他或她多大了？来访者能看见这个部分吗？他或她长什么样？来访者在那张小脸上看到了什么表情？承认这个儿童部分所经历事物的巨大性也能唤起慈悲，只要治疗师明确地问的是"这个孩子经历了什么样的事情？"而非"你在这个年龄发生了什么？"后者更容易触发内隐重现，而前者帮助来访者将孩子"看作"一个无助的、无辜的受害者。最后，来访者接下来被教导用正常生活自我的特征性资源来"帮助"那些如此恐惧和如此痛苦的儿童部分。

In session after session, as clients present the issues or feelings most troubling on that day, the therapist continues to ask them to notice "which part" is upset today and what has triggered that part. The assumption that upset is always a communication from a part is not a scientific fact, of course—it represents a way of relating to triggered states or implicit memories in a mindful, compassionate, non-pathologizing way.

在一次次会谈中，当来访者呈现当天最令其困扰的问题或感受时，治疗师继续请他们注意今天"哪个部分"感到不安，以及是什么触发了那个部分。假设不安总是来自某个部分的沟通，这当然不是科学事实——它代表着一种以正念、慈悲、非病理化方式与被触发状态或内隐记忆相处的方式。

Underlying this assumption is a mindfulness-related bias that noticing our thoughts, feelings, and body experience with interest, curiosity, and compassion is likely to lead to positive change (Davis & Hayes, 2011; Ogden & Fisher, 2015). If we as therapists consistently encourage the normal life self to take a mental step back, increase curiosity about the younger parts that are "having a hard time," notice the bodily and emotional signs that communicate "their" feelings, and then experiment with what might help the parts feel safer, better protected, less ashamed, we will be "processing" post-traumatic memory. Simply by noticing spontaneously evoked implicit memories and assigning the feelings to younger selves, clients can learn to feel less afraid of their triggered responses and more connected to and protective of their parts, rather than ashamed and alienated.

这一假设的基础是与正念相关的偏向：以兴趣、好奇心和慈悲注意我们的思维、感受和身体体验，可能会带来积极变化（Davis & Hayes，2011年；Ogden & Fisher，2015年）。如果我们作为治疗师持续鼓励正常生活自我在精神上退一步，增加对那些"度日艰难"的年幼部分的好奇心，注意传达"他们"感受的身体和情绪信号，然后尝试什么可能帮助各部分感到更安全、更受保护、更少羞耻，我们就将"处理"创伤后记忆。仅仅通过注意自发唤起的内隐记忆并将感受归因于更年轻的自我，来访者就能学会对被触发的反应不那么恐惧，更与保护各部分相连，而不是羞耻和疏离。

The Body as a Shared Whole

身体作为共同的整体

When I help clients foster empathy for their vulnerable or protector parts, they cannot help but feel that empathy in their bodies. If I were to ask, "Do you feel compassion for yourself, too?" the answer would be "Absolutely not!" But when they say, "I feel badly for that little part—I feel sad for him [her]," I can observe their faces softening and their bodies relaxing a little bit. They can feel the empathy extended to a young child part or brave protective fight part, can feel the part responding positively, and it feels good inside the shared whole of the body. Although human beings tend to put words to experiences of empathy ("I feel understood—it feels like someone 'gets it'—I feel like you believe me"), attunement and empathy are actually nonverbal somatic experiences of warmth, relaxation, being able to breathe more deeply, and feeling emotionally closer and more connected.

当我帮助来访者培养对脆弱或保护者部分的共情时，他们无法不在身体中感受到那种共情。如果我问："你也对自己感到慈悲吗？"答案将是"绝对不！"但当他们说，"我为那个小部分感到难受——我为他[她]感到悲伤"，我可以观察到他们的脸庞变得柔和，身体稍微放松了一些。他们能感受到延伸到年幼儿童部分或勇敢的保护性战斗部分的共情，能感受到那个部分积极地回应，在身体共同整体的内部感觉良好。尽管人类倾向于用语言表达共情的体验（"我感到被理解了——感觉有人'懂得了'——我感觉你相信我"），协调和共情实际上是温暖、放松、能够更深呼吸、感觉情感上更亲近和更有连接的非语言躯体体验。

Because, despite the presence of many parts, there is only one shared whole of a body, it also means that any intervention having a positive effect on body experience will have a positive effect in some way on each part. For example,

因为尽管有许多部分，却只有一个共同的身体整体，这也意味着对身体体验产生积极效果的任何干预，都将以某种方式对每个部分产生积极效果。例如，

Ted had been "hijacked" or taken over by a depressed, ashamed submit part many years previously when early professional success unexpectedly triggered a flooding of post-traumatic implicit memory, sending him into a tailspin from which he had never recovered. Now, twenty years later, he was still depressed, still struggling to function, still ashamed of his "fall from grace" as he termed it. A tall, thin man, his shoulders and spine were collapsed; he walked with a duck-footed awkwardness; and he tended to look down at the floor rather than at me. His refrain was: "You don't understand." He was correct about that: it was hard for me to understand how this bright, talented man had just given up and given in to the depression—until one day, as I listened to his self-punitive confession of the week's failures, I felt myself collapse. My spine and shoulders sunk; I began to feel energy-less and helpless; I found myself questioning my ability as a therapist.
Without consciously choosing to disclose, I heard myself saying, "You know, Ted, as you talk, I can feel myself collapsing in my chair, going numb, feeling absolutely helpless, questioning my adequacy … I may not be as good at this as I thought I was …"
Suddenly, he sat up: "That's how I feel!" he said. "You finally got it! Now you know what I'm going through."

Ted曾在许多年前被一个抑郁、羞耻的顺从部分"劫持"或接管，当时早期职业上的成功意外地触发了创伤后内隐记忆的泛滥，将他送入了一个从未恢复的螺旋式下降。现在，二十年后，他仍然抑郁，仍然难以维持功能，仍然为他所称之为的"恩宠的失去"感到羞耻。一个高挑、消瘦的男人，他的肩膀和脊柱塌陷；他走路时有一种外八字的笨拙；他倾向于低头看地板而不是看我。他的口头禅是："你不理解。"他说得对：我很难理解这个聪明、有才华的男人是如何就这样放弃、向抑郁缴械的——直到有一天，当我聆听他对那周失败的自我惩罚性忏悔时，我感到自己塌陷了。我的脊柱和肩膀下沉；我开始感到无精打采、无助；我发现自己质疑自己作为治疗师的能力。
我没有有意识地选择自我披露，却听到自己说："你知道，Ted，当你说话时，我能感觉到自己在椅子上塌陷，变得麻木，感到绝对无助，质疑自己的充分性……我可能没有我以为的那么擅长这件事……"
突然间，他坐直了："那就是我的感受！"他说。"你终于明白了！现在你知道我在经历什么了。"

ME: "I do." [Still slumped in my chair with no energy to meet his energy.]

我：「是的。」[仍然在椅子上塌陷，没有精力去迎接他的能量。]

TED: "I feel so much better now that I know you 'get' it!" Now he was sitting up with his back straight and aliveness in his face and tone of voice.

TED：「现在我知道你'懂了'，我感觉好多了！」现在他坐直了，背部挺直，脸上和声音里都充满了活力。

ME: "It seems like you felt better as soon as you sat up, though. Is it OK if I do that, too?" [I imitate his posture of excitement and pleasure] "Oh, that is so much better—thank you."

我：「不过，好像你一坐直就感觉好多了。我也这样做可以吗？」[我模仿他兴奋和愉悦的姿势]「哦，这样好多了——谢谢你。」

TED: [Sitting up even straighter with his shoulders back] "Yes, that does help, doesn't it?"

TED：[坐得更直，肩膀向后]「是的，这确实有帮助，不是吗？」

ME: "Would it be OK if we stood rather than sit? Maybe that would help me with this hopeless feeling …" [We both stood up.]

我：「我们站起来而不是坐着，可以吗？也许这会帮助我摆脱这种绝望的感觉……」[我们两人都站了起来。]

TED: "This is much better!" [He suddenly looked like a new person: more assured, more masculine, more related to me instead of alone in his depressive world.]

TED：「这样好多了！」[他突然看起来像一个新人：更有自信，更有男子气概，与我更有关联，而不是孤独地在他的抑郁世界中。]

ME: "It sure is—what a difference! In you, too—it's like your grownup self is standing tall and sending a whole new message to the depressed part!"

我：「确实——多大的不同啊！你也是——就像你的成年自我昂首挺立，向那个抑郁的部分发出了一个全新的信息！」

TED: "I feel like a man," he said. "It's been a long time since I felt like a real man. If that makes the depressed part feel better, I'm glad."

TED：「我感觉像个男人，」他说。「很久没有这种真正是个男人的感觉了。如果这能让那个抑郁的部分感觉更好，我很高兴。」

ME: "Maybe before, your physical collapse communicated to him that he was right—he should be depressed and hopeless and question himself. Now your body is sending him a really different message, isn't it?"

我：「也许以前，你身体的塌陷向他传达了他是对的——他应该抑郁、绝望、质疑自己。现在你的身体向他发送了一个截然不同的信息，不是吗？」

Utilizing movement interventions drawn from Sensorimotor Psychotherapy (Ogden et al., 2006; Ogden & Fisher, 2015), Ted transformed his internal experience, especially that of the depressed submit part. His new body language communicated to the depressed part that he wasn't a little boy alone in an intimidating world, that he wasn't "less than," and that the boy could hold his head high along with Ted. By combining a parts perspective with the somatic interventions of Sensorimotor Psychotherapy, Ted and I could work simultaneously with the parts and the whole, rather than feeling pressure to choose one approach or the other.

利用来自感觉运动心理治疗的运动干预（Ogden et al.，2006年；Ogden & Fisher，2015年），Ted转变了他的内在体验，尤其是那个抑郁的顺从部分的体验。他新的身体语言向那个抑郁的部分传达，他不是一个独自在令人生畏的世界中的小男孩，他不是"低人一等"的，那个男孩可以与Ted一起昂首挺立。通过将部分视角与感觉运动心理治疗的躯体干预相结合，Ted和我可以同时处理各部分和整体，而不必感受到必须选择其中一种方法的压力。

The Changing Role of the Therapist

治疗师角色的转变

Not only does a parts approach require role changes for the therapist (from listener to educator, from individualistically oriented to systems-oriented, from facilitator to role model), but so do the demands of neurobiologically informed trauma treatment. The emphasis on greater differentiation between parts as a vehicle for mindful self-observation conflicts with the prevailing view in the field that the therapist must de-emphasize parts language and emphasize that the patient is one whole person in one body. However, when that one mind and body is in chaos or bent on self-destructive behavior or so fragmented that reality-testing is compromised, the goal of treatment must be to restore order and provide a period of stability during which clients can learn to identify the different perspectives inside them, develop more conscious and effective defenses, and differentiate their normal life selves from the impulsive, ashamed, or critical voices they hear inside. When the client reports many years of traditional talking therapy without the kind of progress in treatment one might expect, or describes having been stuck in an ongoing internal conflict over months or years without much success in resolving it, or describes the signs of structurally dissociated parts, it should be clear that treating the client as one person in one integrated body has not worked. Traditional talking therapy approaches might work well with individuals who are less fragmented or traumatized, but it does not work with clients whose habits of self-alienation and self-rejection recreate the rejections and humiliations of childhood.

部分取向不仅要求治疗师进行角色转变（从倾听者到教育者，从个体导向到系统导向，从促进者到角色模型），神经生物学知情的创伤治疗的需求亦然。强调将各部分的更大分化作为正念自我观察媒介的做法，与领域内主流观点相冲突，后者认为治疗师必须淡化部分语言，强调患者是一个身体中的一个完整的人。然而，当那一个心灵和身体处于混乱状态、或倾向于自我毁灭行为、或如此碎片化以至于现实检验受损时，治疗的目标必须是恢复秩序，提供一段稳定期，在此期间来访者可以学习识别内部的不同视角，发展更有意识和有效的防御，并将正常生活自我与他们内心听到的冲动、羞耻或批评的声音区分开来。当来访者报告多年传统谈话治疗没有获得人们可能期望的那种进展，或描述在持续数月或数年的内部冲突中陷入困境而没有太多成功解决，或描述结构性解离部分的迹象时，应该清楚地认识到，将来访者视为一个整合身体中的一个人的治疗方式并没有奏效。传统的谈话治疗方法对于碎片化或创伤程度较轻的个体可能效果良好，但对于那些自我疏离和自我排斥的习惯重演了童年拒绝和屈辱的来访者来说，它是无效的。

Processing Experience Instead of Events

处理体验而非事件

Therapists often feel pressure to address traumatic memory as early in treatment as possible because they have been taught that "trauma processing" is the gold standard of trauma therapy. Often unaware of changes in the standard of care in the field or familiar with new mindfulness-based treatments, they assume the need to access event memories.

治疗师常常感到压力，要尽早在治疗中处理创伤记忆，因为他们被教导"创伤处理"是创伤治疗的金标准。往往没有意识到领域内护理标准的变化，或对新的正念为基础的治疗不熟悉，他们假设需要访问事件记忆。

But in the model of treatment described here, the focus is not on traumatic events but on the "legacy of trauma" as it is carried by the parts and continues to intrude even decades later into the minds, bodies, and ongoing lives of survivors. "Processing the trauma" is equated in this model with "transforming" how the parts have encoded the effects of the traumatic events and transforming the client's relationship to the parts from one of alienation to one of unconditional acceptance and "earned secure attachment." For therapists with years of event-focused trauma treatment experience, it is often hard to shift from a narrative approach to a "repair" perspective. What they need to remember is that the event focus of the early trauma treatment field simply reflected an extension of the "talking cure" to trauma therapy (Rothschild, in press), not the creation of an approach specifically tailored to the in-depth understanding of traumatization available to therapists today (Van der Kolk, 2014).

但在这里描述的治疗模型中，焦点不在于创伤事件，而在于创伤的"遗产"，它由各部分所携带，并在数十年后继续侵入幸存者的心灵、身体和持续的生活。在这个模型中，"处理创伤"等同于"转化"各部分如何编码了创伤事件的影响，以及转化来访者与各部分的关系，从疏离转变为无条件接纳和"习得的安全依恋"。对于有多年以事件为中心的创伤治疗经验的治疗师来说，从叙事方法转向"修复"视角往往很难。他们需要记住的是，早期创伤治疗领域的事件焦点只是反映了"谈话疗法"向创伤治疗的延伸（Rothschild，待出版），而不是创造一种专门为今天治疗师可用的对创伤化深入理解而量身定制的方法（Van der Kolk，2014年）。

Throughout treatment, the therapist will encounter event-related issues. There will inevitably be parts that want to "tell all" or parts that tell and retell stories of the same events over and over again. Equally likely are parts that resist the therapist and the therapy in order to keep the secrets of the past intact or avoid "going there." Because therapists will encounter all these different points of view in their clients, it helps to keep in mind that the goal in trauma treatment is not remembering what happened but the ability to be "here" instead of "there" (Van der Kolk, 2014).

在整个治疗过程中，治疗师将遇到与事件相关的问题。不可避免地会有想要"倾诉一切"的部分，或反复讲述相同事件故事的部分。同样可能的是，有些部分抵抗治疗师和治疗，以保持过去的秘密完整或避免"去那里"。因为治疗师将在来访者中遇到所有这些不同的观点，记住创伤治疗的目标不是记住发生了什么，而是能够"在这里"而不是"在那里"（Van der Kolk，2014年），是有帮助的。

When individuals can be conscious and present in the here-and-now and tolerate the ups and downs and the highs and lows of normal life, they are ready to heal the injuries caused by the trauma—the injuries to innocence, to trust, to faith—the injuries to the body and the injuries to the heart and soul. Remembering the past is helpful only to the extent that it helps to heal rather than reopen the wounds. However much remembering plays a role in trauma treatment, it should never be used in the service of reliving the painful past or asking the parts to relive it.

当个体能够有意识地活在当下，并容纳正常生活的起伏高低时，他们就准备好愈合创伤所造成的伤害——对无辜的伤害、对信任的伤害、对信念的伤害——对身体的伤害和对心灵与灵魂的伤害。记住过去只有在有助于愈合而不是重新开放伤口的程度上才是有益的。无论记忆在创伤治疗中扮演什么角色，它都不应该被用来服务于重新经历痛苦的过去，或要求各部分重新经历它。

Remembering in fact should serve a larger purpose: to help the client "be here now" by transforming the past and changing the ending to each part's story. Remembrance should be used as a catalyst to evoke a deeper appreciation of how the client has survived "with heart and soul intact" and a gratitude for all the parts that helped the client survive and now deserve to be part of a safe and healthy present.

记忆实际上应该服务于一个更大的目的：通过转化过去、改变每个部分故事的结局，帮助来访者"活在当下"。回忆应该被用作催化剂，唤起对来访者如何"带着完整的心灵和灵魂"存活下来的更深感激，以及对所有帮助来访者存活、现在值得成为安全健康当下一部分的各部分的感恩。

References

Chodron, P. (2008). The pocket Pema Chodron. Boston: Shambhala Publications.

Damasio, A. (1999). The feeling of what happens: body and emotion in the making of consciousness. New York: Harcourt, Brace.

Davis, D. M. & Hayes, J. A. (2011). What are the benefits of mindfulness? A practice review of psychotherapy-related research. Psychotherapy, 48(2), 198–208.

Diamond, S., Balvin, R., & Diamond, F. (1963). Inhibition and choice. New York: Harper and Row.

Hanson, R. (2014). Hardwiring happiness: the new brain science of contentment, calm, and confidence. New York: Harmony Publications.

Herman, J. L. (1992) Trauma and recovery. New York: Basic Books.

Liotti, G. (2004). Attachment, trauma and disorganized attachment: three strands of a single braid. Psychotherapy: Theory, Research, Practice, Training, 41, 472–486.

Lyons-Ruth, K. et al. (2006). From infant attachment disorganization to adult dissociation: relational adaptations or traumatic experiences? Psychiatric Clinics of North America, 29(1).

Meichenbaum, D. (2012). Roadmap to resilience: a guide for military, trauma victims and their families. Clearwater, FL: Institute Press.

Ogden, P. & Fisher, J. (2015). Sensorimotor Psychotherapy: interventions for trauma and attachment. New York: W.W. Norton.

Ogden, P., Minton, K., & Pain, C. (2006). Trauma and the body: a sensorimotor approach to psychotherapy. New York: W.W. Norton.

Rothschild, B. (in press). The body remembers. Volume II: revolutionizing trauma treatment. New York: W.W. Norton.

Schwartz, R. (2001). Introduction to the internal family systems model. Oak Park, IL: Trailheads Publications.

Siegel, D.J. (1999). The developing mind: toward a neurobiology of interpersonal experience. New York: Guilford Press.

Siegel, D. J. (2010). The neurobiology of 'we.' Keynote address, Psychotherapy Networker Symposium, Washington, D.C.

Van der Hart, O., Nijenhuis, E.R.S., & Steele, K. (2006). The haunted self: structural dissociation and the treatment of chronic traumatization. New York: W.W. Norton.

Van der Kolk, B.A. (2014). The body keeps the score: brain, mind and body in the healing of trauma. New York: Viking Press.

Van der Kolk, B.A. & Fisler, R. (1995). Dissociation and the fragmentary nature of traumatic memories: overview & exploratory study. Journal of Traumatic Stress, 8(4), 505–525.

CHAPTER 6
Complications of Treatment: Traumatic Attachment

第6章 治疗的复杂之处：创伤性依恋

“Attachment is [a reflection of] the infant’s need to be safe from danger. We are not born securely attached. To the infant, the world is not a safe place.”

“依恋〔反映了〕婴儿需要免于危险、获得安全的需求。我们并非生来就拥有安全的依恋。对婴儿而言，世界并非一个安全的地方。”

(Solomon, 2011)

“In human infancy, experienced threat is closely related to the caregiver’s affective signals and availability rather than to the actual degree of physical or survival threat inherent in the event itself. Equipped with limited behavioral or cognitive coping capacities, the infant cannot gauge the actual degree of threat.”

“在人类婴儿期，所体验到的威胁与照料者的情感信号及其可及性密切相关，而非与事件本身所固有的身体或生存威胁的实际程度相关。婴儿所具备的行为或认知应对能力有限，无法估量威胁的实际程度。”

(Lyons-Ruth et al., 2006, p. 6)

The “Missing Experience” of Secure Attachment

安全依恋的“缺失体验”

In the first few minutes after birth, newborn and mother generally meet heart against heart as the baby is laid across the mother’s chest. These and other early experiences of attachment are body-to-body experiences: holding, rocking, feeding, stroking, gaze-to-gaze contact. Rather than using words, we communicate to infants with coos, mmmmm’s, and terms of endearment that evoke a lilt in the voice and bring a smile to our lips. Preverbal children take in the warm gaze, the smile, the softness or playfulness and respond with smiles, vocalizations and chuckles of delight, relaxing or brightening in a dyadic dance with their caregivers (Schore, 2001a). But infants and young children are equally equipped to perceive the body tension of the caregiver, the still, expressionless face (Tronick, 2007), the irritable tone of voice, or the rough movements. A baby’s immature nervous system is easily alarmed by intense emotional reactions, loud voices, sudden movements, or manifest anxiety in the mother (Lyons-Ruth et al., 2006). Whether the quality of parental care promotes secure attachment or is “frightened or frightening” (Lyons-Ruth et al., 2006) as in traumatic or “disorganized attachment,” these early bonding experiences are later remembered not as visual or verbal narratives but in the form of “implicit” or “emotional memories” and procedurally learned autonomic, motoric, visceral, and behavioral responses.

在出生后的最初几分钟里，当婴儿被横放在母亲胸前时，新生儿与母亲通常会心贴着心地相遇。这些以及其他早期的依恋体验都是身体对身体的体验：抱持、摇晃、喂养、抚摸、目光与目光的接触。我们不是用言语，而是用咕咕声、嗯嗯声以及那些会让声音变得抑扬顿挫、让我们嘴角浮起微笑的爱称来与婴儿交流。尚未会说话的孩子接收着那温暖的注视、微笑、柔和或嬉戏，并以微笑、发声和欢快的咯咯笑作出回应，在与照料者的二元之舞中放松下来或变得明亮起来（Schore，2001a）。但婴儿和幼儿同样具备感知照料者身体紧张、静止而面无表情的脸（Tronick，2007）、暴躁的语气或粗暴动作的能力。婴儿尚未成熟的神经系统很容易被强烈的情绪反应、高声、突然的动作或母亲明显的焦虑所惊扰（Lyons-Ruth等，2006）。无论父母照料的质量是促进了安全依恋，还是如创伤性依恋或“混乱型依恋”中那样“受惊或令人受惊”（Lyons-Ruth等，2006），这些早期的联结体验日后被记住的方式都不是视觉或言语的叙事，而是以“内隐”或“情绪记忆”的形式，以及以程序性习得的自主神经、运动、内脏和行为反应的形式被记住的。

Relational Habits: One Way of “Remembering” Early Attachment

关系性习惯：“记住”早期依恋的一种方式

The better the quality of our early attachment experiences, the greater our capacity to tolerate distress as we develop into adulthood. Our capacity for affect tolerance, self-soothing, and achievement of an integrated sense of self later in life is dependent upon the self-regulatory or self-soothing abilities acquired during the first 2 years of life (Shore, 2003), including both the ability for interactive regulation (to be soothed by others) and auto-regulation (the ability to soothe ourselves). Affect tolerance in adulthood appears to be directly tied to the smooth acceleration, braking, and deceleration of the autonomic nervous system (Ogden et al., 2006) developed in very early secure attachment relationships. The experience-dependent development of the right orbital prefrontal cortex (Schore, 2001b), the brain’s “self-soothing center,” is also facilitated by secure attachment in early life. In order for children’s nervous systems to develop a “window of tolerance” (Ogden et al., 2006; Siegel, 1999) for the highs and lows of emotional arousal, they require repeated emotional-somatic experiences of “interactive regulation,” that is, a caregiver who soothes, comforts, reassures, or otherwise down-regulates their states of distress or who distracts, cuddles, or playfully up-regulates their moods in the context of fatigue, boredom, depression, or shutting down. If an “attachment style” represents a child’s adaptation to a particular caregiving environment and a given caretaker, then we might think of attachment strategies as “procedurally learned,” that is, habits of action and reaction stored in the brain’s nonverbal memory system for function and habit. Many different memory systems interface in attachment relationships: “what we do with one another,” how we relate, reflects the procedural memory system. Autobiographical memory for family relationships and events captures “what we know about one another,” and emotional memory determines how our emotional states are altered in relationship to one another (Grigsby and Stevens, 2002). The attachment “habits” of each individual also reflect implicit memories describing what ratio of closeness to distance created the most safety and what was the best adaptation to the attachment demands in a particular family environment. Some clients may automatically tense up in response to proximity or human touch. Some may have developed habits of avoiding those closest to them, and others habits of preferential orienting just to family members or significant others, away from strangers and acquaintances. For some, eye contact may have been a lifeline, leaving the client with little ability to disengage from “staring” at others; but, for some individuals, eye contact might have been an aversive experience of looking into frightening eyes, resulting in habits of disengaging or looking away later noted by therapists as “poor eye contact” without awareness that habits of eye contact tell us valuable information about early attachment experiences. Where clients sit (closer or farther from the therapist), whether their bodies are oriented toward or away, lean toward or pull back from the therapist, already provide us with important information about the client’s attachment style and history.

我们早期依恋体验的质量越好，在成长为成年人的过程中，我们承受痛苦的能力就越强。我们日后的情感耐受能力、自我安抚能力以及达成整合的自我感的能力，取决于生命最初两年里获得的自我调节或自我安抚能力（Shore，2003），这既包括互动调节的能力（被他人安抚），也包括自我调节的能力（自己安抚自己的能力）。成年期的情感耐受似乎直接关联于自主神经系统平稳的加速、刹车和减速（Ogden等，2006），而这是在极早期的安全依恋关系中发展起来的。右眶额前额叶皮层（Schore，2001b）——大脑的“自我安抚中心”——其依赖经验的发展，也由生命早期的安全依恋所促进。为了让孩子的神经系统针对情绪唤起的高低起伏发展出一个“耐受之窗”（Ogden等，2006；Siegel，1999），他们需要反复的“互动调节”的情绪—躯体体验，也就是一位会安抚、抚慰、安慰、或以其他方式下调他们痛苦状态的照料者，或者一位在他们疲惫、无聊、抑郁或关闭的情境中，会分散他们注意力、搂抱他们、或以嬉戏的方式上调他们情绪的照料者。如果一种“依恋风格”代表着孩子对某种特定照料环境和特定照料者的适应，那么我们或许可以把依恋策略看作是“程序性习得”的，也就是储存在大脑那个负责功能与习惯的非言语记忆系统中的行动与反应的习惯。在依恋关系中有许多不同的记忆系统在交互作用：“我们彼此之间做什么”，我们如何相处，反映的是程序性记忆系统。关于家庭关系和事件的自传体记忆捕捉的是“我们彼此了解什么”，而情绪记忆则决定了我们的情绪状态如何在彼此的关系中发生改变（Grigsby和Stevens，2002）。每个个体的依恋“习惯”也反映出内隐记忆，它描述了怎样的亲近与距离之比创造了最大的安全，以及在某个特定家庭环境中，对依恋需求的最佳适应是什么。有些来访者可能会对亲近或人的触碰自动地紧绷起来。有些人可能形成了回避最亲近之人的习惯，另一些人则形成了只优先朝向家庭成员或重要他人、而远离陌生人和熟人的习惯。对一些人来说，目光接触或许曾是一条生命线，使来访者几乎没有能力从“盯着”他人看中脱离出来；但对某些个体而言，目光接触可能曾是一种望进令人恐惧的眼睛的厌恶性体验，由此形成了脱离或移开目光的习惯，日后被治疗师注意到，称之为“目光接触差”，却没有意识到目光接触的习惯告诉了我们关于早期依恋体验的宝贵信息。来访者坐在哪里（离治疗师更近还是更远）、他们的身体是朝向还是背离、是倾向还是从治疗师那里退缩，这些都已经为我们提供了关于来访者依恋风格和历史的重要信息。

Trauma and Attachment: The Source of Safety Becomes the Source of Danger

创伤与依恋：安全的来源变成了危险的来源

“[W]ith a [frightened/frightening] caregiver, infants are caught in a relational trap: their defense systems motivate them to flee from the caregiver, while at the same time their attachment system motivates them, under the commanding influence of separation fear, to strive for achieving comforting proximity to her or him.”

“面对一位〔受惊／令人受惊〕的照料者，婴儿陷入了一个关系性的陷阱：他们的防御系统驱使他们逃离照料者，而与此同时，在分离恐惧的主导影响下，他们的依恋系统又驱使他们努力去获得与他或她之间令人安心的亲近。”

(Liotti, 2011, p. 235)

Because children’s innate attachment behavior is organized around proximity-seeking and social engagement, caregivers who are neglectful and abusive pose a double threat: not only does their frightening behavior evoke fear/flight/fight responses but it also intensifies the child’s yearning for proximity. The result is what Main and Hesse (1990) first termed “disorganized” or Type D attachment, the result of what Main termed “fright without solution.” When parents are “frightened or frightening,” Main and Hesse concluded, the child’s instinctive source of comfort and safety becomes the source of danger. Rather than attachment figures providing protection and interactive regulation for the child, their behavior is alarming. Frightening, frightened, and/or abusive parents stimulate proximity-seeking drives and activate the child’s survival defenses of fight and flight, or they evoke rapid activation of the parasympathetic dorsal vagal system to initiate freezing, shutting down or “playing dead.” Beatrice Beebe’s infant research (2009) has demonstrated that, as early as 3 to 6 months, babies develop what she calls “expectancies,” patterns of behavior that anticipate interactions with their caregivers. In her observations of infants with disorganized attachment, these expectancies range from shutting down and going limp to matching the mother’s dysregulated states (e.g., imitating maternal laughter in response to their distress). In both instances, the infants succeed in regulating their responses to their mother’s alarming behavior but in ways that, if procedurally learned, set the stage for longer term autonomic dysregulation: either automatic parasympathetic shutdown or mimicking of maternal sympathetic responses.

由于孩子与生俱来的依恋行为是围绕寻求亲近和社会参与组织起来的，忽视和虐待孩子的照料者构成了双重威胁：他们令人恐惧的行为不仅会引发恐惧／逃跑／战斗反应，而且还会加剧孩子对亲近的渴望。其结果便是Main和Hesse（1990）最先称之为“混乱型”或D型的依恋，它是Main所称的“无解之惊恐”的产物。Main和Hesse总结道，当父母“受惊或令人受惊”时，孩子那本能的安慰与安全的来源就变成了危险的来源。依恋对象非但没有为孩子提供保护和互动调节，他们的行为反而令人惊恐。令人受惊的、受惊的和／或施虐的父母会激起寻求亲近的驱力，并激活孩子战斗和逃跑的生存防御，或者引发副交感背侧迷走神经系统的快速激活，从而启动冻结、关闭或“装死”。Beatrice Beebe的婴儿研究（2009）表明，早在3至6个月大时，婴儿就会发展出她所称的“预期”，即一种预先料想与照料者互动的行为模式。在她对混乱型依恋婴儿的观察中，这些预期从关闭、变得瘫软，到匹配母亲失调的状态（例如，以模仿母亲的笑声来回应自己的痛苦）不等。在这两种情况下，婴儿都成功地调节了自己对母亲令人惊恐之行为的反应，但其方式一旦经程序性习得，便为更长期的自主神经失调埋下了伏笔：要么是自动的副交感关闭，要么是对母亲交感反应的模仿。

Because infants and young children, dependent on their caretakers for survival, cannot effectively flee or fight, their repertoire of survival responses is limited to the resources of their young bodies (Ogden et al., 2006). Driven to seek proximity to attachment figures when alarmed or hurt, they defend against threat by backing away, closing their eyes, hiding, shutting down, or dissociating. When the source of danger is the attachment figure, the mind and body must find a way to maintain an attachment bond while simultaneously mobilizing animal defense survival responses to protect the child. These two powerful innate drives (to attach and to defend) each remain highly activated, one drive dominating at times and then the other. The result is a child (and later adult) caught between two equally strong “pulls”: the yearning for proximity and closeness and the animal defenses of fight, flight, freeze, and submission. “Too much” closeness feels dangerous, but so does “too much” distance. Without any narrative memory, without a conscious thought, Karin’s story illustrates how powerful early nonverbal attachment learning can be.

由于婴儿和幼儿依赖照料者才能生存，无法有效地逃跑或战斗，他们生存反应的全部曲目仅限于他们幼小身体的资源（Ogden等，2006）。当受惊或受伤时，他们被驱使去寻求与依恋对象的亲近，他们以后退、闭上眼睛、躲藏、关闭或解离来防御威胁。当危险的来源正是依恋对象本身时，心智和身体就必须找到一种方法，在维持依恋纽带的同时，又调动动物性防御的生存反应来保护孩子。这两种强大的、与生俱来的驱力（依恋与防御）各自都保持着高度激活，时而这种驱力占据主导，时而又是另一种。其结果便是一个孩子（以及日后的成年人）被夹在两股同样强大的“拉力”之间：对亲近与亲密的渴望，以及战斗、逃跑、冻结和顺从的动物性防御。“太多”的亲近让人感到危险，但“太多”的距离同样如此。在没有任何叙事记忆、没有任何有意识念头的情况下，Karin的故事说明了早期非言语的依恋学习可以何等强大。

Karin had no narrative or event memories of the first year and a half of her life spent in a Romanian orphanage, but she had many unrecognized implicit and procedural memories: her body remembered that closeness is dangerous, propelling her to push away boyfriends as the relationship grew closer, especially if they were kind and loving. As these romantic relationships endured despite her negative reactions to the closeness, she found herself becoming increasingly hypervigilant, suspicious, and reactive to any failure of attunement or attention. Each time she felt abandoned, unseen, or unheard, she would erupt in anger and threaten to leave. When, after many months of conflict and rejection, the young man finally succumbed to being pushed away, Karin would feel overcome with feelings of loss, abandonment, and separation anxiety: “How could he leave me?” she would ask. “Maybe he didn’t love me …” Once he was gone, the urge to push him away suddenly yielded to the intense yearning to pull him closer.

对于在罗马尼亚一家孤儿院度过的生命最初一年半，Karin没有任何叙事或事件记忆，但她有许多未被识别的内隐记忆和程序性记忆：她的身体记得亲近是危险的，这推动她在关系日渐亲近时把男友推开，尤其当他们善良而充满爱意时。尽管她对亲近怀有负面反应，这些恋爱关系仍得以延续，而她发现自己变得越来越过度警觉、多疑，并且对任何调谐或关注上的失误都极易作出反应。每当她感到被抛弃、不被看见或不被听见时，她就会勃然大怒，威胁要离开。在经历了数月的冲突与拒绝之后，当那个年轻人最终屈服于被推开时，Karin便会被失落、被抛弃和分离焦虑的感受所淹没：“他怎么能离开我？”她会问。“也许他根本不爱我……”一旦他离去，把他推开的冲动便骤然让位于把他拉得更近的强烈渴望。

As Liotti (2011) describes it, “[In the context of frightened/frightening caregiving], ‘the caregiver becomes at the same time the source and the solution of the infant’s alarm’ (Main & Hesse, 1990, p. 163). Fear comes to paradoxically coexist, in the infant’s experience, with the soothing provided by proximity to the caregiver” (p. 234). The tragedy for children like Karin is the strong association that develops between soothing or proximity and fear. The warm, positive feelings evoked by her boyfriends’ loving behavior very quickly activated fear and vigilance, leading to crisis after crisis in the relationship until finally they abandoned their efforts to win her.

正如Liotti（2011）所描述的，“〔在受惊／令人受惊的照料情境中〕，‘照料者同时成为婴儿惊恐的来源与解决之道’（Main和Hesse，1990，第163页）。在婴儿的体验中，恐惧矛盾地与亲近照料者所提供的安抚共存”（第234页）。像Karin这样的孩子的悲剧，在于安抚或亲近与恐惧之间形成了强烈的关联。她男友充满爱意的行为所唤起的温暖、积极的感受，会很快激活恐惧与警觉，导致关系中一场又一场的危机，直到他们最终放弃了赢得她的努力。

Not only do children like Karin fail to develop a window of tolerance, but worse yet, their nervous systems become biased toward sympathetic hyperactivity, impulsive proximity-seeking, and fight-flight behavior, often diagnosed as oppositional-defiant disorder in childhood and borderline personality disorder in adulthood. Or they become parasympathetically dominant: shut down, inhibited, hopeless and helpless, without initiative or energy, a state frequently mistaken for depression. There are no stronger evolutionary instincts than the attachment drive and its polar opposite, the animal defense survival responses. The tendencies of babies and young children to seek and maintain proximity, to explore the environment while using caregivers as a “safe base,” and to seek a parent figure when alarmed or distressed have contributed to child safety and protection for centuries. Even when a parent appears frightened and is therefore frightening, the proximity-seeking drive can still be activated by anxiety about a parent’s safety or moods. Primitive signs of this conflict between proximity and safety can be observed in orphanage-raised adoptees: at first, they often arch away from the adoptive mother’s body or stiffen on contact, look away rather than toward the caregiver. In contrast, babies in secure attachment relationships actively search the faces of adults to establish gaze-to-gaze contact and then socially engage by smiling, laughing, and cooing.

像Karin这样的孩子不仅无法发展出耐受之窗，更糟糕的是，他们的神经系统会偏向交感神经的过度活跃、冲动性的寻求亲近以及战斗—逃跑行为，这在儿童期常被诊断为对立违抗性障碍，在成年期则被诊断为边缘型人格障碍。或者他们变得以副交感神经为主导：关闭、受抑制、绝望而无助，缺乏主动性或能量，这种状态常被误认为抑郁。没有什么进化本能比依恋驱力及其极端对立面——动物性防御的生存反应——更为强大。婴儿和幼儿寻求并维持亲近、把照料者当作“安全基地”来探索环境、以及在受惊或痛苦时寻找父母形象的这些倾向，数个世纪以来一直有助于儿童的安全与保护。即便一位父母显得受惊、并因此令人受惊，对父母安全或情绪的焦虑仍可能激活寻求亲近的驱力。这种亲近与安全之间冲突的原始迹象，可以在孤儿院养大的被收养儿童身上观察到：起初，他们常常从养母的身体旁拱起身子躲开，或一被接触就僵硬，看向别处而非朝向照料者。与此相反，处于安全依恋关系中的婴儿会主动搜寻成年人的面孔以建立目光与目光的接触，然后通过微笑、大笑和咕咕作声来进行社会参与。

“Controlling Attachment Strategies” and Trauma

“控制性依恋策略”与创伤

By the preschool years, now possessing language and motor skills they did not have in infancy, children with disorganized attachment status are observed by researchers to develop “controlling tendencies”: a pattern of behavior that manages or controls the caregiver’s actions and reactions in one of two characteristic ways (Liotti, 2011). One subgroup exhibits “controlling-caretaking” behavior, a parentified style of relating by soothing, reassuring, and helping their mothers. The other subgroup exhibits “controlling-punitive” behavior: attacking the mother verbally and/or physically, humiliating and devaluing her. Researchers note that the controlling-caretaking pattern is more common in girl children and more common when mothers exhibit role-reversal (i.e., are needy and childlike) and guilt-inducing behavior; controlling-punitive behavior is more common in boys, especially in response to maternal hostility. In each case, the child has found a way to defend and attach simultaneously: to remain close to the parent while inhibiting the dependency needs usually associated with attachment.

到了学龄前阶段，如今拥有了婴儿期所不具备的语言和运动技能，具有混乱型依恋状态的孩子被研究者观察到会发展出“控制性倾向”：一种以两种特征性方式之一来管理或控制照料者行动与反应的行为模式（Liotti，2011）。一个亚组表现出“控制—照顾型”行为，即一种亲职化的相处风格，通过安抚、安慰和帮助母亲来与之相处。另一个亚组则表现出“控制—惩罚型”行为：在言语上和／或身体上攻击母亲，羞辱并贬低她。研究者指出，控制—照顾型模式在女孩中更为常见，并且在母亲表现出角色反转（即变得有需求、孩子气）和诱发内疚的行为时更为常见；控制—惩罚型行为在男孩中更为常见，尤其是作为对母亲敌意的反应。在每一种情况下，孩子都找到了一种同时进行防御与依恋的方法：在抑制通常与依恋相关联的依赖需求的同时，与父母保持亲近。

“Phobia of Therapy and the Therapist”

“对治疗和治疗师的恐惧”

This legacy of disorganized attachment and controlling strategies affects all later adult relationships, including the therapeutic one. Van der Hart, Nijenhuis, and Steele (2006) call this latter phenomenon “phobia of therapy and the therapist.” To the extent that traumatized clients come to therapy craving the relief, understanding, and care offered by the therapist (proximity-seeking), they are equally likely to experience fear and distrust of both the relationship and the process either early in treatment or as the relationship with the therapist grows. The prospect of trusting someone, of being seen, of disclosing one’s secrets does not bring relief: it brings trepidation.

这种混乱型依恋和控制性策略的遗留物，会影响日后所有的成年关系，包括治疗关系。Van der Hart、Nijenhuis和Steele（2006）将后一种现象称为“对治疗和治疗师的恐惧”。受创伤的来访者前来接受治疗，渴求着治疗师所提供的解脱、理解与关怀（寻求亲近），与此同时，他们也同样可能在治疗早期、或随着与治疗师关系的增进，而体验到对这段关系和这一过程两者的恐惧与不信任。信任某人、被看见、吐露自己秘密的前景并不带来解脱：它带来的是惶恐不安。

As Jessica Benjamin (1994) describes it, “To be known or recognized is immediately to experience the other’s power. The other becomes the one who can give or withhold recognition: who can see what is hidden; who can reach, conceivably even violate, the core of the self” (p. 539). The lived experience of traumatized individuals has created an unavoidable and painful paradox: closeness cannot be trusted, but distance or aloneness is also not safe. Their experience was that being alone and without protection created greater vulnerability, while being in proximity was also not safe. Because they could not depend upon the protection of the non-offending caretaker, these clients are either loathe to depend upon the therapist, or they assume the opposite: that their only safety lies in dependency. The yearning to self-disclose tends to conflict with the fear that self-disclosure will be used against the client, that secrets will not be believed, that he or she will be humiliated, not validated. Simon illustrates the dilemma in which therapist and client can find themselves: in coming to therapy, he expressed his wish for help, but his parts could not allow him to accept help, much less trust it!

正如Jessica Benjamin（1994）所描述的，“被了解或被认可，就是立即体验到他者的权力。他者成为那个能够给予或扣留认可的人：那个能够看见被隐藏之物的人；那个能够触及、甚至可以设想会侵犯自我核心的人”（第539页）。受创伤个体的亲历体验制造出一种无法回避而又痛苦的悖论：亲近不可信任，但距离或孤身一人也不安全。他们的体验是，独自一人、得不到保护会带来更大的脆弱，而处于亲近之中也并不安全。由于他们无法依靠那个未施害的照料者的保护，这些来访者要么不愿依靠治疗师，要么作出相反的假设：他们唯一的安全在于依赖。吐露自我的渴望往往与一种恐惧相冲突——担心自我吐露会被用来对付来访者，担心秘密不会被相信，担心他或她会被羞辱，而非被确认。Simon说明了治疗师与来访者可能陷入的两难处境：在前来接受治疗时，他表达了对帮助的渴望，但他的各部分却无法允许他接受帮助，更不用说信任它了！

Each time I brought more warmth to my tone, more determination to help him, the more I could see Simon’s body tensing up. When I leaned forward to make contact with him, I felt him pulling back. Although he verbalized a wish for help, I could feel him withdrawing from whatever I offered. If I leaned forward to emphasize a point, I could see his body stiffen and pull back.

每一次我的语气中带上更多的温暖、更多帮助他的决心，我就越能看到Simon的身体紧绷起来。当我前倾身子想与他建立接触时，我感到他在往后退缩。尽管他用言语表达了对帮助的渴望，我却能感到他从我所提供的任何东西中退缩。如果我前倾身子去强调某一点，我就能看到他的身体僵硬起来、往后退缩。

ME: “Seems like you want to take in what I’m saying, but it’s hard, isn’t it?”

我：“看起来你想要把我说的话接纳进去，但这很难，是吧？”

SIMON: “It feels like you’re trying to sell me something and I should be careful because it might not be safe.”

SIMON：“感觉就像你在试图向我推销什么东西，而我应该小心，因为它可能不安全。”

ME: “Yes, I can tell it doesn’t feel safe. Your body is just trying to protect you, huh? It’s saying, ‘Be careful—don’t just accept whatever you’re told’ …”

我：“是的，我看得出来它让人感觉不安全。你的身体只是在努力保护你，对吧？它在说，‘小心点——别人跟你说什么你别照单全收’……”

Simon was paralyzed by an internal conflict: he wanted help with his debilitating thoughts and feelings, but somehow he couldn’t allow himself to accept the help offered.

Simon被一种内部冲突所瘫痪：他想要有人帮他处理那些令他衰弱的想法和感受，但不知何故，他无法允许自己接受所提供的帮助。

To further complicate Simon’s dilemma, different parts of him were in head-to-head conflict about the therapeutic relationship. His judgmental, cynical fight part questioned the therapist’s credentials, methods, and orientation. His more intellectual going on with normal life self, who had researched my work in advance, thought the approach seemed “appropriate.” His lonely, lost child part just yearned for the therapist to “say something nice,” something that would put a balm on his emotional wounds. The submit part whose depressive beliefs about himself kept Simon perpetually dysphoric both liked and felt threatened by the therapist’s challenging of those beliefs as just a survival strategy. Not knowing which internal pull or voice was “his,” Simon alternately identified with all of them. At some appointments, he would be open to working on changing his relationship to the depression by understanding it as that of a young boy who had learned to keep himself quiet and shut down, so he could “fly below the radar.” At other times, he would express ambivalence about continuing in therapy or even anger that, “I’ve wasted all these years seeing therapist after therapist—this is just one more failed attempt.”

使Simon的两难处境进一步复杂化的是，他的不同部分就治疗关系而陷入了针锋相对的冲突。他那爱评判、愤世嫉俗的战斗部分质疑治疗师的资历、方法和取向。他那个更偏理智的正常生活自我——曾事先研究过我的工作——认为这种方法似乎“合适”。他那孤独、迷失的孩子部分只是渴望治疗师“说点好听的话”，某种能在他情感创伤上敷一层香膏的话。那个顺从部分——它那些关于自身的抑郁性信念使Simon永远处于烦躁不安之中——对治疗师将这些信念质疑为不过是一种生存策略，既喜欢又感到威胁。由于不知道究竟哪一股内在的拉力或声音才是“他自己的”，Simon轮流地认同它们全部。在某些会谈中，他会愿意去改变自己与抑郁的关系，把它理解为一个学会了让自己保持安静、关闭起来、以便能够“在雷达下方飞行”的小男孩的抑郁。而在另一些时候，他又会表达对继续治疗的矛盾心态，甚至愤怒地说：“我浪费了这么多年，看了一个又一个治疗师——这不过是又一次失败的尝试罢了。”

Each structurally dissociated part, driven by a particular animal defense response or combination of responses, tends to be biased in its perspective on attachment versus safety. As each is evoked on different days by different aspects of the treatment, the therapist can become confused and disoriented if he or she does not recognize the fragmentation and identify the parts. The attach parts often idealize the therapist and actively seek a relationship that at first may seem like healthy therapeutic collaboration: “I need help, and you have expert help to give me.” But, over time, the client, blended with the attach part, becomes progressively more childlike or needy, develops separation anxiety, or is increasingly in crisis. Driven by their innate proximity-seeking instincts, the bias of the attach parts is that the only safety lies in closeness, in being cared about, not being separated. One day, Annie and I decided to gather more information about what “caring” meant to the parts who repeatedly questioned whether I really cared about her or them, who incessantly worried that they would displease me and provoke abandonment—to the point that their anxiety made it difficult to focus on issues other than their preoccupation with me.

每一个结构性解离的部分，受某种特定的动物性防御反应或反应组合所驱动，往往在它对依恋与安全的视角上带有偏见。由于每个部分在不同的日子里被治疗的不同方面所唤起，倘若治疗师没有识别出这种碎裂、辨认出各个部分，他或她就可能变得困惑和迷失方向。依恋部分常常理想化治疗师，并主动寻求一种起初看起来像是健康的治疗协作的关系：“我需要帮助，而你有专业的帮助可以给我。”但随着时间推移，与依恋部分融合的来访者会逐渐变得越来越孩子气或有需求，发展出分离焦虑，或越来越频繁地陷入危机。在与生俱来的寻求亲近本能的驱使下，依恋部分的偏见在于：唯一的安全在于亲近，在于被在乎、不被分离。有一天，Annie和我决定收集更多信息，去了解“在乎”对那些部分意味着什么——这些部分反复质疑我是否真的在乎她或它们，不停地担心它们会惹我不快、招致被抛弃——以至于它们的焦虑使人难以专注于除了它们对我的全神贯注之外的其他议题。

When I asked why her little parts were so focused on evoking evidence that I cared, Annie became quiet and turned her attention inside to better hear the internal conversation. “They’re saying that if someone cares about you, they’ll protect you. They won’t leave you alone to get taken—they’ll watch out for you.” The night she had been kidnapped at age 7, no adult was watching out for her—she was all alone. The parts’ implicit memories of that experience made “caring” all important, but no matter how many times Annie or I reassured them that I had proven I cared many times over, they could be momentarily reassured if they felt “cared for” but then that moment of relief would immediately quickly trigger more anxiety.

当我问及为什么她那些小部分如此专注于唤起我在乎的证据时，Annie安静了下来，把注意力转向内在，以便更好地听见内部的对话。“它们在说，如果有人在乎你，他们就会保护你。他们不会把你独自留下、让你被抓走——他们会照看你。”在她7岁那年被绑架的那个夜晚，没有任何成年人在照看她——她孤身一人。各部分关于那段经历的内隐记忆，使“在乎”变得至关重要，但无论Annie或我多少次向它们保证我已经一再证明了我的在乎，倘若它们感到被“在乎”，它们可以一时间得到安抚，可随后那一刻的宽慰又会立即迅速触发更多的焦虑。

Awakening the Yearning for Care

唤醒对关怀的渴望

Rather than feeling comforted by the therapeutic relationship or by the growing closeness that usually occurs as a natural, healthy outgrowth of psychotherapy, the attach parts can often have the opposite reaction. As they feel “closeness” at long last, it is both a relief and a trigger. Their fears of abandonment and sensitivity to empathic failure typically intensify, often leading to increasing demands on the therapist’s time and energy. Concerned by the increasing levels of distress, volume of calls, mounting instability, or accusations of empathic failure, therapists may not realize that their valiant attempts to create safety and attunement in the therapy are instead evoking implicit memories. The feeling memories of painful yearning for someone to care, to comfort, to be close often evoke a hunger for contact that can become obsessive and is often pathologized as psychotic or erotic transference. In addition, if therapists are not familiar with the Structural Dissociation model or have been trained to diagnose the symptoms of disorganized attachment as evidence of borderline personality disorder, they can be dysregulated by the shifting states and conflicting presentations of the client. The going on with normal life self might trust the therapist’s offer of safety, might be willing to “work” in therapy with little need for reassurance. The attach parts will trust the therapist immediately and unconditionally but their yearning for closeness will also be triggered by kindness, warmth, and care, resulting in an increasing hunger for more and more proximity. Desperate for contact, the attach part often has difficulty leaving the therapist’s office at the end of sessions and/or seeks “proximity” between visits—through voicemail, email, or text. Because these young parts are highly anxious and alarmed, their messages often appear to be signs of crisis to which therapists feel a responsibility to respond. Over time, however, the therapist may begin to notice a pattern: the same level of urgency is evoked by both large and small stressors; therapeutic reassurance is less rather than more successful over time; sensitivity to empathic failure becomes heightened; and the number of crisis calls does not diminish over time or may even increase. That is because the job of these parts is to “cry for help” and because their implicit memories of yearning for contact and fear of abandonment are exacerbated, rather than soothed, by proximity to an attachment figure. Without the therapist’s awareness that these parts are just one aspect of an otherwise competent adult or that their distress represents activation of memory, he or she may feel responsible for soothing them.

依恋部分非但不会因治疗关系、或因心理治疗作为一种自然、健康的产物而通常出现的日渐亲近而感到安慰，反而常常会有相反的反应。当它们终于感受到“亲近”时，这既是一种解脱，也是一个触发因素。它们对被抛弃的恐惧以及对共情失败的敏感通常会加剧，常常导致对治疗师时间与精力越来越多的索求。治疗师为不断升级的痛苦程度、来电数量、日益加剧的不稳定、或对共情失败的指责而忧心，却可能没有意识到，他们为在治疗中创造安全与调谐所作的英勇尝试，反倒在唤起内隐记忆。那种渴望有人在乎、有人安慰、有人亲近的痛苦的感受记忆，常常唤起一种对接触的饥渴，这种饥渴可能变得具有强迫性，并常被病理化为精神病性移情或情欲性移情。此外，如果治疗师不熟悉结构性解离模型，或被训练成把混乱型依恋的症状诊断为边缘型人格障碍的证据，他们就可能被来访者不断变换的状态和相互冲突的呈现所失调。正常生活自我可能会信任治疗师所提供的安全，可能愿意在治疗中“工作”，几乎不需要安抚。依恋部分会立即、无条件地信任治疗师，但它们对亲近的渴望也会被善意、温暖和关怀所触发，从而产生对越来越多亲近的日益强烈的饥渴。由于极度渴求接触，依恋部分常常在会谈结束时难以离开治疗师的办公室，和／或在两次会面之间寻求“亲近”——通过语音留言、电子邮件或短信。由于这些年幼的部分高度焦虑、惊恐，它们的讯息往往看起来像是危机的信号，治疗师感到有责任去回应。然而，随着时间推移，治疗师可能开始注意到一种模式：无论是大的还是小的压力源，都唤起同样程度的紧迫感；治疗性的安抚随着时间推移不是越来越有效，而是越来越无效；对共情失败的敏感变得更加强烈；危机来电的数量并未随时间减少，甚至可能增加。这是因为这些部分的职责就是“呼救”，也因为它们那渴望接触、害怕被抛弃的内隐记忆，因与依恋对象的亲近而被加剧，而非被安抚。如果治疗师没有意识到，这些部分只是一个原本胜任的成年人的一个方面，或者意识到它们的痛苦代表的是记忆的激活，他或她就可能感到有责任去安抚它们。

One way for therapists to recognize when they are being “inducted into the system” (i.e., have taken responsibility for regulating and soothing a part whose job it is to maintain proximity to potential attachment figures) is to look at whether the treatment is successfully stabilizing the client and expanding the window of tolerance. When, despite the out-of-session support, the client needs more rather than less contact to remain stable, therapists can be quite certain that they have inadvertently been responding to an attach part whose job it is to elicit care, not an adult client needing some temporary support in resolving a crisis while developing more ego strengths and resources.

治疗师辨认自己何时正在“被纳入这个系统”（即，承担起了调节和安抚某个部分的责任，而该部分的职责正是维持与潜在依恋对象的亲近）的一种方法，是看治疗是否在成功地稳定来访者并扩展耐受之窗。当尽管有会谈之外的支持，来访者却需要更多而非更少的接触才能保持稳定时，治疗师就可以相当确定，他们一直在无意中回应一个职责为引出关怀的依恋部分，而不是一个在发展出更多自我力量和资源的同时、需要一些暂时支持来化解危机的成年来访者。

Recontextualizing Disorganized Attachment as an Internal Struggle

将混乱型依恋重新情境化为一场内部斗争

If therapists interpret the disorganized attachment as the expression of a whole integrated client, the symptoms are likely to be understood as a “personality disorder.” Only when the assumption is made that these behaviors represent disorganized attachment associated with structurally dissociated parts can the therapist avoid becoming inducted into the system, whether as rescuer, potential victimizer, or uncaring bystander. Without the conceptual framework of structural dissociation, therapists can easily become confused and frustrated by the alternating appearances of attach parts expressing needs for more proximity and flight or fight parts distancing, controlling, or devaluing the treatment.

如果治疗师把混乱型依恋解读为一个完整、整合的来访者的表达，这些症状就很可能被理解为一种“人格障碍”。只有当我们假定这些行为代表的是与结构性解离的各部分相关联的混乱型依恋时，治疗师才能避免被纳入这个系统——无论是作为拯救者、潜在的施害者，还是冷漠的旁观者。如果没有结构性解离这一概念框架，治疗师很容易被以下情形所困惑和挫败：依恋部分表达对更多亲近的需求，与逃跑或战斗部分疏远、控制或贬低治疗，二者交替出现。

Often early on or as the attach part becomes more vulnerable, the flight part manifests in the therapy as a client expressing ambivalence about the treatment. “I didn’t want to come today,” that part typically announces. “I have nothing to talk about.” “I’m not sure I want to continue.” Flight parts’ instinctual avoidance is likely to be triggered by therapy sessions. When the focus turns to painful emotion, the client might suddenly flee the session, or, just as the therapist feels the treatment is “deepening,” the client’s flight part might suddenly cancel remaining appointments. The attach part or normal life self then is likely to return in a crisis weeks or months later with no memory of why “he” or “she” left the therapy previously. The client’s normal life self might come regularly to each appointment but then, hijacked by the flight part, shut down, become mute, or dissociate. Attempts to process these patterns as if they were those of a whole integrated individual are usually frustrating at best. Therapists often find themselves dismissing such clients as “resistant,” “unmotivated,” or “guarded,” without realizing that they have been stymied by a series of parts whose job it is to distance in relationships, avoid the trauma, and detach emotionally.

常常在早期、或当依恋部分变得更加脆弱时，逃跑部分会在治疗中表现为来访者对治疗表达矛盾心态。“我今天本来不想来，”那个部分通常会宣告。“我没什么可谈的。”“我不确定我想继续下去。”逃跑部分本能的回避很可能被治疗会谈所触发。当焦点转向痛苦的情绪时，来访者可能突然逃离会谈，或者，恰当治疗师感到治疗正在“深入”之际，来访者的逃跑部分可能会突然取消剩下的预约。随后，依恋部分或正常生活自我很可能在几周或几个月后在一场危机中回来，却不记得“他”或“她”之前为什么离开了治疗。来访者的正常生活自我可能按时来赴每一次预约，但随后又被逃跑部分劫持，关闭、变得沉默或解离。试图把这些模式当作一个完整、整合的个体的模式来处理，通常充其量也只会令人挫败。治疗师常常发现自己把这样的来访者打发为“有阻抗的”“缺乏动机的”或“戒备的”，却没有意识到，他们是被一系列部分难住了，而这些部分的职责正是在关系中保持距离、回避创伤、并在情感上抽离。

When attach and flight parts alternate in therapy, the therapist often becomes even more confused and frustrated: for example, the “client” asks to talk on the phone between sessions, sends daily emails and texts, and expresses fears of abandonment, yet at each face-to-face appointment, this same “client” shuts down, cancels at the last minute, or expresses the wish not to have come at all. In this example, there is no one “client”; we are dealing with two different subparts with conflicting wishes and fears. If we tell the client’s flight part that she is not obligated to come if she doesn’t want to, the attach part will feel rejected and pushed away. If we tell the attach part that she seems ambivalent about the therapy, she will feel even more deeply wounded. She would come every day if we just invited her! If we ask the flight part to reflect on the urgent need to talk on the phone Wednesday evening followed by a disinterest in coming to therapy on Thursday, we are most likely to get a shrug of the shoulders as if to say, “I wouldn’t know.”

当依恋部分和逃跑部分在治疗中交替出现时，治疗师常常变得更加困惑和挫败：例如，“来访者”要求在两次会谈之间通电话，每天发送电子邮件和短信，表达对被抛弃的恐惧，然而在每一次面对面的预约中，同一个“来访者”却关闭、在最后一刻取消、或表达根本不愿前来的意愿。在这个例子中，并不存在某一个“来访者”；我们面对的是两个不同的子部分，它们怀有相互冲突的愿望和恐惧。如果我们告诉来访者的逃跑部分，如果她不想来就没有义务来，依恋部分就会感到被拒绝、被推开。如果我们告诉依恋部分，她似乎对治疗心存矛盾，她就会感到伤得更深。只要我们邀请她，她每天都会来！如果我们请逃跑部分反思一下星期三晚上那种通电话的迫切需要、随后星期四又对前来治疗毫无兴趣，我们极有可能得到的是耸一耸肩，仿佛在说，“我哪知道。”

Another manifestation of the flight part is observed in eating disordered or addictive behavior. Rather than distancing externally, eating disorders and substance abuse provide a way of distancing or “fleeing” dysregulated emotions and sensations internally. In the treatment of both addictive behavior and eating disorders, it is helpful for therapists to make a clear distinction between the normal life self, often highly motivated to stay sober or engage in harm reduction, and the flight part, undeterred in its determination to numb or disconnect or facilitate a false temporary window of tolerance. If that differentiation is not made, therapists are likely to find themselves engaging in a struggle in which they become the spokespersons for abstinence, sobriety, and healthy behavior, while the flight part must defend the use of the substance or eating disorder against what feels like an enemy. Rather than engaging in a head-to-head battle with a flight part, it is more useful for the therapist to capitalize on the compartmentalization by working with the normal life self, using its capacity for reflection to increase curiosity about the flight or addict part: what is its intention? What outcome does it want? (See Chapter 7 for more on working with parts and self-destructive behavior.)

逃跑部分的另一种表现可以在进食障碍或成瘾行为中观察到。进食障碍和物质滥用提供的不是向外的疏远，而是一种在内部疏远或“逃离”失调的情绪和感觉的方式。在治疗成瘾行为和进食障碍时，治疗师有必要在以下两者之间作出明确区分：正常生活自我，它往往有着保持清醒或进行减害的强烈动机；以及逃跑部分，它麻木、断开连接、或营造一个虚假而暂时的耐受之窗的决心毫不动摇。如果不作出这种区分，治疗师就很可能发现自己陷入一场斗争，在其中他们成了戒断、清醒和健康行为的代言人，而逃跑部分则必须为使用该物质或维持进食障碍而抵御一个感觉像是敌人的对象。与其和逃跑部分针锋相对地交战，治疗师更有益的做法是利用这种区隔化，与正常生活自我一起工作，借助其反思的能力来增加对逃跑部分或成瘾部分的好奇：它的意图是什么？它想要什么样的结果？（关于与各部分以及自我毁灭行为工作的更多内容，参见第7章。）

Not One but Many Transferences

不是一种而是多种移情

Because the therapist is an attachment trigger for all the parts, it is crucial to be aware of the different transferential relationships each part will tend to develop. Attach needs to feel the therapist is warm, connected, and attuned to its needs for care. Flight needs space and acceptance of its need to keep a distance or to come and go. Fight requires proof that the therapist will not “use” secrets against the client, will not try to use dependency to control the parts, and has no hidden agenda. “Proof” sometimes means that the therapist is subjected to tests of her patience, testing of boundaries, and tests of her ability to hold the treatment frame. Submit just wants to please by complying with whatever the therapist seems to want, often increasing the need for more testing by fight, and freeze just doesn’t want to be hurt. To ensure that the therapy does not become derailed by these traumatic attachment issues, the therapist must be prepared for the issues posed by disorganized attachment and assume that the work will include negotiating multiple transferential relationships.

由于治疗师对所有部分而言都是一个依恋触发因素，意识到每个部分往往会发展出的不同移情关系至关重要。依恋部分需要感到治疗师是温暖的、有连接的、并且调谐于它对关怀的需求。逃跑部分需要空间，需要它保持距离或来去自如的需求被接纳。战斗部分则要求得到证明：治疗师不会“利用”秘密来对付来访者，不会试图利用依赖来控制各部分，并且没有隐藏的图谋。“证明”有时意味着治疗师要经受对她耐心的考验、对边界的试探，以及对她稳住治疗框架之能力的考验。顺从部分只想通过顺从治疗师似乎想要的一切来取悦对方，这常常增加战斗部分进行更多试探的需要，而冻结部分则只是不想受到伤害。为了确保治疗不致因这些创伤性依恋议题而脱轨，治疗师必须为混乱型依恋所带来的问题做好准备，并假定这项工作将包括对多重移情关系的协商。

Recognizing the Transference of Parts

识别各部分的移情

If disorganized attachment reflects the relationship between a proximity-seeking attach part and a hypervigilant, protective fight part, then other parts with similar goals will be active in the treatment and supportive of one or the other side. Although the submit part can appear as the “identified patient,” referred for chronic depression, issues of shame, or an inability to set limits and boundaries, the submit part also frequently serves the needs and goals of the attach part by trying to please those whose connection the attach part seeks, avoid displeasing potential attachment figures, and ensure that the demands of the attach part do not overwhelm the therapist.

如果混乱型依恋反映的是一个寻求亲近的依恋部分与一个高度警觉、起保护作用的战斗部分之间的关系，那么其他怀有相似目标的部分也会在治疗中活跃起来，支持其中一方或另一方。尽管顺从部分可能以“被指认的病人”的身份出现，因慢性抑郁、羞耻议题、或无力设立限度和边界而被转介，但顺从部分也常常服务于依恋部分的需求和目标，它会努力去取悦那些依恋部分想要与之连接的人，避免惹潜在依恋对象不快，并确保依恋部分的索求不致压垮治疗师。

In some clients, the submit part may be more burdened and submissive and, in others, more compliant and pleasing. The submit part might even strive to be the best client the therapist has yet encountered so as to increase the positive feelings the attach part craves. But, when the “good client” is actually a submit part, somehow the progress we would expect from a client with this level of intelligence, functioning, and willingness to engage does not happen. Instead, the client takes one step forward and one back, appears to make progress but then mysteriously is back to wherever he or she started. The willingness to do whatever the therapist asks does not lead to integration of new information or new skills. It is as if we have been conducting the treatment with a child who listens and acts as if she understands but lacks the cortical functioning that would enable the information to be useful. Or, because submission as survival response is dependent upon parasympathetic dominance, the submit part has no access to energy for change and no influence on the other fragmented selves of the client.

在一些来访者身上，顺从部分可能更为负重和屈从，而在另一些来访者身上，则更为顺从和讨好。顺从部分甚至可能竭力成为治疗师迄今所遇到的最好的来访者，以增加依恋部分所渴求的积极感受。但是，当这个“好来访者”实际上是一个顺从部分时，不知何故，我们本应从一个具有这种智力、功能水平和参与意愿的来访者身上期待的进展却没有发生。相反，来访者前进一步又后退一步，看似取得进展，随后却又神秘地回到了他或她出发的地方。愿意去做治疗师所要求的任何事，并不会导向对新信息或新技能的整合。这就好像我们一直在与一个孩子进行治疗，她倾听着、行动着，仿佛她听懂了，却缺乏能让这些信息派上用场的皮层功能。又或者，由于作为生存反应的顺从依赖于副交感神经的主导，顺从部分无法获取用于改变的能量，对来访者其他碎裂的诸自我也毫无影响力。

Key indicators that a theme is being expressed by a part is the degree of rigidity associated with it: parts are likely to see the world as black or white, have difficulty comprehending new information or widening their perspective to take in multiple points of view. If therapists find themselves engaged in a struggle with clients or “resisting their resistance,” that is often a sign that they are in dialogue with one part of the client, not the larger consciousness of a normal life self. If the therapist responds to submit by saying, “That’s interesting—so there’s a belief inside that ‘nice people don’t say No’—no wonder that’s such a hard word to say,” the submit part is likely to reply: “Well, that’s true.” This response is very different from what we might hear from a going on with normal life self who, despite being avoidant of overwhelming emotions or unsure if his or her childhood experience really qualifies as “traumatic,” is likely to be more curious about the therapist’s point of view: “Really, you mean other people have that experience, too?”

表明某个主题正由一个部分所表达的关键指标，是与之相关的僵化程度：各部分很可能把世界看成非黑即白，难以理解新信息，或难以拓宽自己的视角去容纳多种观点。如果治疗师发现自己陷入了与来访者的较量，或在“抵抗他们的阻抗”，这往往是一个迹象，表明他们正在与来访者的某一个部分对话，而非与正常生活自我那更广阔的意识对话。如果治疗师回应顺从部分说：“这很有意思——所以内心里有一个信念是‘好人不会说不’——难怪这个字这么难说出口，”顺从部分很可能会回答：“嗯，确实如此。”这种回应与我们可能从一个正常生活自我那里听到的非常不同——后者尽管会回避压倒性的情绪，或不确定他或她童年的经历是否真的够得上“创伤性”，却很可能对治疗师的观点更为好奇：“真的吗，你是说别人也有这种经历？”

Creating an Alliance with the Fight Part

与战斗部分建立联盟

If disorganized attachment reflects an internal conflict between proximity-seeking drives and fight/flight responses, then the transferential relationship with the fight part will inevitably become an important focus of the therapy. First of all, fight parts are generally the most hypervigilant and wary of attachment, least likely to trust therapists or the process of therapy, especially to the extent that the treatment focuses on the client’s vulnerabilities: on disclosing secrets, sharing deeply personal information, connecting to expressing strong emotions. Often, the presence of the fight part is felt subtly and indirectly: for example, in how much the client is comfortable sharing about his or her history or even daily life, in questions put to the therapist about office policies (especially around confidentiality, fees, and boundaries), or when the client starts to say something and then stops in mid-sentence, unable to recall what he or she wanted to say. We might also encounter indicators of an active fight part in the client’s history: a previous therapy that ended “badly”; friendships that were dropped after recurrent conflicts; difficulties at work due to interpersonal struggles or confrontations; breakups in relationship. Or we might see the fight part play an active role in the treatment. When therapists “fail the client empathically,” for example, they are informed of their failure by a fight part activated by the hurt feelings of young parts. “Empathic failure” generally describes a choice of words or actions that has disappointed or hurt the client’s feelings—or, more accurately, the feelings of the attach part. Most of the time, these moments of “empathic failure” occur because the therapist is speaking to someone perceived to be an integrated adult, not realizing that the client is blended with a needy, lonely, sad, or ashamed child part. If spoken to an adult, the words or tone used may have been harmless or even compassionate, but spoken to a child part with urgent hopes for care or rescue, the words are deeply hurtful. For example, the therapist might raise a billing issue or a change in appointment time, announcement of a vacation or change in policy. Spoken matter-of-factly to a 40- or 50-year-old adult, the words, “I need to talk to you about billing issues” or “about my vacation,” are simply information, but they feel cold or cruel to the child part. Rarely is the resulting empathic failure brought to our attention by that child part, though. Our clients do not generally look confused, hurt, or wounded, much less burst into tears, which would alert the therapist to the inadvertent rupture. Instead, therapists hear about these empathic failures from an indignant, angry, or even outraged fight part, making it more difficult for the therapist to understand much less empathize with what has happened. The vulnerability of the child part is vehemently defended by the fight part, but, unable to “see” the little part, the therapist feels put on the defensive, distanced or disrespected by an angry, indignant client—the very opposite of the attach part’s needs and wishes. We are inducted into the disorganized attachment “system,” feeling badly for having hurt the client but also defensive in the face of being criticized, devalued, and found wanting. Without the realization that an “empathic failure” represents the inadvertent wounding of a child part coupled with the defensive efforts of an angry part seeking restitution or protection of the little parts’ vulnerability, the therapist’s efforts at “repair” may also be misattuned.

如果混乱型依恋反映的是寻求亲近的驱力与战斗／逃跑反应之间的一种内部冲突，那么与战斗部分的移情关系将不可避免地成为治疗的一个重要焦点。首先，战斗部分通常是最为高度警觉、最为提防依恋的，最不可能信任治疗师或治疗的过程，尤其是当治疗聚焦于来访者的脆弱时：聚焦于吐露秘密、分享极为私人的信息、连接并表达强烈的情绪。战斗部分的存在往往是以微妙而间接的方式被感受到的：例如，来访者在分享他或她的历史、乃至日常生活时感到自在的程度，向治疗师提出的关于办公室规定的问题（尤其是围绕保密、费用和边界），或者当来访者开始说某句话、却又中途停下，想不起来他或她原本想说什么。我们也可能在来访者的历史中遇到一个活跃的战斗部分的指标：一段“糟糕”收场的既往治疗；在反复冲突后中断的友谊；因人际较量或对抗而在工作中遇到的困难；关系中的分手。或者我们可能看到战斗部分在治疗中扮演一个积极的角色。例如，当治疗师“在共情上辜负了来访者”时，他们是被一个由年幼部分受伤感受所激活的战斗部分告知自己的失误的。“共情失败”通常描述的是一种用词或行动的选择，它令来访者失望或伤害了来访者的感受——或者更确切地说，是依恋部分的感受。大多数时候，这些“共情失败”的时刻之所以发生，是因为治疗师所对话的对象被知觉为一个整合的成年人，而没有意识到来访者正与一个有需求的、孤独的、悲伤的或羞耻的孩子部分相融合。如果是对一个成年人说的，所用的词语或语气可能是无害的、甚至是充满慈悲的，但若是对一个迫切盼望关怀或拯救的孩子部分说的，这些话就深深伤人。例如，治疗师可能提出一个账单问题，或预约时间的变动，或宣布休假或规定的变更。以就事论事的口吻对一个四五十岁的成年人说，“我需要和你谈谈账单问题”或“谈谈我休假的事”，这些话不过是信息而已，但对孩子部分而言却感觉冷漠或残忍。然而，由此产生的共情失败很少会被那个孩子部分提请我们注意。我们的来访者通常不会显得困惑、受伤或受创，更不会突然哭起来——那本可以提醒治疗师注意到这一无意间造成的破裂。相反，治疗师是从一个愤慨的、愤怒的、甚至暴怒的战斗部分那里听说这些共情失败的，这使治疗师更难理解、更遑论共情所发生的事。孩子部分的脆弱被战斗部分激烈地捍卫着，但由于无法“看见”那个小部分，治疗师感到自己被一个愤怒、愤慨的来访者置于守势、被疏远或不被尊重——这恰恰与依恋部分的需求和愿望相反。我们被纳入了混乱型依恋“系统”，既为伤害了来访者而感到难过，又在被批评、被贬低、被认为有所欠缺时心生防卫。如果没有意识到，一次“共情失败”代表的是孩子部分被无意间弄伤，再加上一个愤怒部分为寻求补偿或保护小部分脆弱而作出的防御性努力，治疗师“修复”的努力也可能是调谐失当的。

Another manifestation of disorganized attachment can be a preoccupation with suicide, a tendency to self-harm, or a tendency toward promiscuous or unsafe sexual behavior. Suicidality and self-harm always reflect the role of the fight part because of its unique capacity for aggression. No other part has the physical strength and violent impulses that accompany the animal defense of fight. Submit may dream of going to sleep and never waking up; flight may wish to escape intense emotions, but neither has the physical ability to end life or harm the body. (See Chapter 7 for a more extensive discussion of treating suicidal and self-destructive behavior as manifestations of parts.)

混乱型依恋的另一种表现可以是对自杀的全神贯注、自我伤害的倾向，或者放纵或不安全性行为的倾向。自杀倾向和自我伤害总是反映着战斗部分的角色，因为它具有独特的攻击能力。没有任何其他部分拥有伴随战斗这一动物性防御而来的体力和暴力冲动。顺从部分可能梦想着睡去、再也不醒来；逃跑部分可能希望逃离强烈的情绪，但二者都不具备结束生命或伤害身体的身体能力。（关于把自杀和自我毁灭行为作为各部分的表现来治疗的更广泛讨论，参见第7章。）

What most often triggers suicidal and self-injuring parts are empathic failures, losses, painful loneliness—anything that reopens the emotional wounds of the attach part. Other common precipitants are intrusive memories or flashbacks, both of which can be linked to the attach parts’ cry for help and both of which increase feelings of vulnerability and shame.

最常触发自杀部分和自伤部分的，是共情失败、丧失、痛苦的孤独——任何重新揭开依恋部分情感创伤的东西。其他常见的诱发因素是侵入性记忆或闪回，二者都可以与依恋部分的呼救相关联，也都会增加脆弱和羞耻的感受。

Vulnerability is the enemy of the fight part. At age one, three, six, even ten, there is little a fight part can do to defend against those on whom the child depends. In adulthood, any situation in which dependency and/or vulnerability are stimulated is likely to activate the fight part. That means that any therapy that appears to emphasize the creation of dependency or encourage vulnerability is likely to be highly threatening to those parts. Although most therapists would rightly insist that evoking vulnerability or dependency is not their conscious goal, we have to remember two things: first, that the fight part is hypervigilant and focused narrowly on threat. Even as normal a stimulus as the box of tissues sitting in the therapist’s coffee table is a danger signal to the fight part. Secondly, most therapists do encourage self-disclosure, expression of feelings, and learning to ask for and receive support—all of which can be misconstrued as the encouragement of vulnerability—especially when the attach part is eagerly awaiting a sign that dependency will be welcomed by the therapist and the fight part is on guard against exactly that danger.

脆弱是战斗部分的敌人。在一岁、三岁、六岁、乃至十岁时，面对孩子所依赖的那些人，战斗部分几乎无能为力去防御。在成年期，任何会激起依赖和／或脆弱的情境都很可能激活战斗部分。这意味着，任何看起来强调制造依赖或鼓励脆弱的治疗，都很可能对那些部分构成高度威胁。尽管大多数治疗师会理直气壮地坚称，唤起脆弱或依赖并非他们有意识的目标，我们却必须记住两件事：第一，战斗部分高度警觉，狭隘地专注于威胁。即便是像放在治疗师茶几上的那盒纸巾这般寻常的刺激，对战斗部分而言也是一个危险信号。第二，大多数治疗师确实会鼓励自我吐露、情绪的表达、以及学习去寻求和接受支持——所有这些都可能被误解为对脆弱的鼓励——尤其是当依恋部分正热切地等待一个治疗师将欢迎依赖的信号、而战斗部分恰恰提防着那种危险时。

There is No “He” or “She”

没有“他”或“她”

Often, therapists are understandably confused by the relationship between the fight and attach parts. At the start of therapy they may encounter a “client” who is closed, counterdependent, guarded, and reluctant to disclose his or her secrets. Not realizing that they have encountered a part of the client, not an integrated whole, they encourage reaching out and asking for support—or they reach out to the client, believing that the gesture will reduce shame or fear. But beneath the militant counterdependence of the fight part, there is always an attach part whose longing and hurt are being defended, who is being “protected” by the avoidance of dependence. When the therapist attempts to help the counterdependent client or part “open up,” the attach part is inevitably activated by the reaching out, resulting in a client who, in the therapist’s mind, is now still counterdependent at times but can also be extremely dependent and easily wounded. The attach part’s implicit memories and unmet yearning for connection have been stimulated, and both feel emotionally unbearable. The fight part’s distrust of connection has been equally heightened.

治疗师常常被战斗部分与依恋部分之间的关系所困惑，这是可以理解的。在治疗伊始，他们可能遇到一个封闭的、反依赖的、戒备的、不愿吐露自己秘密的“来访者”。没有意识到他们所遇到的是来访者的一个部分、而非一个整合的整体，他们便鼓励对方伸出手去、寻求支持——或者他们主动向来访者伸出手去，相信这一举动会减轻羞耻或恐惧。但在战斗部分那好斗的反依赖之下，总有一个依恋部分，它的渴望与伤痛正在被防御着，它正通过回避依赖而被“保护”着。当治疗师试图帮助这个反依赖的来访者或部分“敞开”时，依恋部分不可避免地被这一伸手之举所激活，结果是，在治疗师心目中，这个来访者如今时而仍然反依赖，时而又可能极度依赖、极易受伤。依恋部分的内隐记忆以及那未被满足的对连接的渴望都被激起，二者在情感上都让人无法承受。与此同时，战斗部分对连接的不信任也被同等地强化了。

When the therapist does not continue to reach out, believing that the client has successfully softened the counterdependence, the attach part’s separation anxiety intensifies, and fight must go to its defense. If the therapist continues to reach out, concerned about triggering shame or fears of abandonment, the attach part’s hunger for connection continues to be triggered, causing more distress and often the need for more and more contact. The more frequent the contact, the greater the fight part’s sense of threat. To make matters worse, as the fight part pushes the therapist away or uses harm to the body to regulate unbearable emotions, the attach part is likely to feel more vulnerability instead of less, increasing demands for contact and further activating the fight part. Many therapists notice that as the need for contact intensifies and they try to meet the demand, they increasingly are accused of empathic failure: “I was suicidal, and you could only stay on the phone for 5 minutes?!” “You really think ‘a few minutes’ is enough when I’m in this living hell?” It is helpful to remember at those moments that the client’s parts are re-enacting their early experience of disorganized attachment: caught up in a painful, wrenching struggle between the implicitly remembered need of little parts for more care and the implicit distrust connected to the dangers of neediness when attachment figures are abusive.

当治疗师认为来访者已成功软化了反依赖、因而不再继续伸出手去时，依恋部分的分离焦虑就会加剧，而战斗部分必须挺身去捍卫它。如果治疗师出于对触发羞耻或被抛弃恐惧的顾虑而继续伸出手去，依恋部分对连接的饥渴就会持续被触发，造成更多的痛苦，并常常需要越来越多的接触。接触越频繁，战斗部分的威胁感就越强。更糟糕的是，当战斗部分把治疗师推开、或用伤害身体的方式来调节无法承受的情绪时，依恋部分很可能感到的不是更少而是更多的脆弱，从而加大对接触的索求，并进一步激活战斗部分。许多治疗师注意到，随着对接触的需要加剧、而他们试图去满足这种需求时，他们越来越多地被指责共情失败：“我都想自杀了，你却只能在电话里待5分钟？！”“你真觉得当我身处这活生生的地狱里时，‘几分钟’就够了吗？”在那些时刻，记住以下这点会有所帮助：来访者的各部分正在重演他们早期的混乱型依恋体验——被困在一场痛苦的、撕扯人心的斗争之中，一边是小部分被内隐地记住的、对更多关怀的需要，另一边是与依恋对象施虐时有所需求之危险相关联的内隐不信任。

Diagnostically, the client with disorganized attachment is increasingly likely to fulfill criteria for borderline personality disorder, and if diagnosed as such, may be judged “attention-seeking” and “manipulative.” The role of the trauma and traumatized parts is likely to go unrecognized and untreated; the manifestations of disorganized attachment will be confused with personality disorder symptoms. The worst fears of the going on with normal life self will also be realized: he or she is getting worse in therapy, not better. As with addicted and eating disordered flight parts, it is easy for therapists to become engaged in a struggle with self-destructive or suicidal fight parts centered on safety and risk management issues and to lose the opportunity to help clients use their normal life selves to work with parts bent on ending life rather than being rendered vulnerable. (See Chapter 7 for more information on how to manage issues of safety.)

从诊断上看，具有混乱型依恋的来访者越来越可能符合边缘型人格障碍的标准，而一旦被如此诊断，可能就会被判定为“寻求关注”和“爱操纵”。创伤以及受创伤部分的作用很可能得不到识别、也得不到治疗；混乱型依恋的种种表现将与人格障碍的症状混为一谈。正常生活自我最深的恐惧也将成为现实：他或她在治疗中变得更糟，而非更好。正如对待成瘾的和进食障碍的逃跑部分一样，治疗师很容易卷入一场围绕安全与风险管理议题、与自我毁灭或自杀的战斗部分进行的较量之中，并因此失去帮助来访者运用其正常生活自我去与那些一心要结束生命、而非让自己变得脆弱的部分工作的机会。（关于如何处理安全议题的更多信息，参见第7章。）

A Therapist for All the Parts, Not Just for the “Client”

做所有部分的治疗师，而不只是“来访者”的治疗师

Most therapists take on a single client, not a motley collection of parts sharing a common body. But since structural dissociation and splitting is statistically likely in the context of trauma, therapists should assume that by taking on any traumatized client, they may be taking on his or her parts, too. That means that the therapist must listen, speak, and conduct the treatment somewhat differently than he or she otherwise would in treating more integrated clients whose early lives did not require splitting and self-alienation. As the therapist meets the client for the first time, hears the presenting issues and takes a history, he or she should already be attuned to the trauma-related themes likely to be echoed by different parts: painful loneliness and the need for connection, despair and self-defeating beliefs, fear and avoidance of being seen, addictions and eating disorders, the impact on relationships of problems with anger and hypervigilance.

大多数治疗师接手的是单一的一个来访者，而非一群共享同一具身体的、形形色色的部分的集合。但既然从统计上看，结构性解离和分裂在创伤情境中很可能发生，治疗师就应当假定，他们接手任何一个受创伤的来访者，也可能就是在接手他或她的各个部分。这意味着，治疗师在倾听、说话和开展治疗时，必须与他或她在治疗那些更为整合、早年生活并不需要分裂和自我疏离的来访者时有所不同。当治疗师初次会见来访者、听取主诉议题并采集病史时，他或她就应当已经调谐于那些很可能被不同部分所回响的、与创伤相关的主题：痛苦的孤独与对连接的需要，绝望与自我挫败的信念，对被看见的恐惧与回避，成瘾与进食障碍，以及愤怒和过度警觉的问题对关系的影响。

Listening for the “Voices” of the Parts

倾听各部分的“声音”

Encouraging curiosity, providing psychoeducation about trauma and trauma treatment, mindful noticing of patterns and themes, and an introduction to the language of triggering are all important even in a first or intake visit. Even as we are gathering information from a new client, therapists should be listening intently for the “voices” of the different parts and also for signs of a normal life self: a home, career or job, relationships, interests, some areas of stability, and, most importantly, a functioning prefrontal cortex and the capacity to observe what happens moment to moment. The trauma-informed therapist is also alert for signs of dysregulation either visible in the session or reported by the client (“I just shut down,” “I had to leave,” “I just starting screaming”). Until the therapist is certain that the client has an adequate window of tolerance and equally sure there is an observing self that can relate to intense feelings (i.e., stay connected to the emotions without dissociating or becoming dysregulated), he or she does not pull for emotions (the landscape of the parts), only for an awareness of their different “voices.” How clients regulate whatever emotions come up spontaneously tells the therapist more about the extent of their windows of tolerance. Aware that traumatic events are past events that intrude on the present when triggered by reminders of the past, the therapist introduces the language of triggering early in treatment—along with the language of parts.

鼓励好奇，提供关于创伤及创伤治疗的心理教育，以正念注意各种模式和主题，以及引入触发的语言，即便在初次或接案访谈中也都很重要。即便我们正在从一位新来访者那里收集信息，治疗师也应当全神贯注地倾听不同部分的“声音”，同时倾听正常生活自我的迹象：一个家，事业或工作，各种关系，兴趣，某些稳定的领域，以及最重要的，一个运作中的前额叶皮层，和观察时时刻刻所发生之事的能力。具备创伤知情视角的治疗师也对失调的迹象保持警觉，无论这些迹象是在会谈中可见的，还是由来访者报告的（“我整个人就关闭了”，“我不得不离开”，“我就开始尖叫起来”）。在治疗师确定来访者拥有一个充分的耐受之窗、并同样确定存在一个能够与强烈感受建立关系的观察性自我（即，在不解离、不失调的情况下与情绪保持连接）之前，他或她不去引出情绪（各部分的景观），而只去引出对它们不同“声音”的觉察。来访者如何调节任何自发涌现的情绪，会更多地告诉治疗师有关他们耐受之窗范围的信息。治疗师意识到，创伤事件是过去的事件，当被过去的提示物所触发时，它们会侵入当下，于是便在治疗早期引入触发的语言——连同各部分的语言。

Mark came to his first session with a paradoxical issue: his rich, satisfying life after trauma was missing one ingredient, a partner or spouse. “I’ve never fallen in love, never had a relationship that lasted more than 6 months—but on the other hand, I don’t really see the need for one in my day to day life. I’m here just in case I might be missing something.” The therapist replied, “So there’s a part of you that has made sure you never fall in love, and another part that wonders if, someday, that will feel like a loss. Could we be curious about both of them?”

Mark带着一个自相矛盾的议题来到他的第一次会谈：他创伤之后那丰富、令人满意的生活缺少了一样东西——一个伴侣或配偶。“我从未坠入爱河，从未有过一段持续超过6个月的关系——但另一方面，我在日复一日的生活里并不真的觉得需要一个。我来这里只是以防万一我可能正错过着什么。”治疗师回答道：“所以你有一个部分确保了你从不坠入爱河，还有另一个部分在想，会不会有一天，那将让你感觉像是一种损失。我们能对它们俩都保持好奇吗？”

Jacqueline told her therapist: “I’m here because I have a long history of trauma. Do you want me to tell you all of the things that have happened?”
“Not unless there is something special that you want me to know—I’m really more curious about how the trauma has stayed with you, how it’s still affecting your life day to day.”
“It’s ruined my life …”
“Is it still ruining your life? What triggers it?”
She describes a pattern of many years: each time she has built a stable, satisfying relational and work life, she’s found herself precipitously fleeing it to take care of one or another member of her family of origin, thereby losing everything she had built for herself.
I respond, “So, there is a very strong—very, very strong—going on with normal life part of you that keeps on rebuilding your life, no matter what, and then there’s a very self-sacrificing part that feels compelled to give it all up to take care of your family, even those members who abused you as a child. Could we be curious about that pattern?”

Jacqueline告诉她的治疗师：“我来这里是因为我有很长的创伤史。你想让我把所发生过的所有事情都告诉你吗？”
“除非有什么特别的事情你想让我知道——其实我更好奇的是创伤如何一直伴随着你，它如今又如何仍在日复一日地影响你的生活。”
“它毁了我的生活……”
“它现在还在毁掉你的生活吗？是什么触发了它？”
她描述了一种持续多年的模式：每一次她建立起稳定、令人满意的关系生活和工作生活，她都发现自己仓促地从中逃离，去照顾她原生家庭中的某一位成员，从而失去了她为自己所建立起来的一切。
我回应道：“所以，你有一个非常强大——非常、非常强大——的正常生活部分，它无论如何都不断地重建你的生活，然后还有一个极其自我牺牲的部分，它感到被迫要放弃这一切去照顾你的家人，甚至是那些在你儿时虐待过你的成员。我们能对那种模式保持好奇吗？”

ME: “What did you do?”

我：“你当时是做什么的？”

CLIENT: “I was a family medicine doctor—I loved it, but I couldn’t handle the stress, especially after I stopped being able to drive.”

来访者：“我曾是一名家庭医学医生——我热爱它，但我应付不了那种压力，尤其是在我没法再开车之后。”

ME: [Curious about any loss of normal life functioning] “You stopped being able to drive? What happened that made it no longer possible to drive?”

我：〔对任何正常生活功能的丧失感到好奇〕“你没法再开车了？发生了什么，使得开车不再可能？”

CLIENT: “I would start to go somewhere, and I’d suddenly forget where I was going or how to drive the car. I would panic! Then I’d have to call my secretary and tell her to come get me. I couldn’t do it by myself.”

来访者：“我会动身要去某个地方，然后突然忘了我要去哪儿、或者怎么开车。我会惊恐发作！然后我不得不打电话给我的秘书，叫她来接我。我自己一个人做不到。”

ME: “It seems that driving and going to work and having a normal life must have been very threatening to your traumatized parts—they panicked, and you didn’t know it was them—you thought it was you. How sad …”

我：“看起来，开车、去上班和过上正常生活，对你那些受创伤的部分而言一定是非常具有威胁性的——它们惊恐起来，而你却不知道那是它们——你以为那是你自己。多么悲伤啊……”

“I used to be able to function, but I haven’t for a while now,” Robert disclosed.

“我以前是能够正常运作的，但已经有一阵子不行了，”Robert吐露道。

These three clients included a doctor, a therapist, and a teacher—all ideal candidates for therapy—all of whom reported symptoms that were paradoxical in some way. Putting aside what might be viewed as the “bigger” issue of the client’s trauma history, I habitually listen for the subtle indicators of losses of functioning, internal conflicts, self-sabotage, and paradoxical behavior. In addition, I am not thinking of parts as tied to the clients’ histories—I listen for how the parts’ implicit memories are being triggered in the client’s current life. Are they being triggered by the client’s determination to live a normal life after trauma? By the client’s exposure to certain kinds of trauma-related triggers (e.g., a boss who is controlling and critical, a child at an age at which the client was traumatized, family members connected to the perpetrator)? Or I am listening for some life event that is likely to stir up earlier trauma, such as a loss, betrayal or recent traumatic event, or even a happy life transition (engagement, marriage, birth of a child, promotion or graduation). Is there a pattern in the client’s life that might be telling a story of unresolved trauma being re-enacted at an implicit level?

这三位来访者包括一名医生、一名治疗师和一名教师——全都是理想的治疗对象——他们全都报告了在某种意义上自相矛盾的症状。把可能被视为来访者创伤史这一“更大”议题搁在一边，我习惯于倾听那些功能丧失、内部冲突、自我破坏和矛盾行为的微妙指标。此外，我并不把各部分想成是与来访者的历史绑定在一起的——我倾听的是各部分的内隐记忆如何在来访者当前的生活中被触发。它们是否正被来访者创伤之后过上正常生活的决心所触发？是否被来访者暴露于某些与创伤相关的触发因素所触发（例如，一个爱控制、爱批评的上司，一个正处于来访者受创伤时之年龄的孩子，与加害者相关联的家庭成员）？又或者，我在倾听某个很可能搅动起早先创伤的生活事件，比如一次丧失、背叛或近期的创伤事件，乃至一次愉快的人生转变（订婚、结婚、孩子的出生、晋升或毕业）。来访者的生活中是否有一种模式，可能正讲述着一个在内隐层面被重演的、未解决之创伤的故事？

Becoming the therapist for all the parts begins with listening for their chorus of voices and themes, beginning to name the themes and the parts as they are heard, and evoking the client’s curiosity about what has been happening. Most clients come to therapy with a feeling of confusion, desperation, unbearable pain, and unspoken fears that they are losing their minds. Although they may have created a story to explain their bewildering symptoms, the first few visits mark the point in time when they are often most open to hearing a new perspective that reassures them they are not crazy or defective. As I tell them a different story, one that makes sense of what they have been experiencing, often the relief is palpable.

成为所有部分的治疗师，始于倾听它们那合唱般的声音和主题，始于在听到它们时开始为这些主题和部分命名，并唤起来访者对一直在发生之事的好奇。大多数来访者带着一种困惑、绝望、无法承受的痛苦，以及不曾说出口的、担心自己正在失去理智的恐惧来到治疗中。尽管他们可能已经编造出一个故事来解释自己那些令人迷惑的症状，但最初的几次来访恰恰标志着这样一个时间点：他们往往最愿意去听一种新的视角，这种视角让他们安心，告诉他们自己并非疯了或有缺陷。当我向他们讲述一个不同的故事、一个能够说明他们一直以来所经历之事的故事时，那种解脱常常清晰可感。

TO MARK, I SAID: “I get it, and you will, too! After what happened to you as a kid, some part of you inside you made a vow that he would never, ever, ever, ever let someone hurt him again. He’s just trying to protect himself and you—even now.”

我对Mark说：“我懂，而你也会懂的！在你儿时所遭遇的事情之后，你内心里的某个部分立下了誓言，发誓他绝不、绝不、绝不、绝不会再让任何人伤害他。他只是在努力保护他自己和你——即便是现在。”

TO JACQUELINE: “Of course, that young girl who survived by taking care of her parents and her brothers and sisters, would feel no right to a life of her own—maybe having a life actually made her feel guilty and ashamed rather than safe and stable.”

对Jacqueline：“当然了，那个靠照顾父母和兄弟姐妹而存活下来的小女孩，会觉得自己没有权利拥有属于自己的生活——也许拥有一种生活实际上让她感到内疚和羞耻，而非安全和稳定。”

TO ROBERT: “It makes so much sense: you created a very rich, challenging grownup life as a husband, father, and medical professional. You were being recognized in your community. That probably scared the parts so much that they couldn’t let it keep happening—they felt exposed and in danger. They had to stop you, and they succeeded.”

对Robert：“这太说得通了：你作为丈夫、父亲和医疗专业人员，创造了一种非常丰富、富有挑战的成年生活。你在你的社区里受到认可。那很可能把那些部分吓坏了，以至于它们无法让这种情形继续下去——它们感到自己暴露在外、身处危险之中。它们不得不阻止你，而它们成功了。”

Speaking on Behalf of the Parts

代表各部分发声

It is common for clients to have difficulty sustaining access to the going on with normal life self, difficulty feeling empathy for their parts, difficulty maintaining access to the prefrontal cortex, even retaining their initial curiosity about this new way of thinking. Because the language of “I” is an automatic “default setting” for most of us, our procedurally learned tendency when we feel something is to say, “I feel this way.” It takes repetition and practice to use the words, “a part of me feels this way,” as comfortably or automatically. Often, the therapist feels discouraged by the slow pace or begins to question if the approach is helpful, but it is important to remember that we are changing a kind of learning that is meant to be indelible. Human beings never forget procedural learning: how to shake hands, how to drive a car, how to pick up a knife and fork, and we never lose the tendency to say “I.” Learning to use the word “part” instead of “I,” remembering to think in parts language, listening for their different voices: all of these skills take the same kind of practice involved in learning a foreign language.

来访者常常难以持续地接触到正常生活自我，难以对自己的各部分感到共情，难以维持对前额叶皮层的接触，甚至难以保住他们对这种新的思考方式最初的好奇。由于“我”的语言对我们大多数人来说是一种自动的“默认设置”，当我们感受到某种东西时，我们那程序性习得的倾向就是说，“我有这样的感受。”要把“我的一个部分有这样的感受”这句话说得同样自在或同样自动，需要反复的重复和练习。治疗师常常会因进展缓慢而感到气馁，或开始质疑这种方法是否有帮助，但重要的是要记住，我们正在改变的是一种本应不可磨灭的学习。人类永远不会忘记程序性学习：如何握手，如何开车，如何拿起刀叉，而我们也永远不会失去说“我”的倾向。学习用“部分”这个词来代替“我”，记得用各部分的语言去思考，倾听它们不同的声音：所有这些技能都需要与学习一门外语所涉及的同一种练习。

Practice can come in many forms:

练习可以有许多种形式：

As a “practice” that reminds the client that all distressing emotions, thoughts, and life problems reflect communications from parts, I can include the language of parts in my opening greeting to the client: “How have the parts been this week? How did the week go for them?”

作为一种提醒来访者所有令人痛苦的情绪、想法和生活问题都反映着来自各部分之沟通的“练习”，我可以在向来访者打招呼的开场白中纳入各部分的语言：“这周各部分过得怎么样？这一周对它们来说如何？”

To interrupt and inhibit the automatic assumption of “I,” I can repeatedly remind clients of the multiple points of view inside: “Which ‘I’ feels that way? And is there any ‘I’ who feels differently?”

为了打断并抑制对“我”的自动假定，我可以反复提醒来访者内心里的多重视角：“是哪一个‘我’有那种感受？而有没有哪个‘我’有不同的感受？”

I can reiterate the psychoeducation on structural dissociation: “Let me remind you about the structural dissociation model … Which part would have been most likely to be shamed by that experience? Yes, it would be submit—she always assumes it’s her fault. And how did the fight part react to the same criticism? Very differently, huh?”

我可以重申关于结构性解离的心理教育：“让我提醒你一下结构性解离模型……哪个部分最有可能因那段经历而感到羞耻？对，会是顺从部分——她总是认定那是她的错。那么战斗部分对同样的批评又作何反应？非常不一样，是吧？”

I can mirror what has just been said, reflecting the client’s words while simultaneously translating them into parts language: “So, there’s a part of you that feels very ashamed and unsure of himself today …”

我可以映照刚刚所说的话，在反映来访者言语的同时，把它们翻译成各部分的语言：“所以，你有一个部分今天感到非常羞耻、对自己很没把握……”

To which the client might reply, “Yes, I almost cancelled because I didn’t want to face you.”

对此，来访者可能会回答：“是的，我差点取消了，因为我不想面对你。”

ME: “Hmmm … So interesting … That part didn’t want to face me. Who was he afraid I would be? How was he afraid I would act?”

我：“嗯……真有意思……那个部分不想面对我。他害怕我会是谁？他害怕我会怎么做？”

Often, the client immediately free-associates to someone by whom he or she was once shamed or intimidated: “He’s afraid you’ll look down on him like all those teachers did because his clothes don’t match and they’re dirty and torn.”

来访者常常会立即自由联想到某个曾经羞辱或恐吓过他或她的人：“他害怕你会像所有那些老师一样看不起他，因为他的衣服不搭配，又脏又破。”

Here, the therapist must bring the normal life self’s attention to the words and meaning just expressed by the child part to ensure that they are being heard. Using a mindful “contact statement” (Ogden & Fisher, 2015), the therapist repeats, “Yes, he’s afraid I’ll look down on him just like all those teachers did. He thinks I’ll see that his clothes are torn and don’t match, and I’ll think he’s no good.”

在这里，治疗师必须把正常生活自我的注意力引向孩子部分刚刚所表达的言语和意义，以确保它们被听见。运用一句正念的“接触陈述”（Ogden和Fisher，2015），治疗师复述道：“是的，他害怕我会像所有那些老师一样看不起他。他以为我会看到他的衣服又破又不搭配，然后我会觉得他一无是处。”

CLIENT: “Yeah, the teachers could see how neglected he was, and they thought he was trash.”

来访者：“是啊，那些老师看得出来他被忽视得多么严重，他们觉得他是垃圾。”

ME: “That’s what their looks and eyes said: he was trash. And now that’s what he’s afraid I’ll see, too.”

我：“那就是他们的神情和眼睛所说的：他是垃圾。而如今那也正是他害怕我同样会看到的。”

As the client connects emotionally to the parts and reports the fears and phobias still affecting them, the therapist has an opportunity to speak “on their behalf” (Schwartz, 2001), to generate a deeper level of felt compassion in the client for the parts. Voicing a question used throughout Internal Family Systems work, the therapist asks: “When you hear those words, how do you feel toward that part now?” “Feeling toward” is a mindful phrase, different from “feeling for” (having sympathy) or “feeling about” (an attitude of mind). It asks the question, “What feelings do you notice having toward this part now?”

当来访者在情感上与各部分连接、并报告那些仍在影响它们的恐惧和恐惧症时，治疗师便有机会“代表它们”发声（Schwartz，2001），从而在来访者内心激发对各部分一种更深层次的、被感受到的慈悲。治疗师说出一个贯穿内部家庭系统工作的问题，问道：“当你听到那些话时，你现在对那个部分有怎样的感受？”“朝向……的感受”（feeling toward）是一个正念的短语，不同于“为……而感受”（feeling for，怀有同情）或“关于……的感受”（feeling about，一种心智上的态度）。它问的是：“你注意到自己现在对这个部分有怎样的感受？”

CLIENT: “I feel sad for him.”

来访者：“我为他感到悲伤。”

ME: “Yes, you feel sadness for him—it wasn’t his fault he was so neglected, was it? Could you let him know that—not so much with words as with your feelings and your body? [Short period of silence] What’s it like for him to sense someone caring how he feels?”

我：“是的，你为他感到悲伤——他被忽视得这么严重并不是他的错，对吧？你能让他知道这一点吗——与其说用言语，不如说用你的感受和你的身体？〔短暂的沉默〕对他来说，感觉到有人在乎他的感受，是一种什么样的体验？”

CLIENT: “It’s very new, but he likes it …”

来访者：“这很新鲜，但他喜欢……”

ME: “Yes, you can tell he likes it, but it is very new … Nobody ever felt for him … Let him know you understand just how new it is and maybe hard to trust …”

我：“是的，你看得出来他喜欢，但这很新鲜……从来没有人为他而感受过……让他知道，你明白这有多么新鲜、也许还很难去信任……”

One of the keys to this work is the use of the therapist’s own compassion and insight as an instrument. When the therapist communicates, “I get it” and when the normal life self and wounded part both feel “gotten” by each other, there is a shift in inner experience. When an increasingly warm inner dialogue between adult and child is facilitated by a therapist whose words and body communicate empathy and emotional connection to both, a spontaneous deepening and bonding takes place between them. The therapist is not just teaching the client to do “the work” or doing the work with a passive client. He or she is actively helping to build a relationship between a traumatized child and an innately caring adult, both held by the therapist as a compassionate third presence. That “is” the work.

这项工作的关键之一，是把治疗师自己的慈悲与洞察当作一种工具来运用。当治疗师传达出“我懂”，当正常生活自我和受伤的部分彼此都感到被对方“懂得”时，内在体验便发生了一种转变。当一位治疗师以其言语和身体向二者传达共情和情感连接，从而促成成年人与孩子之间一种日渐温暖的内在对话时，他们之间便自发地发生了一种深化与联结。治疗师不只是在教来访者去做“工作”，也不只是在与一个被动的来访者一起做工作。他或她正在积极地帮助在一个受创伤的孩子与一个天生富有关爱的成年人之间建立一种关系，二者都被治疗师作为一个充满慈悲的第三方存在所抱持着。那“就是”这项工作。

Avoiding the Tendency to “Pick Sides”

避免“选边站”的倾向

Without realizing it, therapists and clients have a tendency to side with some parts over others. The therapist might find it hard to work with the level of risk caused by an eating disordered or addicted flight part or a self-injurious fight part. It might be easier to work with submit’s willingness to go along with the therapist’s agenda or with the attach part’s neediness than with the resistance or devaluing of fight or the chronic ambivalence about therapy expressed by the flight part. Without doubt, the therapist will find it more rewarding to work with the normal life part’s difficulties with daily functioning than to sit with a mute, shutdown freeze part or a fight part in “Level 4 lockdown” mode.

在没有意识到的情况下，治疗师和来访者都有一种偏袒某些部分、而非另一些部分的倾向。治疗师可能会觉得难以应对一个进食障碍或成瘾的逃跑部分、或一个自伤的战斗部分所造成的风险程度。与战斗部分的阻抗或贬低、或逃跑部分所表达的对治疗的慢性矛盾心态相比，与顺从部分愿意配合治疗师议程的意愿、或与依恋部分的有需求一起工作，可能会更容易些。毫无疑问，治疗师会发现，与正常生活部分在日常功能上的困难一起工作，比起陪伴一个沉默、关闭的冻结部分、或一个处于“四级封锁”模式的战斗部分，更有成就感。

The biggest challenge for the therapist is being able to remember that these frustrating, alarming issues are driven by the internal conflicts between parts, rather than automatically assuming that the client is an integrated “he” or “she.” When that happens, we are more rather than less likely to be drawn into what was an internal struggle.

对治疗师而言最大的挑战，是能够记住这些令人挫败、令人惊慌的议题，是由各部分之间的内部冲突所驱动的，而不是自动地假定来访者是一个整合的“他”或“她”。当后一种情况发生时，我们被卷入这场原本属于内部的斗争的可能性反而更大，而非更小。

Whether our agenda is to get the “client” to verbalize more, express more affect, or curb unsafe behavior, once we lose the parts framework, we can only contribute to the internal polarization. The more we emphasize with the client that this is a struggle between part and part, the outcome of which will be determined by the system rather than by us, the more quickly it will be resolved. The therapist’s job then becomes twofold: first, to provide the bird’s eye perspective of the internal conflicts and, second, to “dance” with each part and with the system as a whole.

无论我们的议程是让“来访者”更多地用言语表达、表达更多的情感、还是遏制不安全的行为，一旦我们丧失了各部分的框架，我们就只会助长内部的两极分化。我们越是向来访者强调这是一场部分与部分之间的斗争，其结果将由这个系统、而非由我们来决定，它就会越快地得到化解。于是，治疗师的工作变成了双重的：第一，提供对内部冲突的鸟瞰视角；第二，与每一个部分、并与作为整体的系统一同“起舞”。

Dyadic Dancing

二元之舞

Attunement to all parts and to the system as a whole is expressed through the therapist’s body: the face softens or looks firm but calm or communicates warmth; the tone becomes one of curiosity, fascination, or determination. The therapist might lean forward or sit back in rhythm with the client. He or she uses the right brain perception to monitor the client’s body and nervous system, and then mindfully adjusts breathing, tone of voice, energy level, and facial expression accordingly. Seeing that the client is getting agitated, the therapist slows respiration, slows the pace of speech, and softens the tone. Avoiding questions that require thinking, he or she asks the client to “notice” the agitation or notice the belief that goes with it. Rather than listening to the entirety of the client’s statement or story before replying, as is the custom in most therapeutic methods, the therapist immediately engages in a “duet” or dialogue. The client makes an observation; the therapist responds by echoing the words or translating them into parts language; a reaction occurs, hopefully but not necessarily an increase in curiosity, and the therapist echoes that statement in parts language, makes a “bird’s eye perspective” comment, or asks the client to simply stay mindful and interested. Long “filibuster” monologues are interrupted and, as often as possible, turned into dialogues centered on shifting the normal life self’s attention to the interplay between parts or between parts and triggers.

对所有部分、以及对作为整体的系统的调谐，是通过治疗师的身体来表达的：脸庞变得柔和，或显得坚定却平静，或传递出温暖；语气变成一种好奇、着迷或坚定的语气。治疗师可能会随着来访者的节奏前倾身子或往后靠坐。他或她运用右脑的知觉来监测来访者的身体和神经系统，然后以正念据此调整呼吸、语气、能量水平和面部表情。看到来访者变得激动，治疗师便放慢呼吸，放慢说话的节奏，并柔化语气。避开那些需要思考的问题，他或她请来访者去“注意”这种激动，或注意伴随它而来的信念。治疗师不是像大多数治疗方法的惯例那样，在回应之前先听完来访者陈述或故事的全部，而是立即投入一场“二重奏”或对话之中。来访者作出一个观察；治疗师以回响其言语、或把它们翻译成各部分的语言来作出回应；一个反应随之发生，但愿——尽管未必——是好奇心的增加，于是治疗师用各部分的语言回响那句陈述，作一个“鸟瞰视角”的评论，或请来访者只是保持正念和兴趣。冗长的“拖延式”独白会被打断，并尽可能频繁地被转化为对话，其核心是把正常生活自我的注意力转移到各部分之间、或各部分与触发因素之间的相互作用上。

The key to ensuring that clients feel no loss of empathy when they are interrupted or when their words are reinterpreted as a communication from a part is the sensitivity of the attunement. To the extent that the therapist is curious, excited, fascinated, awed, touched, tickled, or deeply sympathetic, clients and their parts will feel “met” by the interruptions, rather than cut off.

确保来访者在被打断时、或在他们的话被重新诠释为来自某个部分之沟通时不会感到共情的丧失，其关键在于调谐的敏感度。治疗师越是好奇、兴奋、着迷、敬畏、感动、被逗乐、或深怀同情，来访者及其各部分就越会因这些打断而感到被“相会”，而非被切断。

“Dyadic dancing” is the term Allan Schore (2001a) uses to describe the “co-regulation” of mother and infant in those interchanges in which they feed off each other’s body language, sounds, smiles, and facial expressions in mutual attunement. The success of therapeutic dialogue rests on it feeling like a dyadic dance. In infant dialoguing, each maternal response either soothes or builds excitement, and the attuned caregiver makes sure to track the baby’s signals to ensure that the infant is enjoying the exchange, neither over- or understimulated. Similarly, the attuned therapist observes the client’s body language, tracks what elicits the going on with normal life self’s curiosity and interest, what reassures submit or attach parts, what helps the fight part to feel less phobic of emotion or closeness, what regulates the autonomic nervous system so that the client’s body is neither over- or understimulated.

“二元之舞”是Allan Schore（2001a）用来描述母亲与婴儿“共同调节”的术语，指的是在那些彼此从对方的身体语言、声音、微笑和面部表情中相互汲取、彼此调谐的交流之中所发生的协调。治疗性对话的成功，取决于它是否让人感觉像一场二元之舞。在与婴儿的对话中，母亲的每一个回应要么起安抚作用，要么积聚兴奋，而调谐的照料者会确保追踪婴儿的信号，以确保婴儿享受这种交流，既不过度刺激、也不刺激不足。同样地，调谐的治疗师观察来访者的身体语言，追踪什么引出了正常生活自我的好奇和兴趣，什么安抚了顺从部分或依恋部分，什么帮助战斗部分对情绪或亲近不那么恐惧，什么调节了自主神经系统、从而使来访者的身体既不过度刺激、也不刺激不足。

What makes the exchange more challenging for the therapist is the need to attend not just to one but a number of parts at once. Our words of reassurance for a young part, for example, cannot be so touching that we trigger flight or fight parts’ aversion to any emotion other than anger. While discussing fee increases, vacation plans, and other logistical issues, we have to take care not to provoke anxiety in the child parts, to reassure them even while discussing logistics with the adult client. Including the parts in our awareness instead of automatically reverting to an “I-thou” perspective can actually facilitate the success of these “housekeeping” conversations. I can announce my vacation dates to the normal life self, and then add reassurance for the attach part: “I know you [the normal life self] are fine with my taking vacations, but the little girl gets very nervous—she gets afraid no one will be here for her, and she’ll have no one to protect her. She might like it if you were willing to meet with the person who is covering for me—the fight part would hate it, but the attach part might like it. It might reassure her that she’s not going to be alone and unprotected. The other option is to offer to be her protector while I’m away. How do those two choices sound?” Another arena in which young parts can be triggered is the subject of billing, especially when the parts have feelings of shame connected to money. Here, too, the therapist can make sure to acknowledge the views of all parts: “I completely trust your normal life self’s integrity, and I know you’ve had a lot of other things on your plate for the last few months, so don’t feel badly that I had to remind you. And please, please reassure your child parts that they have done nothing wrong. It’s OK for us to talk about things that come up.”

使这种交流对治疗师而言更具挑战性的，是需要同时不只关照一个、而是若干个部分。例如，我们安抚某个年幼部分的话语，不能动人到触发逃跑部分或战斗部分对愤怒以外任何情绪的厌恶。在讨论涨价、休假计划和其他事务性问题时，我们必须小心不要激起孩子部分的焦虑，即便是在与成年来访者讨论事务时也要去安抚它们。把各部分纳入我们的觉察、而不是自动地退回到一种“我—你”的视角，实际上能够促成这些“家务事”式对话的成功。我可以向正常生活自我宣布我的休假日期，然后再为依恋部分加上一句安抚：“我知道你〔正常生活自我〕对我休假没有问题，但那个小女孩会变得非常紧张——她会害怕没有人在这里陪她，她将没有人来保护她。如果你愿意去见一见替我代班的那个人，她也许会喜欢——战斗部分会讨厌这样，但依恋部分也许会喜欢。这也许能让她安心，知道她不会孤身一人、无人保护。另一个选择是，在我离开期间，由你来担当她的保护者。这两个选择听起来怎么样？”另一个可能触发年幼部分的领域是账单这一话题，尤其是当各部分有着与金钱相关联的羞耻感时。在这里，治疗师同样可以确保去承认所有部分的看法：“我完全信任你正常生活自我的诚信，而且我知道过去这几个月你手头上还有很多别的事情，所以不必因为我得提醒你而感到难过。还有，请，请安抚一下你的孩子部分，告诉它们它们没有做错任何事。我们去谈论那些冒出来的事情是没关系的。”

The discussion of safety is another topic that can trigger parts’ survival responses. Some parts might feel confused or frightened by the word “safety,” having been told they were “safe” when they were not. If the flight and fight parts are engaging in unsafe behavior, it is very important for the therapist to voice respect for their different conceptions of safety. For them, “safety” is not to be found in asking for help or sharing their feelings. The therapist and normal life self might view the hospital as a safety net, forgetting that if fight and flight view it as “dangerous” or a “trap,” hospitalization should not be the first line of safety planning. Contracting for safety can be reassuring to the normal life self but a red flag to the fight part, triggering feelings of being controlled or asked to depend. Decisions about safety planning and differentiating safe versus unsafe actions are best made by the normal life self, but if the goal is simply restraint of the fight or flight part, then the opportunity to reach higher-level goals will be missed. (See Chapter 7 on unsafe and self-destructive behavior) In this model, the higher-level goal of the treatment is the development of increasingly close emotional bonds between the going on with normal life survivor and the young parts that are still afraid, still grieving what they never got, still deeply ashamed and alone. The bonds of internal between parts and normal life self trust support trusting the therapist, but, more importantly, they support collaboration and consensus.

关于安全的讨论是另一个可能触发各部分生存反应的话题。有些部分可能会被“安全”这个词弄得困惑或惊恐，因为他们曾在并不安全时被告知自己是“安全的”。如果逃跑部分和战斗部分正在从事不安全的行为，治疗师为它们关于安全的不同观念表达尊重就非常重要。对它们而言，“安全”并不存在于寻求帮助或分享自己的感受之中。治疗师和正常生活自我可能把医院视为一张安全网，却忘了如果战斗部分和逃跑部分把它视为“危险的”或一个“陷阱”，那么住院就不应当是安全规划的第一道防线。订立安全契约对正常生活自我可能起到安抚作用，但对战斗部分却是一面危险的警示旗，会触发被控制或被要求去依赖的感受。关于安全规划、以及区分安全行动与不安全行动的决定，最好由正常生活自我来作出，但如果目标仅仅是约束战斗部分或逃跑部分，那么达成更高层次目标的机会就将被错过。（关于不安全和自我毁灭行为，参见第7章）在这一模型中，治疗的更高层次目标，是在那个正常生活的幸存者与那些仍然害怕、仍然为他们从未得到之物而哀伤、仍然深深羞耻而孤独的年幼部分之间，发展出日益亲密的情感纽带。各部分与正常生活自我之间内在的信任纽带支持着对治疗师的信任，但更重要的是，它们支持着协作与共识。

To the degree that the therapist speaks from a place of authentic respect, warmth, and admiration for all the parts and empathizes with each point of view, the going on with normal life self can begin to accept each part as a potential resource, not just a liability, and a “real” person worthy of compassion. To do so requires the therapist to speak to and about each part from the point of view of other parts.

治疗师越是从一个对所有部分怀有真诚的尊重、温暖和赞赏的位置去说话，并对每一种观点都加以共情，正常生活自我就越能开始把每一个部分接纳为一种潜在的资源，而不只是一种负担，接纳为一个值得慈悲对待的“真实”的人。要做到这一点，需要治疗师从其他部分的视角出发，向每一个部分说话、并谈论每一个部分。

“The submit part must be so worried that fight’s ‘straight on don’t mince words’ style of speaking will displease or anger others.”
“What the fight part doesn’t realize is that when we tell children to shut up and stop crying, they might do it, but they get more scared. The other way to get them to stop crying is to reassure them that you won’t let them get hurt. Could you ask the fight part to give you a chance to see if that works faster?”
“I know the little part wants to tell me about the bad people who hurt her, but I also know that the fight part believes that it’s dangerous for her to tell. I am going to make a promise to the little part. In fact, the grownup Lucy and I could do that together—we need to promise her she won’t be hurt anymore. She doesn’t have to tell us what happened because we ‘get it.’ Then let’s see if the fight part is willing to have her tell us—or whether, once she feels protected, it’s not so important to tell us.”
“Could I be the defense attorney for the flight part for a moment? All these years, the flight part has tried to protect you by numbing your feelings and zoning you out on drugs. He knew you couldn’t handle the emotions or knowing what happened, so he took you ‘away.’ I realize that it’s gotten out of hand, that the addiction is now dangerous and has to be treated, but I don’t want you to forget that the addict part was trying to help—he did help. You wouldn’t be where you are today without him by your side.”

“顺从部分一定非常担心，战斗部分那种‘直来直去、毫不婉转’的说话风格会让别人不快或生气。”
“战斗部分没有意识到的是，当我们叫孩子闭嘴、别哭时，他们或许会照做，但他们会变得更害怕。让他们停止哭泣的另一种方法，是让他们安心，告诉他们你不会让他们受到伤害。你能不能请战斗部分给你一个机会，看看那种方法是不是更快奏效？”
“我知道那个小部分想告诉我那些伤害过她的坏人，但我也知道战斗部分认为她说出来是危险的。我要向那个小部分作一个承诺。事实上，成年的Lucy和我可以一起来做这件事——我们需要向她保证，她不会再受到伤害了。她不必告诉我们发生了什么，因为我们‘懂’。然后让我们看看，战斗部分是否愿意让她告诉我们——又或者，一旦她感到被保护了，告诉我们这件事是否就没那么重要了。”
“我能不能暂时充当逃跑部分的辩护律师？这么多年来，逃跑部分一直试图通过麻痹你的感受、用药物让你恍惚出神来保护你。他知道你应付不了那些情绪、也承受不了知道所发生之事，所以他把你‘带走了’。我意识到这已经失控了，成瘾如今很危险、必须加以治疗，但我不想让你忘记，那个成瘾部分一直在努力帮忙——他确实帮了忙。要不是有他在你身边，你不会走到今天。”

Often therapists hesitate to use the language like “inner person” for fear that it will exacerbate the dissociative fragmentation, but to the extent that the parts are visualized and treated as if they were small children and teens, it will be easier for the going on with normal life part to gaze fondly at them. The more the normal life self experiences warm, open, relaxed interest in the parts, the less need for distancing or disconnection from them. Especially as clients stabilize, the survival contributions of fight and flight parts must be enthusiastically acknowledged. They must be treated like war veterans: the therapist or client might not believe that the war was necessary or useful, but these parts fought hard for a worthy cause: the survival of the client. So therapist and client together must honor their service.

治疗师常常犹豫是否要使用像“内在的人”这样的语言，唯恐它会加剧解离性的碎裂，但只要各部分被想象、被对待成仿佛是年幼的孩子和青少年，正常生活部分就会更容易满怀爱意地注视它们。正常生活自我对各部分越是体验到温暖、开放、放松的兴趣，就越不需要与它们疏远或断开连接。尤其是当来访者趋于稳定时，战斗部分和逃跑部分在生存上的贡献必须得到热忱的承认。它们必须被当作战争老兵来对待：治疗师或来访者也许并不认为那场战争是必要的或有用的，但这些部分曾为一项值得的事业奋力而战：来访者的生存。因此，治疗师和来访者必须一同向它们的服役致敬。

The submit and freeze parts often benefit from being honored, too. Although their service consisted of avoidance strategies (freezing, becoming mute, serving others, pleasing and self-sacrifice, floating up to the ceiling), they too were essential to the client’s survival and adaptation. Without them, most childhood survivors of neglect and abuse might have reacted in ways that threatened the abuser(s) and evoked far worse punishment. Often, the attach part won moments of support from grandparents, teachers, the mothers of friends, neighbors—moments that provided hope, role models, even the belief that they could be loved. Even though these parts still get triggered and continue to drive trauma-related symptoms, the therapist must emphasize, “How is this part still trying to help?” “What is this part worried about? How is this an attempt at a solution?”

顺从部分和冻结部分也常常从被致敬中受益。尽管它们的服役由种种回避策略构成（冻结、变得沉默、服侍他人、讨好和自我牺牲、飘浮到天花板上去），它们对来访者的生存和适应也同样至关重要。要是没有它们，大多数儿时遭受忽视和虐待的幸存者，可能会以威胁到施虐者、招致糟糕得多的惩罚的方式去作出反应。依恋部分常常从祖父母、老师、朋友的母亲、邻居那里赢得片刻的支持——那些提供了希望、榜样、乃至自己能够被爱之信念的片刻。尽管这些部分仍然会被触发、并继续驱动着与创伤相关的症状，治疗师却必须强调：“这个部分如今是如何仍在试图帮忙的？”“这个部分在担心什么？它如何是一种寻求解决之道的尝试？”

Annie reminded her therapist: “You know, they’re all trying to fix it in their own ways.”
“Fix it?”
“Yes, fix what was wrong then—when we were all young—they’re still trying to do that now the way they learned to do it then.”

Annie提醒她的治疗师：“你知道吗，它们全都在用各自的方式试图修补它。”
“修补它？”
“是的，修补那时候——在我们都还年幼时——出了差错的东西——它们如今仍在试图这样做，用的是它们当年学会的那种方式。”

References

Beebe, B. et al. (2009). The origins of 12-month attachment: a microanalysis of 4-month mother-infant interaction. Attachment & Human Development, 12(1–2), 1–135.

Benjamin, J. (1994). What angel would hear me? The erotics of transference. Psychoanalytic Inquiry, 14(4), 535–557.

Grigsby, J. & Stevens, D. (2002). Memory, human dynamics and relationships. Psychiatry, 65(1), 13–34.

Liotti, G. (2011). Attachment disorganization and the controlling strategies: an illustration of the contributions of attachment theory to developmental psychopathology and to psychotherapy integration. Journal of Psychotherapy Integration, 21(3), 232–252.

Lyons-Ruth, K. et al. (2006). From infant attachment disorganization to adult dissociation: relational adaptations or traumatic experiences? Psychiatric Clinics of North America, 29(1).

Main, M. & Hesse, E. (1990). Parent’s unresolved traumatic experiences are related to infant disorganised attachment status. In Greenberg, M. et al., Attachment in preschool years: theory, research and intervention. Chicago: University of Chicago Press.

Ogden, P., Minton, K., & Pain, C. (2006). Trauma and the body: a sensorimotor approach to psychotherapy. New York: W.W. Norton.

Schore, A.N. (2003). Affect dysregulation and disorders of the self. New York: W.W. Norton.

Schore, A.N. (2001a). The effects of early relational trauma on right brain development, affect regulation, & infant mental health. Infant Mental Health Journal, 22, 201–269.

Schore, A.N. (2001b). The right brain as the neurobiological substratum of Freud’s dynamic unconscious. In D. Scharff & J. Scharff (Eds.). Freud at the millennium: the evolution and application of psychoanalysis. New York: Other Press.

Siegel, D.J. (1999). The developing mind: toward a neurobiology of interpersonal experience. New York: Guilford Press.

Solomon, M. (2011). The trauma that has no name: early attachment issues. Presentation at the Psychotherapy Networker Symposium, Washington, D.C., March 2011.

Tronick E. (2007). The neurobehavioral and social-emotional development of infants and children. New York: W.W. Norton.

Van der Hart, O., Nijenhuis, E.R.S., & Steele, K. (2006). The haunted self: structural dissociation and the treatment of chronic traumatization. New York: W.W. Norton.

CHAPTER 7
Working with Suicidal, Self-Destructive, Eating Disordered, and Addicted Parts

第7章
与自杀、自我毁灭、饮食障碍及成瘾部分工作

"When neither resistance nor escape is possible, the human system of self-defense becomes overwhelmed and disorganized. Each component of the ordinary response to danger, having lost its utility, tends to persist in an altered and exaggerated state long after the actual danger is over."

"当既无法反抗也无法逃脱时，人类的自我防御系统便会不堪重负、陷入混乱。危险应对反应的每一个组成部分，在失去其功能之后，往往会在实际危险已经过去很久之后，仍以一种变形而夸大的状态持续存在。"

(Herman, 1992, p. 92)

"[Abused children] will need to have the potential to mobilize an intense flight-fight response and to react aggressively to challenge without hesitation … [These survival responses] markedly augment the individual's capacity to rapidly and dramatically shift into an intense aggressive state when threatened by danger or loss."

"〔受虐儿童〕需要具备调动强烈逃跑—战斗反应的潜能，并能毫不犹豫地以攻击性方式应对挑战……〔这些生存反应〕显著增强了个体在面临危险或失去威胁时，迅速而剧烈地转入高度攻击状态的能力。"

(Teicher et al., 2002, p. 18)

Surviving trauma, going on each day as if nothing has happened, coping with both the normal challenges of daily life and the abnormal challenges of traumatogenic environments—all tax an individual's belief in safety and erode the determination to live. Feeling helpless, overwhelmed, inadequate, vulnerable, terrified, and alone, the lived experience is that there is nowhere to turn, nowhere to hide, no one to help. The only resources upon which each individual can draw reside in the body: disconnection, numbing, dissociation, neurochemicals such as adrenaline and endorphins, and the animal defense survival responses of fight, flight, freeze, submit, and attach for survival. These are "desperate times requiring desperate measures."

从创伤中幸存，每天若无其事地继续生活，同时应对日常生活的正常挑战和创伤性环境带来的异常挑战——这一切都消耗着个体对安全的信念，侵蚀着生存的意志。感到无助、不堪重负、力不从心、脆弱、恐惧、孤独无援，切身体验是无处可去、无处躲藏、无人相助。每个人所能依赖的唯一资源存在于身体之中：断联、麻木、解离、肾上腺素和内啡肽等神经化学物质，以及战斗、逃跑、冻结、顺从和依恋求生等动物性防御生存反应。这正是"非常之时，需非常之举"。

It is not surprising that trauma and self-destructive behavior go hand-in-hand. "Road rage," sexual compulsivity, the inability to anticipate danger and take self-protective measures, indifference to normal safety concerns, inability to leave dangerous situations or relationships—all are congruent with past experiences of being treated as an object whose welfare doesn't matter, whose life has no purpose other than to be used. It is no wonder that the prospect of death can be comforting as an alternative to entrapment, not surprising that wishing to die rather than live with such pain could be procedurally learned as a way of surviving. There is scientific support for this hypothesis as well as clinical evidence. Suicidal ideation, threats of suicide, and suicide attempts have all been statistically correlated with a diagnosis of PTSD, as have substance abuse, eating disorders, and self-injury (Khoury et al., 2007; Krysinska & Lester, 2010; Min et al., 2007). Even after repeated treatments for these symptoms and disorders, rates of relapse are extremely high among those with trauma histories (Najavits, 2002), suggesting that these different forms of addictive behavior have a complex inter-relationship with the effects of traumatic experience. How can we understand the coexistence in one individual of a strong will to live and an equally intense longing to die at one and the same time?

创伤与自我毁灭行为如影随形，这并不令人意外。"路怒症"、性强迫、无法预见危险并采取自我保护措施、对正常安全顾虑漠然置之、无力离开危险处境或关系——所有这些都与过去被当作福祉无关紧要、除了被利用别无价值的客体对待的经历相吻合。因此，死亡的前景作为摆脱困境的替代选择而令人感到宽慰，也就不足为奇；宁愿死去也不愿在如此痛苦中继续生活，作为一种程序性习得的生存方式，同样不难理解。这一假设既有科学支持，也有临床证据。自杀意念、自杀威胁和自杀未遂均在统计上与创伤后应激障碍（PTSD）的诊断相关，物质滥用、饮食障碍和自伤亦然（Khoury et al.，2007年；Krysinska & Lester，2010年；Min et al.，2007年）。即便经过反复治疗，有创伤史者的复发率仍极高（Najavits，2002年），这表明这些不同形式的成瘾行为与创伤经历的影响之间存在复杂的相互关系。我们如何理解一个人同时拥有强烈求生意志与同等强烈的求死渴望这两者的共存？

A Way Out or a Way to Go On?

一条出路，还是继续前行的方式？

Surviving trauma requires immense determination to keep on "keeping on" while simultaneously taxing an individual's belief in safety and eroding the wish to live. Having to cope both with the normal challenges of daily life and the abnormal challenges of traumatogenic environments is a heavy load for any human being to bear, much less a child. Having a sense that there is relief in sight; an exit plan, a parachute, or a "Get Out of Jail Free" card, brings a glimmer of hope or lessening of helplessness: "There is something I can do." When we are very young, the only resources upon which we can draw reside in the body: disconnection, numbing, dissociation, our body's neurochemicals (adrenaline, endorphins, cortisol), and animal defenses of freeze, total submission, or cry for help. By the teenage years, there are more options afforded us by a more physically powerful body and rapidly developing brain. As we develop during puberty, the animal defense survival responses of fight and flight become effective actions rather than the wishes and fantasies of a small child.

从创伤中存活需要巨大的决心去持续"坚持下去"，同时也消耗着个体对安全的信念，侵蚀着求生的意愿。既要应对日常生活的正常挑战，又要应对创伤性环境带来的异常挑战，对任何人而言都是沉重的负担，对孩子来说更是如此。感到解脱近在眼前——一个退出计划、一把降落伞，或一张"免出监狱"牌——能带来一丝希望或减轻无助感："还有什么我能做的。"当我们还很小的时候，能够依赖的唯一资源存在于身体之中：断联、麻木、解离、身体的神经化学物质（肾上腺素、内啡肽、皮质醇），以及冻结、完全顺从或求救等动物性防御反应。到了青少年时期，更加强壮的身体和快速发育的大脑为我们提供了更多选择。随着青春期的发育，战斗和逃跑的动物性防御生存反应变成了有效的行动，而不再只是小孩子的愿望和幻想。

Whether trapped under enduring conditions of threat or triggered by everyday stimuli, and whether we are three, thirteen, or thirty, the felt sense is that these are desperate moments requiring desperate measures to survive. The choice of "desperate measure" is only limited by our circumstances and our bodies. The sympathetic nervous system mobilizes the body to defend itself in the face of threat, but when fighting and fleeing are too dangerous, the body instinctively inhibits action by freezing or redirecting the impulse. We punch the wall; imagine ourselves crashing into a telephone pole; throw something; punch or bite ourselves. Immediately, there is a felt sense of control—just as we might feel when we duck for cover, get away, or push back the attacker.

无论是持续处于威胁之下，还是被日常刺激所触发，无论我们是三岁、十三岁还是三十岁，内心的感受都是：这是需要采取非常之举才能存活的紧迫时刻。"非常之举"的选择仅受制于我们的处境和身体。交感神经系统在面临威胁时动员身体进行自我防御，但当战斗和逃跑都太危险时，身体会本能地通过冻结或转移冲动来抑制行动。我们捶墙；想象自己撞上电线杆；扔东西；捶打或咬自己。顿时，有一种掌控感——就像我们躲避、逃脱或还击攻击者时所感受到的那样。

Desperate Measures

非常之举

Self-destructive behavior thus has its origin in the experience of feeling terrified of annihilation, isolated and abandoned, helpless against overwhelming emotions, and filled with despair and hopelessness. Whether these states are reactions to threat and violence or repeatedly triggered implicit memories, they feel equally true (and therefore equally frightening) now. To further amplify the desperation, manifestations of vulnerability feel unsafe, too. Emotions and emotional expression rarely result in greater safety for child victims and more often provoke intensified violence—to the point that many traumatized individuals become more afraid of their feelings than afraid for their lives.

自我毁灭行为的根源，在于对被消灭的恐惧、孤立无援的隔绝感、面对汹涌情绪时的无力感，以及充斥内心的绝望与无望。无论这些状态是对威胁和暴力的反应，还是被反复触发的内隐记忆，此刻它们感觉同样真实（因而同样令人恐惧）。更令人绝望的是，脆弱的流露同样令人感到不安全。情绪和情感表达对受害儿童来说极少能带来更多安全感，反而更常引发更剧烈的暴力——以至于许多创伤幸存者对自己的情感比对生命本身更加恐惧。

The fact that the normal sensations and emotions resulting from any adverse event are experienced as threatening, not liberating, is something important for therapists to keep in mind. In the effort to help clients acknowledge their feelings, rather than shutting down or acting out, therapists often forget that these emotions were once a source of danger and are now connected to implicit memories of overwhelm, threat, or humiliation. When clients learn instead to associate emotions that feel overwhelming or unsafe to a young child part of the self, the relationship to the feeling is altered. The client can feel the emotion still, but perceiving it as a child part's feelings reduces its threat, reduces the client's sense of vulnerability. It is OK for a child to feel ashamed or lonely or sad. It is even understandable that the child's vulnerability triggers fight and flight parts. The client's job is to mindfully notice the emotions as communications from a child part, to name them as "the little one's sadness" or "the little boy's fear," and inhibit the automatic tendency to identify with the fight or flight part and act on their impulses.

任何不良事件所引发的正常感觉和情绪都被体验为威胁而非解脱，这一事实对治疗师来说十分重要。在努力帮助来访者承认自身感受、而非关闭情感或付诸行动的过程中，治疗师往往忘记这些情绪曾经是危险的来源，如今与不堪重负、威胁或屈辱的内隐记忆相连。当来访者学会将感觉不堪重负或不安全的情绪与自我中年幼的儿童部分相关联时，与该情绪的关系便会改变。来访者仍能感受到这种情绪，但将其理解为儿童部分的感受，会降低它的威胁性，减少来访者的脆弱感。一个孩子感到羞愧、孤独或悲伤是没关系的。孩子的脆弱触发战斗和逃跑部分，甚至是可以理解的。来访者的任务是正念地将这些情绪觉察为来自儿童部分的信息，将其命名为"小家伙的悲伤"或"小男孩的恐惧"，并抑制自动认同战斗或逃跑部分、付诸冲动的倾向。

Another contributor to self-destructive behavior in traumatized individuals is the absence of ways to soothe or regulate intense, autonomically driven feelings and sensations. The ability to self-soothe is directly related to consistent early experiences of soothing that condition the nervous system to settle and recalibrate until the child is in an "optimally aroused" state (Ogden & Fisher, 2015). Under conditions of inadequate early attachment followed by traumatic threat, our clients' nervous systems learn habits of sympathetic hyperarousal to drive hypervigilence and readiness for action or habits of parasympathetic hypoarousal to ensure inaction and numbing (Ogden et al., 2006). Lacking the ability to self-regulate, overwhelmed by apparently dangerous emotions and sensations, the child's felt sense is, "I can't survive these feelings—if I can't make them stop, I will explode into a million pieces—I will die." The result: both ordinary and autonomically exacerbated emotional reactions come to feel unbearable, intolerable, and life-threatening. On the other hand, the dangers associated with high-risk behavior seem "unreal." The client is used to surviving life threat by dissociating or minimizing the danger in order to "keep on keeping on." Dying is not what the client fears. The client fears his or her own feelings. What feels dangerous is the implicit memory: "I can't tolerate these emotions by myself—if no one can help me, I will die—I have to do something."

创伤个体自我毁灭行为的另一个成因，是缺乏安抚或调节由自主神经驱动的强烈感受和感觉的方式。自我安抚的能力与早期持续的安抚体验直接相关，这些体验使神经系统学会平静下来并重新校准，直至儿童达到"最佳唤醒"状态（Ogden & Fisher，2015年）。在早期依恋不足、继而遭受创伤性威胁的条件下，来访者的神经系统会形成交感神经过度唤醒的习惯，以驱动过度警觉和备战状态，或者形成副交感神经低度唤醒的习惯，以确保无所作为和麻木（Ogden et al.，2006年）。缺乏自我调节能力、被看似危险的情绪和感觉所淹没，儿童的内心感受是："我无法在这些感受中活下去——如果我无法让它们停止，我会碎成千万片——我会死。"结果是：无论普通的还是被自主神经加剧的情绪反应，都变得令人无法承受、难以忍受、仿佛危及生命。另一方面，与高风险行为相关的危险却显得"不真实"。来访者习惯于通过解离或淡化危险来在生命威胁中存活，以便"坚持下去"。来访者所恐惧的并非死亡，而是自己的感受。感到危险的是内隐记忆："我独自无法承受这些情绪——如果没有人帮助我，我会死——我必须做些什么。"

Mastering Unbearable Emotions

掌控难以承受的情绪

The most common error made by professionals and lay people alike in understanding high-risk behavior is the automatic assumption that self-harm, suicidality, eating disorders, and substance abuse are destruction-seeking, rather than relief-seeking. If we assume that self-harm induces pain, then we interpret it as masochism or self-punishment or a cry for help. If we assume that suicidal ideation reflects a conscious intention to die, we will interpret it as a life-threat or a scream for help. And if we do, we will miss the core issue in self-harm: the pursuit of mastery over unbearable feelings or relief-seeking.

专业人士和普通人在理解高风险行为时最常犯的错误，是自动假设自伤、自杀倾向、饮食障碍和物质滥用是寻求毁灭，而非寻求解脱。如果我们假设自伤会带来痛苦，便会将其解读为受虐倾向、自我惩罚或求救信号。如果我们假设自杀意念反映了有意识的求死意图，便会将其解读为生命威胁或嘶声呼救。一旦如此，我们便会错过自伤的核心问题：追求对难以承受情绪的掌控，或寻求解脱。

At the heart of all self-destructive behavior is a simple fact: hurting the body, starving it, planning its annihilation, or compulsively engaging in addictive behavior result in welcome relief from physical and emotional pain. Ironically, based on its physiological effects, high-risk behavior seems to be an ingenious attempt to cope with pain, or to live through it, in the only ways the client knows how. If we can validate that clients currently have no better way of self-soothing, if we can acknowledge why self-harm or suicidal ideation and self-destructive behavior have been successful in bringing relief—albeit in a paradoxical way—we have the opportunity to develop a collaborative relationship with the client (and the fight or flight parts) in facing the challenges of relief-seeking. Rather than reacting immediately to suicidal ideation, active addiction, or self-harm as a safety concern, the therapist should begin by communicating curiosity: what problem might this be a solution for? What triggered this impulse? What is it the client is hoping for as a result of the action? Has he or she found relief in this way previously?

所有自我毁灭行为的核心是一个简单的事实：伤害身体、使其挨饿、谋划其毁灭，或强迫性地参与成瘾行为，都能带来令人欣慰的身体和情感痛苦的解脱。具有讽刺意味的是，从其生理效应来看，高风险行为似乎是以来访者所知的唯一方式来应对痛苦或在痛苦中活下去的巧妙尝试。如果我们能够认可来访者目前没有更好的自我安抚方式，如果我们能够承认自伤、自杀意念和自我毁灭行为为何能够成功地带来解脱——尽管是以一种矛盾的方式——我们便有机会与来访者（以及战斗或逃跑部分）建立合作关系，共同面对寻求解脱的挑战。治疗师不应将自杀意念、活跃的成瘾或自伤立即视为安全问题加以应对，而应首先传递好奇心：这可能是什么问题的解决方案？是什么触发了这种冲动？来访者希望通过这一行为获得什么？他/她以前是否曾以这种方式找到过解脱？

Providing psychoeducation about why these behaviors are so effective in regulating unbearable states mitigates client shame and secrecy. Describing the range of positive intentions that might underlie a self-destructive impulse makes it all the more likely that clients will volunteer their doubts and fears about achieving relief in these ways, rather than trying to convince the therapist that addictive or unsafe behavior is their only or best option.

就这些行为为何如此有效地调节难以承受的状态提供心理教育，可以减轻来访者的羞耻感和秘密感。描述自我毁灭冲动背后可能存在的各种积极意图，更有可能使来访者主动表达对以这些方式获得解脱的疑虑和恐惧，而不是试图让治疗师相信成瘾或不安全行为是他们唯一或最好的选择。

Historically, treatments for unsafe behavior have often polarized client and therapist: the therapist's goal of reducing self-injury or preventing suicide is often in conflict with the client's need to hold on to the one kind of relief that can be counted upon to work. Or the therapist's agenda of "safety first" might evoke an interpersonal struggle by putting the therapist in a policing role. In this treatment model, my first priority is to help the client attend to the internal struggle: what feelings are activating fight and flight parts to such desperate measures? Which parts want to die? Which are trying to help? And which want to live? Are any of them frightened by the fight part's capacity for violence? Do the child parts see the fight part as a rescuer or are they afraid of being killed?

从历史上看，针对不安全行为的治疗往往使来访者与治疗师之间产生对立：治疗师减少自伤或预防自杀的目标，常常与来访者依赖那种可以依靠的解脱方式的需求相冲突。或者，治疗师"安全第一"的议程可能通过将治疗师置于执法者角色而引发人际冲突。在这一治疗模式中，我的首要任务是帮助来访者关注内心的挣扎：是什么感受激活了战斗和逃跑部分，驱使其采取如此极端的措施？哪些部分想要死去？哪些部分在试图提供帮助？哪些部分想要活下去？其中是否有部分对战斗部分的暴力能力感到恐惧？儿童部分是将战斗部分视为救援者，还是害怕被杀死？

To effectively treat unsafe and addictive behavior, therapist and client must be able to share the intra-personal dilemma: if self-harming, eating disordered, or addictive behavior is the only means of managing what feels like life-threatening emotional arousal, how else does the client tolerate the pain? How do therapists encourage clients to acquire or make use of the skills, resources, or treatments that are healthier options when "ordinary measures" are slower and less effective than the desperate measures? When the client's internal experience is a sense of life-or-death urgency? Historically, the treatment approaches for trauma-related self-harm, addictive behavior, eating disorders, or suicidality have primarily addressed abstinence and safety as behavioral goals, only to discover that trauma-related triggers and an inadequate window of tolerance consistently undermine the client's attempts at stability. To understand the complex inter-relationship between trauma and unsafe, addictive behaviors requires comprehension of the effects of these behaviors on the body and how they facilitate relief and regulation.

为了有效治疗不安全行为和成瘾行为，治疗师与来访者必须能够共同面对这一内在困境：如果自伤、饮食障碍或成瘾行为是管理那种感觉上危及生命的情绪唤起的唯一手段，来访者还能如何忍受痛苦？当"普通措施"比非常之举更缓慢、更不有效时，治疗师如何鼓励来访者获取或利用那些更健康的技能、资源或治疗方式？当来访者的内心体验是生死攸关的紧迫感时？从历史上看，针对创伤相关自伤、成瘾行为、饮食障碍或自杀倾向的治疗方法主要将戒除和安全作为行为目标，结果却发现，创伤相关触发因素和不足的容忍窗口持续破坏来访者寻求稳定的努力。要理解创伤与不安全、成瘾行为之间复杂的相互关系，需要理解这些行为对身体的影响，以及它们如何促进解脱和调节。

Capitalizing on the Body to Gain Relief

利用身体获取解脱

Child abuse and neglect, torture, domestic violence, and many other categories of trauma share a common characteristic: the victim's body, mind, and emotions have been exploited by others, either to gratify their needs, exert control, or provide an outlet for release of tension (Miller, 1994). It is not surprising that children whose bodies have been used in this way might later become adults who instinctively use their own bodies to relieve tension or act out impulses. They have been deprived of the normal experiences of tension relief (i.e., the soothing of secure attachment), while the abuse has relegated the body to no more than a vehicle for releasing tension, with no other real value.

儿童虐待与忽视、酷刑、家庭暴力以及许多其他类别的创伤有一个共同特征：受害者的身体、思维和情感被他人所利用，或是满足其需求，或是施加控制，或是提供释放紧张情绪的出口（Miller，1994年）。身体以这种方式被使用的儿童，日后成为本能地以自己的身体释放紧张感或付诸冲动的成年人，这并不令人意外。他们被剥夺了正常的紧张解除体验（即安全依恋的安抚），而虐待将身体降格为仅仅是释放紧张的载体，不再具有其他真正的价值。

When distressed, most children seek connections to others, preferably adults, for soothing, reassurance, or comfort. Those who experience neglect or abuse, however, quickly learn to avoid connection, rather than seek it, and to rely almost exclusively on their own resources. Because they cannot trust or depend on others for support, they instinctively seek relief in a variety of behaviors that share one common characteristic: none requires reliance on other human beings. Some clients learned as teenagers to use drugs and alcohol to numb; others discovered in early puberty that self-starvation or binging and purging allowed them to achieve a similar state of calm or "non-feeling." Still others, often beginning when young children, develop a variety of relief-providing self-injurious behaviors: pinching, cutting, scratching, burning, hitting or punching, head-banging, and even blood-letting.

大多数儿童在苦恼时会寻求与他人的连接——最好是成年人——以获得安抚、安慰或comfort。然而，那些经历忽视或虐待的儿童很快学会回避连接，而不是寻求连接，几乎完全依赖自身的资源。由于无法信任或依赖他人的支持，他们本能地在各种行为中寻求解脱，这些行为有一个共同特征：均不需要依赖他人。一些来访者在青少年时期学会了用毒品和酒精麻木自己；另一些人在青春期早期发现，自我节食或暴食清除能使他们达到类似的平静或"无感"状态。还有一些人——往往从幼童时期就开始——发展出各种能提供解脱的自伤行为：掐捏、切割、抓挠、烧灼、撞击或捶打、撞头，甚至放血。

How Self-Destructive Behaviors "Work"

自我毁灭行为如何"奏效"

The biggest challenge in treating self-destructive behavior is how effective it is in producing relief—at least in the early stages before tolerance develops. Harm to the body (cutting, burning, hitting, ingestion of sharp objects) has the same effects as any injury or threat: first, the harm stimulates adrenaline production (resulting in increased energy, focus, feelings of power and control, and decreased emotional and body sensation), and then a heightened endorphin release, facilitating a relaxation/analgesic effect. Both responses occur quite quickly, providing almost instant relief for the client feeling terrified and overwhelmed by the level of intensity or the disconnection.

治疗自我毁灭行为最大的挑战在于它在产生解脱感方面的高度有效性——至少在耐受性形成之前的早期阶段如此。对身体的伤害（切割、烧灼、撞击、吞咽尖锐物体）与任何伤害或威胁具有相同的效应：首先，伤害刺激肾上腺素分泌（导致能量增加、注意力集中、产生力量感和掌控感，情绪和躯体感觉减少），继而引发内啡肽的大量释放，促进放松/镇痛效果。这两种反应发生得相当迅速，为因强度水平或断联感而感到恐惧和不堪重负的来访者提供了几乎即时的解脱。

Although eating disorders have traditionally been conceptualized as resulting from a distorted body image or distorted sense of self, it is striking that their effects quite specifically address the hyperarousal-related symptoms of trauma. In eating disorders, relief can be achieved by under- or over-eating. For example, in anorexia, restricting food intake results in numbing of emotion and sensation while at the same time, due to the effects of ketosis, there is an increase in energy and feelings of well-being. Over-eating also results in numbing accompanied by relaxation, increased parasympathetic hypoarousal, disconnection from the body, spaciness, or drowsiness. Bulimia, too, in both the binging and purging phases, causes a reduction in hyperarousal and decreased pain sensitivity via activation of the dorsal vagal system (Faris et al., 2008), the same branch of the parasympathetic nervous system implicated in total collapse and feigned death survival responses. That bulimia is associated with a higher pain threshold compared to normal controls (Faris et al., 2008), presumably because of the numbing effects of both the binging and purging, may account for the increased number of young women being diagnosed with this disorder.

尽管饮食障碍传统上被概念化为源于扭曲的身体形象或扭曲的自我感，但令人瞩目的是，其效应非常具体地针对创伤的过度唤醒相关症状。在饮食障碍中，解脱可通过进食不足或过度进食来实现。例如，在厌食症中，限制食物摄入会导致情绪和感觉麻木，同时由于酮症的影响，能量增加，幸福感提升。暴饮暴食也会导致伴随放松的麻木感、副交感神经低度唤醒增加、与身体断联、恍惚或嗜睡。神经性贪食症在暴食和清除两个阶段，也通过激活背侧迷走神经系统（Faris et al.，2008年）降低过度唤醒并减少痛觉敏感性，该副交感神经系统分支与完全崩溃和装死生存反应有关。贪食症与正常对照组相比具有更高的痛阈（Faris et al.，2008年），这可能是由于暴食和清除的麻木效应，这或许可以解释为何越来越多的年轻女性被诊断出患有这一障碍。

Both substance abuse and addictive behaviors also tend to result in quite specific effects on autonomic arousal—as reflected in the drug-related terms "uppers" and "downers." Cocaine, speed, MDMA (Ecstasy), Ritalin and Adderall, crystal meth, and other stimulants are the drugs of choice when clients begin to feel "dead" or "empty" but can also be used to increase feelings of power and control or maintain arousal at a heightened level in clients who fear relaxation or confuse it with insufficient hypervigilance. Similarly, alcohol, marijuana, benzodiazepines, and opiods, such as heroin, oxycodone, and morphine, all down-regulate hyperarousal symptoms and overwhelming emotions, but they can also be used to help individuals maintain a chronic state of hypoarousal in which they can be sure of not feeling or sensing "too much." Particularly in eating disorders and addictions, any sense of connection between the drug or behavior of choice and the trauma symptoms they treat has often long been lost. Habitually "using" or engaging in eating disordered behavior prevents the intrusion of feared emotions and sensations—until the client begins to develop tolerance and must restrict, binge and purge, or overeat more frequently or severely to induce the same effect. As clients develop tolerance, eating disorders often spiral out of control. Consistent with the split-brain research showing the tendency of the left brain to create rational arguments for right brain-driven irrational behavior, clients with eating and/or substance abuse disorders will have "stories" or rationales for their symptoms: for example, "I'd be as big as a house if I didn't ___________." But those stories do not account for the relief experienced as a result of eating disordered behavior. They do not explain the panic triggered by the effects of increased tolerance, and the desperate need to numb the feelings again, causing increased eating disordered or addictive behavior. It may be more than a coincidence that substance abuse, eating disorders, self-harm, and suicidal behavior typically begin in the years from 11 to 14—just at the height of a teenagers' mounting internal conflicts between the drive for independence/individuation and the fear of abandonment and separation.

物质滥用和成瘾行为也往往对自主神经唤醒产生相当具体的影响——这体现在与药物相关的"兴奋剂"和"镇静剂"等术语中。可卡因、安非他命、MDMA（摇头丸）、利他林和阿德拉、冰毒以及其他兴奋剂，是来访者开始感到"麻木"或"空洞"时的首选药物，但也可用于增加力量感和掌控感，或在那些害怕放松或将放松与过度警觉不足相混淆的来访者中维持高度唤醒状态。同样，酒精、大麻、苯二氮䓬类药物以及海洛因、羟考酮、吗啡等阿片类药物，均能下调过度唤醒症状和汹涌的情绪，但也可用于帮助个体维持长期的低度唤醒状态，从而确保不会感受或感觉到"太多"。尤其是在饮食障碍和成瘾中，所选择的药物或行为与其所治疗的创伤症状之间的任何关联感，往往早已消失殆尽。习惯性地"使用"或参与饮食障碍行为，可以阻止恐惧的情绪和感觉的入侵——直到来访者开始产生耐受性，不得不更频繁或更严重地限制进食、暴食清除或过度进食才能产生同样的效果。随着来访者产生耐受性，饮食障碍往往愈演愈烈、失控螺旋。与裂脑研究表明左脑倾向于为右脑驱动的非理性行为创造理性论据相一致，患有饮食障碍和/或物质滥用障碍的来访者会对其症状有"故事"或理由：例如，"如果我不___________，我会胖得像头猪。"但这些故事并不能解释饮食障碍行为所带来的解脱感。它们无法解释耐受性增加所触发的恐慌，以及重新麻木感受的迫切需要，从而导致饮食障碍或成瘾行为的加剧。物质滥用、饮食障碍、自伤和自杀行为通常开始于11至14岁之间，这可能不仅仅是巧合——恰好是青少年在独立/个体化驱动与对遗弃和分离的恐惧之间内心冲突不断加剧的顶峰时期。

Self-Destructive Behavior and the Attachment Drive

自我毁灭行为与依恋驱力

Most victims of trauma face some version of the same life-threatening dilemma: how to minimize the dangers facing them and maximize the relational resources that might afford protection while simultaneously avoiding vulnerability to those who might do them harm. To minimize danger, they must avoid antagonizing the predator; they must cultivate good will while simultaneously remaining guarded. For young children, this challenge is especially difficult due to their dependence on adults and the strength of their biological drive to attach or seek proximity. They need a solution that inhibits the attachment drive without increasing the risk of abuse or sacrificing any positive attention that might be available to them.

大多数创伤受害者都面临着某种形式的同一危及生命的困境：如何将面临的危险降至最低，同时最大化可能提供保护的关系资源，同时避免向可能伤害他们的人暴露脆弱性。为了将危险降至最低，他们必须避免激怒捕食者；必须培养善意，同时保持警惕。对于幼童来说，这一挑战尤为艰难，因为他们依赖成年人，且生物性的依恋或寻求亲近的驱力十分强烈。他们需要一种既能抑制依恋驱力、又不增加被虐待风险、也不放弃任何可能获得的积极关注的解决方案。

While her mother and I conferred about her emotionally disturbed older brother's care, 2-year-old Anya ran in, tripped over a toy, and fell hard on her chin. She started to sob but made no eye contact or appeal to her mother for comfort, nor did her mother seem to notice her crying. Seemingly oblivious to either adult, Anya pulled herself up to a standing position and started to rock from foot to foot, quietly sobbing and rocking at the same time. In her own world now, her eyes unfocused, she kept rocking until she was calm and quiet.

Attachment researchers who study disorganized attachment have described behavior like Anya's beginning as early as age two, postulating that it reflects a solution to the challenge of experiencing simultaneous urges to seek proximity and impulses to distance or defend. Presumably wary of seeking proximity to their "frightened and frightening" caregivers when vulnerable or needy, these preschoolers begin to relate in ways that give them more control, termed the "controlling strategies" (Liotti, 2014). One group, described as "controlling-caregiving," engages in parentified or "tend and befriend" behavior: charming, directing, entertaining, soothing, precociously independent, and offering approval and comfort to the parent. The other group of children, termed "controlling-punitive," reacts to proximity in ways that are hostile, provocative, coercive, shaming, and sometimes aggressive or violent, putting them at risk for diagnoses of "oppositional-defiant disorder." It appears from this research that when caregivers are neglectful, dangerous, or unavailable, safety becomes equated with the choice between appeasement or parentification, on the one hand, and hostility or distancing, on the other. Or proximity-seeking and distancing alternate in the same individual, each impulse driven by a different survival defense response: the attach or submit part's using parentified behavior to gain greater control over closeness and the fight part's use of hostile engagement to push others away at the same time. Because closeness and safety are intertwined when we are dependent for survival on caregivers, the implicit message is: "It isn't safe to depend. It isn't safe to get too close or to love those closest to you." These patterns of attachment behavior persist into adulthood and when accompanied by structural dissociation, become increasingly sophisticated, polarized, and easily activated.

研究混乱型依恋的依恋研究者描述了像安雅这样早在两岁就出现的行为，认为它反映了一种应对同时体验寻求亲近的冲动与疏远或防御的冲动这一挑战的解决方案。这些学龄前儿童大概是在脆弱或有需求时，对靠近"既受惊又令人恐惧"的照顾者保持警惕，开始以能给予自己更多掌控的方式与他人互动，这被称为"控制策略"（Liotti，2014年）。一组被描述为"控制-照顾型"的儿童表现出亲职化或"照料与结交"行为：迷人、善于指引、善于娱乐他人、善于安抚他人、早熟地独立，并向父母提供认可和安慰。另一组被称为"控制-惩罚型"的儿童以敌对、挑衅、强制、羞辱，有时甚至是攻击性或暴力性的方式回应亲近，使他们面临被诊断为"对立违抗障碍"的风险。这项研究表明，当照顾者疏于关心、具有危险性或无法获得时，安全便等同于一种选择：要么是讨好或亲职化，要么是敌意或疏远。或者，在同一个体身上，寻求亲近与疏远交替出现，每种冲动由不同的生存防御反应驱动：依恋或顺从部分利用亲职化行为获取对亲密关系的更大掌控，而战斗部分同时利用敌对接触将他人推开。由于当我们依赖照顾者生存时，亲密与安全相互交织，内隐的信息是："依赖是不安全的。与最亲近的人过于亲密或去爱他们是不安全的。"这些依恋行为模式持续到成年，当伴随结构性解离时，变得愈加复杂、两极化，且容易被激活。

Animal Defenses and Unsafe Behavior

动物性防御与不安全行为

Structural dissociation facilitates negotiating unsafe attachment relationships: if the wish for closeness is held by an attach part, the ability to appease by a submit part, the need for distance by flight, the fear of attack by freeze, and the imperative to control the situation is instinctive for the fight part, then the individual has all the "ingredients" necessary to manage in a dangerous world. That each structurally dissociated part can operate somewhat independently of the others to pursue its goals creates an advantage. Quick, automatic transitions from hypervigilant to needy to distancing to robotic compliance facilitate defensive flexibility—important when you have easily provoked abusive caretakers. When perceiving trauma-related stimuli as dangerous increases the chances of avoiding trouble, and staying safe another day, this pattern is adaptive. But, once we are safe (i.e., no longer emotionally or physically dependent on abusive individuals), these defensive patterns are no longer useful. The parts still scan the environment for traumatic triggers salient to their aims and needs and react to each in their own characteristic ways. But their activation increases susceptibility to internal conflicts. The most threatening triggers every part will encounter are likely to be other human beings. Not only will angry, violent, aggressive individuals evoke strong defensive responses, so will authority figures, and even those to whom clients are closest: partners and spouses, therapists, family members, close friends, and love objects of all kinds. Tragically, those who might aid in the healing process are likely to be as triggering for the structurally dissociated parts as those who harmed them.

结构性解离有助于应对不安全的依恋关系：如果对亲密的渴望由依恋部分持有，讨好的能力由顺从部分持有，疏远的需求由逃跑部分持有，对被攻击的恐惧由冻结部分持有，而掌控局势的命令对战斗部分来说是本能的，那么个体便拥有了在危险世界中应对所需的全部"要素"。每个结构性解离部分能够在一定程度上独立于其他部分追求其目标，这创造了一种优势。从过度警觉到需求迫切，再到疏远，再到机器人式服从的快速、自动转换，有助于防御的灵活性——这在面对容易被激怒的施虐照顾者时尤为重要。当将创伤相关刺激感知为危险能增加避免麻烦、再平安度过一天的机会时，这种模式是适应性的。但是，一旦我们处于安全之中（即不再在情感或身体上依赖施虐者），这些防御模式便不再有用。各部分仍然扫描环境中与其目标和需求相关的创伤触发因素，并以各自的特有方式做出反应。但它们的激活增加了内部冲突的易感性。每个部分将遇到的最具威胁性的触发因素很可能是其他人类。不仅愤怒、暴力、攻击性的个体会引发强烈的防御反应，权威人物也会，甚至来访者最亲近的人——伴侣和配偶、治疗师、家庭成员、亲密朋友以及各类爱恋对象——也会。令人悲哀的是，那些可能有助于疗愈过程的人，对结构性解离部分的触发程度，很可能与曾经伤害他们的人一样强烈。

As these struggles inevitably lead to increasing polarization, the internal conflicts intensify. The attach part instinctively idealizes potential attachment figures (including the therapist), while the fight part is likely to become more guarded, hypervigilant, or hostile to those seeking closeness or whomever empathically fails the young parts by disappointing them, not "being there," not caring for them, or having other priorities. Because the others in the client's life believe they are in the company of an adult, not a child, even their most well-meaning and supportive efforts to "be there" can easily disappoint or hurt a young traumatized part's feelings. What is well-meaning and supportive to an adult is very different than "well-meaning and supportive" to a child, as Jessica attests.

随着这些挣扎不可避免地导致日益加剧的两极化，内部冲突愈发激烈。依恋部分本能地理想化潜在的依恋对象（包括治疗师），而战斗部分则可能对那些寻求亲密的人，或任何因令年幼部分失望、"不在场"、不关心他们或有其他优先事项而在共情上令其失望的人，变得更加警惕、过度警觉或充满敌意。由于来访者生命中的其他人认为自己与一个成年人相处，而非与一个孩子相处，即便是他们最善意、最支持性的"在场"努力，也很容易令年幼创伤部分失望或伤害其感情。对成年人来说善意且支持性的事物，与对孩子来说"善意且支持性的"事物截然不同，杰西卡的经历便是明证。

Jessica counted on her friends and their friends to help her during difficult times, and they tried to come through. But their practical offers of rides, help with finding a new job, or being treated to lunch didn't register as "caring" to a 2-year-old attach part. She longed for a hug, for gaze-to-gaze contact, for someone who would hang on her every word, someone who wasn't in a hurry to go somewhere after lunch. As these were not experiences generally offered to a 45-year-old woman, Jessica's attach part was often left feeling hurt and disappointed. Complicating this situation was her fight part's constant alertness to behavior that would wound the attach part or offend the fight part's sense of fairness. Because Jessica's parents had both been hypersensitive and hypercritical, the fight part's alarms went off in the context of what her friends deemed very minor offenses. And once someone offended, the fight part remained hostile and vigilant for months or even years, refusing to allow Jessica to forgive and move on—or even to reassure the little part. Gradually, she became more and more isolated, unable to make new friends because the fight part inevitably found them "cold," "narcissistic," "mean," or "not healthy enough" for her. But isolation did not solve the underlying attachment wound: the child part's loneliness and rejection sensitivity only deepened, while the fight part's hypervigilence increased in tandem.

Particularly as children enter puberty, begin to individuate, and become physically stronger, the fight and flight parts become more active. By age 15, adolescent parts are often physically capable of standing up to authority figures and exercising power and control over the vulnerability of younger parts (yearning, neediness, hurt, disappointment) that could potentially be exploited. It is not a coincidence that eating and substance abuse disorders tend to appear around ages 11 to 12 at a time when separation-individuation instincts require inhibition of the attachment drive but also at a time when the child's physical strength and greater independence increase opportunities for disordered eating, self-harm, and access to substances. Sometimes this is also the stage at which a first suicide attempt takes place.

尤其是当儿童进入青春期、开始个体化、体格变得更强壮时，战斗和逃跑部分变得更加活跃。到15岁时，青少年部分往往在身体上已有能力对抗权威人物，并对可能被利用的年幼部分的脆弱性（渴望、依赖、受伤、失望）施加力量和控制。饮食障碍和物质滥用障碍往往在11至12岁左右出现，这并非巧合——此时分离-个体化本能要求抑制依恋驱力，同时儿童的体力增强和更大的独立性也增加了饮食紊乱、自伤和获取物质的机会。有时，这也是第一次自杀未遂发生的阶段。

Annette could remember the time she first dreamed of dying as a solution to her situation. She was 6 years old, her mother was away at work all day, and her stepfather's abuse became increasingly cold, calculating, and sadistic. Every day, she would promise herself: "If you just get through today, you can die tomorrow." Then she could breathe, knowing there was an end in sight. "If you just get through today, you can die tomorrow." It was a promise that brought welcome relief and helped fortify her for what was to come. Even after her mother left her stepfather and the abuse stopped, the wish to die remained a "fail safe" solution each time she felt overwhelmed or abandoned. She made her first suicide attempt at age 14 after the end of a relationship with her first boyfriend: she downed a bottle of aspirin.

The paradox was that, initially, the wish to die had begun as a way to live through the abuse by exerting control: "I'll only put up with this one more day." That sense of control brought welcome relief each time she made that promise to herself. By age 14, however, just wishing wasn't enough to bring relief anymore. "That's why," she said, "I had to do something. I had to feel that I could end it." She was not relieved to be alive still nor was she disappointed. Once she'd taken the overdose, Annette felt a renewed sense of purpose: she did have a way out when she needed it. At the same time, she was cautious to avoid detection of her suicidality for fear of "being locked up." This continued to be the pattern until Annette was in her 30s: something or someone would hurt or trigger the younger parts' feelings, and the suicidal part would re-establish a sense of control by threatening suicide, self-harming, or taking non-lethal overdoses, often small enough just to render her unconscious for the night until she could wake up the next morning and go on about her life. Of more concern was her use of alcohol.

矛盾之处在于，最初，求死的愿望是作为一种通过施加控制而在虐待中活下去的方式而出现的："我只需再忍一天。"每次她对自己许下这个承诺时，那种掌控感都带来令人欣慰的解脱。然而，到14岁时，仅仅许愿已不再足以带来解脱。"这就是为什么，"她说，"我不得不做些什么。我必须感觉到我能够结束它。"她既不因仍然活着而感到如释重负，也不感到失望。一旦服下过量药物，安奈特感到一种重新焕发的目标感：在需要时，她确实有一条出路。与此同时，她谨慎地避免让人发现她的自杀倾向，以免"被关起来"。这种模式持续到安奈特三十多岁：某事或某人会伤害或触发年幼部分的感受，自杀部分便会通过威胁自杀、自伤或服用非致命性过量药物来重新建立掌控感，剂量往往小到仅能使她昏迷一夜，直到第二天早上醒来继续生活。更令人担忧的是她对酒精的使用。

After a hospitalization following the first suicide attempt at age 14, Annette felt trapped and fearful. If she couldn't control her impulses, she'd be locked up again, but if she gave up her suicidal longing, there would be no source of relief. She began to feel an internal battle. Her littlest part longed for someone to just love her and keep her safe, but that rendered her vulnerable to men looking for sex. Disappointment in not finding someone to care triggered the child's grief, and although the suicidal part bought a little relief by scratching her arms, Annette worried that the scratches would be viewed as signs she wanted to die. On her fifteenth birthday, some friends brought a bottle of wine, and as she drank her first glass, she began to feel "normal." The wine relaxed the tension and fearfulness, allowed her to laugh and smile at people's jokes—and then they smiled back, filling her little part with hope that maybe they liked her after all.

Even after individuals are safe, trauma-related triggers interfere with differentiating what is safe now from what was dangerous then. Once her stepfather was gone, Annette was finally safe from harm, but she and her parts didn't feel safe. Her little part still yearned for the safety of someone's love and protection; her suicidal part still brought relief by promising to end it all; and her addict part had to increase her consumption of alcohol to regulate trauma-related implicit memories and their accompanying autonomic arousal. When boyfriends left or girlfriends disappointed her, the little part panicked, and Annette was flooded with hurt and desperation—requiring yet more wine. As the years went on, though, her once trusty chemical support began to fail her: to make the feelings go away, the flight part now had to drink to blackout. But when she blacked out, what happened next re-exacerbated the disturbing feelings instead of easing them. All too often, her nights out at the bar with her trendy young professional "family" of drinkers ended in blackout, and she would find herself in a stranger's bed the next morning.

即使个体已经安全，创伤相关触发因素也会干扰对当下安全与过去危险的区分。继父离开后，安奈特终于免受伤害，但她和她的各个部分并不感到安全。她的小部分仍然渴望某人的爱与保护所带来的安全感；她的自杀部分仍然通过承诺终结一切来带来解脱；而她的成瘾部分不得不增加酒精消耗，以调节创伤相关的内隐记忆及其伴随的自主神经唤醒。当男友离开或女友令她失望时，小部分陷入恐慌，安奈特被伤害和绝望所淹没——需要更多的酒。然而，随着岁月流逝，她曾经可靠的化学支撑开始失效：为了让感受消失，逃跑部分现在必须喝到断片。但当她断片时，接下来发生的事情不是缓解而是加剧了那些令人不安的感受。太多次，她与一群时髦的年轻职业"家人"喝酒夜归，以断片告终，第二天早上醒来发现自己躺在陌生人的床上。

Treating the Causes of Self-Destructive Behavior

治疗自我毁灭行为的成因

Self-destructive behavior stems from a "perfect storm" of variables: first, a trigger evokes trauma-related implicit memory. Second, the implicit memory's association with danger activates the emergency stress response, inducing a sympathetic nervous system reaction and shutting down the prefrontal cortex, impairing the individual's judgment and disempowering the normal life self. Now, parts with conflicting defensive responses have free rein to act on their survival instincts, leading to some action intended to bring relief—whether it is binging and purging, cutting, a suicide attempt, addictive behavior, or restricting food. For a short time, perhaps only minutes, clients report a temporary feeling of control or well-being that reinforces the connection between the aversive feelings, dysregulated arousal, and immediate need for an action that will bring "relief." Because often there is little felt connection between the apparently benign or mildly distressing trigger, the hurt and sadness or shame of child parts, and the impulsive behavior of fight or flight parts, even the client does not understand his or her behavior except as a statement about the actions taken: "I want to kill myself."

自我毁灭行为源于变量的"完美风暴"：首先，一个触发因素唤起创伤相关的内隐记忆。其次，内隐记忆与危险的关联激活紧急应激反应，引发交感神经系统反应，关闭前额叶皮层，损害个体的判断力，并削弱正常生活自我的力量。此时，具有相互冲突防御反应的各部分可以自由地按照其生存本能行事，导致某些旨在带来解脱的行动——无论是暴食清除、切割、自杀未遂、成瘾行为还是限制进食。在短暂的时间内，也许只有几分钟，来访者报告有一种暂时的掌控感或幸福感，这强化了厌恶感受、失调唤醒与立即需要某种能带来"解脱"的行动之间的联系。由于表面上无害或轻微令人苦恼的触发因素、儿童部分的受伤、悲伤或羞耻，与战斗或逃跑部分的冲动行为之间，往往几乎没有感受到的联系，连来访者自己也无法理解其行为，只能通过所采取的行动来表述："我想杀死自己。"

Stabilization of high-risk behavior requires addressing "the parts' part," a step not included even in newer, cutting edge treatments. Dialectical Behavior Therapy (DBT) addresses the skills needed by the normal life part to tolerate the dysregulated emotions of the traumatized parts but does not address fragmentation or how to differentiate the normal life self from the parts. Internal Family Systems (IFS) addresses the role of the parts but conceptualizes self-destructive behavior as an expression of "firefighter" parts trying to suppress vulnerable "exiles" (Schwartz, 2001). In IFS, the normal life self is thought to be a "manager" and its emphasis on functioning just another way to keep the exiles out of mind. In this model, the normal life self is a competent present-moment-oriented aspect of the individual able to provide social judgment and "top-down" behavior management but is also capable of curiosity, compassion, wisdom, courage, and calm. In IFS, those qualities (along with clarity, confidence, and commitment) are reserved for "self" or what I call "wise mind" or the "wise self." Sensorimotor Psychotherapy (Ogden & Fisher, 2015) is the only treatment model for trauma other than Somatic Experiencing, that focuses on the contributions of autonomic dysregulation and animal defenses to post-traumatic stress disorders but lacks, as does IFS, specific interventions to address unsafe behavior. Each (IFS and Sensorimotor) encourages a mindful interest and curiosity in the habitual patterns rather than a solution-oriented approach to safety issues. In IFS, the therapist understands the firefighters as motivated to protect and defend the exiles. In Sensorimotor Psychotherapy, unsafe behavior is framed as a "survival response" to autonomic dysregulation.

高风险行为的稳定化需要处理"各部分的部分"，这一步骤即便在更新的前沿治疗中也未被纳入。辩证行为疗法（DBT）解决了正常生活部分容忍创伤部分失调情绪所需的技能，但没有处理碎裂问题，也没有处理如何将正常生活自我与各部分区分开来。内部家庭系统（IFS）处理了各部分的角色，但将自我毁灭行为概念化为"消防员"部分试图压制脆弱的"流放者"的表达（Schwartz，2001年）。在IFS中，正常生活自我被认为是"管理者"，其对功能运作的强调只是另一种将流放者驱逐出意识的方式。在本模式中，正常生活自我是个体的一个胜任且以当下为导向的方面，能够提供社会判断和"自上而下"的行为管理，同时也能够表现出好奇心、悲悯、智慧、勇气和平静。在IFS中，这些品质（连同清晰、自信和承诺）被保留给"自我"，即我所称的"智慧心智"或"智慧自我"。感觉运动心理治疗（Ogden & Fisher，2015年）是除躯体体验疗法之外唯一关注自主神经失调和动物性防御对创伤后应激障碍贡献的创伤治疗模式，但与IFS一样，缺乏处理不安全行为的具体干预措施。IFS和感觉运动心理治疗都鼓励对习惯性模式保持正念的兴趣和好奇心，而非对安全问题采取以解决为导向的方法。在IFS中，治疗师将消防员理解为受保护和防御流放者动机驱使。在感觉运动心理治疗中，不安全行为被框定为对自主神经失调的"生存反应"。

Trauma-Informed Stabilization Treatment (TIST)

创伤知情稳定化治疗（TIST）

Trauma-informed stabilization treatment (TIST) (Fisher, 2015) is a treatment model developed to stabilize severe self-destructive behavior unresponsive to conventional treatments. TIST was initially developed in the context of a paradigm shift in the State of Connecticut's Young Adult Services, a division under the Department of Mental Health and Substance Abuse. In an attempt to help some of its most severe cases in the age range from 18 to 25, a daring decision was made to explore the impact of trauma-informed approaches, given that a high percentage of these chronically suicidal, self-destructive clients had histories of severe trauma. The patients for whom the program was first designed had been given many different diagnoses over years of mental health treatment in inpatient and residential settings. What they had in common was an early childhood history of trauma followed by symptoms of severe self-injury, suicidality, substance abuse, eating disorders, and aggression toward others, primarily staff. All of them had been hospitalized for more than six months and as long as 10 years. Their difficulties in benefiting from existing treatment models resulted from the lack of a method that could simultaneously address the separate components of their self-destructive behavior: its origins in their traumatic past, trauma-related triggering, loss of perspective and judgment due to cortical inhibition, and the degree of relief experienced as a result of the behavior. By using the structural dissociation model as the theoretical foundation for TIST, each separate variable contributing to unsafe actions in a client could be identified and each of the self-destructive impulses could be externalized and assigned to the appropriate part. That single intervention in and of itself immediately supported the clients' identification with the going on with normal life self, loosening the identification with the suicidal and self-harming impulses. To ensure that the model was not perceived as shaming by clients, all aspects of self (including the suicidal part) are consistently described in terms of their positive contribution to survival.

创伤知情稳定化治疗（TIST）（Fisher，2015年）是一种为稳定对常规治疗无效的严重自我毁灭行为而开发的治疗模式。TIST最初是在康涅狄格州心理健康与物质滥用部门下属的青年成人服务处范式转变的背景下开发的。为了帮助18至25岁年龄段中情况最为严重的案例，鉴于这些长期有自杀倾向、具有自我毁灭性的来访者中有很高比例具有严重创伤史，一个大胆的决定是探索创伤知情方法的影响。该项目最初服务的患者在住院和居住机构的多年心理健康治疗过程中被给予了许多不同的诊断。他们的共同点是早年童年创伤史，继之以严重自伤、自杀倾向、物质滥用、饮食障碍以及对他人（主要是工作人员）的攻击性症状。他们所有人都曾住院超过六个月，最长达10年。他们难以从现有治疗模式中获益，原因在于缺乏一种能够同时处理其自我毁灭行为各个独立组成部分的方法：其在创伤性过去中的根源、创伤相关触发、因皮质抑制导致的判断力和观察力丧失，以及该行为所带来的解脱程度。通过将结构性解离模型作为TIST的理论基础，可以识别来访者不安全行动中每个独立的变量，并将每种自我毁灭冲动外化并归属于适当的部分。这一单一干预本身便立即支持了来访者对正常生活持续自我的认同，松动了对自杀和自伤冲动的认同。为确保该模型不被来访者视为羞辱性的，自我的所有方面（包括自杀部分）都一贯以其对生存的积极贡献来描述。

When treatment models conceptualize self-destructive behavior as pathological, "borderline," or manipulative, and judge inhibition of unsafe impulses as "healthy," attention is diverted away from the underlying issue: the internal struggle between conflicting drives. Should the client seek relief in impulsive action or find a way to bear the pain and go forward? Successful treatment of any conflict requires acknowledgment of all sides or parties involved, not just those toward whom we are biased. Although on the surface it seems that the answer should be easy, it is not. With no hope or belief in the future, with emotional vulnerability intensified by autonomic activation and adrenaline-driven fight-flight impulses wanting discharge, it is hard for traumatized clients to believe that "keeping on keeping on" has much chance of success. To resolve the struggle, clients have to learn to trust that all their parts are committed to survival in different ways; that even their most intensely suicidal parts "want to die in order to live."

当治疗模式将自我毁灭行为概念化为病态的、"边缘性"的或操纵性的，并将抑制不安全冲动判定为"健康"时，注意力便从根本问题上转移开来：冲突驱力之间的内心挣扎。来访者应该在冲动行为中寻求解脱，还是找到一种承受痛苦并前行的方式？任何冲突的成功治疗都需要承认所有各方，而不仅仅是我们所偏向的一方。尽管表面上看答案似乎应该很简单，但事实并非如此。在对未来没有希望或信念的情况下，在自主神经激活和肾上腺素驱动的战斗-逃跑冲动渴望释放使情感脆弱性加剧的情况下，创伤来访者很难相信"坚持下去"还有多少成功的机会。为了解决这一挣扎，来访者必须学会相信他们所有的部分都以不同的方式致力于生存；即便是其最强烈的自杀部分也"想要死去是为了活下去"。

Acknowledging Self-Destructive Parts

承认自我毁灭部分

"I feel suicidal" is an utterance that strikes fear in the heart of any therapist because it implies that the whole being of the client wants to die, that danger is imminent. The TIST model makes a different assumption. It assumes that the wish to suicide reflects the point of view or impulse of one part but not necessarily all. The question we must ask before jumping to any conclusion is: which "I" feels suicidal? The depressed part? A suicidal part? What triggered this part or parts? What is driving the impulse or feeling?

"我有自杀的感觉"是一句让任何治疗师心生恐惧的话，因为它暗示来访者整个存在都想要死去，危险迫在眉睫。TIST模式做出了不同的假设。它假设想要自杀的愿望反映了某一部分的观点或冲动，但不一定代表所有部分。在急于得出任何结论之前，我们必须问：哪个"我"有自杀的感觉？是抑郁部分？是自杀部分？是什么触发了这个或这些部分？是什么在驱动这种冲动或感受？

Once broken down into its component parts, the suicide threat might just mean, "My little part is really sad and disappointed, and the fight part is trying to prevent her from future rejection by threatening suicide." Or it could mean that the suicidal part has been triggered by the child's tears and frightens her to stop the tears. Or perhaps it means that the depressed part just wants to go to sleep and never wake up again. Each of these answers would require a different solution—which we cannot provide without gaining an understanding of the parts. In addition, TIST would ask: where is the normal life self? Why is he or she missing in action? What could the normal life part do to find out more about what is happening or to soothe distressed parts? Is the normal life self temporarily disempowered by the intense emotions and impulses of the child parts or the fight and flight parts? Or is the going on with normal life self just watching helplessly from a distance?

一旦分解为各组成部分，自杀威胁或许只是意味着："我的小部分真的很悲伤和失望，而战斗部分正试图通过威胁自杀来防止她未来再遭拒绝。"或者它可能意味着，自杀部分被孩子的眼泪所触发，并以恐吓她来让她停止哭泣。又或者它意味着抑郁部分只是想入睡，再也不醒来。这些答案中的每一个都需要不同的解决方案——如果不了解各部分，我们就无法提供。此外，TIST会问：正常生活自我在哪里？为什么他/她缺席了？正常生活部分能做什么来进一步了解正在发生的事情，或安抚苦恼的部分？正常生活自我是否暂时被儿童部分或战斗和逃跑部分的强烈情绪和冲动所削弱？还是正常生活持续自我只是在远处无助地旁观？

Most human beings would agree that criticism is not motivating; that suppressing or blocking feelings results in either depression or anger. Yet these are often the treatment approaches used with suicidal, self-destructive, eating disorder and addicted clients. The message is: these impulses or behaviors are wrong—they are dangerous—and we are going to help you stop engaging in them. To fight and flight parts, this approach is tantamount to waving a red flag at the proverbial bull. It alienates and polarizes the parts whose trust we most want to win, whose motives we want to understand. It can undermine a normal life self who is sincerely trying to work with treatment providers but keeps being told she or he is not trying hard enough—when in fact no amount of "trying" by the normal life self can stop parts driven by adrenaline and convinced that their only safety lies in action. In the TIST model, the intentions of a part are differentiated from its actions: what is the suicidal fight hoping to accomplish? How is it trying to protect the client? The following example describes the first client treated with the TIST model as it was first being developed in a state hospital setting. Katya illustrates how switching from a uni-consciousness model to a parts model and from a treatment method for borderline personality to a treatment approach for trauma could quickly change the treatment picture:

大多数人会同意，批评并没有激励作用；压制或封堵情感只会导致抑郁或愤怒。然而，这些往往正是用于自杀、自我毁灭、饮食障碍和成瘾来访者的治疗方法。传递的信息是：这些冲动或行为是错误的——它们是危险的——我们将帮助你停止它们。对战斗和逃跑部分而言，这种方法无异于向公牛挥舞红旗。它疏远和两极化了那些我们最想赢得信任、最想理解其动机的部分。它可能破坏一个真诚地试图与治疗提供者合作的正常生活自我，却不断被告知他/她努力得不够——而事实上，正常生活自我无论多么努力，都无法阻止那些被肾上腺素驱动、坚信其唯一的安全在于行动的部分。在TIST模式中，部分的意图与其行动被区分开来：自杀性战斗部分希望实现什么？它是如何试图保护来访者的？以下例子描述了在州立医院环境中TIST模式初创时治疗的第一位来访者。卡佳说明了从单一意识模式转换到部分模式，以及从边缘性人格障碍的治疗方法转换到创伤治疗方法，是如何能够迅速改变治疗面貌的：

Katya had been hospitalized now for well over 2 years because of her unrelenting suicidality and self-injury, drug use, and violence toward staff. Although Katya recognized the role of her fight part once the new treatment model was described to her and validated its contribution to her survival, its determination seemed to increase with each unsafe event. Sometimes, Katya could unblend and differentiate herself from the fight part's violent impulses by repeating as a mantra: "It's just the fight part—it's just the fight part—I don't have to do what it says." But sometimes the fight part hijacked her seemingly "behind her back," and suddenly an act of aggressive or self-harming behavior would occur. Worried that the suicidal fight part was treading too close to the edge, I decided it was time that Katya and I found out what was driving it. I inquired, "Could you ask the suicidal part what it's worried about if it pauses and takes some time to let you work on all this? What is the suicidal part afraid will happen if it stops trying to kill you?"
Even Katya was surprised by the answer. "The fight part says: 'It's the only way to push people away—they can't hurt you if they can't get close.'" In the hospital, she had developed close relationships to certain staff who would comfort her little parts, joke around with the adolescent parts, and connect to her normal life self. But the fight part had pushed away her family and successfully convinced her fiancé to end their engagement because he couldn't tolerate the fear that she might die. Hearing the suicidal part's agenda evoked panic in her attach part and worry in her normal life self: what about her wish to love and be loved? To marry and have children someday?
As I coached her, Katya asked the suicidal part: "What would you need from me to trust that I could handle these relationships that I want to have?" The suicidal part replied, "I would have to believe that you would be OK, that you couldn't be devastated." It would take many months for Katya to prove herself to the fight part and many more months to finally be approved for discharge from the state hospital.
Today, she lives on her own, with the love and companionship of her cat, the closest comfort to her attach part and the emotional center and regulator of any negative feelings. She is proud to have grown into the normal life she once dreamed about, a life that includes college classes as well as caring for herself, her apartment, and her cat. The fight part now trusts her to choose relationships well and to soothe parts that might feel hurt or rejected by others before their implicit memories are triggered and become overwhelming. She in turn trusts the fight part to discriminate when people are taking advantage of her or expecting too much. Now, with growing communication and collaboration, Katya can heed the fight part's warnings and set boundaries before it reacts aggressively to potential threat. Her ability to comfort the attach part reduces the sense of aloneness and vulnerability, allowing the fight part to sit back and leave her to do her job.

By learning to "ask inside," Katya learned how to dialogue with her fight part, rather than interpreting its behavior, until she finally discovered why it was so determined to lead her down a self-destructive path, even if that meant she was "incarcerated" on a locked ward in a state hospital. When the fight part acknowledged its primary purpose was to keep her safe from any attachment, even to her parents, the last few years suddenly made sense to her. Knowing how much she and her attach part yearned for closeness, she had immediately understood what she'd have to do to be free to live her life as she wished it to be, rather than the way her traumatic experiences had dictated that it be. Having almost died many times, it was clear that her fight part was unyielding and would ultimately have its way if she didn't do something different.

通过学习"向内询问"，卡佳学会了如何与她的战斗部分对话，而不是解读其行为，直到她最终发现它为何如此坚定地引导她走上自我毁灭之路，即便这意味着她被"关押"在州立医院的上锁病房里。当战斗部分承认其主要目的是保护她免受任何依恋的伤害——甚至包括对父母的依恋——过去几年突然对她来说变得有意义了。知道她和她的依恋部分多么渴望亲密，她立刻明白了她必须做什么，才能自由地过上她希望的生活，而不是她创伤性经历所规定的生活。几乎死过多次，很明显她的战斗部分是不屈不挠的，如果她不做些不同的事情，它最终将以自己的方式行事。

Today, Katya is not reliant on anyone other than her cat for regulating her emotions and actions. She takes no psychiatric medications, no longer goes to therapy, and has been discharged from the Department of Mental Health system. The parts seem to feel safe with her, safe enough to allow her to set up a Facebook page to make contact with others and share her story of survival and redemption. When she first was assigned to the new "trauma program" I developed in the hospital, the pilot version of what has become the TIST approach, she immediately felt a sense of pride: she wasn't sick; she had been harmed, and she was receiving special services as a result. With a basic understanding of trauma that helped her see her symptoms as logical and meaningful, she felt less unworthy. As a "trauma patient," she was being treated as someone who deserved something more than medication, restraints, and injury-proof hospital rooms, someone who was intelligent and capable of participating in her own recovery. She kept repeating to her staff, "I needed a trauma program, and I finally got one—this is what I've needed all this time."

The opportunity to change her relationship to her symptoms, to make meaning of them as a legacy of the trauma, and to externalize them as communications from her parts all helped Katya to "disidentify" or "unblend" from the parts, rather than continuing to interpret their actions and reactions as her own. She could begin to differentiate her willingness to work therapeutically as evidence of an intelligent, motivated normal life self and feel a greater alliance with the staff who wanted to help her, rather than "believing" the hypervigilant suspicions of her fight part or the desperate seeking of contact and validation coming from the attach part. As she identified with her normal life self, without a loss of compassion and loyalty to her young parts, they relaxed ever so slightly—enough that she was less often triggered and more often able to recognize when she was. This process of separating "whom she was meant to be" from the actions and reactions of the parts and learning to regulate their strong responses sufficiently so she could interrupt the fight part's acting out took several years. It required a few of the staff who embraced the TIST model to repeatedly and consistently help her translate her emotions into parts language, connect the feelings and impulses to those parts, feel empathy toward them, and, trusting that this process would allow her to avoid acting on the fight part's impulses, tolerate the risk that she might die before her team could help her learn how to help the parts.

改变她与症状的关系、将它们理解为创伤遗留的意义，以及将它们外化为来自各部分的信息——所有这些都帮助卡佳从各部分"去认同"或"去融合"，而不是继续将它们的行动和反应解读为她自己的。她开始能够将自己在治疗上的合作意愿区分为一个智慧、有动力的正常生活自我的证据，并对想要帮助她的工作人员产生更强的联盟感，而不是"相信"战斗部分的过度警觉的猜疑，或来自依恋部分的对接触和认可的迫切寻求。当她认同自己的正常生活自我，同时不失去对年幼部分的悲悯和忠诚时，这些部分放松了些许——足以让她较少被触发，也更常能够识别出何时被触发了。这一将"她本应成为的人"与各部分的行动和反应分离、并学会充分调节其强烈反应以便能够中断战斗部分的付诸行动的过程，耗费了数年时间。这需要一些接受TIST模式的工作人员反复且持续地帮助她将情绪转化为部分语言，将感受和冲动与这些部分连接起来，对它们产生共情，并在相信这一过程能让她避免按战斗部分的冲动行事的情况下，承受着她可能在团队帮助她学会如何帮助各部分之前就会死去的风险。

Soothing the Vulnerable, Honoring the Protectors

安抚脆弱部分，尊重保护者部分

As in Katya's case, suicidal and self-destructive parts are typically activated by the distress of younger parts associated with the experience of traumatic attachment. In the TIST model, the major focus is not on inhibiting the impulses of the fight and flight parts. It is on anticipating and soothing the emotional activation of young, vulnerable parts before the fight and flight parts take action. First, clients are helped to recognize the signs and symptoms of distressed child parts because even before the client has the ability to "help" them, their appearance can be used to anticipate unsafe situations. The therapist must model mindful observation of "domino effects," patterns in which triggered parts trigger other parts that trigger other parts that eventually trigger fight or flight.

如卡佳的案例所示，自杀和自我毁灭部分通常由与创伤性依恋体验相关的年幼部分的苦恼所激活。在TIST模式中，主要关注点不在于抑制战斗和逃跑部分的冲动，而在于在战斗和逃跑部分采取行动之前，预判并安抚年幼、脆弱部分的情绪激活。首先，帮助来访者识别苦恼的儿童部分的体征和症状，因为即便在来访者有能力"帮助"它们之前，这些表现也可以用来预判不安全情况。治疗师必须示范对"多米诺效应"的正念观察——被触发的部分触发其他部分，其他部分再触发更多部分，最终触发战斗或逃跑反应的模式。

I decided it was important to make Terri aware of the relationship I was seeing between her suicidality and a disowned young part of her. Because I believe that timing and readiness are everything in psychotherapy, I had waited several months—until a moment when Terri expressed her own anxiety about the prospect of future crises: "My boss told me that if I'm hospitalized again, he can't keep me on in my job. No matter how good I am at it. I don't know what to do. I can't tell him I'll never make another suicide attempt!"

ME: "Hmmm … That is a problem, isn't it? Maybe there is a way around this. I'm observing a pattern: have you ever noticed that the suicidal part only gets activated when your depressed 13-year-old is having a hard time? I know you try to ignore her so you can keep working, but I think being ignored just reminds her of never being seen—never feeling she mattered to anyone. It seems to me that the suicidal part deserves to be thanked for getting us to listen to the 13-year-old at last! I don't think the suicidal part wants to die (or kill anyone), but it's clearly stating that it won't stand for her to be left alone to suffer." At first, Terri pooh-poohed this theory and insisted she didn't have parts, so it was irrelevant. I nonetheless continued to watch for signs of the 13-year-old's deepening depressions so I could warn Terri that the suicidal part wouldn't be far behind.

In this instance, the depressed part was a very accurate barometer for anticipating the sudden impulsive actions of the suicidal part, which almost always resulted in months of hospitalization. By intervening to help the 13-year-old by acknowledging her distress before a crisis ensued, suicide attempts could be more predictably warded off in time to prevent threats to her job and threat to life.

在这个例子中，抑郁部分是预判自杀部分突然冲动行动的非常准确的晴雨表，而这几乎总是导致数月的住院治疗。通过在危机发生之前干预、承认13岁部分的苦恼来帮助她，自杀未遂可以更可预测地被及时阻止，防止对她工作和生命的威胁。

Often, depressed parts are the triggers for unsafe behavior. Sometimes, parts who communicate via flashbacks and memories are instigators of fight or flight parts: the body and emotional memories of young parts intrude upon the consciousness of the normal life self to communicate that they are afraid they'll be hurt again, that no one will believe them, that they need protection. The somatic message that things are still unsafe might then trigger fight parts to protective action, for example, to end the risk of being hurt again forever. Ashamed parts are also triggering for the fight part, evoking a painful vulnerability that is intolerable to a part whose biological imperative is to gain control over the enemy. When the therapist can predict the risk ahead of time and help the client's normal life self provide soothing and a sense of no longer being alone to the vulnerable parts, the risk of impulsive behavior diminishes dramatically. Clients are taught the Internal Dialogue Technique (see Appendix C) and asked to practice it in therapy sessions until their ability to regulate parts' unbearable feelings grows sufficiently that they can use it independently of the therapist.

抑郁部分往往是不安全行为的触发因素。有时，通过闪回和记忆进行沟通的部分是战斗或逃跑部分的煽动者：年幼部分的躯体和情感记忆侵入正常生活自我的意识，传递出它们害怕再次受伤、没有人会相信它们、它们需要保护的信息。事情仍然不安全的躯体信息可能随后触发战斗部分采取保护性行动，例如，永远终结再次受伤的风险。羞耻部分也会触发战斗部分，唤起一种令生物命令是控制敌人的部分难以承受的痛苦脆弱感。当治疗师能够提前预判风险，并帮助来访者的正常生活自我为脆弱部分提供安抚感和不再孤单的感受时，冲动行为的风险会大幅降低。来访者被教授内部对话技术（见附录C），并被要求在治疗会谈中练习，直到其调节各部分难以承受感受的能力充分增长，能够独立于治疗师使用为止。

"No Part Left Behind"

"不遗弃任何部分"

"No part left behind" is the motto clients are taught and the standard to which they are held. This standard challenges the survival strategy of self-alienation. As functional as the normal life self might be, he or she will not be allowed to abandon the parts responsible for survival. The ashamed part, the frightened part, the addicted or eating disordered flight part, or the suicidal, the angry, self-injurious or justice-seeking fight part: all deserve respect and compassion.

"不遗弃任何部分"是教给来访者的座右铭，也是对他们的要求标准。这一标准挑战了自我疏离的生存策略。无论正常生活自我多么有功能，都不允许他/她抛弃那些负责生存的部分。羞耻部分、恐惧部分、成瘾或饮食障碍的逃跑部分，或自杀的、愤怒的、自伤的或追求公正的战斗部分：所有这些都值得尊重和悲悯。

When clients are held to the "no part left behind" standard in therapy, the threat of abandonment, which for children is as frightening as the threat of annihilation, is lifted. The parts, hearing the therapist speak on their behalf, have a reparative experience: someone has heard them. The normal life self, I know, will also feel grateful later on as the parts' attachment to him or her grows. Being loved by a small child feels pleasurable to both parties, as every parent knows. And when a mindful normal life self can interpret their implicit memories as "just a feeling" or "just a memory" and develop greater ability to soothe and regulate "their" responses, the parts begin to feel safer. Now a new, safer and more satisfying internal environment can be established.

当来访者在治疗中被要求遵守"不遗弃任何部分"的标准时，遗弃的威胁——对儿童来说与消灭的威胁一样令人恐惧——得以解除。各部分听到治疗师代表它们说话，获得了一种修复性体验：有人听到了它们。正常生活自我，我知道，随着各部分对他/她的依恋增长，也会在日后感到感激。被一个小孩子爱着，对双方来说都是令人愉悦的，这是每位父母都知道的。当一个正念的正常生活自我能够将其内隐记忆解读为"只是一种感受"或"只是一段记忆"，并发展出更强的安抚和调节"它们的"反应的能力时，这些部分开始感到更安全了。一个新的、更安全、更令人满意的内部环境现在可以建立起来了。

In a world that feels safe or safer, traumatized clients can learn to use their capacity for inner communication to co-create a life they were "meant to have," rather than living a life dictated by the trauma. Each part can play a valuable role after trauma. Not only do the parts offer survival defense responses but other important resources as well related to their specialized roles. The fight response, for example, provides increased energy, "grit" or determination, a "backbone," refusal to give way, and the ability to guard our rights and privileges. As the client's normal life self learns to ask the fight part to "give me courage to say No," or "give me the strength to hold my ground," there is a surge of energy or increased strength in the core or spine. The normal life part now has other resources for change and growth; the freeze part feels a bodily sense of being protected; the submit part is not freely "used" by others, and there is energy to counteract its depressive hypoarousal; the flight part doesn't have to run for cover because the parts are safe "here now."

在一个感觉安全或更安全的世界里，创伤来访者可以学习利用内在沟通能力来共同创造一种他们"本应拥有"的生活，而不是过一种被创伤所支配的生活。每个部分在创伤后都可以发挥有价值的作用。各部分不仅提供生存防御反应，还提供与其专门角色相关的其他重要资源。例如，战斗反应提供了增加的能量、"勇气"或决心、"脊梁"、拒绝退让的意志，以及维护我们权利和特权的能力。当来访者的正常生活自我学会请求战斗部分"给我勇气说不"，或"给我坚守立场的力量"时，核心或脊柱会涌现出一股能量或增强的力量。正常生活部分现在拥有了其他变化和成长的资源；冻结部分感受到被保护的躯体感；顺从部分不再被他人随意"利用"，并有能量来对抗其抑郁性的低度唤醒；逃跑部分不必再逃跑躲藏，因为各部分在"此时此地"是安全的。

Robert was a tall gaunt 70-year-old man, tormented since his early 20s by voices warning him that someone wanted to kill him. Having witnessed his mother beaten nearly to death by his abusive father, the fear of being killed was very familiar to him, and since he was a young boy, it could only be soothed by the longing for death. Only his devout Catholic faith prevented him from committing suicide, no matter how much he felt compelled to end his life.
After 2 years of helping him stay alive, I was in his hospital room to say goodbye as he faced death from end-stage cancer. His "wish" was at hand, and he was terrified. "All my life, I've longed to die—but now that I'm really dying, I'm scared—wanting to die gave me control—dying is taking it away." In the 20 years since I said goodbye at his bedside, I've taken his wisdom with me: wanting to die is about taking control, not about wanting death.

References

Faris, P., Hofbauer, R., Daughters, R., Vandenlangenberg, E., Iversen, L., Goodale, R., Maxwell, R., Eckert, E., & Hartman, B. (2008). De-stabilization of the positive vago-vagal reflex in bulimia nervosa. Physiology & Behavior, 94(1), 136–153. DOI: 10.1016/j.physbeh.2007.11.036.

Fisher, J. (2015). The trauma-informed stabilization treatment model. Two-day workshop. Toronto, Canada: Leading Edge Seminars.

Herman, J. L. (1992). Trauma and recovery. New York: Basic Books.

Khoury, L., Tang, Y.L., Beck, B., Kubells, J. F., & Ressler, K.J. (2010). Substance use, childhood traumatic experience, and posttraumatic stress disorder in an urban civilian population. Depress Anxiety, 27(12), 1077–1086.

Krysinska, K. & Lester, D. (2010). Post-traumatic stress disorder and suicide risk: a systematic review. Archives of Suicide Research, 14(1), 1–23.

Linehan, M. M. (1993). Cognitive-behavioral treatment of borderline personality disorder. New York: Guilford Press.

Liotti, G. (2011). Attachment disorganization and the controlling strategies: an illustration of the contributions of attachment theory to developmental psychopathology and to psychotherapy integration. Journal of Psychotherapy Integration, 21(3), 232–252.

Miller, D. (1994). Women who hurt themselves: a book of hope and understanding. New York: Basic Books.

Min, M., Farkas, K., Minnes, S., & Singer, L.T. (2007). Impact of childhood abuse and neglect on substance abuse and psychological distress in adulthood. Journal of Traumatic Stress, 20(5), 833–844.

Najavits, L. M. (2002). Seeking safety: a treatment manual for PTSD and substance abuse. New York: Guilford Press.

Ogden, P. & Fisher, J. (2015). Sensorimotor Psychotherapy: interventions for trauma and attachment. New York: W.W. Norton.

Schwartz, R. (2001). Introduction to the internal family systems model. Oak Park, IL: Trailhead Publications.

Teicher, M.H. et al. (2002). Developmental neurobiology of childhood stress and trauma. Psychiatric Clinics of North America, 25(2), 397–426.

CHAPTER 8
Treatment Challenges: Dissociative Systems and Disorders

第8章
治疗挑战：解离系统与解离障碍

"Dissociation is the essence of trauma. The overwhelming experience is split off and fragmented so that the emotions, sounds, images, thoughts and physical sensations related to the trauma take on a life of their own. The sensory fragments of memory intrude into the present, where they are literally relived. As long as the trauma is not resolved, the stress hormones the body secretes to protect itself keep circulating, and the defensive movements and emotional responses keep getting played out."

"解离是创伤的本质。压倒性的经历被分裂和碎裂，使得与创伤相关的情绪、声音、图像、思想和身体感觉各自独立存在。记忆的感觉碎片侵入当下，在那里被真实地重新体验。只要创伤未被解决，身体为保护自身而分泌的应激激素就会持续循环，防御性动作和情绪反应也会不断地被演绎出来。"

(Van der Kolk, 2014, p. 66)

"The concept of a single, unitary 'self' is as misleading as the concept of a single unitary 'brain.' The left and right hemispheres process information in their own unique fashion and represent a conscious left brain self system and an unconscious right brain self system."

"单一、统一的'自我'这一概念，与单一统一的'大脑'这一概念一样具有误导性。左右半球以各自独特的方式处理信息，分别代表着有意识的左脑自我系统和无意识的右脑自我系统。"

(Schore, A., 2011, p. 76)

In the 1950s, what was then called "multiple personality disorder" came to the attention of mental health professionals initially through books such as The Three Faces of Eve and Sybil. It was controversial and much disputed then, and today, dissociative disorders are still the subject of controversy. Even before therapists encounter a dissociative identity disorder (DID) client, they will have been affected by the anxiety and even hostility raised by any mention of the diagnosis among mental health professionals. The "countertransference" reaction to the idea that individuals can have multiple consciousness, parts with separate identities or separate lives often pits psychiatrists (least likely to believe such disorders exist) against psychologists and psychotherapists who have evidence that it does because they have encountered its distinctive symptoms and presentation. Since the 1950s, dissociative disorders have often been assumed to be "factitious disorders," an assumption that is rarely questioned—and rarely documented. In the context of the institutional bias against it, the field has overlooked or ignored research that validates the reliability of the diagnosis of DID and demonstrates that it is much more common in the population than hitherto believed (Brand et al., 2012; 2016). Though there has been more published research on dissociative symptoms in borderline personality disorder and more establishing the under-diagnosing of dissociative disorders than on demonstrating that DID is a factitious disorder, the field of trauma and dissociation has never been able to shed that stereotype. Korzekwa et al. (2009) and Zanarini (1998), for example, have consistently found statistically significant rates of dissociative symptoms in borderline personality and strong correlations between severity of dissociative symptoms and severity of borderline symptoms, including rates of self-injury and suicidality, depression, global psychopathology, behavior problems, and use of psychiatric services. That strong evidence base is rarely mentioned in the literature on borderline personality disorder. Despite the need for better, more effective models for treating clients diagnosed as borderline, their dissociative symptoms are rarely noted or treated. When I was asked in 2008 to consult to a state hospital and provide training in "trauma-informed care," I was told upfront, "We don't have DID patients here. Our trauma patients are all borderlines." I understood the message. It was clear: "Don't come in here and start diagnosing our patients with DID. If you want to work with us, leave that particular diagnosis at the door." I was untroubled, though. I was bringing to the hospital a training on trauma and a model for understanding unsafe behavior and suicidality, the Structural Dissociation model. To reassure the staff, I just kept saying, "This is a trauma model, not a dissociative disorders model. And it is the best approach to borderline personality that I have encountered in 25 years." If that is not enough to allay anxiety, I say, "The parts language gives clients a way to externalize the problem so they can change their relationship to it—the same way eating disordered clients do better when they externalize their eating disorders as 'Ed.'" All of these statements are true. Whether one believes that each part represents the implicit memories of a child or believes in using the language simply to externalize the behavior, the approach described in this book is helpful to the client. And that is what brings together the skeptics and the believers.

在20世纪50年代，当时被称为"多重人格障碍"的疾病最初通过《夏娃的三张面孔》和《西比尔》等书籍引起了心理健康专业人士的关注。那时它就充满争议且备受质疑，时至今日，解离障碍仍然是争议的对象。甚至在治疗师接触到解离性身份障碍（DID）来访者之前，他们就已经受到了心理健康专业人士中每当提及这一诊断时所引发的焦虑乃至敌意的影响。对于个体可以拥有多重意识、具有独立身份或独立生活的各部分这一观念，"反移情"反应往往使精神科医生（最不相信此类障碍存在的群体）与心理学家及心理治疗师对立起来——后者因亲历其独特症状和表现而拥有其确实存在的证据。自20世纪50年代以来，解离障碍常常被假定为"人为障碍"，这一假设鲜少受到质疑，也鲜少有据可查。在机构偏见的背景下，该领域忽视或无视了验证DID诊断可靠性并证明其在人群中比以往认为的更为普遍的研究（Brand等，2012；2016）。尽管已发表的关于边缘性人格障碍中解离症状的研究，以及证明解离障碍被漏诊的研究，都多于证明DID是人为障碍的研究，但创伤与解离领域始终未能摆脱这一刻板印象。例如，Korzekwa等（2009）和Zanarini（1998）持续发现边缘性人格障碍中解离症状的发生率在统计学上具有显著性，且解离症状严重程度与边缘性症状严重程度之间存在强相关，包括自伤和自杀率、抑郁、整体精神病理学、行为问题以及精神科服务使用情况。这一强有力的证据基础在边缘性人格障碍文献中几乎从未被提及。尽管迫切需要更好、更有效的模型来治疗被诊断为边缘性的来访者，其解离症状却鲜少被注意或治疗。2008年，当我受邀为一家州立医院提供咨询并开展"创伤知情照护"培训时，对方开门见山地告诉我："我们这里没有DID患者。我们的创伤患者都是边缘性人格。"我明白了这个信息。意思很清楚："别进来就给我们的患者诊断DID。如果你想和我们合作，就把那个特定诊断留在门外。"但我并不为此苦恼。我带去的是一个关于创伤的培训以及一个理解不安全行为和自杀意念的模型——结构性解离模型。为了安抚工作人员，我反复说："这是一个创伤模型，而不是解离障碍模型。而且这是我在25年从业生涯中遇到的处理边缘性人格的最佳方法。"如果这还不足以消除焦虑，我会说："'部分'的语言为来访者提供了一种将问题外化的方式，使他们能够改变与问题的关系——就像饮食障碍来访者将饮食障碍外化为'Ed'后表现更好一样。"这些说法都是正确的。无论你相信每个部分代表着一个孩子的内隐记忆，还是仅仅相信使用这种语言来将行为外化，本书所描述的方法对来访者都是有益的。而这正是将怀疑者和信服者聚集在一起的原因。

Recognizing the DID Client

识别DID来访者

Since the statistical probability of therapists encountering a DID or DDNOS client is fairly high (especially for those who treat trauma, borderline, or suicidal clients), it behooves therapists to be familiar with the diagnostic and treatment challenges of treating dissociative disorders (Brand et al., 2016). In this chapter, we will describe the special challenges of working with clients whose parts are not only structurally dissociated but also function autonomously, often with little to no awareness of the others. Although the theoretical model and the treatment are almost the same as described in previous chapters, a dissociative disorder brings with it special complications for the therapist, not just for the client.

由于治疗师遇到DID或其他未特指的解离障碍（DDNOS）来访者的统计概率相当高（尤其是那些治疗创伤、边缘性人格或有自杀倾向的来访者的治疗师），治疗师有必要熟悉治疗解离障碍的诊断和治疗挑战（Brand等，2016）。在本章中，我们将描述与各部分不仅结构性解离、而且自主运作、往往彼此几乎毫无意识的来访者工作所带来的特殊挑战。尽管理论模型和治疗方法与前几章所描述的几乎相同，但解离障碍为治疗师带来了特殊的复杂性，而不仅仅是对来访者而言。

DSM-5 and ICD-9 diagnostic systems both have a "bottom line" criterion for a diagnosis of DID: making the diagnosis requires "evidence of losses of consciousness: two or more parts of the personality take control of the body and operate outside of conscious awareness" (DSM-IV-R, p. 2000).

DSM-5和ICD-9诊断系统对DID诊断都有一个"底线"标准：作出诊断需要"意识丧失的证据：两个或两个以上人格部分控制身体并在意识觉知之外运作"（DSM-IV-R，第2000页）。

Assigned to the inpatient unit during my predoctoral internship, my very first patient was a 40-year-old writer diagnosed as acutely psychotic. Caitlyn was besieged by scathing, humiliating voices telling her to kill herself. "You're a cunt—a whore—you don't deserve to live—make this world a better place." Not knowing that clients with psychotic disorders are generally made worse when their delusions are questioned, I made the rookie mistake of suggesting that she take a stand: "Explain to the voices that they are not helping you get you discharged—you need them to back off a bit if they want you to get out of here." To the amazement of both of us, the voices responded: by the next day, they had quieted enough to win her a discharge. Two admissions later, the reason for my spectacular success became clear: Caitlyn had a dissociative disorder, not a psychotic disorder. Arriving at the hospital to meet with her, I found my stout 40-year-old patient wandering around the unit wearing a lace tutu and combat boots! "It's been a strange day," she said in a lost confused tone, "This morning, I couldn't remember how to put my clothes on …" and her voice trailed off. As I opened the door to the meeting room, she froze on the doorstep and started screaming, "What are you doing to me?! Who are you? Where's my mommy?!!!!" When you've been a mother before becoming a therapist, you have certain instincts. One skill you never lose is the ability to know what to say when children are freaking out. "It's OK," I instinctively began speaking to her as if to a young child: "Your mom knows where you are. I talked to her today. [Which I had.] She knows you're with me, and she said it was OK—do you want me to call her?" Calming down a little but keeping her distance from me, she began to wander around the bare hospital office like a child exploring the room while I made conversation with a child in an adult's body: "Your mom didn't tell me how old you are or if you go to school."

在我博士前实习期间被分配到住院病区时，我的第一位患者是一位被诊断为急性精神病发作的40岁作家。Caitlyn被那些尖刻、羞辱性的声音所围困，那些声音告诉她去自杀。"你是个臭婊子——一个妓女——你不值得活着——让这个世界变得更美好吧。"不知道患有精神病性障碍的来访者在其妄想受到质疑时通常会变得更糟，我犯了一个新手错误，建议她采取立场："向那些声音解释，它们无助于你出院——如果它们想让你离开这里，就需要稍微退让一些。" 令我们双方都惊讶的是，那些声音回应了：到第二天，它们已经足够安静，赢得了她的出院许可。两次住院后，我这一辉煌成功的原因变得清晰起来：Caitlyn患有解离障碍，而非精神病性障碍。当我到医院去见她时，我发现我那位健壮的40岁患者穿着蕾丝芭蕾短裙和军靴在病区里游荡！"今天是奇怪的一天，"她用迷茫困惑的语气说，"今天早上，我想不起来怎么穿衣服了……"声音逐渐消散。当我打开会议室的门时，她在门槛上僵住了，开始尖叫："你对我做了什么？！你是谁？我妈妈在哪里？！！！！" 当你在成为治疗师之前已经是一位母亲，你就拥有某些本能。有一种技能是你永远不会失去的，那就是当孩子恐慌时知道该说什么。"没事的，"我本能地开始像对待小孩子一样跟她说话："你妈妈知道你在哪里。我今天和她谈过了。[确实如此。]她知道你和我在一起，她说没问题——你想让我打电话给她吗？"她稍微平静下来，但与我保持着距离，开始像一个探索房间的孩子一样在简陋的医院办公室里游荡，而我则与一个住在成人身体里的孩子攀谈："你妈妈没有告诉我你几岁，也没有说你是否上学。"

CAITLYN: "I'm 6, and I'm in the red reading group!" [Smiles proudly] Everyone knows that's the best one." The big smile wasn't the smile of a proud woman—I could see the grin of that 6-year-old. My heart ached for her: 6 was the year in which this innocent little girl in the red reading group had been raped by her older brother, bullied by neighborhood boys, and emotionally abandoned and unprotected by her alcoholic mother. Before she was used and abused, my client had once been this confident little girl who was proud of how smart she was and eager to learn.

CAITLYN："我6岁，我在红色阅读小组！"[骄傲地微笑]"每个人都知道那是最好的一组。"那个灿烂的笑容不是一个骄傲女人的笑容——我能看出那个6岁小女孩的咧嘴笑。我的心为她而痛：6岁那年，这个天真无邪的红色阅读小组的小女孩被她的哥哥强暴，被邻居男孩霸凌，被她酗酒的母亲在情感上遗弃和不加保护。在被利用和虐待之前，我的来访者曾经是这个对自己的聪明感到骄傲、渴望学习的自信小女孩。

Thanks to Caitlyn, I learned some important lessons very quickly: first, DID (or multiple personality disorder [MPD] as we called it in the early 1990s) really does exist; second, my previous "job experience" raising small children and working with families was going to make working with dissociative disorders remarkably easier—not easy but easier. What I did not know (but would soon learn) was that my success with the little 6-year-old part of Caitlyn would very shortly stand in stark contrast to my ability to enrage other parts of her! Yet another lesson useful for the novice therapist I was then: "You can't please all the parts all of the time."

感谢Caitlyn，我很快学到了一些重要的课程：第一，DID（或我们在20世纪90年代初所称的多重人格障碍[MPD]）确实存在；第二，我之前养育小孩和与家庭合作的"工作经验"将使与解离障碍的工作变得显著更容易——不是容易，而是更容易。我当时不知道（但很快就会了解到）的是，我与Caitlyn那个6岁小女孩部分的成功，将很快与我激怒她其他部分的能力形成鲜明对比！这对当时还是新手治疗师的我来说又是一个有益的教训："你无法在所有时候取悦所有部分。"

Diagnosing Dissociative Disorders

诊断解离障碍

Steinberg (2013) describes five symptom clusters characteristically found in dissociative disorders that facilitate making the diagnosis:

Steinberg（2013）描述了解离障碍中具有特征性的五个症状群，有助于作出诊断：

• Dissociative amnesia or "missing time" (i.e., amnesia for periods of time after the age of nine or gaps in daily memory not explicable by ordinary forgetfulness).

• 解离性遗忘或"时间失去"（即对九岁以后某段时间的遗忘，或日常记忆中无法用普通遗忘解释的空白）。

• Dissociative fugue: finding one's self in an unfamiliar location with no memory of having planned to go there and no recognition of others around one. Sometimes, fugue episodes are accompanied by dissociative amnesia, the loss of memory for personal information, such as one's name, address, age, and job or significant others.

• 解离性漫游：发现自己身处一个陌生的地点，没有任何关于计划前往那里的记忆，也认不出周围的人。有时，漫游发作伴随着解离性遗忘，即对个人信息的记忆丧失，如姓名、地址、年龄、工作或重要他人。

• Depersonalization (feeling disconnected from one's self or one's experience)

• 人格解体（感到与自身或自身体验脱离）

• Derealization (experiencing other people or familiar surroundings as "unreal")

• 现实解体（体验到其他人或熟悉的环境是"不真实的"）

• Identity confusion ("Who am I?"): Am I the person who functions? Or is that a false self? Am I needy and clingy? Or militantly independent? Do I want to live or do I want to die?

• 身份混乱（"我是谁？"）：我是那个能正常运作的人吗？还是那是一个虚假的自我？我是渴求且依赖的吗？还是强烈地独立？我想活着还是想死？

• Identity alteration: regression experiences, feelings or behavior that do not feel like "mine," being known by different names, evidence of child parts (stuffed animals, sucking ones thumb, being afraid to be alone), or evidence of activities for which one has no memory.

• 身份改变：退行体验，感受或行为感觉不像"我的"，被不同的名字称呼，儿童部分的证据（毛绒玩具、吮拇指、害怕独处），或对某些活动没有记忆的证据。

Psychotic-like symptoms, such as hearing voices, internal dialogues, intrusive voices, thoughts, images, and visual "hallucinations" of the trauma, are also potential signs of a dissociative disorder. These symptoms all represent implicit memory and/or manifestations of parts but unfortunately tend to be diagnosed as symptoms of schizophrenia despite demonstrable differences between trauma-related voices and auditory hallucinations. Dorahy et al. (2009) compared the voices described by two groups of schizophrenic patients (one with histories of trauma and one with no reported trauma) with the voices reported by a group of patients diagnosed with DID. The researchers found that, in this sample, the DID subjects reported hearing voices at a more frequent rate than did the schizophrenic subjects. They also described the voices as having different genders and ages, and they summarized the content of the voices' communications as generally negative and personally directed, focused on pointing out the individual's inadequacies, lack of worth, and using these accusations to justify "why you deserve to die." The voices reported by schizophrenic clients were fewer in number, did not have different ages or genders, and spoke from a more abstract spiritual or paranoid perspective, not a personal one, even if also encouraging self-destruction.

类精神病症状，如幻听、内部对话、侵入性声音、思想、图像以及创伤的视觉"幻觉"，也是解离障碍的潜在迹象。这些症状都代表内隐记忆和/或各部分的显现，但不幸的是，尽管创伤相关声音与听幻觉之间存在可证明的差异，它们往往还是被诊断为精神分裂症的症状。Dorahy等（2009）将两组精神分裂症患者（一组有创伤史，一组无报告创伤）所描述的声音与一组被诊断为DID的患者所报告的声音进行了比较。研究人员发现，在这一样本中，DID被试报告听到声音的频率高于精神分裂症被试。他们还将这些声音描述为具有不同的性别和年龄，并将声音内容总结为普遍负面且针对个人，专注于指出个体的不足、缺乏价值，并利用这些指控来为"为什么你应该去死"进行辩护。精神分裂症来访者所报告的声音数量更少，没有不同的年龄或性别，并且从更为抽象的精神或偏执视角发言，而非个人视角，即便也鼓励自我毁灭。

To Make or Not to Make the Diagnosis?

是否作出诊断？

Making a DID diagnosis is not clinically essential if clients are already using trauma-informed treatment models in which the emphasis is on mindful awareness of the emotions, cognitions, body sensations, and action impulses of parts. The advantages or disadvantages of making a formal diagnosis should always be determined by the client's clinical presentation and source of distress: if the symptoms are leading the client to feel crazy and afraid of being "locked up," it may be reassuring to hear the diagnosis and learn that it is a treatable condition stemming from early traumatic experience. Annie illustrates a situation in which a diagnosis can be a supportive intervention:

如果来访者已经在使用以正念觉察各部分的情绪、认知、身体感觉和行动冲动为重点的创伤知情治疗模型，那么作出DID诊断在临床上并非必不可少。作出正式诊断的利弊应始终由来访者的临床表现和痛苦来源来决定：如果症状导致来访者感到自己快要"发疯"，并害怕被"关起来"，那么听到诊断并了解这是一种源于早期创伤经历的可治疗状况，可能会令他们感到宽慰。Annie说明了一种诊断可以成为支持性干预的情况：

Annie was increasingly troubled by the dissociative amnesia caused by parts switching frantically to gain control of the body and drive their survival strategies. After she sustained a bad fall with no recall of how it happened, and after her husband told their couples therapist "she" had repeatedly asked for a divorce that Annie did not want or recall, she was alarmed. And then, after weeks of being unable to leave the house, brush her teeth, take a shower, or eat regular meals, it became clear that she needed some explanatory system for understanding what was happening to her. I greeted her at the next session with a big smile: "You know, Annie, I've been thinking about our last session and how you've been struggling to just do the simple things, and I'm excited to tell you I think I know why!" I always precede making the diagnosis with excitement or glee, as if I were about to tell my client he or she just won the lottery! Clients with child parts are often sensitive to adult mood changes: if I appear unusually serious or unsure of my words, their alarms will be triggered. Annie was eager to hear "why" she couldn't brush her teeth or eat breakfast or get through the day. After educating her about the structural dissociation model and sharing with her the diagnosis of DID, I explained: "Your parts developed a relay race system for surviving your childhood: one would grab the baton and run the next leg of the 'race,' while others were shielded from what was happening, and then another would grab the baton and run the next leg. It was automatic: the best 'runner' for a particular situation would be instinctively activated to run that leg, then the best runner for the next leg of the race would be triggered, and so on. No one was distracted by how the others were running because each was separate and had little to no awareness of the others. You should thank your parts! It's thanks to them and the dissociative disorder that you and I are sitting here right now having this conversation!" In contrast, there were many clinical disadvantages in making a formal diagnosis with Dustin: he had a lifelong phobia of being diagnosed psychotic after being raised by a schizophrenic mother and told by his father that he was "crazy—just like her." He also wrestled with deeply painful beliefs that he was inadequate and "less than," beliefs that could only be challenged by recalling his professional successes as an adult. Dustin had a very strong going on with normal life self, dating back to an early age, that was driven by the fear of being like his mother and fulfilling the negative expectations of his father. But he also had an intensely ashamed submit part that often took control of his body and led to acting out that part's wish to be invisible and avoid other people, much to his girlfriend's disappointment. She wanted him to be the dynamic professional man she had first dated, not the depressed, self-effacing, withdrawn little boy self he could become—especially in social situations. The little boy part just hoped that someone would be nice to him and not question his right to be there while his presence influenced Dustin to keep a distance from others under the belief that he was still "on the outside, looking in." Though Dustin's girlfriend frequently questioned this pattern, he never did; the physical action of anxious withdrawal to the periphery where he would not be noticed was all the evidence he needed to believe he was inadequate and unwelcome. The procedurally learned beliefs of childhood ("be seen and not heard," "you don't belong," "there's something wrong with you," "no one wants you") continued to condition his emotional and behavioral reactions to the social environment. To give him a diagnosis at this point in his therapy would only have given him ammunition with which to attack himself, rather than giving him hope and illuminating the path to recovery.

Annie越来越为各部分疯狂地争夺对身体的控制权、驱动各自的生存策略所导致的解离性遗忘而苦恼。在她经历了一次严重的跌倒却完全不记得是如何发生的之后，又在她的丈夫告诉他们的婚姻治疗师"她"曾多次提出Annie并不想要也不记得的离婚请求之后，她深感震惊。然后，在几个星期无法离开家、刷牙、洗澡或正常进餐之后，显然她需要某种解释性框架来理解自己正在经历的一切。 我在下一次治疗时带着灿烂的笑容迎接她："你知道，Annie，我一直在想我们上次的治疗，以及你为了做那些简单的事情所做的挣扎，我很高兴地告诉你，我想我知道原因了！"我总是在作出诊断之前带着兴奋或欣喜，就好像我即将告诉来访者他或她刚刚中了彩票！有儿童部分的来访者往往对成人情绪变化很敏感：如果我显得异常严肃或对自己的措辞不确定，他们的警报就会被触发。 Annie迫切地想知道为什么她无法刷牙、吃早餐或度过一天。在向她介绍了结构性解离模型并与她分享了DID诊断后，我解释说："你的各部分发展出了一套接力赛跑系统来度过你的童年：一个部分会拿起接力棒跑'比赛'的下一棒，而其他部分则被屏蔽在外，不知道正在发生什么，然后另一个部分会拿起接力棒跑下一棒。这是自动的：在特定情况下最好的'跑者'会被本能地激活来跑那一棒，然后下一棒的最佳跑者会被触发，如此类推。没有人会被其他人的跑法所分心，因为每个部分都是独立的，彼此几乎没有意识。你应该感谢你的各部分！正是感谢它们和这个解离障碍，你和我才能坐在这里进行这次对话！" 相比之下，对Dustin作出正式诊断在临床上有许多不利之处：他在被一位患有精神分裂症的母亲养大、并被父亲告知他"疯了——就像她一样"之后，终其一生都恐惧被诊断为精神病。他还与深深痛苦的信念搏斗，认为自己不够格，"低人一等"，这些信念只有通过回想他作为成年人的职业成就才能得到挑战。Dustin有一个非常强大的正常生活的持续自我，可追溯到很小的年龄，它受到对变得像他母亲那样并满足父亲负面期望的恐惧所驱动。但他也有一个极度羞耻的顺从部分，常常控制他的身体，并导致付诸行动——表现出那个部分希望隐形和回避他人的愿望，这让他的女友大失所望。她想要的是她最初约会时那个充满活力的职业男性，而不是他可能变成的那个沮丧、自我贬低、退缩的小男孩自我——尤其是在社交场合。那个小男孩部分只是希望有人能对他友善，不质疑他在那里的权利，而他的存在影响着Dustin与他人保持距离，相信自己仍然"站在外面，向里张望"。尽管Dustin的女友经常质疑这种模式，他却从未这样做过；焦虑地退缩到外围、不被注意的身体行动，是他认为自己不够格和不受欢迎所需要的全部证据。童年程序性习得的信念（"要被看见而不是被听见"、"你不属于这里"、"你有什么问题"、"没有人想要你"）继续调节着他对社会环境的情感和行为反应。在治疗的这个阶段给他一个诊断，只会给他提供攻击自己的弹药，而不是给他希望并照亮通向康复的道路。

Assessment Tools for Diagnosing Dissociative Disorders

诊断解离障碍的评估工具

Because DID is such a controversial diagnosis in both the professional and lay worlds, using standardized, validated assessment tools to support making a diagnosis can be very important to clients' ability to accept it as true and useful information, rather than feeling shamed. Without the objectivity of a formal diagnostic instrument, they are likely to become suspicious of the therapist, anxious and defensive about the concept of parts, or apt to assume that it's simply another black mark being imposed upon them. When the therapist uses formal assessment measures, there is a reassurance of objectivity: we are not assessing them but assessing for a condition common to trauma survivors. It can even lend a sense of reassurance that they are not alone with this complex, baffling array of symptoms and are being taken seriously by the therapist. But knowing that formal assessment can be threatening to some parts, it is important that the therapist exude curiosity and enthusiasm as if this endeavor will be interesting and maybe even fun!

由于DID在专业界和普通大众中都是一个极具争议的诊断，使用标准化、经过验证的评估工具来支持作出诊断，对于来访者接受其为真实且有用信息的能力至关重要，而不是感到羞耻。没有正式诊断工具的客观性，他们很可能会对治疗师产生怀疑，对部分的概念感到焦虑和防御，或倾向于认为这只是另一个强加于他们的污点。当治疗师使用正式评估措施时，客观性得到了保证：我们不是在评估他们，而是在评估创伤幸存者中常见的一种状况。它甚至可以让他们感到宽慰，知道自己在面对这一复杂、令人困惑的症状群时并不孤单，并且被治疗师认真对待。但知道正式评估对某些部分可能具有威胁性，治疗师散发出好奇心和热情非常重要，就好像这项工作将会很有趣，甚至可能很好玩！

The most well-known assessment tool, the Dissociative Experiences Scale (Carlson et al., 1993), a self-report instrument, is the easiest to administer but unfortunately is also the least reliable tool. Clinicians using it report a high rate of false negatives (very low scores in clients who later demonstrate very obvious DID symptoms, e.g., switching of parts during a therapy session). These false negatives can be dangerous if they give the therapist a green light to go ahead with therapeutic work (e.g., memory processing) that exceeds the client's window of tolerance and activates the parts to act out self-destructively.

最著名的评估工具——解离体验量表（Carlson等，1993），一种自陈工具，是最容易施测的，但不幸的是也是最不可靠的工具。使用它的临床医生报告了高假阴性率（在后来表现出非常明显DID症状的来访者中得分极低，例如，在治疗会谈中发生人格转换）。如果这些假阴性给治疗师开绿灯继续进行超出来访者耐受窗口并激活各部分以自毁方式付诸行动的治疗工作（如记忆处理），则可能是危险的。

A more reliable measure is the Trauma Symptom Inventory (Briere et al., 1995), also a self-report instrument that elicits information about a range of symptoms from dissociation to intrusive images/sensations, anxiety and depression, and "tension-releasing" behaviors (e.g., self-harm, impulsive behavior, addictions). Although it does not explicitly diagnose DID, one of its measures is a severity of dissociation score and, when clients score high on that symptom cluster, the therapist has an objective statistic, usually along with other related scores, that provides a very natural entry point for a discussion of dissociation and dissociative disorders.

更可靠的测量工具是创伤症状量表（Briere等，1995），同样是一种自陈工具，用于引出从解离到侵入性图像/感觉、焦虑和抑郁，以及"释放紧张"行为（如自伤、冲动行为、成瘾）等一系列症状的信息。尽管它不明确诊断DID，但其中一个测量指标是解离严重程度得分，当来访者在该症状群上得分较高时，治疗师就有了一个客观统计数据，通常与其他相关得分一起，为讨论解离和解离障碍提供了一个非常自然的切入点。

For making accurate and formal diagnoses of DID, there is no better assessment instrument than the Structured Clinical Interview for DSM-IV Dissociative Disorders (SCID-D) (Steinberg, 1994). Most challenging to administer because of its long, very complex interview format (it usually takes 3 to 4 hours to complete in one sitting), it is nonetheless a valuable experience for client and therapist because of the detailed, non-pathologizing discussion of dissociative symptoms it encourages. Many of the SCID-D diagnostic questions can also be introduced separately to elicit information about dissociation bit by bit as the therapy proceeds, rather than the entire interview completed in a formal way.

对于作出准确正式的DID诊断，没有比DSM-IV解离障碍结构化临床访谈（SCID-D）（Steinberg，1994）更好的评估工具了。由于其冗长、非常复杂的访谈形式（通常需要一次性花3至4小时才能完成），施测最具挑战性，但它所鼓励的对解离症状进行详细、非病理化讨论，使其成为对来访者和治疗师都有价值的体验。许多SCID-D诊断问题也可以随着治疗的推进单独引入，逐步引出关于解离的信息，而不是以正式方式完成整个访谈。

Diagnostic Criteria and Questions

诊断标准与问题

Even when there is no immediate need for formal assessment and diagnosis, the therapist who is curious and concerned about a client's dissociative symptoms can still benefit from utilizing portions of the SCID-D (Steinberg, 1994) as the work of information-gathering in therapy naturally proceeds. Many of the SCID-D questions can simply be incorporated into the therapeutic dialogue. For example, Will could not remember the names of a single one of his colleagues or coherently describe what he did every day at work, causing his therapist to become curious about the possible role of dissociation in his self-acknowledged "absent-mindedness." When I suspect that the client may be experiencing transient time loss, I can ask some of the following SCID-D questions:

即使没有立即进行正式评估和诊断的需要，对来访者解离症状感到好奇和关注的治疗师仍然可以从利用SCID-D（Steinberg，1994）的部分内容中受益，因为治疗中的信息收集工作自然地推进。许多SCID-D问题可以简单地融入治疗对话中。例如，Will记不住他的任何一位同事的名字，也无法连贯地描述他每天在工作中做什么，这让他的治疗师对解离在他自认的"心不在焉"中可能扮演的角色产生了好奇。当我怀疑来访者可能正在经历短暂的时间失去时，我可以提问以下一些SCID-D问题：

• Have you ever felt you had memory problems? Ever had gaps, small or large, in your remembering of things? For example, "I remember starting the project, but I don't remember finishing it."

• 你是否曾感到有记忆问题？你是否曾在记忆事情时出现空白，无论大小？例如，"我记得开始做这个项目，但我不记得完成它了。"

• Is it ever hard to remember what you did yesterday or last week?

• 你是否曾难以记起昨天或上周做了什么？

• Are there ever whole hours or days that seem to be missing or that you have difficulty accounting for?

• 是否曾有整整几个小时或几天似乎消失了，或者你很难说清楚自己做了什么？

• Have you ever found yourself having traveled somewhere without remembering how or why you went? (Steinberg, 1994)

• 你是否曾发现自己到了某个地方，却不记得是如何去的或为什么去？（Steinberg，1994年）

Or for clients who frequently talk about being disconnected from themselves, questions eliciting information about depersonalization can be included into the discussion:

或者对于经常谈到与自身脱节的来访者，可以将引出人格解体信息的问题纳入讨论：

• Have you ever felt as if you were watching yourself from a point outside of your body, as if from a distance?

• 你是否曾感觉自己在从身体外的某个点注视自己，就好像从远处一样？

• Have you ever felt that you were going through the motions of living but the "real you" was far away?

• 你是否曾感到自己在机械地经历生活的动作，但"真正的你"却在遥远的地方？

• Have you ever felt like two different people? One going through the motions of living and the other just quietly observing?

• 你是否曾感觉自己像两个不同的人？一个在机械地经历生活的动作，另一个只是静静地观察？

• Have you ever heard yourself speaking and thought, "Is that me?"

• 你是否曾听到自己说话然后想，"那是我吗？"

• Have you ever felt that your words were out of your control? Your thoughts? Your actions? Your feelings? (Steinberg, 1994)

• 你是否曾感到你的言语不受你控制？你的想法？你的行动？你的感受？（Steinberg，1994年）

Questions about derealization often help detect parts that are disoriented in time and place. When they see the client's current environment, it looks unreal to them and unfamiliar, causing the client to complain of experiencing things as "unreal."

关于现实解体的问题往往有助于探测在时间和地点上迷失方向的部分。当它们看到来访者当前的环境时，在它们眼中显得不真实和陌生，导致来访者抱怨将事物体验为"不真实的"。

• Have you ever felt as if familiar surroundings or people seemed unfamiliar or unreal?

• 你是否曾感到熟悉的环境或人似乎变得陌生或不真实？

• Have you ever felt as if your surroundings were fading away?

• 你是否曾感到周围环境正在消退？

• Have you ever had the experience of not recognizing close friends or relatives or even your own home? (Steinberg, 1994)

• 你是否曾有过认不出亲密朋友或亲戚，甚至自己家的经历？（Steinberg，1994年）

Eliciting information about internal struggles and conflicts always moves the therapy forward, regardless of diagnosis:

引出关于内部挣扎和冲突的信息总是能推动治疗前进，无论诊断如何：

• Have you felt as if a struggle was going on inside you?

• 你是否曾感到内心正在进行一场挣扎？

• Have you felt confused about who you really are?

• 你是否曾对自己真正是谁感到困惑？

• Have you ever felt as if there was a struggle going on about who really are, what you really want?

• 你是否曾感到仿佛有一场关于你真正是谁、你真正想要什么的挣扎正在进行？

And if the answer to these questions is "yes," the therapist might want to ask more direct identity alteration questions:

如果这些问题的答案是"是"，治疗师可能会想要提问更直接的身份改变问题：

• Have you ever felt or been told that you were acting like a different person?

• 你是否曾感到或被告知自己表现得像另一个人？

• Have you ever referred to yourself or been referred to by different names?

• 你是否曾用不同的名字称呼自己，或被不同的名字称呼？

• Have you ever found possessions inexplicitly missing? Or inexplicably appearing?

• 你是否曾发现财物莫名其妙地消失了？或者莫名其妙地出现了？

• Have you ever experienced rapid changes in your ability to function? Or does your mood ever change rapidly without clear reason?

• 你是否曾经历功能能力的快速变化？或者你的情绪是否曾无明显原因地快速改变？

• Do you ever have internal dialogues? Are these dialogues more like thoughts or voices? Do they increase under stress? (Steinberg, 1994)

• 你是否曾有过内部对话？这些对话更像是想法还是声音？它们在压力下会增加吗？（Steinberg，1994年）

Because the SCID-D questions are meant to elicit discussion of the client's day-to-day experience, rather than being primarily focused on obtaining a score, they facilitate gathering a detailed understanding of the client's symptoms and struggles that can be invaluable in any trauma therapy, regardless of diagnosis. The SCID-D is a qualitative measure with all the advantages and disadvantages inherent therein: it is thorough, detailed, allows the therapist leeway to inquire further or even compose spontaneous follow-up questions, and it is not limited by standardized questions. Even if the therapist prefers not to make a formal diagnosis, the dialogue facilitated by the SCID-D will be valuable and elicit valuable information needed for the treatment.

由于SCID-D的问题旨在引出对来访者日常体验的讨论，而不是主要专注于获得分数，它们有助于收集对来访者症状和挣扎的详细理解，这在任何创伤治疗中都可能是无价的，无论诊断如何。SCID-D是一种定性测量，具有其固有的所有优缺点：它彻底、详细，允许治疗师有余地进一步询问甚至即兴提出后续问题，并且不受标准化问题的限制。即使治疗师倾向于不作出正式诊断，由SCID-D促成的对话也将是有价值的，并能引出治疗所需的宝贵信息。

There Is No "She"—There Is No "He"

没有"她"——没有"他"

Many therapists are intimidated by the challenge of taking on their first DID clients because they have received so little exposure to or training on the treatment of dissociation or dissociative disorders. In addition, they are often presented immediately with serious and complicated symptoms: regressive behavior, losses of functioning, suicidal or self-harming behavior, dissociative fugue states. Quite quickly, however, they discover the biggest challenge: there is no one "she" or "he" in the client's chair. Though this client is a whole integrated physical being, he or she is not one integrated psychological being, and that proves to be not only confusing but also disturbing to even the most experienced of therapists.

许多治疗师在接手第一位DID来访者的挑战面前感到望而生畏，因为他们几乎没有接受过解离或解离障碍治疗方面的接触或培训。此外，他们往往立即面临严重和复杂的症状：退行行为、功能丧失、自杀或自伤行为、解离性漫游状态。然而，很快他们就会发现最大的挑战：来访者椅子上没有一个单一的"她"或"他"。尽管这位来访者是一个完整统一的身体存在，但他或她并不是一个统一整合的心理存在，这不仅令人困惑，甚至对最有经验的治疗师来说也令人不安。

The therapist is also hindered by the "information gap" inherent in the diagnosis. Clinicians are trained to rely on clients as the experts on their own internal states, to assume that they are the most credible source of information about both past history and moment-to-moment awareness. With DID clients, however, even very basic information can be inaccessible to the client or known to the client but censored by protector parts. Even more challenging is the unexpected, unrequested information the therapist is likely to receive from trauma-related parts seeking to promote their own agendas, usually either to push the therapist away or pull the therapist closer. Whereas adult clients infrequently use text and email as regular channels of communication, child parts driven to make contact with the therapist without the knowledge or consent of the normal life self regularly use these means of communication. When parts are free to act autonomously and secretly outside the awareness of the "observing ego" of the prefrontal cortex, when they are driven by primitive animal defense instincts in response to triggers associated with danger, there is often a loss of reality-testing, continuous consciousness, and behavioral control.

治疗师还受到诊断中固有的"信息鸿沟"的阻碍。临床医生被培训为依赖来访者作为其自身内部状态的专家，假设他们是关于过去历史和即时觉察的最可信信息来源。然而对于DID来访者，即便是非常基本的信息对来访者来说也可能是无法获取的，或者来访者知晓但被保护者部分审查。更具挑战性的是治疗师可能从寻求推进自身议程的创伤相关部分那里收到意想不到的、未经请求的信息，通常是要么将治疗师推开，要么将治疗师拉近。虽然成年来访者不常将短信和电子邮件用作常规沟通渠道，但被驱动着在正常生活自我不知情或未经同意的情况下与治疗师接触的儿童部分，会定期使用这些沟通手段。当各部分可以在前额叶皮层的"观察性自我"的意识之外自主且秘密地行动时，当它们受到对危险相关触发因素做出反应的原始动物防御本能所驱动时，往往会出现现实检验能力、持续意识和行为控制的丧失。

Keeping Secrets Even from One's Self

甚至对自己也保守秘密

It is common for therapists working with DID clients to have secrets disclosed to them by individual parts communicating "behind the back of" (i.e., outside the consciousness of) the client's normal life self. Young child parts who feel endangered by triggering of implicit memories often hijack the body and can end up dominating the therapy in an attempt to elicit protection from the therapist, usually through disclosures of abuse or by having flashbacks in therapy. Fight- and flight-driven aspects of the personality might attempt to control the therapy in a different way, either by pushing the therapist away (devaluing, "firing," impulsively terminating) or punishing the young parts to prevent them from disclosing more secrets or becoming more dependent on the therapist. The therapist, confused by it all, can also inadvertently exacerbate the situation by unconsciously taking sides with young child parts that want a relationship or want to "tell what happened." When therapists continue encouraging disclosure of memory despite evidence that protector parts are alarmed by it, the result is most often increased instability.

与DID来访者工作的治疗师常常会有个别部分向他们披露秘密，这些部分在来访者正常生活自我的"背后"（即意识之外）进行沟通。因内隐记忆被触发而感到危险的年幼儿童部分常常劫持身体，并可能最终主导治疗，试图从治疗师那里引出保护，通常通过披露虐待情况或在治疗中出现闪回。由战斗和逃跑驱动的人格方面可能会以不同的方式试图控制治疗，要么将治疗师推开（贬低、"解雇"、冲动地终止），要么惩罚年幼部分以防止它们披露更多秘密或对治疗师产生更多依赖。治疗师因一切感到困惑，也可能通过无意识地站在想要建立关系或想要"说出发生了什么"的年幼儿童部分一边，无意中加剧了这种情况。当治疗师尽管有证据表明保护者部分对此感到警惕，仍继续鼓励记忆的披露时，结果往往是不稳定性的加剧。

Sheila's therapist approached the treatment of DID using a model first developed in the 1990s and then discontinued because of the risks of decompensation and regression inherent in that way of working. Founded on an assumption that the "talking cure" would also work for trauma, child parts of DID clients were encouraged to "come out" in therapy and "tell their stories" to the therapist, who in turn would inform the going on with normal life self as if reporting child abuse to a parent. When clients had a sufficient window of tolerance, this method was reasonably effective, but few DID clients had sufficient affect tolerance to manage the intensified trauma responses or increased tendencies to fragment. Often, Sheila's normal life self did not want to hear the disclosures, fearing being swept away by a "tsunami" of emotions. That rejection in turn triggered the child parts' painful memories of not being heard or not being believed. The fight and flight parts became alarmed by the therapist's knowledge of the secrets, believing that meant she or he would use them against the client. As they became agitated and desperate to take action, the result was increased addictive and self-injuring behavior. Child parts were being "punished" through self-harm by a fight part determined not to allow further regression or vulnerability.

Sheila的治疗师采用了一种最初在20世纪90年代发展起来、后因这种工作方式固有的失代偿和退行风险而被停止使用的模型来治疗DID。基于"谈话疗法"对创伤也会有效的假设，DID来访者的儿童部分被鼓励在治疗中"出来"并向治疗师"讲述他们的故事"，治疗师再将信息告知正常生活的持续自我，就好像向父母报告儿童虐待一样。当来访者有足够的耐受窗口时，这种方法是相当有效的，但很少有DID来访者有足够的情感耐受力来应对加剧的创伤反应或增加的碎裂倾向。 通常，Sheila的正常生活自我不想听到那些披露，害怕被情绪的"海啸"淹没。那种拒绝反过来触发了儿童部分关于不被倾听或不被相信的痛苦记忆。战斗和逃跑部分对治疗师了解那些秘密感到警惕，认为这意味着治疗师会用它们来对付来访者。随着它们变得焦躁不安、迫切地想要采取行动，结果是成瘾和自伤行为的增加。儿童部分正被一个决心不允许进一步退行或脆弱的战斗部分通过自伤来"惩罚"。

CHAPTER 9
Repairing the Past: Embracing Our Selves

第9章
修复过去：拥抱我们的自我

"At the moment of the trauma, the [child] is utterly helpless. Unable to defend herself, she cries for help, but no one comes to her aid. … The memory of this experience pervades all subsequent relationships. The greater the [child's] emotional conviction of helplessness and abandonment, the more desperately she feels the need for an omnipotent rescuer … [But] because [she] feels as if her life depends on her rescuer, she cannot afford to be tolerant; there is no room for human error. …"

"在创伤发生的那一刻，[孩子]完全无助。她无力自卫，发出求救的呼喊，却无人前来相助。……这段记忆渗透进此后所有的关系之中。[孩子]对无助与被遗弃的情感确信越深，她对全能救援者的渴求就越迫切……[但]正因为[她]感到自己的生命依赖于救援者，她无法做到宽容；不允许任何人为错误的存在。……"

(Herman, 1992, p. 137)

Regardless of whatever cruelties or losses they encounter, human beings are born with the capacities necessary to "keep on keeping on," even to live a full, rich, meaningful life—in spite of adversity. We come into the world with innate drives to attach, explore, laugh and play, bond with our social group, and nurture the young. Even as young children, we have a developing brain that offers us such resources as curiosity, compassion, creativity, and wonder (Schwartz, 2001). We also have the mental ability of imagination: if all is lost, we can still dream, still imagine a life we've never known.

无论遭遇怎样的残酷或失去，人类天生就具备"继续撑下去"的能力，甚至能够在逆境中过上充实、丰盛、有意义的生活。我们来到这个世界，带着依恋、探索、欢笑与玩耍、与社会群体建立纽带、养育幼者的先天驱动力。即便作为幼小的孩子，我们也拥有一个正在发展的大脑，它为我们提供好奇心、慈悲、创造力和惊奇等资源（Schwartz，2001）。我们还拥有想象的心智能力：即便一切都失去了，我们仍然能够梦想，仍然能够想象一种我们从未经历过的生活。

But, under chronic conditions of neglect, trauma, or frightened and frightening parenting, our bodies organize to prioritize the mobilization of animal defense survival responses and anticipation of danger (Ogden et al., 2006; Van der Kolk, 2014). The "luxuries" of normal attachment, exploration and learning, play, even sleeping and eating, take a back seat to hypervigilent attention to potential triggers and a readiness for defensive reactions. As important as it is to have parts whose hypervigilence and preparedness for action support survival under threat, it is equally important to have a part able to "make do" in even the worst of circumstances. The normal life child self smiles for family photographs and events, cares for siblings (or even for parents), goes to school, finds pleasure or mastery in the normal developmental "tasks" of childhood (playing with other kids, exploring nature, engaging in athletic or academic competition, getting lost in books, learning a musical instrument, and "adopting" supportive surrogate parents, such as teachers, neighbors, grandparents).

然而，在长期的忽视、创伤，或充满恐惧且令人恐惧的养育环境下，我们的身体会优先调动动物防御生存反应并时刻预判危险（Ogden等，2006；Van der Kolk，2014）。正常依恋、探索与学习、玩耍，乃至睡眠与饮食等"奢侈"需求，都让位于对潜在触发因素的过度警觉和随时准备防御反应的状态。拥有那些以过度警觉和行动准备支撑威胁下生存的各部分固然重要，同样重要的是拥有一个能够在最恶劣情境下"将就应对"的部分。正常生活的孩子自我在家庭照片和活动中微笑，照料兄弟姐妹（甚至照料父母），去上学，在童年正常发展"任务"中寻找乐趣或掌控感（与其他孩子玩耍、探索自然、参与体育或学业竞争、沉浸于书籍、学习乐器，以及"收养"支持性的代理父母，如老师、邻居、祖父母）。

Often, in taking a client's history, the therapist is drawn to the details of neglect, abuse, and family dysfunction that "need to be addressed" in therapy. Never trained to listen for the indicators of the child's drive for normality, their peer relationships, school life, or what kept that child "going on," therapist and client unwittingly paint a shared portrait of the client as a wounded victim, not a ingenious survivor. Annie provides us with a good example of what happens when the therapist neglects to be curious about the side of the child who "kept on keeping on" and focuses the therapy on the wounds and wounded parts. Despite the severity and chronicity of her neglect and trauma, despite coming from the "wrong side of the tracks," or perhaps because of these things, Annie's normal life self was always strongly driven to make the most out of whatever "normal" she could create or emulate.

在了解来访者历史时，治疗师往往被需要在治疗中"加以处理"的忽视、虐待和家庭功能失调的细节所吸引。治疗师从未被训练去聆听孩子追求正常的驱动力的迹象——他们的同伴关系、学校生活，或是什么让那个孩子"继续撑下去"——于是治疗师和来访者不知不觉地共同描绘出一幅来访者作为受伤受害者而非机智幸存者的共同画像。Annie为我们提供了一个很好的例子，说明当治疗师忽视对那个"一直撑下去"的孩子的一面保持好奇，而将治疗聚焦于伤口和受伤部分时会发生什么。尽管她所受忽视和创伤的严重程度和慢性程度如此之深，尽管来自"错误的那一侧"，或许正是因为这些，Annie的正常生活自我始终被强烈地驱动着，要从她能够创造或模仿的任何"正常"中获得最大收益。

An eager, bright sociable little girl, Annie's normal life self naturally evoked the support and attention of her teachers. Physically active and good at athletics, she discovered early on that owning a baseball mitt or bat was the best ticket to social connection with her peers. Although handicapped in peer relationships by the stigmata of neglect and poverty (dirty hair, unwashed second-hand clothes that didn't fit or match), she managed to compensate with the help of an exuberant personality and sports equipment purchased with her paper route and babysitting money. By the age of 8, as her mother's alcoholism worsened, she was put in charge of running her family's entire household and caring for two younger siblings, a burden to which she submitted for fear of physical abuse but which also earned her a repertoire of precocious competencies in cooking, cleaning, and childcare. Caring for two younger siblings who adored her and to whom she was safely attached provided an important normal developmental experience, one that most likely contributed to her later ability to raise two securely attached children and then "adopt" a series of surrogate children who found safe haven in her home. As an adult, friends, relatives, and neighbors consistently sought refuge and support in Annie's home. She often felt confused about why they would seek her out. The fight parts tried to tell her it was only because they wanted to use her since she was such an easy mark. The person she identified as "I" would never have drawn others to her, would never have been a "wise woman" to whom they would come for safety and support.

Annie是一个热情、聪明、善于交际的小女孩，她的正常生活自我自然地唤起了老师们的支持和关注。身体活跃、擅长体育，她很早就发现拥有一只棒球手套或球棒是与同龄人建立社交联系的最好通行证。尽管因忽视和贫困的烙印（脏乱的头发、未洗的二手衣服，既不合身也不配套）在同伴关系中处于不利地位，她还是凭借开朗的个性和用送报纸、做保姆赚来的钱购买的体育器材设法加以弥补。8岁时，随着母亲酗酒情况恶化，她被安排负责打理整个家庭并照顾两个弟弟妹妹，这一重担她因害怕身体虐待而顺从承担，但也为她赢得了烹饪、清洁和育儿方面超乎寻常的能力。照顾两个深爱她、与她安全依恋的弟弟妹妹提供了一次重要的正常发展体验，这很可能促成了她后来养育两个安全依恋孩子、并继而"收养"一系列在她家找到安全港湾的代理孩子的能力。成年后，朋友、亲戚和邻居不断地在Annie家寻求庇护和支持。她常常困惑于为何他们会寻找她。战斗部分试图告诉她，那只是因为他们想利用她，因为她太好说话了。那个她认同为"我"的人，永远不会吸引他人靠近，永远不会是那个他们为了安全和支持而前来寻找的"智慧女性"。

Despite the strengths and resources of her normal life self, Annie found her day-to-day experience dominated by traumatized child parts, with dramatic ramifications. Although she wished for more contact with others (and so did her attach part), the fight and flight parts held her back from acting on that wish. Instead, she was internally compelled to isolate, avoid going outside, cancel dates with potential friends, and never, ever answer the door or the telephone. Only those individuals seeking caretaking in her home were allowed to have contact with her. Ironically, caretaking had been the safest role she knew in childhood, and many parts did not want to give it up despite the scathing criticism of judgmental protector parts. Although Annie's normal life self wanted to have a routine that balanced regular eating and sleeping habits, household responsibilities and pleasurable activities, following a schedule was impossible. She and I constructed schedule after schedule to no avail. Any type of structure was assiduously avoided by her parts—a phenomenon often seen in clients with histories of neglect, even those with graduate degrees and professional careers. The case of Josh illustrates another example of what happens when the parts' implicit memories and perspectives dominate the individual and pre-empt functioning of the prefrontal cortex, disempowering the normal life self. Without the cortical ability to differentiate his grown-up self from trauma-related parts, he could not see his life or himself in perspective.

尽管她的正常生活自我拥有诸多优势和资源，Annie发现自己的日常体验被被创伤的孩子部分所主导，产生了深远的影响。尽管她渴望与他人有更多接触（她的依恋部分也同样渴望），战斗和逃跑部分却阻止她付诸行动。相反，她在内部被迫孤立、避免外出、取消与潜在朋友的约会，并且永远、永远不接门或接电话。只有那些到她家寻求照料的人才被允许与她接触。具有讽刺意味的是，照料他人曾是她在童年所知的最安全角色，尽管受到评判性保护部分的严厉批评，许多部分仍不愿放弃这一角色。尽管Annie的正常生活自我希望有一个能平衡规律饮食和睡眠习惯、家务责任和愉快活动的日常规律，遵循日程表却是不可能的。她和我制订了一个又一个日程表，均无济于事。任何类型的结构都被她的各部分坚决回避——这一现象在有忽视历史的来访者中很常见，即便是那些拥有研究生学位和专业职业的人也不例外。Josh的案例说明了另一个例子：当各部分的内隐记忆和观点主导个体并抢占前额叶皮层的功能时，会发生什么，从而削弱了正常生活自我的力量。没有皮层能力来区分他成年的自我与创伤相关部分，他无法对自己的生活或自身有整体的视角。

Josh was a very competent, successful, well-liked man in his forties. Respected by his colleagues, loved by his wife and daughters, accepted as "one of the guys" by his Wednesday night basketball buddies, a combination of intelligence, kindness, humility and humor endeared him to most people in his life. At times, he could see glimpses of this man others knew so well, but more often, the positive responses he evoked in others triggered a child part holding anxiety and self-doubt. "It's hard to take in anything positive, not when you know you're inadequate—when you know you come from nothing—or worse. I know the positive things are true of me, but I can't believe them." Attending a positive psychology weekend for couples, he found himself skeptical and at times even cynical: "It's so woo-woo. Say something nice to yourself and you'll feel better. But what if it's not true? I couldn't tolerate saying it and then finding out it's not true." Each time he had a glimpse of something beyond the inadequacy endorsed by his child parts, his cynical part would convince him there was no data to support any positive qualities in himself.

Josh是一位四十多岁的男性，非常能干、成功且深受欢迎。受到同事的尊重，被妻子和女儿们所爱，被周三晚上篮球伙伴们视为"自己人"，智慧、善良、谦逊和幽默的结合使他深受生活中大多数人的喜爱。有时，他能瞥见他人如此熟知的那个他，但更多时候，他在他人身上唤起的积极反应会触发一个持有焦虑和自我怀疑的孩子部分。"很难接受任何积极的东西，尤其是当你知道自己不够好——当你知道自己一无所有——甚至更糟的时候。我知道那些关于我的积极事物是真的，但我就是无法相信它们。"参加一个为夫妻举办的积极心理学周末活动，他发现自己持怀疑态度，有时甚至带着讽刺："这太玄乎了。对自己说些好话，你就会感觉好多了。但如果那不是真的呢？我无法忍受说出来然后发现它不是真的。"每次他瞥见超越孩子部分所认定的那种不够好的状态之外的什么，他的愤世嫉俗部分就会说服他，没有任何数据支持他自身存在任何积极品质。

Dawn also found her perspective distorted by whichever parts' intense emotions and reactivity "hijacked" her body and drove her impulsive behavior.

Dawn也发现，无论哪个部分的强烈情绪和反应性"劫持"了她的身体并驱动了她的冲动行为，她的视角都会因此而扭曲。

Dawn was 12 when she was taken out of the foster care system and sent to a Department of Child Mental Health residential placement. That was OK with her. Life had hardly been normal up to that point, nor had it been safe, and even though it didn't always feel that way, residential programs meant safety. Now 22, she had spent the intervening ten years in and out of residential care and hospitals. There, her chronic self-injury and eating disorder were treated as symptoms of borderline personality disorder and evidence of manipulative, attention-seeking behavior. Each time, her normal life part took a step forward, wanting more out of life, it triggered parts frightened of being seen, harmed, or abandoned. Without a window of tolerance, Dawn had no way of managing either her post-traumatic hyperarousal symptoms or her loneliness and emotional pain, which then tended to trigger vigorous efforts by the drug-seeking and eating disordered parts to alter her state. And if that didn't work, her self-injurious part would use cutting to mobilize adrenaline and thereby counteract the fear and vulnerability. Each time these parts hijacked her body and drove her to relapse or self-harm, it confirmed for the young terrified child part that there was no safety anywhere, increasing the panic that the fight and flight parts tried to shut down. Shown a diagram of the structural dissociation model by her new therapist, Dawn was surprised to feel an instant sense of recognition as the normal life self was described to her. "Oh yeah, I know that part! That's the part of me that used to promise myself that someday I'd get out of 'the system' and have a real home and family of my own. That's the part that kept me trying to get better all this time." Dawn, unlike Josh, immediately identified with her normal life part and felt relieved to give it a name and a purpose. It even began to feel real to her that maybe, after all, she could have a normal life!

Dawn 12岁时被带出寄养系统，被送到儿童心理健康部门的住宿安置机构。这对她来说还好。在那之前，她的生活几乎算不上正常，也不安全，尽管感觉并非总是如此，住宿项目意味着安全。现在22岁了，她在此后十年间在住宿护理机构和医院之间进进出出。在那里，她的慢性自伤和饮食障碍被视为边缘性人格障碍的症状，以及操控性、寻求关注行为的证据。每当她的正常生活部分向前迈一步，渴望从生活中得到更多，就会触发那些害怕被看见、被伤害或被遗弃的部分。没有耐受之窗，Dawn既无法管理她的创伤后过度唤醒症状，也无法应对孤独和情感痛苦，而这些往往会触发寻求毒品和饮食失调部分的强烈努力，以改变她的状态。如果这也不起作用，她的自伤部分就会用割伤来调动肾上腺素，从而抵消恐惧和脆弱感。每次这些部分劫持了她的身体并驱使她复发或自我伤害，都印证了那个年幼恐惧的孩子部分的认知：无处是安全的，增加了战斗和逃跑部分试图关闭的恐慌。新治疗师向Dawn展示了结构性解离模型的图示，当正常生活自我被描述给她时，她惊讶地感到一种即时的认同感。"哦对，我知道那个部分！那是我的那个曾经承诺自己有一天要走出'系统'、拥有自己真正的家和家人的部分。那就是一直让我努力好转的部分。"与Josh不同，Dawn立刻认同了她的正常生活部分，并因为能给它命名和赋予目的而感到释怀。她甚至开始感到，也许终究她能够拥有正常的生活！

Each of these clients had normal life selves with inherent inborn strengths and resources. Despite having never known "normality," even Dawn had the same drive to be her best self, the same curiosity and compassion for others, the same determination despite all the obstacles she had faced. All three normal life selves were strong-willed, creative, and instinctively knew what "normal life" signified for each of them. When their left-brained normal life selves were in charge, their personalities, identities, and values were well-defined. Sadly, because the normal life self blended so easily with the traumatized parts, yet also related to them as "not me" aspects, there was little communication or collaboration with the right brain-related parts. Feeling a sense of defectiveness because of their symptoms and difficulties, they were distracted from seeing how blending with their parts' trauma-related implicit memories and survival defenses was impacting their lives and sense of identity.

这些来访者每一位都拥有具有先天优势和资源的正常生活自我。尽管从未了解"正常"，即便是Dawn也拥有同样的成为最好自我的驱动力、同样对他人的好奇心和慈悲、以及面对所有障碍时同样的坚定。三位正常生活自我都意志坚强、富有创造力，并本能地知道"正常生活"对各自意味着什么。当他们左脑主导的正常生活自我掌控时，他们的个性、身份和价值观都清晰明确。令人遗憾的是，由于正常生活自我如此容易与被创伤的各部分发生融合，同时又将它们视为"非我"方面，与右脑相关部分之间几乎没有沟通或协作。因为症状和困难而感到有缺陷，他们分心于看到与各部分的创伤相关内隐记忆和生存防御的融合如何影响他们的生活和身份感。

Instead, the inner worlds of each tended to be more like battlegrounds: Annie's normal life self wrestled with parts terrified of the world they imagined lay outside her home, a world she had deliberately chosen for a normal life because it was so benign and gave her access to nature. Believing it would be as malevolent as the traumatic environment of childhood, her parts wanted none of it. Josh's intelligent, thoughtful normal life part lost conflict after conflict to critical and ashamed parts holding the conviction that no accomplishment or acceptance could erase the stain of having been "less than." Dawn's normal life self was quite literally on "lockdown," in and out of specialized programs, no match for the violence of her addicted, self-injuring, and eating disordered parts. The traumatic or disorganized attachment they had each experienced early in life created especially intense internal conflicts between the attach part's fear of abandonment and yearning for care versus the fight part's determination to defend against any and all vulnerability. Subsequently, traumatic events of all kinds (from bullying to human trafficking, homelessness to sexual abuse to domestic violence) had exacerbated these fears and further polarized the parts: parts holding implicit memories of fear, dread, and shame triggered parts driven by impulses to flee or fight for life—and vice versa. It was an endless cycle. Each part's belief system, reactivity, defensive responses, and emotions implicitly described its place in their histories and embodied the defensive responses needed at the time. Their conscious childhood memories were the tales of how they were victimized, never seen or never loved. Each failed to mention how they survived. Josh's story was that he would never outlive the humiliation, poverty, abuse, and neglect that characterized his childhood: he would never belong. Dawn's story was similar: she had never been wanted, never been safe, and she never would be. She might as well be dead. Not only were their normal life parts missing in their daily consciousness but also missing from their childhood memories. Flooded with the traumatized parts' emotions, impulses, and beliefs, each normal life self had automatically identified with the parts' implicit memories. Each was disconnected from a felt sense of ownership of the aspects of life he or she had deliberately created to support "keeping on" despite it all. Blended with the parts, all three identified with the traumatic lives of their childhoods rather than with their consciously created "life after trauma."

相反，每个人的内心世界往往更像是战场：Annie的正常生活自我与那些对想象中家门外世界感到恐惧的部分搏斗——而那个世界是她刻意为了正常生活而选择的，因为它如此温和并让她接近自然。这些部分相信那里将像童年的创伤环境一样充满恶意，完全不想要那一切。Josh聪慧、体贴的正常生活部分在与批评和羞耻部分的一次次冲突中败下阵来，那些部分坚信任何成就或接纳都无法抹去"不够好"的污点。Dawn的正常生活自我实际上处于"封锁"状态，在专业项目之间进进出出，完全无法与她那些成瘾、自伤和饮食失调部分的暴力相抗衡。他们每个人在早年所经历的创伤性或混乱型依恋，在依恋部分对被遗弃的恐惧和对关怀的渴望，与战斗部分抵御一切脆弱性的决心之间，制造了尤为强烈的内部冲突。随后，各种各样的创伤事件（从霸凌到人口贩卖，从无家可归到性虐待再到家庭暴力）加剧了这些恐惧，并进一步使各部分两极化：持有恐惧、恐怖和羞耻内隐记忆的部分触发了被逃跑或为生命而战斗的冲动驱动的部分——反之亦然。这是一个无尽的循环。每个部分的信念体系、反应性、防御反应和情绪都隐含地描述了它在各自历史中的位置，并体现了当时所需的防御反应。他们有意识的童年记忆是关于他们如何被害、从未被看见或从未被爱的故事。每个人都没有提到自己是如何幸存的。Josh的故事是，他永远无法摆脱那些标志着他童年的屈辱、贫穷、虐待和忽视：他永远不会有归属感。Dawn的故事也类似：她从未被人需要，从未安全过，也永远不会。她不如死了算了。不仅他们的正常生活部分在日常意识中缺失，在童年记忆中也同样缺失。被创伤部分的情绪、冲动和信念所淹没，每个正常生活自我都自动认同了各部分的内隐记忆。每个人都与那种对自己刻意创造的、用以支撑"继续坚持"的生活各方面的所有权感断开了联系。与各部分发生融合，三人都认同了自己童年的创伤生活，而非有意识创造的"创伤后的生活"。

The parts' disordered attachment and need for the approval and acceptance by others created a vulnerability to depending on others, leading fight and flight parts to perceive that they were still being used and abused—or could be. Their fight parts attacked their bodies, their credibility, even those closest to them—demoralizing the normal life selves and affecting their ability to be effective or to feel effective or both. None of the three could gain perspective without a trusting relationship between the parts and the self who could create safety, stability, and a life after trauma. When Dawn identified the little girl inside who had been left alone and unprotected to become prey for pedophiles, she was finally able to make the connection between her nightfall terrors and unsafe behavior. She felt an immediate protectiveness that impelled her to buy a little girl doll and doll bed so she could "see her and tell her I'm going to take care of her." But when Dawn's normal life part tried to reassure the little girl who got terrified every night as soon as it got dark, there was no emotional impact. The only interventions that eased the panic caused by blending with the child were restricting food intake and drinking alcohol. Not knowing that she would have to befriend the little girl first and win her trust before she would be able to believe the words of reassurance, Dawn was discouraged and, blended with her depressed submit part, she gave up trying.

各部分的混乱型依恋以及对他人认可和接纳的需求，制造了对他人依赖的脆弱性，使战斗和逃跑部分认为他们仍在被利用和虐待——或有可能被如此对待。他们的战斗部分攻击他们的身体、可信度，甚至那些与他们最亲近的人——使正常生活自我士气受挫，影响其有效行动或感到有效的能力，或两者兼而有之。三人中没有任何一个能够在各部分与能够创造安全、稳定和创伤后生活的自我之间建立信任关系的情况下获得视角。当Dawn辨认出内心那个被单独留下、无人保护而成为恋童癖猎物的小女孩时，她终于能够将她的夜幕降临时的恐惧与不安全行为联系起来。她感到一种即时的保护欲，驱使她购买了一个小女孩玩偶和玩具床，以便她可以"看见她，告诉她我会照顾她"。但当Dawn的正常生活部分试图安慰那个每晚天一黑就感到恐惧的小女孩时，没有任何情感上的影响。唯一能缓解因与孩子融合而产生的恐慌的干预措施是限制食物摄入和饮酒。不知道她必须先与小女孩建立友谊并赢得她的信任，然后小女孩才会相信安慰的话语，Dawn感到沮丧，与她沮丧顺从的部分发生融合，放弃了尝试。

When Josh's judgmental, humiliating fight part was triggered by social situations, Josh's prefrontal cortex could not compete with its emotional intensity. Nor could he reassure the ashamed part or the part that felt he didn't belong. He was too blended with them. The normal life self on whom others relied for words of support and wisdom could not "be there" for his child selves. The parts did not seek him out either. The ashamed little boy and depressed 12-year-old parts had a long though troubled relationship with the fight part; they had no relationship at all with Josh's normal life self. How could they know he was there when he was blended with them?

当Josh那评判性、令人屈辱的战斗部分被社交情境触发时，Josh的前额叶皮层无法与其情感强度抗衡。他也无法安慰那个羞耻部分或那个感到自己不被接纳的部分。他与它们的融合太深了。那个他人依赖以获得支持和智慧之语的正常生活自我，无法为他的孩子自我"在场"。各部分也不寻找他。那个感到羞耻的小男孩和抑郁的12岁部分与战斗部分有着漫长而动荡的关系；他们与Josh的正常生活自我根本没有关系。当他与它们融合时，他们怎么能知道他在那里呢？

Although Annie went through the motions of relating to her parts, she had no emotional connection to the words she spoke to them. In fact, she was afraid to feel too much for her young selves, having found it overwhelming in the past. Historically, once she began to feel their fear or sadness, it would escalate into a tsunami wave of emotion. Her normal life self was exceptionally gifted with her surrogate children and students, had a sensitivity to their trauma, and knew just how to help them find their own normal life selves. She took on more surrogate children of an alcoholic mother in the neighborhood and began to teach them how to survive as she had taught herself. She fed them healthy snacks, made them do their homework, and, over time, went to their parent-teacher conferences. As teenagers, she drove them to work or school activities to make sure they got all the skills and capacities they would need for eventual independence. Annie taught me an important lesson about the effects of neglect: seeing that they had no support or structure but also no help in developing the capacities to feel safe on their own, independent of their mother, she could see that without help, they would never be able to leave. To be on their own without any skills for self-regulation or functioning was terrifying and made a big world feel even bigger.

尽管Annie走过了与各部分建立关系的步骤，她对自己对它们所说的话却没有情感上的联系。事实上，她害怕对自己年幼的自我产生太多感受，因为过去曾发现这令人不堪重负。历史上，一旦她开始感受到它们的恐惧或悲伤，就会升级为情感的海啸。她的正常生活自我在对待代理孩子和学生方面异常有天赋，对他们的创伤有敏感性，并且知道如何帮助他们找到自己的正常生活自我。她接纳了邻居中一位酗酒母亲更多的代理孩子，开始教他们如何生存，就像她教自己一样。她给他们提供健康零食，让他们做作业，随着时间推移，还去参加他们的家长教师会议。当他们成为青少年时，她开车送他们去工作或学校活动，以确保他们获得最终独立所需的所有技能和能力。Annie教会了我一个关于忽视影响的重要课题：看到他们既没有支持或结构，也没有帮助发展在没有母亲的情况下独立感到安全的能力，她能看到如果没有帮助，他们将永远无法离开。在没有任何自我调节或功能技能的情况下独立生活是令人恐惧的，并使一个大世界感觉更大。

But Annie couldn't access these insights and abilities on behalf of her own parts, especially when overwhelmed by the emotions of younger parts or the defensive responses of fight and flight parts. The result: when she was triggered, she couldn't forge a relationship with her parts because she blended with them and could not stay present. For the parts, it was as if they had just cried for help, and the person to whom they called out heard their screams and then walked away. The parts felt abandoned, just as they had when their favorite aunt "walked away" back to her own life even after she had seen what was being done to them at home. When she could feel differentiated and separate, Annie's normal life self kept a safe distance from the parts' emotions—aided and abetted by a professional self, the teacher, who preferred a left-brain understanding of the parts to any emotional connection. But to the parts holding memories of yearning for some sign of care or kindness, the teacher's unemotional reassurance that they were safe now was as often alarming as it was reassuring.

但Annie无法代表自己的各部分获取这些洞见和能力，尤其是当被年幼部分的情绪或战斗和逃跑部分的防御反应所淹没时。结果是：当她被触发时，她无法与各部分建立关系，因为她与它们融合，无法保持在场。对于这些部分来说，就好像他们刚刚发出求救呼喊，而他们呼求的那个人听到了他们的呼喊，然后走开了。这些部分感到被遗弃，就像当他们最喜欢的姑妈在见识了家里对他们的所作所为之后，仍然"走开"回到自己的生活一样。当她能够感到有所区分和分离时，Annie的正常生活自我与各部分的情绪保持着安全距离——这由一个职业自我，即老师，所助长，老师更倾向于对各部分进行左脑式的理解而非任何情感联系。但对于那些持有渴望某种关怀或善意迹象记忆的部分来说，老师那种不带情感的"你们现在安全了"的安慰，往往既令人安心又令人警觉。

Midway through a discussion of her fear of leaving the house or yard, I asked Annie to be curious about why some protector parts were still holding her on "house arrest," the term I used for her agoraphobia. I wanted to communicate that it was more than the fears of the young part that wouldn't even let her open the door. She was also being prevented from leaving by some unidentified protector part. As she reassured the frightened part and headed toward the door, her body would suddenly tense up until she was frozen and couldn't move.
Asking "inside" to find out more about why she was on "house arrest," she got the following communication: "They're worried about the bad people outside the house like the ones who grabbed you as a kid."

I ASKED HER: "That makes sense—they were very dangerous people, very dangerous. And you were very little. But didn't anyone ever tell the parts that they're safe from those people now? Did anyone bother to tell them that you took them far away from New Jersey a long time ago and brought them to a place where no one could find them? You did that for them and you. Did anyone ever tell them that you changed your name so you couldn't be followed? Do they know anything about the life you've built here for the past 40 years?"

我问她："这很有道理——他们是非常危险的人，非常危险。而你那时很小。但有没有人曾经告诉过这些部分，他们现在已经远离那些人、安全了？有没有人费心告诉他们，你很久以前就把他们带离新泽西州，带到了一个没有人能找到他们的地方？你为了他们和你自己做到了这一切。有没有人告诉他们，你改了名字，这样就没人能跟踪你了？他们对你在这里过去40年所建立的生活了解任何事情吗？"

ANNIE: "It didn't occur to me that I had to tell them—I thought they'd just know."

Annie："我没有想到我需要告诉他们——我以为他们自然会知道的。"

I challenged her but with a tone that spoke to the parts' needs to be told, not her failure to tell them: "How could they have known? As far as they know, they're still in New Jersey, and they are still little. No one takes care of them, and anyone could take them. They were fair game for any creepy person, and they believe they still are. That's why they're so scared." Reassuring her that she hadn't failed (she hadn't known about the parts then), I appeal to her compassion for children: "You didn't know it, Annie, but they experienced it as you leaving them there. If you didn't tell them you were going, didn't say you were taking them away from all that—if you didn't tell them where they were when you arrived in Maine, then they don't know!"
On another day in a session with Josh, discussing his shame and fear of failure after he'd been triggered by a business meeting with male peers, I asked Josh a similar question: "Josh, does that little boy know that he doesn't live in that place anymore? Does he know that he doesn't have to wear clothes that are too big for him anymore? That no one will make fun of him now? I bet he doesn't even know that people here look up to you! He just remembers being fat, not having the right clothes, not being able to play sports with the other boys—and he remembers the shame of being bullied. This, your life, isn't real to him … only the bullying feels real."

我挑战了她，但语气着眼于各部分需要被告知，而非她未能告知他们："他们怎么可能知道呢？就他们所知，他们仍在新泽西州，仍然是小孩子。没有人照顾他们，任何人都可以带走他们。他们是任何可怕的人的猎物，他们相信自己依然如此。这就是他们如此害怕的原因。"向她保证她没有失败（她那时还不了解这些部分），我诉诸她对孩子的慈悲："你不知道，Annie，但他们体验到的是你把他们留在了那里。如果你没有告诉他们你要离开，没有说你要带他们离开那一切——如果你没有告诉他们你到达缅因州时他们在哪里，那么他们就不知道！"
另一天，在与Josh的一次会谈中，讨论他在被一次与男性同龄人的商务会议触发后感到的羞耻和对失败的恐惧时，我问了Josh一个类似的问题："Josh，那个小男孩知道他不再住在那个地方了吗？他知道他不再需要穿着太大的衣服了吗？知道现在没有人会嘲笑他了吗？我打赌他甚至不知道这里的人对你刮目相看！他只记得自己胖，没有合适的衣服，不能和其他男孩一起打球——他记得被霸凌的羞耻感。这一切，你的生活，对他来说并不真实……只有霸凌才感觉真实。"

Annie and Josh both identified with their ashamed parts early in adulthood, facilitating their ability to be "seen but not heard" and minimizing the abuse in their families. They had a need for a "damage limitation strategy" (Gilbert & Andrews, 1998) to survive that conditioned judgmental parts and ashamed parts to dominate their inner lives and sense of identity for many years. Looking through the telescopic lens of their ashamed parts, neither could recognize, much less integrate, the healthy normality they had created in their lives as adults, the way they drew people to them. Both were inspiring examples of how the inborn drive to be healthy, conscious, compassionate, kind, and do meaningful work could surmount poverty, abuse, socioeconomic status, and post-traumatic stress. Neither, of course, could relate to such descriptions of themselves, so I kept these insights to myself and instead tried to evoke their interest and curiosity in the parts holding the shame. I encouraged each to thank those parts for helping them survive without losing their hearts or their souls.

Annie和Josh都在成年早期认同了他们的羞耻部分，这使他们能够"被看见但不被听见"，并将家庭中的虐待最小化。他们需要一种"损害控制策略"（Gilbert和Andrews，1998）来生存，这使评判性部分和羞耻部分被训练成多年来主导他们的内心生活和身份感。通过羞耻部分的望远镜式视角看世界，两人都无法认识到——更不用说整合——他们作为成年人在生活中创造的健康正常，以及他们吸引他人的方式。两人都是鼓舞人心的例子，说明健康、有意识、慈悲、善良和做有意义工作的先天驱动力如何能够超越贫困、虐待、社会经济地位和创伤后应激。当然，两人都无法与对自己的这些描述产生共鸣，所以我把这些洞见藏在心底，转而试图唤起他们对持有羞耻感的部分的兴趣和好奇心。我鼓励每个人感谢那些部分帮助他们在不失去内心或灵魂的情况下生存了下来。

Dawn, having never known "normality" outside of the mental health system, was especially out of touch with her normal life self's ability to function and to persevere. But, unlike Annie or Josh, she could unblend from her parts and have warm feelings toward the frightened part and respect for her fight and flight parts. Her treatment team took every opportunity to point out signs of the normal life part so Dawn could begin to recognize it as a force in her life despite the up's and down's caused by the parts' strong triggered reactions to her attempts to go forward.

Dawn从未了解过心理健康系统以外的"正常"，尤其与她的正常生活自我的运作和坚持能力脱节。但与Annie或Josh不同，她能够从各部分中去融合，对那个恐惧的部分产生温暖的感受，并对她的战斗和逃跑部分感到尊重。她的治疗团队抓住每一个机会指出正常生活部分的迹象，这样Dawn就能开始将其认识为她生活中的一种力量，尽管各部分对她尝试前进时的强烈触发反应造成了起起伏伏。

Accessing the Resources of a Wise Adult

获取智慧成人的资源

For many trauma survivors, the past as conveyed by the incessantly triggered implicit memories of the parts continues to be experienced as more "real" than the present. When that happens, the parts continue to relive and relive, over and over, the neglect, abuse, rage, fear, and dread—and to re-experience being abandoned by the normal life self just as they were abandoned by their caretakers years and decades ago. Annie, Josh, and Dawn illustrate this phenomenon.

对许多创伤幸存者来说，通过各部分不断被触发的内隐记忆所传递的过去，持续被体验为比现在更"真实"。当这种情况发生时，各部分继续一遍又一遍地重活忽视、虐待、愤怒、恐惧和恐惧——并再次体验被正常生活自我所遗弃，就像多年乃至数十年前被照料者所遗弃一样。Annie、Josh和Dawn说明了这一现象。

To break the cycle requires several steps on the part of the therapist: first, the therapist must challenge the client's automatic beliefs and habitual patterns so that the tendency to identify with the autonomically activated emotions and drives of the parts is inhibited.

打破这一循环需要治疗师采取几个步骤：首先，治疗师必须挑战来访者的自动信念和习惯模式，从而抑制认同各部分自主激活的情绪和驱动力的倾向。

Carla came to therapy in a highly activated state, having just had to take a leave of absence at work after she became too overwhelmed with fear, sadness, and a sense of numb unreality. As she described the past year of her life, it became clear that she had functioned highly for so long because her normal life self was supported by two trauma-related parts, one afraid of failure and one equally determined to succeed. This team drove her to develop a successful professional career and long-term relationship with her partner, but, I explained, "It was held together with rubber bands and chewing gum." Then her partner had an affair; she was mugged at knifepoint in her own neighborhood; and her father died, activating the trauma-related parts and completely incapacitating the normal life part. "No wonder you have been feeling 'not yourself.' Your parts staged a coup d'etat—probably right after you found out about the affair," I commented. "These emotions that have been overwhelming you belong to very young distressed parts."
At the next session, as Carla made connections between her reaction to the affair and a childhood spent parenting her mother and soothing her father to ensure her safety, I translated her narrative into the language of parts: "So that little girl was all on her own—with no one to help her take care of her mother or protect her from her father—she had to grow up very fast, didn't she?" Carla responded immediately to the language of parts: "She did—she couldn't afford to feel lonely and scared—she had to take care of herself because no one else was going to."
"That's how it felt when I found out Amelia was cheating on me. I felt all alone again."
Concerned about how overwhelmed she was by her feelings and their parts, I drew on her strong prefrontal cortex and scientific background to begin deconstructing the situation: we subdivided the stressors, differentiated her reactions to each, and then connected the different sets of feelings to the different parts communicating them. By dividing an overwhelming situation into smaller components, each could be experienced as more manageable. "So not only were the losses hard for the strong normal life part of you to come to terms with," I validated, "they were devastating for this young girl." I added, "Remember: a betrayal would be deeply distressing for any adult, but on top of that, it triggered the worst fears of your younger parts. Children are so much more vulnerable to feeling unimportant and unseen. They fear being abandoned more than they fear attack."

CARLA: "True, but even though the little girl was heartbroken, I put up a wall with Amelia—'you can't hurt me anymore because I am not really connected to you.'"

Carla："确实，但尽管那个小女孩心碎了，我还是对Amelia筑起了一道墙——'你再也不能伤害我了，因为我实际上与你没有真正的连接。'"

ME: "That sounds like a bodyguard part that didn't want that little girl's heart broken again! But if I recall, your normal life self also got on the phone and found a couples therapist right away. It doesn't sound as if you were putting up a wall—just trying to save your relationship. But someone clearly was! If you feel the wall there in your body, some part is responsible for it."

我："那听起来像是一个不想让那个小女孩的心再次破碎的保镖部分！但如果我没记错的话，你的正常生活自我也立刻拿起电话找了一位伴侣治疗师。听起来不像是你在筑墙——只是在努力拯救你们的关系。但显然有人在！如果你在身体里感受到那道墙，某个部分是负责的。"

CARLA: "The wall is still there—I can't take it down—I've tried. But maybe that makes sense if I didn't put it up?"

Carla："那道墙还在——我无法拆除它——我试过了。但也许如果不是我筑起它的，这就说得通了？"

A week later, Carla was back with good news: "I've been thinking a lot about the little girl and meditating—and crying a lot for her. I've been remembering what it was like. Before, I was so focused on my career that I never thought of what she had been through and how lonely she was, which is just what Amelia complained about! [She chuckled with recognition of the irony.] I've been taking good care of the little girl this week, holding her close to me, and the wall is softening a little—just a little. The wall wants me to know that it doesn't trust me yet to protect her."

Carla来到治疗时处于高度激活的状态，她刚刚不得不从工作中请假，因为她被恐惧、悲伤和麻木的不真实感所压倒。当她描述过去一年的生活时，清楚地表明她之所以能长期高度运作，是因为她的正常生活自我得到了两个创伤相关部分的支持，一个害怕失败，另一个同样坚定地要成功。这个团队驱使她发展出成功的职业生涯和与伴侣的长期关系，但我解释说，"这一切是靠橡皮筋和口香糖勉强维持在一起的。"然后她的伴侣出轨了；她在自己的街区被人持刀抢劫；她的父亲去世了，激活了创伤相关部分，完全使正常生活部分丧失了能力。"难怪你一直感觉'不像自己了'。你的各部分发动了一场政变——可能就在你得知那次外遇之后，"我评论道。"那些一直让你不堪重负的情绪属于非常年幼的、痛苦的各部分。"
在下一次会谈中，当Carla将她对外遇的反应与童年花在照顾母亲和安抚父亲以确保自己安全上的时间联系起来时，我将她的叙述翻译成各部分的语言："所以那个小女孩完全是独自一人——没有人帮她照顾妈妈或保护她免受父亲的伤害——她不得不很快成长，不是吗？"Carla立刻回应了各部分的语言："是的——她承受不起孤独和恐惧的感觉——她必须照顾好自己，因为没有其他人会这样做。"
"当我发现Amelia出轨时，那种感觉就是如此。我再次感到完全孤独。"
担心她的感受和各部分让她如此不堪重负，我借助她强大的前额叶皮层和科学背景开始解构这种情况：我们细分了压力源，区分了她对每个压力源的反应，然后将不同的感受组与传递它们的不同部分联系起来。通过将一个压倒性的情况分成更小的组成部分，每一部分都可以被体验为更易于管理。"所以损失不仅对你强大的正常生活部分来说难以接受，"我认可道，"对这个年幼的女孩来说更是毁灭性的。"我补充说，"记住：背叛对任何成年人来说都会造成深深的痛苦，但除此之外，它触发了你年幼部分最深的恐惧。孩子们对感到不重要和不被看见更为脆弱。他们害怕被遗弃甚于害怕被攻击。"
一周后，Carla带来了好消息："我一直在思考那个小女孩并冥想——为她哭了很多。我一直在回忆过去是什么感觉。以前，我太专注于我的职业，从来没有想过她经历了什么，她有多孤独，而这恰恰是Amelia抱怨的！[她会心地笑着，认识到这一讽刺。] 这周我一直在好好照顾那个小女孩，把她紧紧抱在怀里，那道墙正在慢慢软化——只是一点点。那道墙想让我知道，它还不信任我能保护她。"

It took very little for Carla to resonate immediately to her little girl part rather than identify with her. It was as if she had been waiting for someone to give her the language for something she already knew or sensed. Her compassion for the little girl was easily accessible, and perhaps because of her meditation practice, she could experience a felt connection to her mindful observer self while also feeling connected to the little girl and to the protective wall. Over the weeks to come, Carla guided the therapy herself from a wise mindful place, and I had only the job of supporting and commenting on the work she was doing. Sometimes, she chose to work on her relationship to the little girl and sometimes on strengthening her capacity to be calm, curious, accepting, and centered (what Richard Schwartz [2001] calls "self-energy") through her meditation practice. She felt her heart increasingly open and, with that, she was able to observe without judgment how closed it had been before. "I thought of myself as gentle and caring, but I'm sure that's not how other people saw me. They just saw the professional distance that I rationalized as the price I paid for success in my work."

Carla只需很少的引导就能立即与她的小女孩部分产生共鸣，而非认同她。就好像她一直在等待有人给她语言，来表达她已经知道或感受到的事情。她对小女孩的慈悲很容易获得，也许因为她的冥想练习，她能够体验到与正念观察自我的感受联系，同时也感到与小女孩和保护性的墙相联系。在接下来的几周里，Carla从一个充满智慧的正念之处自己引导着治疗，我只需要支持和评论她所做的工作。有时，她选择致力于与小女孩的关系，有时则通过冥想练习加强她保持平静、好奇、接纳和专注的能力（Richard Schwartz [2001]称之为"自我能量"）。她感到自己的心越来越开放，随之，她能够不带评判地观察到之前它曾经多么封闭。"我以为自己温柔而有关怀，但我确信其他人不是这么看我的。他们只看到了专业距离，而我将其合理化为我在工作中取得成功所付出的代价。"

Not all clients have the immediate response to or compassionate understanding of their parts as Carla did—or the intuitive access to her "wise mind" (what would be termed "self" or "self-energy" in the language of Internal Family Systems). Carla, for example, intuitively sensed the need to meditate as a way of developing a mindful relationship to the multitude of painful thoughts, feelings, and body sensations she and her parts were experiencing.

并非所有来访者都像Carla那样对各部分有即时的回应或富有慈悲的理解——或者对她的"智慧心灵"（在内部家庭系统语言中被称为"自我"或"自我能量"）有直觉性的接触。例如，Carla凭直觉感到需要通过冥想来对她和她的各部分所经历的大量痛苦思想、感受和身体感觉发展一种正念关系。

For other clients, simply shifting from a narrative approach to a mindful dual awareness stance might have taken many months. Clients are used to equating therapy with talking, "getting things off my chest," or "venting." Even certain parts can be very attached to narrative therapy because it gives them an opportunity "to be heard" or "heard and believed." Normal life parts may be attached to talking because their priority is problem solving the issues that are most troubling or most triggering on a daily basis and avoiding the "not-me" feelings. Child parts yearning for connection may feel soothed by the quality of the therapist's listening and empathy; parts focused on avoiding the trauma (or the emotions connected to it) might be attached to complaining and/or analyzing. But since the key ingredient in a parts approach is mindful, compassionate noticing of thoughts, feelings, and bodily reactions as communications from parts, the shift from narrating to noticing is crucial for the success of the work. Narrating will yield an understanding of a part's role in the client's trauma history or even in day-to-day life, but it will not heal that part's wounds or "earn" secure attachment. Just think of a small child crying: if the adult responds by saying, "The child is crying," or "I am crying," the child is unlikely to feel any comfort or relief. If the adult hears the teenager's anger and comments, "I am angry about that," or "It made me angry, too," or "Why did that make me so angry?" it is unlikely to have an effect other than to make the adolescent angrier. But these are what the parts hear when their feelings and reactions are narrated by the client as "my feelings."

对于其他来访者来说，仅仅从叙述性方法转变为正念双重觉察的立场，可能就需要好几个月。来访者习惯于将治疗等同于谈话、"一吐为快"或"发泄"。甚至某些部分可能非常依附于叙事治疗，因为它给了它们"被倾听"或"被倾听和被相信"的机会。正常生活部分可能依附于谈话，因为它们的优先事项是解决每日最令人烦恼或最具触发性的问题，并回避"非我"的感受。渴望联系的孩子部分可能因治疗师倾听和共情的质量而感到被安抚；专注于回避创伤（或与之相连的情绪）的部分可能依附于抱怨和/或分析。但由于各部分方法中的关键要素是对想法、感受和身体反应作为来自各部分的信息进行正念、慈悲的觉察，从叙述转向觉察对于工作的成功至关重要。叙述将产生对一个部分在来访者创伤历史中甚至在日常生活中的角色的理解，但它不会治愈那个部分的伤口或"赢得"安全依恋。想想一个小孩哭泣：如果成年人回应说，"孩子在哭"，或"我在哭"，孩子不太可能感到任何安慰或宽慰。如果成年人听到青少年的愤怒并评论，"我也对此感到愤怒"，或"它也让我感到愤怒"，或"为什么这让我如此愤怒？"除了使青少年更加愤怒之外，不太可能有任何效果。但当各部分的感受和反应被来访者叙述为"我的感受"时，这正是各部分所听到的。

CHAPTER 10
Restoring What Was Lost: Deepening the Connection to Our Young Selves

第10章
恢复失去的：深化与年幼自我的连结

"When those aspects [of ourselves] that have been unconsciously refused are returned, when they are made conscious, accepted, tolerated or integrated, the self can then be at one, the need to maintain the self-conscious edifice disappears, and the force of compassion [is] automatically unleashed."

"当那些被无意识拒绝的〔自我〕面向得以回归，当它们被意识到、被接纳、被容忍或被整合，自我便可以趋于合一，维持自我意识外壳的需求随之消失，慈悲的力量便会自然而然地释放出来。"

(Epstein, 1995, p. 19)

As clients learn to speak the language of parts, increase their ability to unblend, and cultivate a dual awareness relationship characterized by curiosity rather than aversion, there is often a spontaneous settling of the nervous system, calming trauma-related parts. The habit of mindful noticing creates a little space between the young child and a wise adult who finds it much easier to be curious now that he or she is less overwhelmed. Cause-and-effect relationships become clearer. The client feels less "crazy" when "over-reactions" are reframed as normal reactions of traumatized children. Now, the client can observe the influence of the parts on their actions and reactions and practice being aware of impulses to blend and make a conscious choice: "If I blend with the despair of the depressed part, it will upset the little parts and trigger the suicidal part—maybe I don't want to 'give in' to the feeling of hopelessness after all." With a conscious, voluntary separation from trauma-related parts and a more regulated nervous system, clients begin to develop less aversion and more compassion for them—or at least perspective toward them. Particularly with clients with chronic high-risk symptoms, self-destructive behavior, substance-abuse, and/or eating disorders, stabilization is almost entirely dependent upon acquiring the ability to differentiate the aims and goals of a normal life versus those of a desperate flight or fight part more afraid of trauma-related vulnerability than of death. Traditional treatments for these issues typically focus on cessation of unsafe behavior, thereby alienating and polarizing the fight and flight parts and often jeopardizing stabilization. Similarly, shame, exhaustion, and self-doubt are most often treated as indications of chronic depression or low self-esteem, rather than understood as communications from parts who bear the burden of submission and humiliation. Worse yet, when client symptoms are chronic or treatment-resistant, they are often labeled as "personality disordered," confirming already held beliefs in their defectiveness and not belonging. But stabilization of even the most dysregulated, dissociated clients can gradually be achieved with repeated practice of the following simple steps described in more detail in Chapters 4 and 5:

随着来访者学会使用"部分"的语言、增强去融合的能力，并培养出以好奇而非厌恶为特征的双重觉察关系，神经系统往往会自发地趋于平静，创伤相关部分也随之安定下来。正念觉察的习惯在年幼孩子与智慧成人之间创造出一点空间——由于不再那么不知所措，这位成人发现保持好奇变得容易多了。因果关系变得更加清晰。当"过度反应"被重新诠释为受创伤儿童的正常反应时，来访者便不再那么感到"疯狂"。现在，来访者能够观察各部分对其行为与反应的影响，并练习觉察融合的冲动，进而做出有意识的选择："如果我与抑郁部分的绝望相融合，就会扰动那些年幼部分，并触发自杀部分——也许我并不想向绝望感'屈服'。"通过与创伤相关部分有意识、自愿地保持距离，以及更趋于调节的神经系统，来访者开始对这些部分减少厌恶、增多慈悲——或至少发展出某种视角。对于有慢性高风险症状、自我毁灭行为、物质滥用和（或）饮食障碍的来访者而言，稳定化几乎完全取决于能否获得区分能力：辨别正常生活的目标与愿望，与那些对创伤相关脆弱性的恐惧甚于死亡的、拼命逃跑或战斗部分的目标与愿望之间的差异。对这些问题的传统治疗通常聚焦于停止不安全行为，从而疏离并两极化了战斗与逃跑部分，常常危及稳定化进程。同样，羞耻、疲惫与自我怀疑往往被视为慢性抑郁或低自尊的表征，而非被理解为承载着顺从与屈辱重负的部分所发出的沟通信号。更糟的是，当来访者症状慢性化或对治疗产生抵抗时，他们常被贴上"人格障碍"的标签，从而印证了他们早已持有的关于自身缺陷与不归属感的信念。但即便是最为失调、最为解离的来访者，也可以通过反复练习以下简单步骤逐步实现稳定化，这些步骤在第4章和第5章中有更详细的描述：

• Learning to recognize triggered emotional and somatic reactions as "triggering" and avoid interpreting them as here-and-now responses to the environment.

• 学会将被触发的情绪与躯体反应识别为"触发状态"，避免将其解读为对当下环境的即时回应。

• Evoking curiosity by reframing these responses as "communications from parts."

• 通过将这些反应重新诠释为"来自部分的沟通"，唤起好奇心。

• Increasing client ability to mindfully notice moment-to-moment interactions between triggering stimuli and triggered parts.

• 提升来访者正念觉察触发刺激与被触发部分之间逐时互动的能力。

• Differentiating the qualities of an observing normal life self with either the ability or desire for a life beyond trauma from the characteristic signs and symptoms of traumatically activated parts.

• 区分具有观察能力的正常生活的持续自我——其具有能力或渴望过超越创伤的生活——与被创伤激活的部分所呈现的特征性症状与表现之间的差异。

• Cultivating not only the ability to name the parts but growing compassion for their youth and ability to survive in the face of "what happened."

• 不仅培养为各部分命名的能力，还要对它们的年幼稚嫩以及在"所发生之事"面前求生存的能力，生发出慈悲之情。

• Learning to communicate internally, building trust, and making felt connections to the parts.

• 学习内部沟通，建立信任，并与各部分建立情感上的连结。

These simple initial tasks are the foundation upon which any deeper work must be built, and it is well worth the therapist taking the extra time to stabilize these abilities until the client can use them independently outside of therapy, not just with the therapist present. It is not helpful to clients to move ahead to "the deeper work," only to discover in hindsight that the client was more dysregulated and more blended with his or her parts than the therapist realized and now is overwhelmed by emotions or traumatic memories.

这些简单的初始任务是一切深层工作赖以建立的基础。治疗师值得花费额外的时间来巩固这些能力，直到来访者能够在治疗室之外、无需治疗师在场的情况下独立运用它们。若贸然推进至"深层工作"，事后才发现来访者比治疗师意识到的更为失调、与各部分融合程度更深，以致被情绪或创伤记忆所淹没，这对来访者并无裨益。

Therapists (and sometimes their clients, too) put enormous pressure on themselves to accomplish therapeutic goals quickly. Often, the sense of urgency is driven by the client's suffering and the empathic wish to relieve it, sometimes by the pressures of limited sessions and/or insurance coverage. Sometimes, we push ourselves because we believe or are led to believe that a particular method "should" work in just a short time, and we question ourselves rather than the method when it does not generate quick results. We also do not take into account the role of structural dissociation: structurally dissociated clients cannot integrate new information or tolerate emotional intensity, and they are also hindered by the internal conflicts between parts. Always in trauma work, the therapist's motto should be, "Slower is faster." Taking the time to build a foundation for each piece of work allows a steady progression toward resolution, rather than a great leap forward followed by two steps back—a pattern to which traumatized clients are all too prone.

治疗师（有时来访者也是如此）给自己施加了巨大压力，希望迅速实现治疗目标。这种紧迫感往往源于来访者的痛苦以及想要缓解痛苦的共情愿望，有时也来自疗程有限和（或）保险覆盖范围的压力。有时，我们鞭策自己，是因为相信或被引导相信某种特定方法"应当"在短时间内奏效——当它未能快速产生效果时，我们质疑自己而非方法本身。我们也没有充分考虑结构性解离的作用：结构性解离的来访者无法整合新信息，也无法耐受情绪强度，同时还受到各部分之间内部冲突的阻碍。在创伤工作中，治疗师的座右铭始终应当是："慢即是快。"花时间为每个工作环节奠定基础，能够实现稳步推进、走向解决，而非大步跃进之后又退两步——这种模式恰恰是受创伤来访者极易陷入的。

In traditional phase-oriented treatment, stabilization is followed by a phase of "memory-processing" based on the assumption that unmetabolized memories of traumatic events are the active ingredient in post-traumatic stress. However, as discussed throughout this book, research suggests that the "active ingredients" underlying post-traumatic disorders are chronic autonomic dysregulation, situationally activated implicit memories without words, and fragmented parts that experience themselves as still in danger of annihilation or abandonment or both (Van der Kolk, 2014; Ogden et al., 2006). "Trauma processing" must therefore include the body and the parts, and it must focus on reorganizing the individual's implicit memories and relationship to the traumatic past. For clients to transform their relationship to frightening, overwhelming, humiliating events necessitates acquiring the ability to be "on speaking terms" with the traumatic past without fear of being overwhelmed or humiliated. In Sensorimotor Psychotherapy (Ogden et al., 2006), the litmus test for assessing client readiness to process memory is the question, "What happens when you just 'think about thinking about it?'" I once asked that question of Annie, and the next week, she reported that she'd been having flashbacks all day and all night ever since. Clearly, the question was very premature.

在传统的分阶段治疗中，稳定化之后是"记忆处理"阶段，其基础假设是：未被代谢的创伤事件记忆是创伤后应激的主要活性成分。然而，正如本书始终讨论的，研究表明，创伤后障碍的"活性成分"是慢性自主神经失调、由情境激活的无语言内隐记忆，以及仍将自身置于毁灭或遗弃危险之中——或两者兼有——的碎片化部分（Van der Kolk，2014年；Ogden等，2006年）。因此，"创伤处理"必须纳入身体与各部分，并聚焦于重组个体的内隐记忆及其与创伤过去的关系。为使来访者转化其与恐惧性、压倒性、屈辱性事件的关系，需要培养一种能力：能够与创伤过去"建立对话"，而无需担心被淹没或再受屈辱。在感觉运动心理治疗中（Ogden等，2006年），评估来访者准备好处理记忆的试金石是这个问题："当你只是'想着去想它'时，会发生什么？"我曾经问过安妮这个问题，下周她告诉我，从那以后她整日整夜地经历闪回。显然，那个问题提得太早了。

To "process memory" requires preparation: learning to overcome the fear of emotional vulnerability, of the body, and of the parts, reduce sensitivity to traumatic triggering, and inhibit the automatic tendency to "self-defeating stories" or self-blame. While stabilization requires the ability to notice, identify, and differentiate one's parts, the healing of traumatic wounds necessitates an additional step: making an emotional connection to the parts and providing reparative experiences that serve as antidotes to the past.

"处理记忆"需要准备：学会克服对情绪脆弱性、对身体以及对各部分的恐惧，降低对创伤触发因素的敏感性，并抑制自动化的"自我挫败叙事"或自我责备的倾向。稳定化需要觉察、识别和区分各部分的能力，而创伤伤口的疗愈则需要额外的一步：与各部分建立情感连结，并提供作为过去解毒剂的修复性体验。

Reorganizing the Relationship to the Past

重组与过去的关系

Developing compassionate relationships with parts who are hurt, lonely, consumed by rage, frightened, and ashamed is a challenging job, however. Because their emotions are so raw and overwhelming, welcoming them requires tolerating their traumatic activation, learning how to remain unblended despite the distraction of strong physical impulses, and regulating their over- or underwhelming affects. In practical terms, this means that the therapist must help clients maintain their ability to stay curious, despite the intense internal struggles, and cultivate enough compassion to communicate welcome to each part. Therapists will be challenged here by training that prioritizes the felt connection to strong emotions over other types of experience, but it is important to be patient. If the client feels "too much" for the parts, he or she will become flooded with their emotions. To the extent that the normal life self has been able to develop confidence in being able to stay present, has learned to recover from when flooded and "come back," has slowly come to appreciate each part's role in surviving the traumatic past, and has the ability to offer a healing or "loving presence" (Kurtz, 1990) to wounded selves, he or she will be prepared to offer reparative experiences to the parts. "Loving presence" is a state of being: warm, compassionate, curious, looking for what is right instead of what's wrong, unconditionally accepting. Ron Kurtz emphasizes the importance of the therapist cultivating a "loving presence," that is, finding something to "love" in all clients, even those who are stuck, resistant, devaluing, narcissistic, or demanding. In that state of consciousness, time slows down; our bodies relax; there is a feeling of warmth—all is "OK." As important as this concept is in the therapeutic relationship, it is equally important in individuals' relationships to their parts. They must find something to love about each one.

然而，与那些受伤、孤独、被愤怒吞噬、恐惧以及充满羞耻感的部分建立慈悲的关系，是一项充满挑战的工作。由于这些部分的情绪如此原始、如此具有压倒性，欢迎它们的到来需要容忍其创伤激活状态，学会在强烈躯体冲动的干扰下保持去融合，并调节其过度或不足的情感反应。从实际操作而言，这意味着治疗师必须帮助来访者在激烈的内部挣扎中保持好奇的能力，并培养足够的慈悲来向每个部分传递欢迎的信息。治疗师在这里会面临来自培训的挑战——那种将对强烈情绪的感受连结置于其他体验类型之上的训练——但保持耐心至关重要。如果来访者对各部分感受"太多"，就会被它们的情绪所淹没。在正常生活的持续自我能够发展出保持临在的信心、学会从被淹没中恢复并"回来"、逐渐欣赏每个部分在度过创伤过去中所扮演的角色，并具备向受伤自我提供疗愈性或"爱的临在"（Kurtz，1990年）的能力的程度上，他或她将做好准备向各部分提供修复性体验。"爱的临在"是一种存在状态：温暖、慈悲、充满好奇，寻找正确之处而非错误之处，无条件地接纳。Ron Kurtz强调治疗师培养"爱的临在"的重要性，即在所有来访者身上找到值得"爱"的东西，即便是那些停滞、抗拒、贬低、自恋或苛求的来访者。在那种意识状态中，时间放缓；我们的身体放松；有一种温暖的感觉——一切都"好"。这一概念在治疗关系中固然重要，在个体与自身各部分的关系中同样重要。他们必须在每一个部分身上找到值得爱的东西。

The Role of Memory

记忆的作用

Although processing traumatic memory is not the objective of this work, often memories of specific events come up spontaneously as information is obtained about a part's fears, doubts, and longings. Rather than being the "target" of the therapy, memories and images should be capitalized upon to provide a context for evoking compassion for the young child who felt the loneliness, fear, pain, or shattered faith in those he or she loved.

尽管处理创伤记忆并非这项工作的目标，但当获取到某个部分的恐惧、疑惑与渴望的信息时，特定事件的记忆往往会自发浮现。记忆与意象不应成为治疗的"靶点"，而应被善加利用，为唤起对那个年幼孩子的慈悲提供情境——那个感受过孤独、恐惧、痛苦或对所爱之人的信仰破碎的孩子。

The most important therapeutic purpose of such memories is to deepen a heartfelt bond between a normal life self and the young child he or she once was. Transformation of the client's relationship to the unfinished past often happens spontaneously when the normal life self suddenly connects to the felt experience of the child and immediately feels sadness or protectiveness. Tears spring up spontaneously; the chest or heart opens; the client's arms feel the impulse to reach out to the child; words of compassion arise spontaneously. There is a feeling of welcome and attunement in the client's body—the child in that memory can "come home" now. It's safe. In my mind, these moments are what it means to "process" memory: the client can tolerate the memory when he or she observes it as "what happened" to the little part, and creating the new ending to that event transforms the experience. Now, it ends with the child safely in the arms of someone safe and caring. Both adult and child feel a warm and loving connection to each other.

此类记忆最重要的治疗目的，在于加深正常生活的持续自我与其曾经身为的年幼孩子之间发自内心的连结。来访者与未竟过去的关系之转化，往往在正常生活的持续自我突然连结到孩子的感受体验并立刻感到悲伤或保护欲时自发发生。泪水自然涌现；胸口或心灵敞开；来访者的双臂感受到向孩子伸出的冲动；慈悲的话语自然涌现。来访者的身体中有一种欢迎与协调的感觉——记忆中的那个孩子现在可以"回家"了。是安全的。在我看来，这些时刻正是"处理"记忆的真正含义：当来访者将记忆观察为发生在年幼部分身上的"往事"时，便能容忍那段记忆，而为那个事件创造新的结局便转化了整个体验。现在，它以孩子安全地依偎在某个安全、关爱的人的怀中而告终。成人与孩子都感受到彼此之间温暖而充满爱的连结。

If clients are helped to notice those moments, to identify how it feels emotionally and somatically to connect empathically to young parts, and then to focus on these new feelings for 30 seconds or more, the brain will begin to encode them as memory (Hanson, 2014; Ogden & Fisher, 2015). These new experiences are further deepened when new meaning is made of them: "Notice that when the parts feel your caring and protectiveness, they can relax a little bit. Ask them: do they feel safer when they feel heard and understood?" Asking child parts about their feelings in response to the adult self's protectiveness is an intimate question, one that can only enhance the felt sense of closeness and attunement. When the child part says "Yes!" or even "I wish I could believe you," clients experience a stronger felt sense of bonding and a felt sense of responsibility to stay present and protective.

如果帮助来访者注意到这些时刻，识别共情连结到年幼部分时在情感和躯体层面的感受，然后将注意力集中在这些新感受上持续30秒或更长时间，大脑就会开始将它们编码为记忆（Hanson，2014年；Ogden与Fisher，2015年）。当对这些新体验赋予新的意义时，它们会得到进一步深化："注意，当各部分感受到你的关怀与保护时，它们可以稍稍放松。问问它们：当它们感到被倾听、被理解时，是否感到更安全？"询问孩子部分对成人自我保护性的感受，是一个亲密的问题，只会增强亲近感与协调感。当孩子部分说"是的！"甚至"我希望我能相信你"时，来访者会体验到更强烈的连结感，以及保持临在与保护姿态的责任感。

Unable to unblend from parts afraid of leaving the house, Annie tried to go back to work by opening a tutoring business in her home. That way, she didn't have to leave the house because children came to her for their lessons. Nonetheless, her ability to create lesson plans was constantly interrupted by inexplicable deletions of material from her computer, anxious predictions of failure ("You'll be found out"), and a fear so intense she literally shook like a leaf before her student arrived.
Asking Annie to notice what the parts were trying to tell her, I asked, "What are they afraid of? Ask inside …"
After listening for a minute, Annie said: "A lot of things—making a mistake, not knowing enough, even just having someone in the house."

由于无法与害怕出门的部分去融合，安妮试图通过在家开设辅导业务来重返工作。这样一来，她不必离开家，因为孩子们会来找她上课。尽管如此，她制定课程计划的能力不断被打断——电脑上莫名其妙的资料删除、焦虑的失败预言（"你会被揭穿的"），以及一种在学生到来之前令她字面意义上战栗如叶的恐惧。
我请安妮注意各部分试图告诉她什么，问道："它们害怕什么？向内问问……"
沉听片刻后，安妮说："很多事情——犯错误、知道的不够多，甚至仅仅是家里有人。"

ME: "Ask them: what did it mean in their home to make a mistake or not know enough?"

我："问问它们：在它们的家里，犯错或知道得不够多意味着什么？"

ANNIE: "They say it meant that you got punished—or you didn't see things coming before it was too late."

安妮："它们说，那意味着你会受到惩罚——或者你没有在为时太晚之前预见到将要发生的事。"

ME: "And what did it mean to have people in the house?"

我："那家里有人又意味着什么？"

Annie, after a pause: "It meant that they had come to take you somewhere bad or do something bad to you." [Notice that events are validated but not explored to keep the emphasis on how such experiences would make a child feel.]
I try to translate the parts' communication to help Annie "get" these fears at a more visceral level: "Annie, do you see what they're saying? Your parts aren't just worried about being embarrassed or 'failing.' They are worried about being killed. They just want to make it out alive! Is that right? Ask them if that's true."

安妮，沉默片刻后："这意味着他们来把你带去一个糟糕的地方，或者对你做某些坏事。"〔注意，事件被确认但未被深入探索，以便将重点保持在这样的经历会让一个孩子有何感受上。〕
我尝试翻译各部分的沟通，帮助安妮在更直觉的层面上"理解"这些恐惧："安妮，你看到它们在说什么了吗？你的各部分不仅仅是担心尴尬或'失败'。它们担心的是被杀死。它们只想活着出去！是这样吗？问问它们是否如此。"

ANNIE: "They say you're right: they don't think it's safe out there. They don't want to risk it. I didn't realize what it meant from their point of view. I just thought they felt ashamed of me, so I tried to push through their objections and just get the job done."

安妮："它们说你说得对：它们认为外面不安全。它们不想冒这个险。我没有意识到从它们的角度来看这意味着什么。我只是以为它们对我感到羞耻，所以我试图压制它们的反对，把事情做完。"

ME: "Ask them: what did it mean to them to be so scared and have their fears ignored?" [Annie pauses as if listening inside to the parts.]

我："问问它们：如此害怕却被忽视，对它们来说意味着什么？"〔安妮停顿，像是在向内倾听各部分。〕

ANNIE: "It means that they still aren't safe if no one cares enough about them to listen."

安妮："这意味着，如果没有人在乎它们到愿意倾听，它们仍然不安全。"

ME: "And how are you feeling toward them now as you 'get' that?"

我："当你'理解'了这些，你现在对它们有什么感受？"

ANNIE: "I feel badly. I didn't mean to scare them."

安妮："我感到很难过。我不是有意要吓到它们的。"

ME: "Let them know that—with your feelings and your body, not just your words. Let them know you feel badly that they were so scared."

我："让它们知道这一点——用你的感受和身体，而不仅仅是语言。让它们知道，你为它们如此害怕而感到难过。"

ANNIE: "It's hard—I just feel their anxiety. When I try to feel for them, I just blend with them."

安妮："这很难——我只是感受到它们的焦虑。当我试着去感受它们时，我只是和它们融合了。"

The therapist now models an intervention for Annie to try out with her parts: "Ask them if you could have their full attention because you have an important announcement for them, a very serious announcement. See how they respond if you say it both with your words and with your body very emphatically, 'I would never let anyone in this house who would hurt you—never. No one bad is ever allowed in this house.' [I model the emphatic tone I want her to use.] Don't say it if you don't believe it, but I think that's the rule you created years ago, even before you had children."
Annie could feel her body relax a little, so I asked her to repeat the same words again: "I would never, ever let anyone in this house who would hurt you." A calm began to settle in her body.

治疗师现在为安妮示范一个干预，让她尝试与各部分一起做："问问它们，你是否可以得到它们的完全关注，因为你有一个重要的声明要告诉它们，一个非常严肃的声明。看看当你用言语和身体都非常有力地说出这些时，它们如何回应：'我绝不会让任何会伤害你的人进入这栋房子——永远不会。任何坏人都绝对不允许进入这栋房子。'〔我示范我希望她使用的有力语调。〕如果你不相信这些话，就不要说，但我认为这是你多年前就制定的规则，甚至在你有孩子之前。"
安妮能感受到身体稍稍放松，于是我请她重复同样的话："我绝不会，永远不会让任何会伤害你的人进入这栋房子。"一种平静开始在她的身体中安定下来。

ANNIE: "I've spent so many years trying to ignore the parts or just being blended with them—I never thought about why they were so scared. It never occurred to me that they thought they were still in New Jersey."

安妮："我花了这么多年试图忽视这些部分，或者只是与它们融合——我从未想过它们为什么如此害怕。我从未想到它们认为自己仍然在新泽西。"

"See what happens," her therapist suggested, "if each time you sit down at the computer or are expecting kids for lessons, you start by making the same announcement: 'I wouldn't be doing this if it wasn't safe. I will never allow anyone to enter this house who would hurt you. Never, ever.'"
When Annie remembered the meaning of her parts' alarm reactions to her students and reassured them using the same words over and over again, the parts relaxed and more easily allowed her to do her job without interruption. When she forgot, lost connection to the felt sense of wanting to protect and reassure them, and automatically tried to push through their fears, she would immediately experience renewed difficulty once again. Pushing through their fears was necessary when she was young, but it was a cruel re-enactment of the traumatic past now.

"看看会发生什么，"她的治疗师建议道，"如果每次你坐到电脑前或等待孩子来上课时，你都以同样的声明开始：'如果不安全，我不会做这件事。我永远不会允许任何会伤害你的人进入这栋房子。永远，永远不会。'"
当安妮记起各部分对学生的警报反应的含义，并一遍又一遍地用同样的话安抚它们时，各部分放松了，更容易允许她在不受打扰的情况下完成工作。当她忘记、失去想要保护和安抚它们的感受连结，并自动试图压制它们的恐惧时，她会立即再次经历新的困难。在她年幼时，压制它们的恐惧是必要的，但现在这是一种残酷的创伤过去的重演。

"Me Now" versus "That Part of Me Then"

"现在的我"与"彼时那个我的部分"

Because traumatized and normal life parts share the same mind and body, because triggered responses activate the body and nervous system as a whole, most clients are accustomed to being blended with their parts, losing connection to their experiences of competency, mastery, or enjoyment of life. When Annie was asked, "Why might the parts have been afraid to do this then? Why would it have been frightening in New Jersey? In that house? With that family?" she was reminded that she, as an adult, now lived in another house with another family (her family of procreation), in a different state, even in a different decade. And when the parts reminded her that they lived under constant threat of physical, sexual, and emotional abuse, she felt a sense of surprise. For the normal life part of Annie, the trauma was far away, a distant memory that she did not care to revisit or even think about. In her adulthood, she hadn't stopped to ask herself, "Why don't I want to revisit those memories?" She had been too busy raising children, tending to her home and garden, participating in the community, and being a surrogate parent to students and neighborhood children. Almost all of those activities involved some kind of repair of the traumatic past: giving her children and surrogate children the experiences of care and understanding she had never had, creating an environment in her home that communicated safety, keeping her home and yard well-tended (as unlike her neglected childhood family home as possible). At this stage of the work, it is particularly important for the therapist to challenge any "false self" assumptions that come up. Because the left brain normal life part is not connected to strong trauma-driven emotions, unless blended with them, and is fearful of overwhelm, it is easy for clients to feel a sense of being an empty shell just going through the motions of life and to conclude that their ability to function is a pseudo-self. Annie illustrates how unwise that conclusion can be: believing that she had created a false self, she failed to see how closely her values and priorities as an adult reflected her, how she had unconsciously made meaning of the past by creating a very healthy, creative, compassionate environment for her family of choice, very different from that of her family of origin.

由于受创伤部分与正常生活部分共享同一个心灵与身体，由于被触发的反应会整体激活身体与神经系统，大多数来访者习惯于与各部分融合，失去与自身能力、掌控感或生活乐趣体验的连结。当有人问安妮："各部分当时为什么可能害怕做这件事？在新泽西会为什么让人感到恐惧？在那栋房子里？与那个家庭在一起？"她被提醒：作为成年人，她现在住在另一栋房子里，与另一个家庭（她自己组建的家庭）在一起，在不同的州，甚至在不同的年代。当各部分提醒她，它们曾生活在身体、性和情感虐待的持续威胁之下时，她感到一种惊讶。对安妮的正常生活部分而言，创伤是遥远的，是一段她不想重温甚至不想去想的遥远记忆。在成年生活中，她从未停下来问自己："为什么我不想重温那些记忆？"她一直太忙了——养育孩子、打理家庭与花园、参与社区活动、做学生和邻居孩子的代理父母。几乎所有这些活动都涉及对创伤过去某种形式的修复：给予她的孩子和代理孩子她从未得到过的关怀与理解体验，在家中创造一个传递安全感的环境，将家园与庭院打理得井井有条（尽可能地有别于她那个被忽视的童年家庭）。在工作的这一阶段，治疗师挑战任何浮现的"虚假自我"假设尤为重要。因为左脑的正常生活部分与强烈的创伤驱动情绪并无连结（除非与之融合），并且对被淹没感到恐惧，来访者很容易感到自己只是一个空洞的躯壳，仅仅在走过生活的动作，并得出结论认为自己的功能能力是一个伪自我。安妮说明了这个结论可能多么不明智：她相信自己创造了一个虚假自我，却未能看到她作为成年人的价值观和优先事项如何真实地反映了她自己，她如何无意识地通过为自己选择的家庭创造一个非常健康、富有创造力、充满慈悲的环境来赋予过去以意义——这与她的原生家庭截然不同。

For Sam, the sense of his "real self" was most connected to a young depressed boy part who just wanted to read and daydream and to a teenager whose mood depended on regular access to "sex, drugs, and rock 'n roll." His normal life self was less palpable to him despite the evidence of his professional achievements, marriage, friends, and young son. He had a tendency to ignore adult commitments and minimize his normal life self as just a persona he needed to get through the day—mostly to humor others. As often happens, the minimizing of the normal life self increased the power of the younger parts to influence his decisions: rather than paying bills or taking the car to be serviced, the child part would pull him to read another chapter in his book or watch a movie on TV. Days passed in sexual fantasy or lost in the exploits of fictional characters.

对山姆而言，他"真实自我"的感觉最多地与一个年幼抑郁的男孩部分相连——那个只想读书和做白日梦的部分——以及一个情绪依赖于定期获得"性、毒品和摇滚乐"的青少年部分。尽管有他的职业成就、婚姻、朋友和年幼儿子作为证据，他的正常生活的持续自我对他而言却不那么真实可感。他有一种忽视成人责任的倾向，将正常生活的持续自我贬低为只是他为了熬过每天而需要扮演的角色——主要是为了迎合他人。正如常常发生的那样，对正常生活的持续自我的贬低增加了年幼部分影响其决策的力量：孩子部分会拉着他去读书中的另一章或看电视电影，而不是去缴账单或把车开去保养。日子在性幻想中流逝，或迷失在虚构人物的冒险中。

Challenging "false self" assumptions requires the therapist to believe that the ability to function is just as important as the ability to feel emotion, an attitude not always taught in therapist training programs. Functioning and feeling each represent a different hemisphere of the brain: the left brain prioritizes order, sequence, organization, and good judgment, while the right brain is driven by emotional and survival imperatives. The left brain is more positive in outlook because it has access to facts, while the right brain, though deeply emotional, is also more focused on the negative and on threat (Hanson, 2014). Both sides of the brain and both priorities are necessary to living a full, rich life. Additionally, as I remind my clients, a false self is a physiological impossibility: even when different individuals emulate the same person or borrow the same verbal expressions or mannerisms, each will be unique. Each imitation will be molded by the individual's own brain, body, and personality—which in turn reflects his or her unique developmental history. The therapist must help clients to appreciate how, lacking normal role models in the family, the normal life part nonetheless persevered. Borrowing role models from other families or imitating valued qualities missing in traumatic and neglectful environments was a manifestation of the normal life self's determination to build a new life no matter how insurmountable the odds. Helping clients to appreciate the qualities and resources of their normal life selves and be more aware of their capacity for curiosity, compassion, clarity, creativity, confidence, and commitment is an important responsibility for the therapist. Without explicit attention to befriending the normal life "me now," clients will continue to assume that the "me then" conveyed by their parts' feelings and dysregulation is "who I am."

挑战"虚假自我"假设要求治疗师相信：功能运作的能力与感受情绪的能力同等重要——这种态度并非总是在治疗师培训项目中被教授。功能运作与感受各自代表大脑的不同半球：左脑优先处理秩序、序列、组织与良好判断，而右脑则受情绪与生存命令驱动。左脑在展望上更为积极，因为它能获取事实，而右脑尽管情感深厚，也更专注于负面事物和威胁（Hanson，2014年）。大脑两侧及两种优先级对于过上完整、丰富的生活都是必要的。此外，正如我提醒我的来访者，虚假自我在生理上是不可能的：即便不同个体模仿同一个人或借用相同的言语表达或举止，每个人都将是独特的。每一种模仿都将被个体自身的大脑、身体和人格所塑造——而这些反过来又反映了其独特的发展历史。治疗师必须帮助来访者欣赏：尽管在家庭中缺乏正常的榜样，正常生活部分仍然坚持下来。从其他家庭借鉴榜样，或模仿在创伤与疏忽环境中缺失的珍贵品质，是正常生活的持续自我无论困难多么难以逾越都要建立新生活之决心的体现。帮助来访者欣赏正常生活的持续自我的品质与资源，并更加意识到他们对于好奇、慈悲、清明、创造力、信心与承诺的能力，是治疗师的一项重要责任。若不明确关注与正常生活的"现在的我"建立友好关系，来访者将继续假设各部分的感受与失调所传递的"彼时的我"就是"我是谁"。

To challenge entrenched cognitive schemas centered on her worthlessness and failure, I asked Gilda if we could work on the practice of "just owning" or acknowledging the facts of her adult life and normal life self. I made the first "thing to own" very factual and easy for her. "Just take a moment to 'own' that you are the mother of three children." "They are the best thing that ever happened to me," replied Gilda.

为了挑战以无价值感和失败为中心的根深蒂固的认知图式，我问吉尔达，我们是否可以练习"直接承认"或确认她成人生活和正常生活的持续自我的事实。我将第一个"需要承认的事"设计得非常基于事实且对她来说容易接受。"就花一点时间'承认'你是三个孩子的母亲。""他们是我生命中发生的最好的事，"吉尔达回答道。

ME: "Yes, they feel like the best thing that's ever happened to you—and just 'own' that feeling. Is that a good feeling?"

我："是的，它们感觉像是你身上发生过的最好的事——就'承认'那种感受。那是一种好的感受吗？"

GILDA: "Yes, it is—I'm so proud of them. By the way, I've been helping out in my daughter's class once a week. Those kids are so cute."

吉尔达："是的——我为他们感到非常骄傲。顺便说一句，我每周在我女儿班里帮忙一次。那些孩子真可爱。"

ME: "They are, aren't they? Such a cute age. So 'own' that, too. You love kids, and you like helping out in Julie's class. I bet you never had a parent who'd have come to your first grade class!"

我："确实可爱，不是吗？多么可爱的年纪。所以也'承认'这一点。你热爱孩子，你喜欢在朱莉的班里帮忙。我敢打赌，你从未有过一个会来参加你一年级活动的父母！"

GILDA: (laughs) "That's for sure, and I'm not sure I'd have wanted them to come. It would have been mortifying."

吉尔达：（笑）"那是肯定的，我也不确定我是否想让他们来。那会令人非常难堪。"

ME: "But your daughter doesn't have to feel that way, does she? I bet she likes it when you come. 'Own' that, too. You've been a parent whose daughter is proud to have helping out in her classroom."

我："但你的女儿不必那样感受，不是吗？我敢打赌她喜欢你来。也'承认'这一点。你是一位让女儿为有你在课堂里帮忙而感到骄傲的父母。"

Owning the facts of one's life is a left brain activity: gathering information and categorizing it. Gilda had been confused by her experience of the parts' strong, right brain-related emotions coupled with an emotionally disconnected left brain functioning self. It made her feel fraudulent to feel so vulnerable and dysregulated at some times and to feel nothing at other times—a perception she held as a belief for many years without ever taking the time to orient to the facts of her history, her life now, and her environment. Though she worked as an accountant, a job for which her left brain was an asset, the overwhelming nature of the parts' feelings made her normal life self feel "dead" inside. By being asked to "own" the pleasure she took in her daughter as well as her daughter's friends and classmates, she could experience that her normal life left brain self did have emotions. She just hadn't recognized them before because they were less intense and quite enjoyable—and because she had endorsed self-defeating story about herself without ever adding up the facts. Week after week, she noticed and practiced "owning" facts about herself, many of which surprised her. "You have been asked to host three weddings and a graduation party at your home—could you take a moment to 'own' that fact?" "Wow," she said, "people must really love me or love my home or both … and now I can hear a part saying, 'They are just using her, Gilda—face it,' and the pleasure I just felt went away."

承认生活事实是一项左脑活动：收集信息并对其进行分类。吉尔达一直被这种体验所困扰——各部分强烈的右脑相关情绪，加上情感上断裂的左脑功能性自我。有时感到如此脆弱与失调，有时又什么都感受不到，这让她感到虚假——这种感知作为一种信念在她心中持续了多年，她从未花时间去朝向自身历史、当下生活和所处环境的事实定向。尽管她作为会计师工作，一份左脑是优势的工作，但各部分感受的压倒性使她的正常生活的持续自我在内心感到"死寂"。当被要求"承认"她从女儿以及女儿的朋友和同学身上获得的乐趣时，她能够体验到正常生活的左脑自我确实有情感。她只是以前没有认识到这些，因为它们不那么强烈且相当令人愉悦——也因为她认可了关于自己的自我挫败叙事，而从未将事实加总起来。一周又一周，她注意并练习"承认"关于自己的事实，其中许多令她感到惊讶。"你曾被邀请在家中举办三场婚礼和一场毕业派对——你能花一点时间'承认'这个事实吗？""哇，"她说，"人们一定真的很爱我，或者很爱我的家，或者两者都有……而现在我能听到一个部分在说，'她们只是在利用她，吉尔达——面对现实吧，'刚才那种乐趣感就消失了。"

I commented: "Well, I think you and I just got a glimpse into why it's hard to own the facts of your life now—it brings up 'too much' pleasure to feel the richness of your chosen life, and your fight part gets alarmed."

我评论道："嗯，我想你和我刚刚瞥见了为什么现在承认你生活的事实如此困难——感受你所选择的生活的丰盛带来了'太多'的愉悦，你的战斗部分因此感到警觉。"

Establishing Internal Communication with Dysregulated Parts

与失调部分建立内部沟通

While continuing to identify their roles, resources, capacities, and daily activities as evidence of a strong normal life part, the therapist also repeatedly continues to remind clients to assume that day-to-day difficulties with feelings or functioning are an expression of parts being triggered by normal life trauma-related stimuli. Next, as the normal life self "listens" with curiosity or compassion or both to the dysregulated emotions being conveyed by parts, he or she is taught to respond to these communications by asking the parts to say more about their feelings: What are they worried about? Notice that the term "worried about" is consistently used in response to expressions of fear, shame, anger, sadness, even numbing and shutdown. The assumption is that all feeling responses represent a worry about something. "Worry" is a term familiar to children and adults alike. Perhaps more importantly, it is a word that does not threaten any of the parts: "anger" would be a threatening word for attach and submit; "scared" would be difficult for fight and flight parts to endorse. The expression, "What are you worried about if ______________," can be used to gather more information about almost any situation therapist or client is likely to encounter. I can ask, "What is the little part worried about if I go on vacation?" "What is the ashamed part worried about if he gives up the shame and holds his head high?" "What is the hopeless part worried about if she were to be hopeful?" "What is the suicidal part worried about if Felicia makes a commitment to live?"

在继续识别来访者的角色、资源、能力和日常活动作为强大正常生活部分的证据的同时，治疗师也反复提醒来访者：假设日常的情感或功能困难是各部分被正常生活中的创伤相关刺激所触发的表达。接着，当正常生活的持续自我带着好奇、慈悲或两者兼具地"倾听"各部分所传递的失调情绪时，他或她被教导回应这些沟通，方式是请各部分多说说它们的感受：它们在担忧什么？注意，"担忧"一词被一贯地用于回应恐惧、羞耻、愤怒、悲伤、甚至麻木和关闭的表达。假设所有情感反应都代表对某事的担忧。"担忧"是一个儿童和成人都熟悉的词语。或许更重要的是，它是一个不会威胁到任何部分的词语："愤怒"对依恋和顺从部分而言是一个威胁性词语；"害怕"对战斗和逃跑部分而言难以认同。"如果______你担忧什么"这一表达，几乎可以用于收集治疗师或来访者可能遇到的任何情境的更多信息。我可以问："如果我去度假，小部分担忧什么？""如果羞耻部分放弃羞耻并昂首挺胸，它担忧什么？""如果绝望部分变得充满希望，它担忧什么？""如果费莉西亚承诺活下去，自杀部分担忧什么？"

Usually, the worries initially expressed by parts are concrete or superficial: afraid of making a mistake, afraid of being hurt, afraid of being judged or rejected, afraid things will fall apart. Just like children, child parts tend to be more concrete and stimulus-bound. The next step is to inquire more deeply, just as we would with any child: What is he worried about if someone judges him? What is she worried about if she makes a mistake? Then the normal life self is asked to make a connection between the parts' fears and the childhood environment in which the trauma occurred: why would a child be scared of being judged in that world? Why would he be terrified of making a mistake in that family? The purpose of this step is not to retrieve memory. Making a connection between past and present always reflects the goal of increasing empathic connections to the parts' emotions and cultivating attunement. The memory is not explored in detail but serves as a vehicle for empathy: "No wonder the ashamed part won't give up her shame—it kept her safe. Maybe you could let her know that it's OK if she feels safer keeping it as long as she knows that it's just a way to survive—it doesn't mean it's true."

通常，各部分最初表达的担忧是具体的或表层的：害怕犯错、害怕受伤、害怕被评判或被拒绝、害怕事情会崩溃。就像孩子一样，孩子部分往往更为具体，更受刺激束缚。下一步是更深入地询问，就像我们对待任何孩子一样：如果有人评判他，他担忧什么？如果她犯了错误，她担忧什么？然后请正常生活的持续自我在各部分的恐惧与创伤发生的童年环境之间建立连结：在那个世界里，一个孩子为什么会害怕被评判？在那个家庭里，他为什么会对犯错感到恐惧？这一步骤的目的不是提取记忆。在过去与现在之间建立连结始终反映着增强对各部分情感的共情连结并培养协调的目标。记忆不会被详细探索，而是作为共情的载体："难怪羞耻的部分不肯放弃她的羞耻——那让她保持安全。也许你可以让她知道，如果她觉得保留它更安全，那没关系，只要她知道那只是一种生存方式——并不意味着它是真实的。"

However, initiating and sustaining an internal dialogue with parts autonomically activated by perceived threat is not always simple. It requires helping clients maintain dual awareness in the face of intrusive anxiety-provoking thoughts, shaking and jitters, elevated heart rate, tightness in the chest, sick feelings in the stomach, constriction in the throat, and impulses to run away, crawl under the covers, punch a wall, or claw at one's own skin. These somatic reactions are challenging for most clients to tolerate and often exceed their ability to describe, much less regulate. As unaccustomed as they are to the vocabulary of emotion, traumatized individuals are even more at a loss for words when it comes to their bodies (Ogden & Fisher, 2015). Even the word "body" can be so triggering that it evokes more activation rather than less.

然而，与被感知威胁自主激活的各部分发起并维持内部对话并非总是简单的。这需要帮助来访者在面对侵入性的引发焦虑的想法、颤抖与紧张、心率升高、胸部紧绷、胃部不适、喉咙收缩，以及逃跑、躲入被窝、打墙或抓自己皮肤的冲动时，保持双重觉察。这些躯体反应对大多数来访者来说难以忍受，往往超出了他们描述、更不用说调节的能力。与对情绪词汇的不熟悉一样，受创伤的个体在涉及身体时更加词穷（Ogden与Fisher，2015年）。甚至"身体"这个词本身就可以具有如此强的触发性，以至于它唤起的是更多而非更少的激活。

The therapist's job is to assume that these challenges are just part of the work, not a risk to life or a "deal breaker." Anytime we help clients learn a new skill outside of their current repertoire or try out a new approach, it is often triggering for the parts. As many clients describe it, "I know I can survive this way, but if I try something different, what if it doesn't work? What if I can't survive?" Clearly, these are the voices of parts anticipating attack or annihilation, but their strong reactions to change often paralyze both the therapist and the normal life self. The therapist asks: Is this new step or skill too much? Should the fears be ignored, acknowledged, or are they a sign that the client is not ready?

治疗师的工作是假定这些挑战只是工作的一部分，而非生命的威胁或"交易破坏者"。每当我们帮助来访者学习当前技能库之外的新技能或尝试新方法时，往往会触发各部分。正如许多来访者所描述的："我知道这样我能活下去，但如果我尝试不同的方式，如果它不奏效怎么办？如果我活不下去怎么办？"显然，这些是预期攻击或毁灭的部分的声音，但它们对变化的强烈反应往往使治疗师和正常生活的持续自我都陷入瘫痪。治疗师问道：这个新步骤或技能是否太多了？这些恐惧应该被忽视、被承认，还是它们是来访者尚未准备好的信号？

Rupture and Repair

破裂与修复

Therapists can be reassured by the research demonstrating that even as infants, the window of tolerance expands and resilience increases when infants are exposed to experiences or stimuli just slightly outside their comfort zone and then are soothed and re-regulated. (Tronick, 2007) In the attachment literature, this phenomenon is labeled "rupture and repair": the child's experience of discomfort is followed by some kind of repair (encouragement, soothing, reassurance, distraction) that reinstates attunement and facilitates positive feeling states. When these are repeated experiences, the body and mind begin to develop an expectation that repair will come: that someone will soothe the rupture, that good experiences will follow bad, and that fear will be reassured by safety.

研究表明，即便是婴儿，当暴露于稍稍超出舒适区的体验或刺激之后随即得到安抚与重新调节时，耐受窗会扩展，韧性会增强——这一发现可以让治疗师感到放心。（Tronick，2007年）在依恋文献中，这一现象被称为"破裂与修复"：孩子的不适体验之后随之而来某种修复（鼓励、安抚、保证、转移注意力），这种修复重建协调并促进积极的感受状态。当这些成为重复性体验时，身体和心灵开始发展出一种期待：修复将会到来，有人会抚慰破裂，好的体验将跟随坏的体验，而恐惧将被安全所安抚。

When we as therapists assume that, as much as something new might be welcomed by the normal life self, it is likely to be threatening to trauma-related parts, we will be better prepared to help clients. When the parts "resist" our interventions, it is because they are afraid of change: after all, trauma is a sudden "change." One minute, nothing was happening, and the next minute, it all changed. When the therapist helps the client notice the resistance as the parts' understandable hesitation or hypervigilance, there is an opportunity for increasing internal compassion. When therapeutic work is complicated by the client's hyper- or hypoarousal, by a narrow window of tolerance, or by parts triggered by the process occurring in the session, it is crucially important that the therapist attend more to helping the client regulate distress or dysregulation than to the content or focus of the session. Just as a parent often has to interrupt a conversation to attend to a child's distress, the same goal also serves to build the bonds of attachment to the parts.

当我们作为治疗师假定：某些新事物尽管可能受到正常生活的持续自我的欢迎，却很可能对创伤相关部分构成威胁，我们就会更充分地准备好帮助来访者。当各部分"抗拒"我们的干预时，是因为它们害怕变化：毕竟，创伤是一种突如其来的"变化"。前一刻什么都没发生，下一刻一切都改变了。当治疗师帮助来访者将这种抗拒注意为各部分可以理解的犹豫或过度警觉时，便出现了增强内部慈悲的机会。当治疗工作因来访者的过度或低度唤起、狭窄的耐受窗，或因在会谈中发生的过程而触发各部分而变得复杂时，治疗师更多地关注帮助来访者调节痛苦或失调，而非关注会谈的内容或焦点，这一点至关重要。就像父母常常不得不中断对话以照顾孩子的痛苦一样，同样的目标也有助于建立与各部分的依恋纽带。

A very important principle of internal attachment work is that all difficulties that arise in the session become opportunities to increase compassion and acceptance and foster a repair of the past. If clients are having trouble maintaining dual awareness as parts intrude thoughts, images, and intense emotions, the therapist can help them regulate autonomic activation without losing focus on attachment issues. For example, a Sensorimotor Psychotherapy somatic intervention could be reframed as a way to support the parts: "See what happens if you feel your feet on the ground … like you are communicating to the freaked out parts that you are solid on your feet. Does it help if you also lengthen your spine? Try it—put a little space between the vertebrae in your lower back, and see what happens. Maybe then they can feel how tall you are and how strong your body is" (Ogden & Fisher, 2015). Notice that the interventions are explicitly worded to communicate that they are not being used to silence or stop the parts' dysregulated input: the message is that all interventions are in the service of helping them as well as the normal life part.

内部依恋工作的一个非常重要的原则是：会谈中出现的所有困难都成为增强慈悲与接纳、促进过去修复的机会。如果来访者在各部分侵入思维、意象和强烈情绪时难以维持双重觉察，治疗师可以帮助他们调节自主激活而不失去对依恋问题的关注。例如，感觉运动心理治疗的躯体干预可以被重新框架为一种支持各部分的方式："看看当你感受到脚踩在地面上时会发生什么……就像你在向那些惊慌失措的部分传达你脚踏实地的信息。如果你同时拉长脊柱，是否有帮助？试试看——在下背部椎骨之间创造一点空间，看看会发生什么。也许这样它们就能感受到你有多高、你的身体有多强壮"（Ogden与Fisher，2015年）。注意，这些干预在措辞上明确传达它们不是用来压制或阻止各部分失调输入的：信息是所有干预都是为了帮助各部分以及正常生活部分。

Another way of helping clients regulate activation stemming from triggered parts is to use a technique drawn from Internal Family Systems (Schwartz, 2001): asking the parts to "step back" or "sit back." In the IFS model, this technique can be used to get past parts defending the status quo in order to access deeply hidden exiled parts. In this instance, it is used to help the client maintain a window of tolerance and maintain an ongoing dialogue with all parts. As the client reports "too much activation," "too much noise in my head," "too many thoughts going too fast," or "critical voices humiliating me," the therapist asks her to see what happens if she asks the parts to "just sit back a little" or "sit back and make more room for you. Explain that you can help them better if they will sit back just a little." Framed in this way, the parts are not threatened, and there is something in it for them—the availability of help. When clients report no response, they are instructed to be curious: "Ask the part: What is it afraid of if it does sit back?" Most often, parts reply, "If I sit back, I'll be ignored—no one will hear me." Often these responses reflect implicit memory of the past (of not having a voice, not being able to cry for help, not being heard), but often they are accurate reflections of past experience. The normal life part has been trying to ignore them, suppress their feelings, or deny hearing their voices. The therapist has to validate that fact: "You know, it's true—not knowing that they were parts, not knowing they were young and frightened, most people do exactly what you did: try to ignore them. How sad, huh? Would you like to be the first person these parts have ever known to admit having hurt them? I know it would mean a lot to them …" By universalizing the description of what has happened ("most people," "not knowing"), clients can hear these truths without the therapist triggering ashamed parts. Notice that the normal life self is always treated as a sane, competent, caring adult capable of learning and responsible for his or her actions; the parts are always described with empathy as children or adolescents whose magical thinking, fears, idealism, and traumatic wounding make them act impulsively and emotionally. Less is expected of them, but more is expected from the adult normal life self because, just as in biological adults, he or she has access to the prefrontal cortex, to states of curiosity and compassion, and has the functional abilities to take responsibility for the parts' safety in the body and in the world.

帮助来访者调节来自被触发部分的激活的另一种方式，是使用来自内部家庭系统（Schwartz，2001年）的技术：请各部分"退后"或"坐回去"。在IFS模型中，这一技术可以用来越过维护现状的部分，以便接触深藏的被放逐部分。在此处，它被用来帮助来访者保持耐受窗并与所有部分维持持续对话。当来访者报告"太多激活"、"脑子里太多噪音"、"太多思维运转太快"或"批评的声音在羞辱我"时，治疗师请她看看如果她请求各部分"只是稍微退后一点"或"退后并为你腾出更多空间，向它们解释如果它们稍微退后一点，你就能更好地帮助它们"，会发生什么。以这种方式框架，各部分不会受到威胁，而且其中对它们有益的东西——获得帮助的可能性。当来访者报告没有回应时，他们被指示保持好奇："问问这个部分：如果它退后，它害怕什么？"最常见的是，各部分回答："如果我退后，我就会被忽视——没有人会听到我。"这些回应往往反映了过去的内隐记忆（没有声音、无法呼救、不被倾听），但也往往是对过去经历的准确反映。正常生活部分一直在试图忽视它们，压制它们的感受，或否认听到它们的声音。治疗师必须确认这一事实："你知道，这是真的——不知道它们是部分，不知道它们年幼而恐惧，大多数人都做了你所做的：试图忽视它们。多悲伤，是吧？你愿意成为这些部分所认识的第一个承认曾经伤害过它们的人吗？我知道这对它们来说意义重大……"通过将所发生的事情普遍化（"大多数人"、"不知道"），来访者可以听到这些真相，而不会让治疗师触发羞耻部分。注意，正常生活的持续自我始终被视为一个神志清醒、能力出众、充满关爱的成人，能够学习并对其行为负责；各部分始终被带着共情地描述为孩子或青少年，其魔法思维、恐惧、理想主义和创伤创伤使他们冲动而情绪化地行事。对它们的期望更少，但对成人正常生活的持续自我的期望更高，因为就像生物学意义上的成人一样，他或她能够获得前额叶皮质、好奇与慈悲的状态，并具备在身体和世界中承担对各部分安全责任的功能能力。

Communicating Compassion toward Wounded Child Parts

向受伤的孩子部分传达慈悲

Children and adults alike believe the reassuring words of others only if they feel "gotten"; that is, when they sense that they are believed, understood, cared about, or important to someone. Empty reassurances not only fail to comfort but are often a trigger, evoking emotional memories of abusers whose reassurances were a way of "grooming" the child. Clients can learn the right words to tell their parts, "You are safe now—no one can hurt you—this is now, not then," but without empathic attunement, these clarifications literally fall on deaf ears. Even in therapeutic relationships, our ability to successfully reassure is directly proportional to our emotional resonance to the client's feelings and fears. If the therapist can teach the client the ability to stay connected to states of curiosity and compassion without losing the sense of boundary differentiating parts from wise 'self," they can begin to offer their parts the "missing experiences" (Kurtz, 1990; Ogden & Fisher, 2015) that repair the past, elicit "the grief of relief," and cultivate secure internal attachment.

孩子与成人都只有在感到被"理解"时，才会相信他人安抚的话语——也就是说，当他们感到被信任、被理解、被关心，或对某人来说是重要的时候。空洞的保证不仅无法给人安慰，反而常常是一种触发，唤起对施虐者的情绪记忆，因为那些人的保证是一种"诱骗"孩子的方式。来访者可以学会正确的话语来告诉自己的各部分："你现在安全了——没有人可以伤害你——这是现在，不是过去，"但如果没有共情性协调，这些澄清简直是对牛弹琴。即使在治疗关系中，我们成功安抚的能力也与我们对来访者感受和恐惧的情感共鸣直接成正比。如果治疗师能够教会来访者保持与好奇和慈悲状态的连结，同时不失去区分各部分与智慧"自我"的边界感，他们就可以开始为各部分提供"缺失的体验"（Kurtz，1990年；Ogden与Fisher，2015年），这种体验修复过去，引发"解脱的悲伤"，并培养安全的内部依恋。

For that reason, internal communication aimed at "repairing" the trauma-related implicit memories of parts is always focused on eliciting just the right amount of emotional connection between the normal life self and the parts: not so much connection that the normal life self gets blended or flooded but enough that there is a growing emotional resonance. First, based on the assumption that the parts' emotions, impulses, and behaviors are their "language," the normal life part is asked to "hear" each channel of communication as a message from a young, wounded part and to remain interested and curious in their reaching out. The therapist's responses to the part's communications should reflect the child's apparent age, feelings, and predicament. In normal life, adults rarely use the same "language" to talk to or about a 2-year-old as they would with a 16-year-old. When we communicate with little children, we use simple words, express concern not just verbally but with our body language, and we use words familiar to young children, such as "scary," "bad people," "mad," "not fair." With teenagers, the therapist has to be sufficiently connected to his or her own rebellious or adolescent self so his or her communications do not feel condescending or therapizing. "Oh shit, really?!" is far more effective with an adolescent, for example, than, "That must have been hard for you." Then the normal life part is coached to respond compassionately and to convey understanding or, if he or she doesn't understand, to ask the questions we would ask any child. As a next step, the normal life part is encouraged to explore the part's feelings or reactions by inquiring, "What are you worried about? What's scary? What makes you so sad?" Sometimes, parts reply with a traumatic or hurtful image, sometimes in words such as, "I'm bad—that's why people are mean to me," and sometimes with feelings like, "I need a friend—I'm lonely." It can be helpful at this point for the therapist to encourage the normal life part to think: Why would it make sense for a child part to feel that way? What was happening at that point in my life that made him feel so ashamed?

因此，旨在"修复"各部分创伤相关内隐记忆的内部沟通，始终专注于在正常生活的持续自我与各部分之间引发恰到好处的情感连结：连结不能太多，以至于正常生活的持续自我被融合或淹没，但要足够，使情感共鸣不断增长。首先，基于各部分的情绪、冲动和行为是它们的"语言"这一假设，正常生活部分被要求将每一种沟通渠道"听"作来自年幼的受伤部分的信息，并对它们的接触保持兴趣与好奇。治疗师对各部分沟通的回应应反映孩子的表观年龄、感受和处境。在正常生活中，成人与2岁孩子交谈的"语言"与跟16岁孩子交谈时几乎不会相同。当我们与小孩子沟通时，我们使用简单的词语，不仅通过言语而且通过肢体语言表达关切，并使用小孩子熟悉的词语，如"可怕的"、"坏人"、"生气"、"不公平"。与青少年交流时，治疗师必须与自己叛逆或青少年的自我保持足够的连结，使其沟通不会显得居高临下或过度治疗化。例如，"哦，真的吗？！"对青少年的效果远胜于"那一定很难受。"然后，正常生活部分被指导以慈悲方式回应并传达理解，或者如果他或她不理解，就提出我们会向任何孩子提出的问题。作为下一步，正常生活部分被鼓励通过询问"你担忧什么？什么让你害怕？什么让你如此悲伤？"来探索各部分的感受或反应。有时，各部分用创伤性或伤人的意象回应，有时用语言如"我不好——这就是为什么人们对我不好，"有时用感受如"我需要一个朋友——我很孤独。"此时，鼓励正常生活部分思考以下问题可能会有帮助：为什么一个孩子部分会有这样的感受是有道理的？在我生命的那个时刻发生了什么，使他感到如此羞耻？

As the normal life self takes in the fear, shame, confusion, anger, or vulnerability that lives on in the child part and seems to be making an emotional connection to the part, the therapist asks an IFS question, "How do you feel toward that part now?" (Schwartz, 2001). If clients have truly connected with the part, compassion and empathy are evoked spontaneously by that question, and the responses reflect the growing attachment to the young part: "I feel sad for her," "I want to help him," "I want to protect that little one."

当正常生活的持续自我接收到孩子部分中存续的恐惧、羞耻、困惑、愤怒或脆弱，并似乎在与该部分建立情感连结时，治疗师提出一个IFS问题："你现在对那个部分有什么感受？"（Schwartz，2001年）。如果来访者确实与该部分建立了连结，这个问题会自发地唤起慈悲与共情，而回应则反映了对年幼部分日益增长的依恋："我为她感到难过，""我想帮助他，""我想保护那个小家伙。"

For internal attachment work to be successful, it is important to use the exact wording above. "How do you feel about?" is a different question than, "How do you feel toward?" "Feeling about" involves left brain information retrieval reflected in clients who reply, "I don't know—let me think about it." "How do you feel toward" accesses right brain intuitive responses that can be felt by the part as true and authentic. As "feeling toward" the part transforms the normal life self's habitual alienation, the therapist guides the client's normal life self to connect to feeling sad or protective or proud toward the child and to communicate that empathic connection back. Often, the part simply needs to hear, "I believe you" or, better yet, "I know how bad it was."

要使内部依恋工作成功，使用上述确切措辞非常重要。"你对……有什么感觉？"与"你对……有什么感受？"是不同的问题。"对……有感觉"涉及左脑信息提取，体现在来访者回答"我不知道——让我想想"。"对……有感受"则访问右脑的直觉反应，这种反应可以被部分感受为真实而真诚的。随着对部分的"感受"转变了正常生活的持续自我习惯性的疏离，治疗师引导来访者的正常生活的持续自我连结到对孩子的悲伤、保护或骄傲的感受，并将那种共情连结传达回去。通常，部分只需要听到"我相信你"，或者更好的是，"我知道当时有多糟糕。"

Because communication involves reciprocity, an experience missing from the lives of most traumatized children, the therapist concentrates on the mutuality of the exchange: "What's it like for the little boy to feel your sadness? He isn't used to people feeling for him …" "What's it like for her to hear that you want to protect her? Does that feel good or a little scary?" Most often, the child part expresses positive feelings, either in words or in emotions and body sensations. As the client is guided to ask, "What's it like for the child part to hear us expressing concern about her feelings?" they often feel a spontaneous change in body experience: relaxation, warmth, a smile, a deep breath. The therapist, like a good family therapist, underscores all positive changes in family relationships: "Yes, she can breathe—knowing you want to protect her must be a relief, I think. Ask her if that's correct." "It feels good to him to feel that someone cares about his feelings, huh?"

由于沟通涉及互惠性——这是大多数受创伤儿童生命中缺失的体验——治疗师专注于交流的相互性："小男孩感受到你的悲伤是什么感觉？他不习惯有人为他感受……""她听到你想保护她是什么感觉？感觉好还是有点害怕？"最常见的是，孩子部分用语言、情绪或身体感觉表达积极的感受。当来访者被引导去问"孩子部分听到我们对她的感受表达关切是什么感觉？"时，他们往往会感受到身体体验的自发改变：放松、温暖、微笑、深呼吸。治疗师就像一位优秀的家庭治疗师，强调家庭关系中所有积极的变化："是的，她能呼吸了——知道你想保护她一定是一种解脱，我想。问问她是不是这样。""感觉到有人关心他的感受对他来说很好，是吗？"

Equally important is the question that should always follow, "And what's it like for you to feel how much it means to him?" As mutuality is built interaction by interaction, just as it is in parent-child relationships, this dialogue can continue: "It feels very special and heartwarming to know he's so touched … And what's it like for him to hear you say it warms your heart to have this connection with him?" "When he says he wishes he could go home with you, what's that like for you?" "OK, you're ready to take him home?! That was immediate—you're 'on that' right away, huh? How does he like that?"

同样重要的是应该始终紧随其后的问题："而对你来说，感受到这对他意味着多少是什么感觉？"随着互惠性在互动中一点一滴地建立——就像亲子关系中一样——这种对话可以继续："知道他如此感动，感觉非常特别而温暖……他听到你说与他的这种连结让你心里暖暖的是什么感觉？""当他说他希望能跟你回家时，你是什么感觉？""好，你准备好带他回家了？！那很迅速——你立刻就'行动起来了'，是吗？他怎么看？"

Especially when the part has shown the normal life self an image or there is some connection to memory, the normal life self is asked to validate the part's event-specific emotions: "I 'get' how afraid you are of leaving the house and being seen, and I understand it completely. It wasn't a good idea then to have people watching you—it was creepy." Or, "I completely understand—it wasn't a good idea to try something new unless you were absolutely sure you knew what would happen." When the parts feel the empathic "getting it" as an emotional communication, not just verbal one, there is relief and a building of trust in the normal life self.

尤其是当部分向正常生活的持续自我展示了一个意象，或与记忆有某种连结时，正常生活的持续自我被要求确认部分与特定事件相关的情绪："我'理解'你有多害怕离开家被人看到，我完全理解。那时被人注视不是个好主意——那令人毛骨悚然。"或者，"我完全理解——除非你绝对确定知道会发生什么，否则尝试新事物不是个好主意。"当各部分将共情性的"被理解"感受为情感沟通而非仅仅是语言沟通时，就会有解脱感，以及对正常生活的持续自我的信任建立。

Interference with Reparative Experiences

对修复性体验的干扰

The next step is to help clients stay connected to the reparative experience they are providing for a young traumatized child self, whether it is the felt sense of being understood, of being genuinely moved by the child's hurt and fear, or the somatic experience of warmth, muscles relaxing, heart-rate slowing. Inner dialogues can deepen as trust builds between child and adult parts, but often, just at these moments of deepening, other parts intrude to cause distraction from the moments of attunement occurring between the normal life self and the wounded child. Threatened by the feelings of attunement, warmth, loving presence, softness, and vulnerability, the critical voices of fight parts often intervene, as do annoyed parts, confused parts, superior parts ("I don't need to be here—I know all this"), or anxious parts. Generally, the normal life self is coached through these interruptions by the therapist: "Seems as if the critical part is not so comfortable with the closeness between you and the little part … Would you like to find out more about what the critical part worried about? Or would you rather ask the critical part to sit back while you finish talking to this young boy?" Notice that a choice is given as a way of supporting the new learning: when clients have to make a choice or initiate an action, they exercise weakened muscles. Having had to be passive, or to overcompensate by being impulsive, developing habits of intentionality and choice is an important part of recovery.

下一步是帮助来访者保持与他们为年幼受创孩子自我提供的修复性体验的连结，无论是被理解的感知感觉、被孩子的痛苦和恐惧真正打动，还是温暖、肌肉放松、心率减慢的躯体体验。随着孩子部分与成人部分之间信任的建立，内部对话可以加深，但往往就在这些加深的时刻，其他部分会侵入，使正常生活的持续自我与受伤孩子之间的协调时刻分心。受到协调、温暖、充满爱的临在、柔软和脆弱感的威胁，战斗部分的批评声音经常干预，恼怒的部分、困惑的部分、优越的部分（"我不需要在这里——我什么都知道"）或焦虑的部分也是如此。通常，治疗师会引导正常生活的持续自我度过这些打扰："看起来批评部分对你和小部分之间的亲密感不太自在……你想更多地了解批评部分在担忧什么吗？还是你宁愿请批评部分退后，同时你继续跟这个小男孩说话？"注意，提供选择是支持新学习的方式：当来访者必须做出选择或发起行动时，他们在锻炼已经弱化的肌肉。曾经不得不被动，或通过冲动过度补偿，培养有意图和选择的习惯是康复的重要部分。

The Four Befriending Questions

四个结交问题

Many clients have the capacity for engaging in internal dialogues with their parts: those who are less dysregulated or dissociative, clients with a wider window of tolerance, those with more ability to be meditative or mindful. These individuals often benefit from the Meditation Circle technique (see Appendix B) in which they imagine a meditation circle with a place in it for each part and then wait in silence to observe each part as it arrives and takes its seat. Having a place in the circle, being asked to express their feelings and worries, hearing concern in the normal life part's voice, even the experience of being able to count on a predictable way to be heard are all reparative experiences for young trauma-related parts and contribute to an increased feeling of safety inside. When parts feel safer and more trusting, their autonomic dysregulation settles, the window of tolerance expands, and with it, there is more activity in the prefrontal cortex, increasing the ability of the normal life self to be curious, creative, calm, compassionate, and hold onto perspective.

许多来访者有能力与各部分进行内部对话：那些失调或解离程度较低的人、耐受窗较宽的来访者、具有更强冥想或正念能力的人。这些个体通常受益于冥想圈技术（见附录B），在这种技术中，他们想象一个冥想圈，圈中有每个部分的位置，然后静静等待，观察每个部分到来并就座。在圈中有一席之地、被邀请表达感受和担忧、在正常生活部分的声音中听到关切，甚至拥有可以依赖的可预测方式被倾听的体验，都是年幼创伤相关部分的修复性体验，有助于增强内部安全感。当各部分感到更安全、更信任时，其自主失调平息，耐受窗扩展，随之前额叶皮质活动增加，提高了正常生活的持续自我保持好奇、有创造力、平静、慈悲并保持视角的能力。

For clients who are more dysregulated, more phobic of their parts, or who have fight parts preoccupied with limiting the therapist's power or attach parts focused on the therapist's caring, being able to engage in a compassionate dialogue with parts is more challenging. With clients who cannot establish free-flowing inner communication or who are in the early stages of learning to do so, it is helpful to have a more structured internal dialogue that does not require as much capacity on the client's part. The "Four Befriending Questions" address the need for a structured, easy-to-learn technique for carrying on internal conversation even in the context of dissociation or dysregulation. The name for this technique is a headline for its intent: to befriend the parts so they feel heard and welcome. The first three questions are all focused on understanding a part's core fears, usually either the fear of harm and annihilation or the fear of abandonment. What prompts the use of the Four Befriending Questions is any feeling or issue that represents a communication from a part. I often use this dialoguing technique with clients who are getting hijacked in their daily lives as a way to intervene and re-establish stability. It is also helpful when their lives are being constricted by parts afraid of the day-to-day triggers. Here is an example:

对于失调程度更高、对各部分更为恐惧、或有战斗部分专注于限制治疗师权力、或有依附部分专注于治疗师关爱的来访者来说，能够与各部分进行慈悲对话更具挑战性。对于无法建立自由流动的内部沟通、或处于学习早期阶段的来访者，拥有一种更结构化的内部对话是有帮助的，这种对话不需要来访者付出太多能力。"四个结交问题"解决了对结构化、易于学习的技术的需求，即使在解离或失调的背景下也能进行内部对话。这一技术的名称是其意图的标题：与各部分交朋友，使它们感到被倾听和被欢迎。前三个问题都专注于理解部分的核心恐惧，通常是对伤害与毁灭的恐惧，或对被遗弃的恐惧。促使使用四个结交问题的是任何代表部分沟通的感受或问题。我经常对那些在日常生活中被劫持的来访者使用这种对话技术，作为干预和重建稳定的方式。当他们的生活被害怕日常触发因素的部分所限制时，这也很有帮助。以下是一个例子：

As she is discussing whether or not to accept a birthday invitation from an old friend whom she hasn't seen for many years, Annie is overcome with shame at the very thought of going. Invited to assume that this shame belongs to a part and to focus on the feelings as a message from that part, I coach her through the following steps:

当Annie正在讨论是否接受多年未见的老朋友的生日邀请时，她一想到要去就被羞耻感淹没。我邀请她假定这种羞耻属于某个部分，并将这些感受作为来自那个部分的信息来关注，然后引导她完成以下步骤：

• Ask this part that feels so ashamed what she's worried about if you go to the party?
Annie: "She says she's worried people will see me."

• 问问这个感到如此羞耻的部分，如果你去参加派对，她担忧什么？
Annie：「她说她担忧人们会看到我。」

• Ask her what she's worried about if people see her?
"They won't like what they see. They'll be grossed out."

• 问她如果人们看到她，她担忧什么？
「他们不会喜欢他们所看到的。他们会觉得恶心。」

• "And what is she worried about if they don't like what they see?"
"She says 'They'll reject me, and then I'll be all alone.'" [The core fear.]

• "如果他们不喜欢他们所看到的，她担忧什么？"
「她说'他们会拒绝我，然后我就会孤单一人了。'」〔核心恐惧。〕

• And then the fourth and final question: "Ask her what she needs from you right here, right now to not be so afraid of being rejected and abandoned." [It is important that this final question include the exact words of the part and clearly communicate that it is asking what the normal life self can do this in very minute to relieve those feelings and fears.]
Annie heard a voice inside saying sadly: "I need you not to be ashamed of me." As Annie took in the words of this young girl, tears came up: "I feel so badly for her! She's right—I have been ashamed of her, and I don't want to do that to her anymore."

• 然后是第四个也是最后一个问题："问她现在此刻她需要你做什么，才能不那么害怕被拒绝和被遗弃。"〔重要的是，最后这个问题要包含部分的确切用词，并清楚地传达它是在问正常生活的持续自我此刻可以做什么来缓解那些感受和恐惧。〕
Annie听到内心一个声音悲伤地说："我需要你不要为我感到羞耻。"当Annie听进这个小女孩的话时，泪水涌上来："我为她感到非常难过！她说得对——我一直为她感到羞耻，我不想再那样对她了。"

• "Tell her that—let her know how badly you feel about having been ashamed of her all these years—and tell her with your body and your feelings so she knows you mean it …"

• "告诉她这些——让她知道这些年来你为羞耻了她感到多么难受——用你的身体和感受告诉她，让她知道你是认真的……"

In the following weeks, Annie tried to remember to express support and reassurance to the 13-year-old part: to apologize for having made her feel more ashamed and to promise her that Annie would not abandon her or let anyone reject her. To her surprise, she felt strangely calm the day of the party. Rather than anxiously obsessing about how awful it was going to be or shaming herself in advance, she reminded herself (and the 13-year-old) that she didn't have to stay but she could if she was enjoying herself.

在接下来的几周里，Annie努力记得向那个13岁的部分表达支持和保证：为让她感到更加羞耻而道歉，并向她承诺Annie不会抛弃她，也不会让任何人拒绝她。令她惊讶的是，派对当天她感到奇怪地平静。她没有焦虑地沉浸于想象会有多糟糕，也没有提前羞辱自己，而是提醒自己（和那个13岁的部分）她不是必须留下来，但如果她玩得开心，她可以留下来。

The next week, she described her experience: "It was fun! Lynn was glad to see me, and, for the first time ever, I didn't feel like I had to work hard to impress people. In fact, I listened a lot more than I normally would—I just spoke when I had something to say. I didn't have to keep talking to make sure they couldn't reject me."

下一周，她描述了自己的体验："很有趣！Lynn很高兴见到我，而且，有生以来第一次，我没有感到必须努力给人留下深刻印象。事实上，我比平时听得多多了——我只有在有话要说时才说话。我不必一直说话来确保他们无法拒绝我。"

ME: "And what was that like for the 13-year-old to feel your ability to just be yourself, knowing you didn't need to impress anyone? Ask her now …"

我：「那个13岁的部分感受到你只是做自己、知道你不需要给任何人留下印象，那是什么感觉？现在问问她……」

ANNIE: "She says it made her feel proud. If I belong, she belongs. If people accept me, she's more confident they will accept her."

ANNIE：「她说这让她感到骄傲。如果我属于那里，她也属于那里。如果人们接受我，她就更有信心他们也会接受她。」

ME: "Well, it probably helped that you were focused on her feeling comfortable instead of being ashamed! All the anxious parts who'd be coaching you and the critical part who'd be telling you that you were failing couldn't get a word in edgewise because you were focused on her. She helped you out!"

我：「嗯，你专注于让她感到舒适而不是羞耻，这可能很有帮助！所有那些会指导你的焦虑部分和会告诉你正在失败的批评部分都插不上话，因为你专注于她。她帮了你！」

Notice that the therapist leads her through the four Befriending Questions, step by step, and then helps her focus on the moment of repair with the 13-year-old: "Tell her how badly you feel … What is it like for her to feel someone's distress over having hurt her?" In these moments, only the therapist will be able to fully grasp the meaning of each step: with the meta-awareness of the witness, the therapist can understand that Annie would feel badly for hurting any child but also understand that, for the 13-year-old, it is a yearned for but also very new and strange experience to matter to anyone or for anyone to feel badly about hurting her. Often, the child parts feel nourished, warmed, or "held" by the caring of the normal life self but then suddenly pause and hold back, anxious or hesitant, afraid to believe that it is true or unwilling to let themselves believe it to be true. How can they trust someone who cares when all they have known is a lack of caring?

注意，治疗师引导她一步一步地完成四个结交问题，然后帮助她专注于与13岁部分修复的时刻："告诉她你有多难受……她感受到有人因伤害了她而感到痛苦，那是什么感觉？"在这些时刻，只有治疗师才能完全掌握每一步的意义：凭借见证者的元觉察，治疗师可以理解Annie会为伤害任何孩子感到难受，但也能理解对那个13岁的部分来说，对任何人来说重要、或有人为伤害她感到难受，是一种渴望已久却也非常新奇而陌生的体验。通常，孩子部分感到被正常生活的持续自我的关爱所滋养、温暖或"抱持"，但随后突然停顿并退缩，焦虑或犹豫，害怕相信这是真实的，或不愿让自己相信这是真实的。当他们所知道的一切都是缺乏关爱时，他们怎么能相信一个关心他们的人呢？

The therapist will need to help clients capitalize on these moments by validating the part's fears and lack of trust: "This is so new—ask her, does it feel good to know that you hurt for her? That you don't like hurting her? Or is it a little uncomfortable?" The client's normal life self might respond: "It feels like she wants to trust me—wants to believe I'll be here for her—but she keeps relaxing and then stiffening again and pulling back." The therapist may need to translate the child part's responses in such a way that more compassion is evoked: "Maybe she's pulling back because she wants to trust you … Ask her: would she like to trust you? Would she like to believe that you won't leave and you won't hurt her?"

治疗师需要通过确认部分的恐惧和不信任来帮助来访者把握这些时刻："这太新奇了——问问她，知道你为她而痛，感觉好吗？你不喜欢伤害她？还是有点不舒服？"来访者的正常生活的持续自我可能会回应："感觉她想信任我——想相信我会在这里支持她——但她一直在放松然后又再次紧绷并退缩。"治疗师可能需要以唤起更多慈悲的方式来翻译孩子部分的回应："也许她退缩是因为她想要信任你……问问她：她想信任你吗？她想相信你不会离开、不会伤害她吗？"

When therapists begin guiding clients through repair work with their parts, they may feel uncomfortable "putting words in the client's mouth" or assuming they know what the child part might be feeling. It is important to remember that, in trauma work, we provide psychoeducationally informed explanations for clients because they don't have the words for their trauma responses: past and present are intertwined, the language spoken by the normal life self is a different language from that spoken by the child part, and we are faced with the choice of supplying words to make sense of their experience or leaving traumatized clients in confusion. Therapist bias or client over-compliance is counteracted by asking clients to observe the effects of each intervention (Ogden & Fisher, 2015) and by asking them to check in and ask the part if "that feels right." With clients capable of tracking their emotions or body experience in more detail, the therapist can ask more detailed questions: "What happens to the tension (or fear, hypervigilance, or shakiness) when you tell her that you're here now to protect her?" With clients whose ability to observe or feel is limited, the therapist may have to provide more language or more structure or both. A simple technique for ensuring that the therapist is not "leading the witness" to a harmful extent is to give clients a menu of possibilities (Ogden & Fisher, 2015): "Does she feel more tense or more relaxed? More guarded or more anxious? Does the fight part agree or disagree with your offering comfort to the little part?" The therapist can also offer a menu of emotions: "Is he more ashamed or more sad?" Or body responses: "Does the fight part's anger feel more like energy? More like strength? Or does it want to do something?" We can even offer a menu of parts: "Does that sadness feel more connected to the attach part or to the depressed part?"

当治疗师开始引导来访者进行与各部分的修复工作时，他们可能会对"把话塞进来访者嘴里"或假定自己知道孩子部分可能的感受感到不舒服。重要的是要记住，在创伤工作中，我们为来访者提供心理教育性的解释，因为他们没有描述创伤反应的语言：过去与现在相互交织，正常生活的持续自我所用的语言与孩子部分所用的语言不同，我们面临着要么提供词语来帮助他们理解自己的体验，要么让受创伤的来访者陷入困惑的选择。通过请来访者观察每次干预的效果（Ogden与Fisher，2015年），以及请他们核实并询问部分"那感觉是否正确"，可以抵消治疗师的偏见或来访者的过度顺从。对于能够更详细地追踪情绪或身体体验的来访者，治疗师可以提出更详细的问题："当你告诉她你现在在这里保护她时，紧张（或恐惧、过度警觉或颤抖）会发生什么？"对于观察或感受能力有限的来访者，治疗师可能必须提供更多语言或更多结构，或两者兼而有之。确保治疗师不会在有害程度上"引导证人"的一个简单技术是给来访者提供一份可能性菜单（Ogden与Fisher，2015年）："她感觉更紧张还是更放松？更戒备还是更焦虑？战斗部分同意还是不同意你为小部分提供安慰？"治疗师还可以提供情绪菜单："他更羞耻还是更悲伤？"或身体反应菜单："战斗部分的愤怒更像是能量吗？更像是力量吗？还是想做些什么？"我们甚至可以提供一份部分菜单："那种悲伤感觉与依附部分还是抑郁部分更有连结？"

The importance of encouraging embodied communication cannot be stressed too much:

鼓励具身沟通的重要性怎么强调都不为过：

• "Let the little boy know with your feelings and your body that you completely understand why he feels that way."

• "用你的感受和身体让小男孩知道，你完全理解他为什么有那种感受。"

• "Use your feelings to tell her that you're here now, and you mean to stay."

• "用你的感受告诉她你现在在这里，而且你是认真要留下来的。"

• "Just hold him gently so he gets the message that he's not alone."

• "只是温柔地抱住他，让他收到他并不孤单的信息。"

Building Impulses to Care

建立关爱的冲动

Often, in trying to educate clients about young parts and their need to be cared for, therapists offer generalizations, such as "the child parts will need you to take care of them" or "when you learn how to make them feel safe," but psychoeducation such as this is frequently too abstract to grasp even by the normal life self: what does it actually mean to "take care of" or "make a child part feel safe?" Not only can those words intimidate the normal life self but can also be triggering for child parts, evoking fears of failure or beliefs that the therapist wants nothing to do with taking care of them. On the other hand, providing concrete suggestions for what exactly to say or do with young parts can be useful, especially when given in multiple choice or "menu" form (Ogden & Fisher, 2015): "You could tell him that you're a grownup now—or that the bad people have gone away—or that you're here to protect him so he doesn't get hurt again." By offering a set of choices, we can evoke the client's intuitive sense of what this young part might need: for example, "I think I should start by telling him that I'm a grownup now—that I'm not little like he is anymore. That's the only way he could believe I'm actually capable of protecting him."

通常，在试图向来访者介绍年幼部分及其被照顾的需求时，治疗师会提供泛泛的说法，例如"孩子部分需要你照顾它们"或"当你学会如何让它们感到安全时"，但这类心理教育通常过于抽象，即便是正常生活的持续自我也难以把握："照顾"或"让孩子部分感到安全"究竟意味着什么？这些词语不仅可能令正常生活的持续自我感到不知所措，还可能触发孩子部分，唤起对失败的恐惧，或使它们相信治疗师不想承担照顾它们的责任。另一方面，提供关于具体说什么或对年幼部分做什么的具体建议可以很有用，尤其是以多选或"菜单"形式提供时（Ogden与Fisher，2015年）："你可以告诉他你现在已经长大了——或者坏人已经走了——或者你在这里保护他，让他不再受伤。"通过提供一组选择，我们可以唤起来访者对这个年幼部分可能需要什么的直觉感知：例如，"我想我应该从告诉他我现在是个成年人开始——我不再像他那样小了。这是他相信我真的有能力保护他的唯一方式。"

Overcoming Internal Distrust and Fear

克服内部的不信任与恐惧

A frequent deterrent to restoring a sense of hope and safety to child parts comes from either skeptical, hypervigilent parts or from young parts afraid to trust that they are now finally getting what they have most desired. It would make sense that fight and flight parts might manifest as suspicious, mistrustful, cynical, or sabotaging parts. It would be understandable that the protector parts of some clients (e.g., those whose abusers were exceptionally sadistic, manipulative, or malevolent) would be more vigilant in armoring themselves against taking in anything positive or allowing vulnerable parts to let down their guard. This phenomenon is particularly common in clients with dissociative disorders (see Chapter 8) but also occurs in clients whose parts are more integrated and less dissociatively compartmentalized. The internal distrust of protector parts manifests very differently from that of vulnerable parts. For example, when the normal life part asks a question inside and gets no response, he or she is generally encouraged to ask the question again or to change the words slightly. But when the result is still the same, the best assumption is that the silence is a communication. It could mean, "I'm not talking to you," or "I'm afraid to talk to you," or "I don't know who you are." Or there might be a response that appears silent at first because it comes without words. The client might notice an emotion, such as anxiety or sadness or anger, or a body response, for example, tensing, going numb, a change in heartbeat or breathing. Sometimes, when the emotion is sadness and there is a physical sense of vulnerability, these communications without words are coming from a preverbal child part. In that case, the therapist coaches the normal life part to communicate just the way an adult would with any infant or toddler and to use the part's nonverbal responses to gauge the success or failure of repair.

向孩子部分恢复希望和安全感的一个常见障碍，来自怀疑、过度警觉的部分，或来自害怕相信自己终于得到了最渴望之物的年幼部分。战斗和逃跑部分可能表现为多疑、不信任、愤世嫉俗或破坏性的部分，这是有道理的。某些来访者的保护者部分（例如，施虐者特别残酷、操控或恶意的来访者）更加警惕，将自己武装起来抵御任何积极的东西，或不让脆弱部分放松警惕，这也是可以理解的。这种现象在患有解离障碍的来访者中尤为常见（见第八章），但也出现在各部分更整合、解离隔离程度更低的来访者中。保护者部分的内部不信任与脆弱部分的内部不信任表现非常不同。例如，当正常生活部分在内心提出一个问题却没有得到回应时，他或她通常被鼓励再次提问或略微改变措辞。但当结果仍然相同时，最好的假设是沉默就是一种沟通。它可能意味着，"我不跟你说话，"或"我害怕跟你说话，"或"我不知道你是谁。"或者可能有一种起初看起来沉默的回应，因为它没有语言。来访者可能会注意到一种情绪，例如焦虑、悲伤或愤怒，或者一种身体反应，例如紧绷、麻木、心跳或呼吸的变化。有时，当情绪是悲伤并且有身体上的脆弱感时，这些无言的沟通来自前语言期的孩子部分。在这种情况下，治疗师指导正常生活部分以成人与任何婴儿或幼儿沟通的方式进行沟通，并使用部分的非言语反应来衡量修复的成功或失败。

But if the normal life self asks inside, "What is this part worried about?" and the answer is silence coupled with anger, muscle tension, or numbing, it is safest to assume that this is a message from a hypervigilant or angry part: "Perhaps there is a part communicating that it doesn't trust you." Often, it is helpful at this point to externalize the part by asking the normal life self to imagine a similar scenario and notice his intuitive sense about the silent part: "If you had just adopted a traumatized child, and he wasn't talking to you when you tried to get closer to him, what would you make of that?" Most clients in their normal life parts immediately respond: "He doesn't trust me yet, of course." "And what would you do next?" "I'd tell him that I understand—how could he trust me this quickly? I'd tell him he can take his time and get to know me before he makes up his mind." Even clients who insist that they don't know how to understand or what to do about a child part very quickly access "expertise" when asked to imagine being the foster parent of traumatized children and teenagers or the director of a group home for traumatized youth.

但是，如果正常生活的持续自我在内心问："这个部分在担忧什么？"而答案是沉默加上愤怒、肌肉紧张或麻木，那么最安全的假设是这是来自过度警觉或愤怒部分的信息："也许有一个部分在传达它不信任你。"此时，通过要求正常生活的持续自我想象一个类似的场景，并注意他对沉默部分的直觉感知来将该部分外化，往往是有帮助的："如果你刚刚收养了一个受创伤的孩子，当你试图靠近他时他不跟你说话，你会怎么想？"大多数处于正常生活部分的来访者立即回答："他当然还不信任我。""那你下一步会怎么做？""我会告诉他我理解——他怎么可能这么快就信任我？我会告诉他可以慢慢来，在做决定之前先了解我。"即使那些坚称不知道如何理解或如何对待孩子部分的来访者，当被要求想象自己是受创伤儿童和青少年的寄养父母，或受创伤青少年集体家庭的院长时，也会很快获得"专业知识"。

The therapist can support the client's intuition and insight by helping the normal life self share them with the part: "That makes total sense—now, can you communicate this same message to the part that's not speaking to you right now? Let him know that it's up to him—there's no pressure coming from you—you understand why it's hard for him to trust anyone." Using the client's report of body and emotional responses to interpret the part's reaction, clients can be encouraged to just keep talking to the "silent part" and to experiment with different approaches. Perhaps the silent part could be asked, "What would you need from me [the normal life self] to be willing to tell me more?" Or the client could affirm the part's caution: "I want the silent part to know that I appreciate his cautiousness. Better to say less than say more until you know who you're talking to." Often, when protector parts are given respect and greater control, they are more willing to engage in a dialogue.

治疗师可以通过帮助正常生活的持续自我与该部分分享其直觉和洞察来提供支持："这完全说得通——现在，你能将同样的信息传达给那个现在不跟你说话的部分吗？让他知道这取决于他——没有来自你的压力——你理解为什么对他来说信任任何人都很难。"利用来访者对身体和情感反应的报告来解读该部分的反应，可以鼓励来访者继续与"沉默部分"交谈，并尝试不同的方法。也许可以问沉默部分："你需要我（正常生活的持续自我）做什么才愿意告诉我更多？"或者来访者可以肯定该部分的谨慎："我想让沉默部分知道我欣赏它的谨慎。在知道自己在跟谁说话之前，少说比多说更好。"通常，当保护者部分被给予尊重和更大的控制权时，它们更愿意参与对话。

It became clear in Jennifer's therapy that her protector part shut down everything it perceived as threatening. She could be in mid-sentence when a voice would interrupt with: "And what is the point of this? Why are we talking about it? Where are we going?" When asked, "What are you worried about if we talk about this?" the part fell silent. I suggested that her "evaluator part" was obviously concerned about wasting time in therapy and had correctly perceived that she and Jennifer jumped around from topic to topic quite frequently. Jennifer was asked to thank the evaluator part for its efforts—still silence. Then I suggested that Jennifer propose a topic to discuss and ask the evaluator part if it was OK to talk about it. To her surprise, Jennifer heard an "OK" from inside. Each time she wanted to explore something more deeply or change the subject, she was encouraged to ask the evaluator part if it was OK. Both she and I began to see that the evaluator was almost always willing to OK the request, and when it didn't, there was often a useful reason. A reparative dialogue had begun: the evaluator had been unable to protect her from parents who manipulated her little girl part's attachment strivings, but this part could protect her now—as long as Jennifer remembered to give it a place in her life.

在Jennifer的治疗中逐渐清晰的是，她的保护者部分会关闭它认为具有威胁性的一切。她可能正说到一半，一个声音就会打断："这有什么意义？我们为什么要谈这个？我们要去哪里？"当被问到"如果我们谈这个，你担忧什么？"时，那个部分陷入沉默。我提出她的"评估部分"显然担心在治疗中浪费时间，并正确地感知到她和Jennifer经常从一个话题跳到另一个话题。Jennifer被要求感谢评估部分的努力——仍然是沉默。然后我建议Jennifer提议一个要讨论的话题，并询问评估部分是否可以谈论它。令她惊讶的是，Jennifer听到内心有一个"好的"。每次她想更深入地探索某件事或改变话题，她都被鼓励询问评估部分是否可以。她和我都开始看到，评估部分几乎总是愿意批准请求，而当它不批准时，往往有一个有用的原因。一个修复性对话已经开始：评估部分曾经无法保护她免受操控她小女孩部分依附渴望的父母的伤害，但这个部分现在可以保护她——只要Jennifer记得给它在她生活中的一席之地。

Creating a New Purpose and Mission for Each Part

为每个部分创造新的目的与使命

When protector parts are given power and control consciously and voluntarily by the client's normal life self, there are many positive benefits. A better balance of vulnerability versus feelings of mastery is achieved; protector parts are more willing to allow access to young wounded or innocent parts; internal communication improves; and the client receives help in becoming more resourced, self-protective, and better boundaried—all from an unlikely source, his or her own fight and flight parts. The most frequent mistake likely to be made by the therapist is to give up in the face of the protector's silence, resistance, or devaluing of the client or the therapy, rather than reframing these responses as natural, normal, and protective in intent. The other common error results when client, therapist, or both "demonize" the protector parts: that is, see them as an interference in therapy rather than as part of the work. When the therapist urges the client to push through the objections of the fight parts or try to ignore them, it further polarizes them and reinforces their distrust. When the therapist expresses respect, gratitude, and understanding of the fight and flight parts' actions and reactions, and encourages the client to do the same, protector parts begin to be more open to collaboration. And as client and therapist persist in their efforts to make contact with the fight part, no matter how often rebuffed, it sends an important nonverbal message, one that might make even the most hypervigilant protector more curious, that they are committed and willing to have that commitment tested.

当保护者部分由来访者的正常生活的持续自我有意识地、自愿地被给予权力和控制时，会有许多积极的益处。脆弱感与掌控感之间实现了更好的平衡；保护者部分更愿意允许接触年幼的受伤或无辜部分；内部沟通改善；来访者从一个意想不到的来源——他或她自己的战斗和逃跑部分——获得帮助，变得更有资源、更能自我保护、边界更好。治疗师最可能犯的最常见错误，是在面对保护者的沉默、抗拒或贬低来访者或治疗时放弃，而不是将这些反应重新框架为自然的、正常的、意在保护的。另一个常见的错误是当来访者、治疗师或两者都"妖魔化"保护者部分时产生的：即将它们视为治疗中的干扰而非工作的一部分。当治疗师敦促来访者强行突破战斗部分的反对或试图忽视它们时，这进一步使它们两极分化并强化了它们的不信任。当治疗师对战斗和逃跑部分的行动和反应表达尊重、感谢和理解，并鼓励来访者做同样的事情时，保护者部分开始更愿意合作。当来访者和治疗师坚持努力与战斗部分建立联系，无论被拒绝多少次，都传达了一个重要的非言语信息——一个甚至可能让最过度警觉的保护者更加好奇的信息：他们是认真的，并愿意接受对这种认真的考验。

Researchers have noted that one of the characteristics of mothers who promote secure attachment in their children is the ability to resonate to the baby's state, modulate their own states to avert infant distress or enhance positive affect, and simultaneously mirror both states back to the child (Kim et al., 2014). The mirroring of the infant's state along with the mother's corresponding feelings of concern, enjoyment, empathy, or warmth seems to have the effect of communicating "I understand" but also "and I can help." If the mother simply mirrors the infant's state, both appear stuck in the same distress. They "blend" as does the normal life self with parts in distress. If the mother reflects back only her different, more positive state, there is no comforting sense of being "gotten." It is more like an empty reassurance: "I don't get it, but don't worry—you'll feel better soon."

研究人员注意到，促进孩子安全依恋的母亲的特征之一是能够与婴儿的状态产生共鸣、调节自身状态以避免婴儿的痛苦或增强积极的情感，并同时将两种状态镜像反映给孩子（Kim等人，2014年）。镜像反映婴儿的状态以及母亲相应的关切、享受、共情或温暖的感受，似乎具有传达"我理解"同时也传达"我可以帮助"的效果。如果母亲只是镜像婴儿的状态，两人看起来都陷入同样的痛苦。他们"融合"了，就像正常生活的持续自我与处于痛苦中的各部分融合一样。如果母亲只反映她不同的、更积极的状态，就没有被"理解"的安慰感。这更像是一种空洞的保证："我不明白，但别担心——你很快就会感觉好些的。"

The literature on secure attachment suggests that both resonance and repair are equally important aspects of what has been called "attunement." This concept can be applied to the relationship between parts and normal life self. Just as with mothers and infants, "blending" with the feelings of a part simply leaves that child alone with the distressing emotions, as do disembodied words of reassurance or hope. Not only is it crucial for parts to feel a visceral sense that the normal life "gets" how scared, ashamed, angry, or hurt they are but also to feel the effect of the latter's curiosity, compassion, calm, strength, and protectiveness. But because these are traumatized parts, the need for an adult self to consistently provide "attunement" in this sense will take time and persistence.

关于安全依恋的文献表明，共鸣与修复都是被称为"协调"的同等重要的方面。这一概念可以应用于各部分与正常生活的持续自我之间的关系。就像母亲和婴儿一样，与部分的感受"融合"只是让那个孩子独自承受痛苦的情绪，脱离身体的保证或希望的话语也是如此。不仅各部分感到正常生活"理解"它们有多害怕、羞耻、愤怒或受伤的内脏感至关重要，感受到后者的好奇、慈悲、平静、力量和保护性的效果也同样重要。但由于这些是受创伤的部分，成人自我需要在这个意义上持续提供"协调"，这将需要时间和坚持。

Mason was eager to work on the issue of his phobia of getting sick, which led him to hyper-focus on avoiding "germs"—creating a chronic anxiety that distracted him from being able to enjoy an otherwise satisfying life beyond trauma. As he tuned in to the fear in his body and the sinking feeling that he was getting sick, he noticed the intrusive thoughts that kept coming up ("Why did you touch the door knob? Didn't you notice that man blowing his nose?"), and a childhood image spontaneously arose. He was in a second grade classroom watching a cartoon on germs and hand washing: in each frame, there were flashes of red as the film showed examples of where germs lurked in a child's life, and the voiceover kept saying, "Watch out for germs! Wash your hands after touching surfaces—stay away from sneezing and coughing." He could see his 7-year-old self in the memory becoming more and more panicky, and he could feel the heightened anxiety in his body. As Mason remained mindful and curious about the intensity of this fear, I translated the boy's experience into trauma-related terms: "He has so many bad things happening at home, and now he's being told that there are more bad things to watch out for. No wonder he's scared! But to him, a bad thing is really bad—really traumatic. He must be terrified, huh? How do you feel toward him as you sense how scared he is?"

Mason急切地想处理他对生病的恐惧症，这导致他过度专注于避免"细菌"——造成了一种慢性焦虑，使他无法享受创伤之外本来令人满意的生活。当他关注到自己身体中的恐惧和感到要生病的那种沉陷的感觉时，他注意到不断涌现的侵入性想法（"你为什么要碰门把手？你没注意到那个男人在擤鼻涕吗？"），一个童年意象自发地浮现。他在二年级的教室里观看一部关于细菌和洗手的卡通片：每一帧都有红色的闪光，当影片展示细菌潜伏在孩子生活中的例子时，旁白不断说："小心细菌！触摸表面后要洗手——远离打喷嚏和咳嗽。"他可以看到记忆中那个7岁的自己变得越来越恐慌，他可以感受到身体中升高的焦虑。当Mason保持专注并对这种恐惧的强度感到好奇时，我将那个男孩的体验翻译成创伤相关的术语："他在家里发生了那么多糟糕的事情，现在又被告知还有更多需要提防的糟糕事情。难怪他害怕！但对他来说，一件糟糕的事情是真的很糟糕——真的是创伤性的。他一定吓坏了，是吧？当你感受到他有多害怕时，你对他有什么感受？"

MASON: "I feel sad for him—he never had a safe place or a safe person in his world." [Mason is beginning to mirror both the boy's anxiety and his own empathy.]

MASON：「我为他感到难过——他的世界里从未有过一个安全的地方或一个安全的人。」〔Mason开始镜像那个男孩的焦虑以及他自己的共情。〕

ME: "Yes, he never, ever had a safe place or a safe person … and when you feel the sadness for him, what impulse do you have? To come closer to him? To just let him know you're there?"

我：「是的，他从来，从来没有一个安全的地方或一个安全的人……当你为他感到悲伤时，你有什么冲动？靠近他？还是只是让他知道你在那里？」

MASON: "I just want to pick him up and hold him—but I can sense that he doesn't trust me." [His mirroring gets more attuned, communicating both his wish to hold and comfort and his sensitivity to the boy's fears of being too close.]

MASON：「我只想把他抱起来抱着他——但我能感觉到他不信任我。」〔他的镜像变得更加协调，传达了他想要抱持和安慰的愿望，以及他对男孩害怕太亲近的敏感。〕

ME: "How could he trust any grownup? He never met an adult like you … Maybe just let him know you're there and you want to help …"

我：「他怎么能信任任何成年人？他从未遇到过像你这样的成年人……也许只是让他知道你在那里，你想帮助他……」

MASON: "I can feel he wants to trust me, but he's afraid to let down his guard."

MASON：「我能感觉到他想信任我，但他害怕放松警惕。」

ME: "Ask him if you're right—would he like it if he could trust you?"

我：「问问他你说得对不对——如果他能信任你，他会喜欢吗？」

MASON: "Yes, he's saying that he has to pay attention to bad things like germs—he has to be watchful—he can't relax."

MASON：「是的，他说他必须注意像细菌这样的坏东西——他必须保持警惕——他不能放松。」

ME: "Tell him you could help him with that—assuming you're willing, of course. Ask him if it would be OK if you took over the job of watching out for him—just for a few minutes to see if maybe it helps him out …" [She demonstrated the action of carefully scanning the environment a full 180 degrees to take in the whole room.]

我：「告诉他你可以帮他处理这个——假设你愿意的话。问他如果你接手照看他的工作是否可以——就几分钟，看看是否也许能帮到他……」〔她示范了仔细扫描环境整整180度以观察整个房间的动作。〕

Mason began to turn his head and neck very slowly and carefully, demonstrating for the 7-year-old how thorough and watchful he could be.
"How did I do?" he asked inside.
"Not as good as me but pretty good," the boy responded.
"Show me how you would do it," Mason said inside to the 7-year-old. He could immediately feel his concentration heighten and his gaze seek out spots like doorknobs so prominent in the film. Then he tried intentionally to duplicate the same deliberate focusing of the child: "How was that?" he asked the boy.
He could feel a sense of the boy moving closer to him, a slight relaxation of bodily tension, and then a wave of fatigue hit him. "I don't know what's wrong with me—I just want to go to sleep," he said.
Again I translated, "Maybe this little boy can relax now because you're watching out for him, and you're doing it just the way he needed … He must be exhausted from all that hypervigilance."
"I can feel him leaning up against me—he is tired. I just keep saying, 'You can rest—I'm watching out for you—you don't have to do it anymore." Tears came to Mason's eyes as he heard his own words, and his son came to mind: "My son has never had to watch out for himself—no 7-year-old should have to."

Mason开始非常缓慢而仔细地转动他的头和脖子，向那个7岁的孩子展示他可以多么彻底和警惕。
"我做得怎么样？"他在内心问道。
"没我好，但还不错，"男孩回答。
"告诉我你会怎么做，"Mason在内心对那个7岁的孩子说。他立刻感到自己的专注力提高，目光寻找影片中那么突出的门把手之类的地方。然后他有意地尝试复制孩子同样刻意的专注："那怎么样？"他问那个男孩。
他能感觉到男孩靠近了他，身体紧张略有放松，然后一阵疲劳袭来。"我不知道我怎么了——我只想睡觉，"他说。
我再次翻译："也许这个小男孩现在可以放松了，因为你在照看他，而且你正以他所需要的方式做……他一定因为那些过度警觉而筋疲力尽了。"
"我能感觉到他靠在我身上——他累了。我一直在说，'你可以休息了——我在照看你——你不必再这样做了。'"泪水涌上Mason的眼眶，他听到自己的话，想到了他的儿子："我的儿子从来不必照看自己——没有哪个7岁的孩子应该这样。"

ME: "That's right—and that's why it's important not to forget this boy, just as you don't forget about your son even if he's quiet. Let's think about how you're going to keep an eye out for this little boy and how you can keep letting him know you're there …"

我：「说得对——这就是为什么不忘记这个男孩很重要，就像你不忘记你的儿子即使他很安静一样。让我们想想你将如何照看这个小男孩，以及你怎么不断让他知道你在那里……」

In this example, therapist and client had to become creative because the child part didn't want just proximity and comfort; he wanted protection. Simply reassuring the little boy that Mason would be there for him would have communicated that the normal life self had failed to understand his fundamental concern: once he had seen the film in class, no place was safe anymore. He had to watch out for abusive grownups at home and watch out for dangerous germs outside the home. Notice the importance of my translating the child part's communication which facilitated the suggestion of "taking over" the boy's hypervigilance (Ogden & Fisher, 2015), allowing him to rest. Each child part will be different: each will have different needs for repair of traumatic wounding based on age, developmental stage, experiences of trauma and/or neglect, and the animal defense to which they are connected. For example, a fight part might need a sense of purpose, control, and mastery; an attach part yearns to feel protected, loved, and safe from abandonment; a freeze or fear part could simply crave safety from harm or threat of death; submit parts need to feel worth, autonomy, and initiative; and a flight part might wish freedom from entrapment.

在这个例子中，治疗师和来访者必须富有创造力，因为孩子部分不只是想要亲近和安慰；他想要保护。仅仅向小男孩保证Mason会在他身边，将传达正常生活的持续自我未能理解他的根本关切：一旦他在课堂上看了那部影片，没有任何地方是安全的了。他必须在家里提防有虐待行为的成年人，在家外提防危险的细菌。注意我翻译孩子部分的沟通的重要性，这促成了"接管"男孩过度警觉（Ogden与Fisher，2015年）、让他得以休息的建议。每个孩子部分都会不同：每个部分根据年龄、发展阶段、创伤和/或忽视的经历，以及与之连结的动物防御，对创伤创伤修复的需求各不相同。例如，战斗部分可能需要目的感、控制感和掌控感；依附部分渴望感到被保护、被爱，以及免于被遗弃的安全；冻结或恐惧部分可能只是渴望免于伤害或死亡威胁的安全；顺从部分需要感到价值、自主和主动性；而逃跑部分可能渴望从束缚中获得自由。

In the next chapter, we will address how the work of emotional connection, communication, and repair of dysregulated memory states can become something even more fundamental to children and adults of all ages, whether they are parts of an individual or his or her children. Through repeated experiences of sessions like these and the practice of these same techniques at home, we can help clients "grow" secure attachment—just as attuned parents "grow" attachment bonds with their infants. Each time, the adult self of the client attunes to the child part's unmet need, fear, or painful emotion and "repairs" the distressing experience, attachment bonds are built, piece by piece, experience by experience. With infants, it is the baby's calming and relaxing into the parent's arms that generates a shared felt sense of closeness, safety, and warmth that we label "attunement." As the parent feels the blissful feeling of the infant's little body "melting into" her arms, in turn relaxing her body and engendering feelings of warmth and loving presence, the shared sense of closeness communicates itself back to the infant, enhancing the child's experience, and deepening the parent's sense of well-being and intimacy. The transmission back and forth of the feelings and body sensations that convey "secure attachment" deepens their shared experience, lingers on it so that it can be encoded and internalized as a somatic memory of what it means to feel "safe and welcome."

在下一章中，我们将探讨情感连结、沟通和修复失调记忆状态的工作，如何能够成为对所有年龄段儿童和成人更为根本的东西，无论他们是个体的部分还是他或她的孩子。通过像这样的会谈的重复体验以及在家中练习这些相同的技术，我们可以帮助来访者"培养"安全依恋——就像协调的父母与婴儿"培养"依恋纽带一样。每一次，来访者的成人自我与孩子部分未满足的需求、恐惧或痛苦的情绪协调，"修复"令人痛苦的体验，依恋纽带就在一次次体验中一点一滴地建立起来。对于婴儿来说，婴儿在父母的怀抱中平静和放松，产生了我们称之为"协调"的亲密、安全和温暖的共同感知感觉。当父母感受到婴儿小身体"融入"她怀抱的幸福感，反过来放松她的身体并产生温暖和充满爱的临在的感受时，亲密的共同感知将自身传递回婴儿，增强孩子的体验，加深父母的幸福感和亲密感。传达"安全依恋"的感受和身体感觉的来回传递，加深了他们的共同体验，沉浸其中，使其可以被编码并内化为关于感受"安全与受欢迎"意味着什么的躯体记忆。

When repeated experiences of "safe and welcome" are shared by a compassionate, caring normal life self and a wounded child part, the client experiences the deep sensory and emotional connection evoked by their mutual attunement as a bodily state. Although it is now many years later, the young child at last feels securely held and the client's sense of resilience more stable, just as it is in individuals whose secure attachment experiences happened at the developmentally appropriate times. The client has encoded a bodily and emotional state that conveys love and safety, the certainty of feeling cherished, and the comfort of a warm felt presence of another. At the worst of times, we can "be there" for our selves—like a parent to whom one can turn at any age or stage of life.

当"安全与受欢迎"的重复体验由慈悲、关爱的正常生活的持续自我与受伤的孩子部分共同分享时，来访者将双方相互协调所唤起的深刻感官和情感连结体验为一种身体状态。尽管现在已经是许多年后，那个年幼的孩子终于感到被安全地抱持，来访者的韧性感也更加稳定，就像那些在发展上适当时期经历了安全依恋体验的人一样。来访者编码了一种传达爱与安全的身体和情感状态，一种被珍视的确定感，以及另一个人温暖的感知临在所带来的安慰。在最糟糕的时刻，我们可以"在那里"为我们自己——就像一位无论在生命的任何年龄或阶段都可以转向的父母。

"Earned secure attachment" is a concept that has been discussed for many years in the literature and refers to the unique ability of human beings to heal their own wounds by evoking healing experiences that have been missing from their lives. Regardless of our early attachment experiences, we have an opportunity as adults to "earn" the secure attachment that was not available to us when we were young and dependent for a sense of safety on the attachment status of our parents.

"习得的安全依恋"是文献中讨论多年的一个概念，指的是人类通过唤起生命中一直缺失的治愈体验来治愈自身创伤的独特能力。无论我们早期的依恋体验如何，作为成年人，我们都有机会"赢得"在我们年幼、依赖父母的依恋状态来获得安全感时无法获得的安全依恋。

When our adult selves provide attuned experience of secure attachment to our younger parts, though, there is an added benefit, just as there is for parents who nurture secure attachment in their children. Not only do the child selves feel the safety and loving presence of a securely attached adult but so does that adult. Both are nourished and comforted—both can relax into the moments of attunement—the hearts of both can open.

然而，当我们的成人自我为我们年幼的部分提供安全依恋的协调体验时，就像那些在孩子身上培育安全依恋的父母一样，有额外的益处。不仅孩子自我感受到一个安全依恋成人的安全感和充满爱的临在，那个成人也是如此。两者都被滋养和安慰——两者都可以放松进入协调的时刻——两者的心都可以打开。

References

Hanson, R. (2014). Hardwiring happiness: the new brain science of contentment, calm, and confidence. New York: Harmony Publications.

Kim, S., Fonagy, P., Allen, J., Martinez, S., Iyengar, U., & Strathearn, L. (2014). Mothers who are securely attached in pregnancy show more attuned infant mirroring 7 months postpartum. Infant Behavior and Development, 37(4), 491–504.

Kurtz, R. (1990). Body-centered psychotherapy: the Hakomi method. Updated edition. Mendocino, CA: Life Rhythm.

Ogden, P. & Fisher, J. (2015). Sensorimotor Psychotherapy: interventions for trauma and attachment. New York: W.W. Norton.

Ogden, P., Minton, K., & Pain, C. (2006). Trauma and the body: a sensorimotor approach to psychotherapy. New York: W.W. Norton.

CHAPTER 11
Safety and Welcome: The Experience of Earned Secure Attachment

第11章
安全与欢迎：习得安全依恋的体验

"In attuning to another being, we bring a feeling or empathy with another's feelings as well as a kinesthetic and emotional sensing of another. The listener defixates from his or her experience and lets go of the mind's thinking long enough to enter into another's experience and world. We engage in a reciprocal interaction of emotional expression or affect and an exchange of felt resonance—we feel 'felt.'"

"在与另一个存在协调/共鸣时，我们带入对他人感受的感同身受，以及对另一方的动觉与情感感知。聆听者从自身体验中解脱出来，放下思绪足够长的时间，以进入他人的体验与世界。我们参与情感表达或情感的相互交流，以及感受共鸣的交换——我们感到被'感受'。"

(Friedman, 2012)

"The observed takes in the observer having taken her in, and the two become joined. This is resonance. The boundaries of oneself and another become permeable and the sense of being a separate self softens and loosens. … This is how we feel 'felt,' and this is how two individuals become a 'we.'"

"被观察者接纳了观察者对自己的接纳，两者由此合而为一。这就是共鸣。自我与他者之间的边界变得可渗透，独立自我的感觉随之软化、松动。……这就是我们如何感到被'感受'，也是两个个体如何成为'我们'的方式。"

(Siegel, 2010b, pp. 54–55)

The terms "dissociation" and "integration" have long been synonymous with one another—meant to signify that the only reasonable goal in working with splitting and compartmentalization must be the fusing together of dissociated parts to create one single "homogenized" adult. Daniel Siegel, however, makes a strong case against defining integration as fusion. He asserts (2010a) a different view: "Integration requires differentiation and linkage." Before we can integrate two phenomena, we have to differentiate them and "own" them as separate entities. We can't simply "act as if" they are connected without noticing their separateness. But, having clearly differentiated them so they can be studied and befriended, we then have to link them together in a way that fosters a transformed sense of the client's experience, facilitating healing and reconnection. A part can be connected to the past, to a physical movement or body sensation, to particular emotions. Another emotion can be noticed, related to a younger or older part, and then linked to the reaction of other parts to those same feelings. In the wake of trauma, individuals need to be able to connect implicit memory to trigger and link the trigger to an explicit context. New information about the present must be linked with old perceptions shaped by the past. To feel safe today, a felt connection must be made between the "child I was then" and the "adult I became today." Trauma-related vulnerability feels less painful when it is linked to new body experiences of mastery or to a somatic sense that "it's over—finally, now it's over" (Ogden & Fisher, 2015). Using Siegel's definition of integration, fusion is not necessary nor is it as empowering as coherence, collaboration, and overcoming self-alienation. In this chapter, we will focus on how to foster integration by differentiating parts previously denied, ignored, or disowned, connecting to them emotionally, and providing experiences that replace self-alienation and self-rejection with self-compassion and secure internal attachment relationships.

"解离"与"整合"这两个术语长久以来相互对应——意在表明，处理碎裂与隔离的唯一合理目标，必然是将解离的各部分融合为一个单一的"均质化"成人。然而，Daniel Siegel有力地反对将整合定义为融合。他（2010a）提出了不同的观点："整合需要区分与联结。"在我们能够整合两种现象之前，我们必须将它们区分开来，并将其"拥有"为独立的实体。我们不能仅仅"假装"它们已经连接，而不注意到它们的分离性。但是，在清晰地区分它们以便加以研究和建立友谊之后，我们随即需要以一种促进来访者体验转化的方式将它们联结起来，从而促进疗愈与重新连接。一个部分可以与过去、身体动作或躯体感觉、特定情绪相联结。另一种情绪可以被注意到，与年幼或年长的部分相关联，然后与其他部分对同样感受的反应相链接。在创伤之后，个体需要能够将内隐记忆与触发因素相连接，并将触发因素与明确的情境相链接。关于当下的新信息必须与被过去所塑造的旧感知相联结。为了在今天感到安全感，必须在"昔日的我"与"今日成为的成人"之间建立一种被感受到的连接。当创伤相关的脆弱性与掌控感的新躯体体验相联结，或与"它已经结束——终于，现在它结束了"的躯体感知相联结时，其痛苦会减轻（Ogden和Fisher，2015）。运用Siegel对整合的定义，融合既非必要，也不如连贯性、协作和克服自我疏离来得有力。在本章中，我们将聚焦于如何通过区分此前被否认、忽视或抛弃的各部分、与它们建立情感连接，以及提供以自我慈悲和安全的内部依恋关系取代自我疏离与自我排斥的体验，来促进整合。

When the emphasis in the therapy is not on the recall of traumatic events but on identifying trauma-related parts connected to the implicit memories that still affect the client's current experience, the need to disown the parts is diminished. When clients are helped to see their ashamed parts as "real" children of particular ages and to empathize with their littleness, their bravery, or their pain, disgust and fear give way to empathy.

当治疗的重点不在于回忆创伤事件，而在于识别与仍然影响来访者当下体验的内隐记忆相关联的创伤相关部分时，抛弃各部分的需求便会减弱。当来访者被帮助以将其羞耻部分视为特定年龄的"真实"孩子，并对其渺小、勇敢或痛苦产生共情时，厌恶与恐惧便让位于共情。

"She looks so little," clients say. "He is trying so hard to be brave, but he's really afraid." "He's too ashamed to let me own anything nice—because if it's too nice, he's afraid that someone will take it away because he doesn't deserve it." Moments before they made these observations, all three clients had been blended with their parts.

"她看起来好小，"来访者说。"他在拼命努力表现勇敢，但他其实很害怕。""他因为太羞耻而不让我拥有任何美好的东西——因为如果太美好，他害怕有人会把它夺走，因为他觉得自己不配。"就在他们说出这些话的片刻之前，这三位来访者全都还与各自的部分发生着融合。

Diane described being appalled that she had burst into tears when her boss criticized her performance: "I can't believe I humiliated myself by being so weak." Josh had been trying to replace his old car with a brand new one, only to find that his ashamed part could not let him buy something "nice." Mark came to therapy to talk about his "speechless terror" of speaking in public and the impact of this deficit on his professional life. In each case, the problem could be traced to a young part connected to particular times and events in the client's lives. Interestingly enough, I have a very clear sense of those young parts, but many of the events that wounded them were never described to me. I let the symptoms and the parts tell the client's story.

Diane描述了当老板批评她的表现时她突然哭泣的那份震惊："我不敢相信我如此软弱地丢了自己的脸。"Josh一直试图用一辆崭新的车替换他的旧车，却发现他的羞耻部分不让他购买任何"美好"的东西。Mark来接受治疗，是为了谈论他在公开发言时的"无声恐惧"，以及这一缺陷对其职业生涯的影响。在每个案例中，问题都可以追溯到与来访者生命中特定时间和事件相关联的年幼部分。有趣的是，我对那些年幼部分有非常清晰的感知，但伤害他们的许多事件从未被描述给我听。我让症状和各部分来讲述来访者的故事。

"The Symptoms Tell the Story Better than 'the Story'"

"症状比'故事'本身更能讲述故事"

Because the trauma treatment field has historically been focused on traumatic events and the roles of memory and narrative, therapists and clients alike often forget to listen to the story told by the symptoms and the parts. Taught to be stimulus-bound by the narrative, most therapists use the story to frame the treatment.

由于创伤治疗领域历来聚焦于创伤事件以及记忆与叙事的作用，治疗师和来访者往往都忘记了倾听症状和各部分所讲述的故事。被训练成受叙事束缚的治疗师，大多数人都用故事来构建治疗框架。

"It's her mother," my colleague said of her 55-year-old patient. "Really? She still is being abused by her mother??" I asked, shocked at the thought. "Oh no, her mother died 20 years ago, but she's afraid to do anything because of her mother. She's even afraid to go home after work for fear she'll be criticized and ridiculed." I thought for a moment and then had a realization: "Actually, it no longer has anything to do with her mother. It did once when she was small. But now what's troubling her is how the effect of what her mother did lives on right now in present time in her child selves and in their body memories. It's no longer about the past."

"是她的母亲，"我的同事谈及她那位55岁的患者时说道。"真的吗？她现在还在被她母亲虐待吗？"我惊讶地问道。"哦，不，她母亲20年前就去世了，但她因为母亲而什么都不敢做。她甚至害怕下班后回家，生怕被批评和嘲笑。"我想了片刻，随即有了一个领悟："实际上，这已经与她的母亲没有任何关系了。曾经有过，当她还小的时候。但现在困扰她的，是她母亲所做的事情的影响如何在当下继续活在她的孩子自我和他们的身体记忆之中。这不再是关于过去的事了。"

My colleague had gotten inducted into the interpretation of event memories as described by the client. She hadn't listened for what story the symptoms told—a somewhat different story. The client's most troubling symptom consisted of intrusive shame connected to a yearning to feel "as one" with those she loved, usually her male partners. The client often sobbed for hours after a date that did not include moments of blissful closeness to the man taking her out. Her yearning for contact resulted in numerous close friendships and intimate relationships, but the accompanying rejection sensitivity created conflicts in those relationships and sometimes a self-fulfilling prophecy when they ended because of the boyfriend's frustration over not being able to please her. As I heard the story "narrated" by the symptoms, I was struck that the story I heard had nothing in it regarding harsh criticism and frightening anger. The symptoms told a very different story of disrupted attachment, leaving a small child deeply hungry for contact, yet also frightened of her scary mother. The child who was in need of missing experiences of closeness and attunement was not being "seen" as she lived on in the client's body and emotional life. The therapist encouraged the client to share her recollections of childhood experience but never realized that remembering the events that caused the little girl's pain would not heal and comfort her.

我的同事被来访者描述的事件记忆的诠释所吸引。她没有倾听症状所讲述的故事——一个有所不同的故事。来访者最令人困扰的症状，是侵入性的羞耻感，与渴望感到与她所爱之人"合而为一"相联结——通常是她的男性伴侣。来访者常常在一次没有与约会对象亲密相处的片刻之后，哭泣数小时。她对接触的渴望带来了众多亲密友谊和亲密关系，但伴随而来的被拒绝敏感性在那些关系中制造了冲突，有时当关系因男友对无法取悦她的沮丧而终结时，形成了一种自我实现的预言。当我聆听症状所"叙述"的故事时，我震惊地发现我所听到的故事中没有任何关于严厉批评和令人恐惧的愤怒的内容。症状讲述了一个截然不同的关于破裂依恋的故事，留下一个深深渴望接触的小孩，却同时害怕她那令人恐惧的母亲。那个需要缺失的亲密与协调/共鸣体验的孩子，当她继续活在来访者的身体和情感生活中时，并没有被"看见"。治疗师鼓励来访者分享她对童年体验的回忆，却从未意识到，记住导致那个小女孩痛苦的事件并不能疗愈和安慰她。

Having listened carefully to the story told by Mark's symptoms, it was clear events had taught him it wasn't safe to speak or safe to express his opinions as if they merited a hearing. Josh often made references to the poverty and neglect he experienced, the humiliating verbal abuse, and being bullied by kids at school, but his symptoms added some details he hadn't mentioned: he had had to survive by lying low, by pleasing his parents and placating the bullies. His intelligence, combined with a drive to learn and fear of failure, made him a superior student. Though it didn't help him feel a sense of belonging anywhere, his intellectual resources "got him out of Dodge" and gave him the chance to start a new life. That was the story his symptoms told, just as Diane's described a world in which it was imperative never to show weakness—even as a small child. In each case, the events were only important to create a context for understanding and empathizing with the parts. Trauma resolution occurred organically in the context of attachment repair with each part.

仔细聆听Mark症状所讲述的故事后，很清楚的是，事件教会了他：开口说话或表达意见是不安全的，仿佛它们不值得被倾听。Josh常常提及他所经历的贫困和忽视、屈辱性的语言虐待，以及在学校被孩子们霸凌，但他的症状补充了一些他没有提及的细节：他不得不通过低调行事、讨好父母和安抚霸凌者来生存。他的智慧与学习的驱动力以及对失败的恐惧相结合，使他成为一名出色的学生。尽管这并没有帮助他在任何地方感到归属感，他的智识资源"带他离开了困境"，给了他开始新生活的机会。这就是他症状所讲述的故事，正如Diane的症状描述了一个即使作为小孩也绝对不能示弱的世界。在每个案例中，事件仅在为理解和共情各部分提供背景方面才有重要意义。创伤的解决在与每个部分进行依恋修复的情境中自然地发生。

Capitalizing on Dissociative Symptoms to Heal Dissociative Fragmentation

利用解离症状疗愈解离性碎裂

The essence of dissociative fragmentation is the ability to split off unbearable emotions from the memory of what happened, to encapsulate and disown "not me" parts and experiences, and to be guided by cognitive schemas that exacerbate self-alienation but help children survive and adapt. Most therapists and clients therefore do not realize that dissociative splitting is a mental ability, not just a symptom.

解离性碎裂的本质，是将难以承受的情绪从所发生之事的记忆中分裂出去的能力，是将"非我"的部分和体验包裹封存并加以抛弃的能力，以及被加剧自我疏离但帮助孩子生存与适应的认知图式所引导的能力。因此，大多数治疗师和来访者都没有意识到，解离性分裂是一种心智能力，而不仅仅是一种症状。

The ability to quickly retrieve information and act on it automatically and efficiently, without interference from emotion or intrusive thoughts, is central to the medical professional's ability to save lives. Dissociative splitting is also a prerequisite for the athlete on whom the team depends at a critical moment; it contributes to the ability for peak performance enjoyed by actors, musicians, public speakers, and politicians. Dissociation becomes pathological only when it is unconscious and involuntary, under the control of triggers. As a mental ability, it can be used consciously, thoughtfully, and voluntarily. The goal is not to "cure it" or prevent it but to help clients use it wisely in the service of healing and recovery.

快速检索信息并自动、高效地采取行动——不受情绪或侵入性思维干扰——的能力，是医疗专业人员救死扶伤能力的核心。解离性分裂也是团队在关键时刻所依赖的运动员的先决条件；它有助于演员、音乐家、公众演说家和政治家享有的巅峰表现能力。解离只有在无意识且非自愿的情况下、受触发因素控制时，才会变得具有病理性。作为一种心智能力，它可以被有意识地、深思熟虑地、自愿地使用。目标不是"治愈它"或阻止它，而是帮助来访者明智地运用它，以服务于疗愈和康复。

Creating Safe Places for Child Parts in an Adult's Normal Life

在成人的正常生活中为孩子部分创造安全之所

Often, the difficulty functioning reported by so many survivors of trauma, especially in work settings, can be traced back in retrospect to trauma-related triggers inherent in "normal life": authority figures, work demands (whether reasonable or unreasonable), challenge and change, success or failure, visibility or invisibility, pressure, working in groups, lack of social support, feeling "too little" for the responsibilities being given to us. In each instance, the trigger stimulates a part or parts that hijack or blend with the normal life self, impairing its ability to function.

许多创伤幸存者所报告的功能困难，尤其是在工作环境中，往往可以回溯至"正常生活"中固有的创伤相关触发因素：权威人物、工作要求（无论合理与否）、挑战与变化、成功或失败、被看见或被忽视、压力、团队合作、缺乏社会支持、感到对所承担的责任"太渺小"。在每一种情况下，触发因素都会激活某个或某些部分，这些部分劫持或融合于正常生活的持续自我，损害其正常运作的能力。

Frances was a distinguished-looking, well-dressed professional woman in her early 60s, known in her industry for the large and successful business she established providing services to corporations. Ironically, a divorce led her to therapy; her abuse history was revealed; and her first therapist embarked on a trauma treatment, unaware that she was highly dissociative and fragmented. Within months, she was struggling to function at work and curled up in a fetal position at home, sobbing for hours. "I knew I couldn't do it anymore the day I went into work, and I didn't know how to turn on the computer—I didn't know how the copy machine worked—I couldn't concentrate, and I didn't know whom to trust." Frances had been hijacked by child parts connected to the abuse memories she had been processing in therapy. The severity of her fragmentation, symptoms such as the dramatic "loss of well-learned functions," gaps in memory, and preoccupation with suicide all suggested that she might have dissociative identity disorder (DID). As I began to treat her, evidence of parts' activity was dramatic. She described coming home from work or a therapy session, collapsing in her front hall in sobs, and then having no recall of what happened until she "woke up" on the cold stone floor hours later. The suicidality was cleared related to a suicidal part that, she reported, had had a suicide plan for the last 40 years—along with the means to carry it out.
"I go to the firing range every 6 months to renew my license to carry," she reported proudly as she walked in late to her therapy session. I smiled to myself, noting that this part did not have the same boundaries as Frances did. The latter was punctual to the minute. "She" referred to the gun as her "suicide kit" and assured me she took it everywhere. It was unnerving to hear Frances identify with the suicidal part, but I could not risk alienating that part by questioning this pattern. If she is identified with the suicidal part, I wondered, who has been disowned? Because Frances was so destabilized, I simplified the treatment to the bare minimum: she described her difficulties getting through the day, and I encouraged her to be mindful and aware of the parts whose feelings and symptoms overwhelmed her. One day, she was so blended with a young, grieving part that longed for her father (the father who had sexually abused her but had also loved her and been her "safe" attachment figure) that I spontaneously suggested that we stand up and "rock the baby." We both stood up, facing each other, and rocked from foot to foot, each holding an imaginary baby in our arms.
I could see her body calming, her feelings settling a little bit, as we rocked: "How does she like being held, Frances?" I asked. "She loves it," Frances reported. "Wonderful—she's needed this, hasn't she? She's been so desperate these last few months, poor little thing." "This is good for her—and good for me. It reminds me of rocking my babies 30 years ago—as much as it soothed them, it soothed me. I guess she must have loved it, too."
The next week, she reported that she was rocking the baby part rather than let her cry herself to sleep on the hallway floor. "I guess I can't ignore her anymore—she'll play havoc with my life. … Oh, by the way, it's my birthday this weekend, and the suicidal part is already thinking about how to celebrate it …"
Frances in her dignified professional normal life self had asked me a question at our first session: "Would you ever commit one of your patients to a hospital if he or she were suicidal?" And I answered, "I'm proud to say that I've never committed anyone to a hospital against their will in 30 years of practice, and I'm determined to keep that record until I retire. Patients of mine have gone to the hospital when needed," I clarified, "but always on their own volition." Now I had to discuss the suicidal part's views on birthday celebrations still bound by my policy of avoiding involuntary commitment of any patient. I had told Frances that I "always work it out with each individual."

Frances是一位六十出头、外表优雅、衣着考究的职业女性，因为她为企业提供服务所建立的庞大而成功的业务而在业界闻名。具有讽刺意味的是，一场离婚将她带到了治疗中；她的虐待史被揭示出来；她的第一位治疗师开始了创伤治疗，却没有意识到她具有高度的解离性和碎裂性。几个月内，她在工作中挣扎着维持功能，在家里蜷缩成胎儿姿势，哭泣数小时。"我知道我再也做不到了，就在那天我去上班，我不知道如何开电脑——我不知道复印机如何工作——我无法集中注意力，也不知道该信任谁。"Frances被与她在治疗中处理的虐待记忆相关联的孩子部分所劫持。她碎裂的严重程度、诸如戏剧性的"已习得功能的丧失"、记忆空白以及对自杀的执念等症状，都表明她可能患有解离性身份障碍（DID）。当我开始治疗她时，各部分活动的证据是戏剧性的。她描述从工作或治疗会谈回家后，在前厅哭倒在地，然后在数小时后"醒来"时躺在冰冷的石地板上，对此期间发生的事毫无记忆。自杀倾向被明确与一个自杀部分相关联，据她报告，这个部分在过去40年里一直有一个自杀计划——连同实施的手段。
"我每6个月去一次靶场，更新我的持枪证，"她在迟到地走进治疗会谈时自豪地报告道。我暗自微笑，注意到这个部分与Frances本人的边界并不相同。后者守时到分钟。"她"将枪称为她的"自杀工具包"，并向我保证她随身携带它。听到Frances认同那个自杀部分令人不安，但我不能冒险通过质疑这种模式而疏远那个部分。我心想，如果她认同的是自杀部分，那么谁被抛弃了？因为Frances如此不稳定，我将治疗简化到最低限度：她描述白天度过的困难，我鼓励她对那些用感受和症状压倒她的部分保持正念觉知。有一天，她与一个渴望父亲的年幼、悲伤的部分发生了深度融合（那个曾对她实施性虐待但也爱她、曾是她"安全"依恋对象的父亲），我自发地建议我们站起来"抱婴儿摇晃"。我们都站了起来，面对彼此，各自抱着一个想象中的婴儿，从一只脚摇到另一只脚。
摇晃着，我看到她的身体平静下来，感受稍稍安定："她喜欢被抱着的感觉吗，Frances？"我问道。"她喜欢，"Frances报告说。"太好了——她一直需要这个，不是吗？这几个月她太渴望了，可怜的小东西。""这对她好——对我也好。它让我想起30年前摇我的孩子——它安抚了他们多少，也同样安抚了我。我想她一定也爱这种感觉。"
下一周，她报告说她在摇那个婴儿部分，而不是让她在走廊地板上哭到入睡。"我想我再也不能忽视她了——她会把我的生活搞得一团糟。……哦，顺便说一下，这个周末是我的生日，那个自杀部分已经在想如何庆祝了……"
Frances以她庄重的职业正常生活自我在我们第一次会谈时问了我一个问题："如果你的某个病人有自杀倾向，你会把他/她强制送入医院吗？"我回答说："我自豪地说，在30年的执业中，我从未在当事人不情愿的情况下强制送任何人入院，而且我决心在退休之前保持这一记录。我的患者在需要时去过医院，"我澄清道，"但始终出于他们自己的意愿。"现在我不得不讨论那个自杀部分对生日庆祝的看法，同时仍受我避免对任何患者实施非自愿强制入院的政策约束。我曾告诉Frances，我"总是与每个人单独协商解决"。

ME: "I'm not sure the suicidal part's idea of a birthday celebration is quite what the little parts of you are dreaming about, and their needs should be uppermost on a birthday. Older kids don't care about birthdays, but little ones do. What were birthdays like in your family?"

我："我不确定那个自杀部分对生日庆祝的想法，是不是你内心那些小部分所梦想的，而在生日这天，她们的需求应当是最重要的。大一些的孩子不在乎生日，但小的孩子会在乎。你家里的生日是什么样的？"

FRANCES: "They were extravaganzas of my mother's making—kids were always envious of me because of them. They didn't know the price I paid: I used to dread my birthday. I'd get a party that just embarrassed me, and then I'd 'get' something 'special' from my father." [She shuddered at the thought.]

Frances："那些都是我母亲精心安排的盛大庆典——孩子们总是因此羡慕我。他们不知道我付出的代价：我曾经非常畏惧自己的生日。我会得到一个只会让我难堪的派对，然后我会从父亲那里'得到'一些'特别'的东西。"[她一想到这里就不寒而栗。]

ME: "It doesn't sound like they ever got what a child wants! A child just wants to feel loved and special, to be the center of attention in a good way, or to get to choose what kind of party she wants, who she wants there, and to be in charge." Then I had an idea. "Why don't you give the child parts a special birthday? They have been waiting a long time to celebrate their birthday 'their way.' First, they need a present—from you. Just go to a nice toy store and walk through it, allowing your eyes to gaze wherever they wish and noticing where they stop and stare or the toy they keep going back to look at. That can be something special you do with them, too—they never had anyone do something special for them."

我："听起来他们从来没有得到孩子真正想要的！孩子只想感到被爱和被重视，以美好的方式成为关注的中心，或者能够选择她想要什么样的派对、她想邀请谁，并且做主。"然后我有了一个想法。"你为什么不给孩子部分一个特别的生日？她们等待以'她们的方式'庆祝生日已经很久了。首先，她们需要一份礼物——来自你的礼物。就去一家好的玩具店，在里面走一走，让你的眼睛随意注视，留意它们在哪里停下来盯着看，或者一再回去看的玩具是什么。那也可以是你和她们一起做的特别之事——她们从来没有人为她们做些特别的事情。"

The next week, Frances arrived, glowing and excited. "You'll never guess what I bought for the parts—I can't get over it! This is 'not me'—it's definitely for them." Reaching into her purse, she proudly pulled out a beautiful pink pig, a stuffed animal representation of Olivia, the pink pig heroine of a children's story. "Can you believe it? Me? A pink pig named Olivia?!! You know that I did this just for them …" And then she paused: "But I have to tell you: I love her, too. Isn't she beautiful?" To this day, whenever I see an Olivia, I think of Frances and how Olivia changed her life. For the first time, the parts were given what they wanted instead of what their parents wanted to gratify narcissistic and pedophile impulses. Something fundamental changed in their sense of safety on that birthday: they could feel someone was there for them. Someone cared enough to buy them Olivia and brought comfort to the crying infant part and a smile to the little girl.
Just before her next business trip, Frances casually commented, "You know, I think I'll take Olivia on this trip instead of my suicide kit …"
"That would be lovely for 'the kids.' Do you think that will be a problem for your suicidal part?" I asked.
"No, I don't think so—he's pretty calm as long as they are OK."

下一周，Frances带着光彩和兴奋到来。"你绝对猜不到我给各部分买了什么——我简直不敢相信！这'不是我的风格'——这绝对是为她们买的。"她伸手进包，自豪地掏出一只漂亮的粉红猪，是儿童故事中粉红猪女主角Olivia的毛绒玩具。"你能相信吗？是我？一只叫Olivia的粉红猪？！！你知道我这样做只是为了她们……"然后她停顿了一下："但我要告诉你：我也爱她。她难道不美吗？"直到今天，每当我看到Olivia，我就会想到Frances，想到Olivia如何改变了她的生活。有生以来第一次，这些部分得到了她们真正想要的东西，而不是她们父母为了满足自恋和恋童癖冲动而给予的。那个生日，她们的安全感发生了根本性的变化：她们能感受到有人在为她们而在。有人足够在乎地为她们买了Olivia，给那个哭泣的婴儿部分带来了安慰，给那个小女孩带来了微笑。
在她下一次出差之前，Frances随口说道："你知道吗，我想这次出差我要带Olivia，而不是我的自杀工具包……"
"那对'孩子们'来说太好了。你认为这对你的自杀部分会有问题吗？"我问道。
"不，我不这么认为——只要她们还好，他就相当平静。"

Frances used her dissociative abilities to allow the eager eyes of the little parts a separation from her more critical eye so they could look around the toy store without her influencing their choices. Then, still maintaining a voluntary and deliberate split, the normal life part's judgments about a pink pig could be kept separate from the little girl who fell in love "at first sight" with Olivia, allowing the purchase to be made. Frances had been a good mother figure: she put her child parts' feelings first, thanks to the voluntary use of the dissociative splits.

Frances运用了她的解离能力，让那些渴望的小部分的眼睛与她更具批判性的眼光分离，这样她们就能在玩具店里四处张望，而不受她的选择影响。然后，在仍然保持自愿而刻意的分裂的同时，正常生活部分对一只粉红猪的评判，可以与"一见钟情"爱上Olivia的小女孩分开，从而使购买得以完成。Frances扮演了一个好母亲的角色：多亏了自愿使用解离性分裂，她将孩子部分的感受放在了首位。

Supporting a Functioning Adult Normal Life Self

支持一个能够正常运作的成人正常生活自我

Josh's ashamed little boy part was asked to orient to the adult Josh's environment: his business office, his home, wife, and three children. Josh asked the little boy to notice how people treated him now that he was an adult: "They act like you're important!" the little boy noticed with awe. He observed how Josh was welcomed by his amateur baseball team, his church community, and his family of choice. It was clear to the boy that Josh "belonged." "You're with me now," Josh kept saying. "No one here is going to take away something nice of mine."

Josh那个羞耻的小男孩部分被邀请去定向到成年Josh的环境：他的商务办公室、他的家、妻子和三个孩子。Josh请那个小男孩注意，现在他是成年人了，人们如何对待他："他们对待你好像你很重要！"小男孩带着敬畏注意到。他观察到Josh是如何被他的业余棒球队、教会社区和自己选择的家人所欢迎的。小男孩清楚地看到，Josh是"有归属的"。"你现在和我在一起，"Josh不断地说。"这里没有人会夺走我的美好东西。"

Mark and I realized that the frightened little boy "trying so hard to be brave" about his upcoming speaking engagement had not been asked to speak—the normal life Mark had! (Many traumatized clients report the same phenomenon: child parts that once had to be precociously adult often confuse adult roles and activities as "things they have to do.") As I coached him, Mark explained to the boy that he was a grownup, and grownups like to speak in public because they want to tell people about their work and share their ideas. "Really?" said the little boy.

Mark和我意识到，那个在即将到来的演讲中"拼命努力表现勇敢"的受惊小男孩，并没有被要求去演讲——正常生活的Mark才被要求！（许多被创伤的来访者报告了同样的现象：曾经不得不早熟成人化的孩子部分，常常将成人的角色和活动误认为是"他们必须做的事情"。）在我指导他的过程中，Mark向那个男孩解释说他是一个成年人，而成年人喜欢公开演讲，因为他们想告诉别人自己的工作并分享他们的想法。"真的吗？"那个小男孩说道。

MARK: "It's because no one will hurt a grownup like they hurt kids or say mean things, like the other kids do. Grownups like to do a lot of things that are scary for children, but you don't have to do those things. You're just a little boy, and kids shouldn't have to do scary grownup stuff." I asked Mark to propose a plan that might work for both him and the child:

Mark："那是因为没有人会像伤害孩子那样伤害成年人，或者说那些刻薄的话，就像其他孩子做的那样。成年人喜欢做很多对孩子来说很可怕的事情，但你不必做那些事情。你只是个小男孩，孩子不应该不得不做可怕的成人事务。"我请Mark提出一个对他和那个孩子都可行的方案：

MARK: "Would it be OK if I spoke at the meeting next week, and you could stay home. You don't have to go to scary things grownups choose to do."

Mark："如果我下周去会议上演讲，而你可以待在家里，这样可以吗？你不必去参加成年人选择去做的那些可怕的事情。"

"I guess so," said the little boy.
"Maybe he'd like to watch you speak," I hinted.
After a moment of silence, Mark's face lit up. "He says he would like to stay home with the cat and watch me on TV!"
We both laughed: "Why not?" I said. "Dissociation is a wonderful ability. It's just as possible for him to stay home and watch you on 'TV' as it is for him to still be trapped in that house in Virginia while you go on with life in New York." Subsequently, Mark's career blossomed: each time he encountered a "scary" challenge, at least scary to the boy, he would have the same discussion. "I know it's very scary for you to get on a plane with so many people and feel trapped inside, but you don't have to do that. Business trips are for grownups because they have jobs. Kids don't have to have jobs, but grownups do. Where would you like to be when I'm on the plane and at my meeting?"
"I want to be home with the cat," the little boy said. "But I'll miss you."

"我想可以吧，"小男孩说道。
"也许他想观看你演讲，"我暗示道。
沉默片刻后，Mark的脸亮了起来。"他说他想待在家里陪猫，在电视上看我！"
我们都笑了："为什么不呢？"我说。"解离是一种美妙的能力。他待在家里在'电视'上看你演讲，与他仍然被困在弗吉尼亚州的那所房子里、而你在纽约继续生活，同样是可能的。"此后，Mark的职业生涯蓬勃发展：每次他遇到一个"可怕"的挑战——至少对那个男孩来说是可怕的——他都会进行同样的讨论。"我知道对你来说和这么多人一起坐飞机并感到被困在里面是非常可怕的，但你不必那样做。出差是为成年人准备的，因为他们有工作。孩子不必有工作，但成年人有。当我在飞机上和会议上时，你想在哪里？"
"我想待在家里陪猫，"小男孩说。"但我会想念你的。"

This simple technique (making conscious, voluntary use of the existing dissociative compartmentalization in the service of growth and healing) has allowed numerous clients of mine to undertake what otherwise would have been very triggering, even overwhelming normal life experiences. One client was able to take her husband and children to visit her parents, a thought that initially caused panic and nausea, communicating how alarmed the parts were at the very thought. By leaving them "at home," she and her family had a short but uneventful visit, and the parts felt heard and protected.

这个简单的技术（有意识地、自愿地利用现有的解离性隔离，以服务于成长和疗愈）使我的许多来访者能够承担原本会非常触发甚至令人不堪的正常生活体验。一位来访者能够带着她的丈夫和孩子去拜访她的父母——这个念头最初引发了恐慌和恶心，传达出各部分对这个想法有多警觉。通过将它们"留在家里"，她和她的家人进行了简短而平静的拜访，各部分感到被倾听和被保护。

Another client was able to finish law school when parts that were intimidated and terrified were allowed to stay home while "she" went. "Law school is something grownups choose—not a place for kids," she told them each morning. She used the same technique when it came time to find a job, buy a home with her husband, adopt a rescue dog, and have a baby. Whenever aspects of her normal life were threatening, the parts were given a choice: "You can come on the job interview if you want—you can help me with the baby if you want … but if you don't want to, you can all stay home." The parts felt a sense of protection and understanding: they were little, too little for law school and home-buying and babies. For the client, it was an empowering experience: she continued growing as a mature adult without always having to battle her parts just to be able to function.

另一位来访者在那些被恐吓和恐惧的部分被允许待在家里、而"她"去上学的情况下，完成了法学院的学业。"法学院是成年人选择的地方——不是孩子待的地方，"她每天早晨告诉它们。当她需要找工作、与丈夫买房、收养一只救助犬、生孩子时，她也使用了同样的技术。每当正常生活的某些方面令人感到威胁时，各部分都被给予选择："你们可以来参加工作面试，如果你们想的话——你们可以帮我照顾婴儿，如果你们想的话……但如果你们不想，你们都可以待在家里。"各部分感到一种被保护和被理解的感觉：她们太小了，太小而不适合法学院、买房和照顾婴儿。对来访者而言，这是一种赋权的体验：她继续作为成熟的成年人成长，而不必总是与自己的各部分搏斗才能正常运作。

"Earned Secure Attachment"

"习得的安全依恋"

In research on earned secure attachment or "earned security," attachment status is evaluated according to the degree of "coherence" in the subjects' narratives as they reflect back on early attachment experience. Siegel, D. J. (2010b). The mindful therapist: a clinician's guide to mindsight and neural integration. New York: W.W. Norton. "Coherence" is the opposite of having fragmented, conflicting, and polarized points of view within one individual. Coherence means arriving at a place where the sum of many views come together—as they did when Mark and the little boy agreed that the child should be spared having to participate in frightening, overwhelming grownup activities. Each time they made that agreement, Mark felt liberated from the past: he could pursue his career, unafraid that its demands would trigger incapacitating feeling memories. Rather than having to be a precocious miniature adult as he had throughout childhood, the child part was offered a very new, previously missing experience. Someone was taking care of him. He could be a little boy and still be safe.

在关于习得的安全依恋或"习得安全感"的研究中，依恋状态根据受试者在回顾早期依恋体验时叙事的"连贯性"程度来评估。Siegel, D. J.（2010b）。《正念治疗师：心智视野与神经整合的临床指南》。纽约：W.W. Norton。"连贯性"与一个个体内部存在碎裂、冲突和两极化观点相对立。连贯性意味着到达一个众多观点汇聚在一起的地方——就像Mark和那个小男孩同意孩子应该被免于参与令人恐惧、令人不堪的成人活动时所发生的那样。每次他们达成那个协议，Mark就感到从过去中解放出来：他可以追求自己的职业，不再害怕职业的要求会触发令人丧失能力的感受记忆。与其像他整个童年那样不得不成为一个早熟的微型成人，这个孩子部分被给予了一种全新的、此前缺失的体验。有人在照顾他。他可以做个小男孩，同时仍然是安全的。

Secure Attachment Is a Somatic and Emotional Experience, Not an Event

安全依恋是一种躯体和情感体验，而非一个事件

Secure attachment is not an objective goal—it is a physical and emotional state that one can call by many names: "safe," "close," "connected," "recognized," "understood." Secure attachment is cocreated and unintentional in its unfolding. It emerges from repeated moments of felt resonance, from the delighted feeling of "speaking the same language." It thrives on pattern and consistency. This is why children love to play the same games of peek-a-boo and hide-and-seek that Laura played imaginatively with her parts in the woods. They thrive on hearing the same words repeated in the same tone over and over, hearing the same song or nursery rhyme or joke, having the same goodnight routine every night. Providing secure attachment experiences to a child requires flexibility of response, a spacious window of tolerance, and the ability to "coregulate," to make little adjustments to the other as the other adjusts to us—until the "fit" feels "just right." In parent-child relationships, this process is aided by the fact that there are two separate bodies, two separate smiles, two sets of arms and legs. It is perceptually clear to both that they are separate beings.

安全依恋不是一个客观目标——它是一种可以用许多名称来称呼的身体和情感状态："安全"、"亲近"、"连结"、"被认可"、"被理解"。安全依恋是共同创造的，在其展开过程中是无意为之的。它从一次次被感知到的共鸣时刻中涌现，从"说同一种语言"的喜悦感受中涌现。它在规律和一致性中蓬勃生长。这就是为什么孩子们喜欢玩Laura在树林里与各部分想象性地玩耍的同样的躲猫猫和捉迷藏游戏。他们在一遍遍以同样的语调听到相同的词语、听到同一首歌或童谣或笑话、每晚有同样的道晚安惯例中蓬勃成长。为孩子提供安全依恋体验需要反应的灵活性、宽阔的耐受窗，以及"共同调节"的能力——在对方调整到我们时，对对方做出细微调整——直到"契合"感觉"恰到好处"。在亲子关系中，这个过程得益于以下事实：有两个分开的身体、两个分开的微笑、两套手臂和双腿。两者在感知上都清楚地知道他们是独立的存在。

When it comes to attuning to their younger selves, traumatized clients are hampered by automatic tendencies to instinctively recoil from the parts' painful emotions and fears. The fact that these emotions and implicit memories are not separate is also challenging: both sets of feelings arise within the boundaries of one body. That biological fact creates difficulties in knowing whose feeling is whose and supports the tendency to "blend" with each other's emotions. As clients often say to me when I notice an emotion and name it as a part's feeling memory: "No, I am having the feeling, and I am having it now." When they identify with the feeling, it usually intensifies—as it also does when they disown the feeling, believing that it's not theirs, and disown the part whose wounding it tells us about. The same thing happens when they are flooded with a tsunami of intense feelings without words that seems to be theirs, no matter how much they would prefer otherwise. Blending and disowning are different strategies that both serve a survival function. Blending enables quick actions and reactions in response to emotions. Disowning preserves the sense of self and allows a parallel "not trauma" track in the midst of the worst moments in our lives.

说到与年幼自我协调，受创伤的来访者受到自动倾向的阻碍，会本能地回避各部分痛苦的情绪和恐惧。这些情绪和内隐记忆并非分开的，这一事实也具有挑战性：两组感受都在一个身体的边界内产生。这一生物学事实在知道谁的感受是谁的方面制造了困难，并助长了与彼此情绪"融合"的倾向。当我注意到一种情绪并将其命名为某个部分的感受记忆时，来访者经常对我说："不，这是我的感受，而且我是现在有这个感受的。"当他们认同这种感受时，它通常会加剧——当他们否认这种感受，认为它不属于他们，并否认它所揭示的那个部分的创伤时，也是如此。当他们被一波没有语言的强烈感受的海啸淹没，而这些感受似乎是他们自己的，无论他们多么希望不是，同样的事情也会发生。融合和否认是两种不同的策略，它们都具有生存功能。融合使人能够对情绪做出快速的行动和反应。否认保留了自我感，并允许在我们生命中最糟糕的时刻有一条平行的"非创伤"轨道。

Avoiding Enmeshment and Alienation

避免纠缠与疏离

Attunement to another requires that we neither reject nor merge: we retain our own sense of selfhood while resonating at the other's frequency and allowing them to resonate at ours. This generalization is equally true in romantic relationships, parenthood, or in relationship to our younger selves. The tendency to merge or to become enmeshed with traumatized or abandoned young parts is natural: we sense a feeling or bodily reaction and we naturally give it a name preceded by the word "I." "I'm tired—I'm anxious—I feel very alone—I am furious." The more intense the feeling state and the more frequently experienced, the more likely we are to preface it with an "I," the more likely it is to be contagious, and the more likely we are to merge with it—a challenge encountered on a daily basis by parents of young children. Equally problematic is the disowning or rejection of some parts (e.g., the vulnerable ones) and/or the identification with the parts who are hostile (e.g., controlling, judgmental, aggressive parts) or hopeless, regressed, and childlike. When either occurs, there is a loss of balance in the system—as well as a loss of reality-testing, perspective, and compassion. If our client identifies with ashamed, submissive, compliant parts, he or she runs the risk of failing to perceive signs of healthy anger or defensive responses; if the client identifies with angry or suicidal parts, he or she runs the risk of anger management issues, self-destructive behavior, or internally recreating the early hostile environment.

与他人的协调要求我们既不拒绝也不融合：我们在以对方的频率共鸣并允许他们以我们的频率共鸣的同时，保留自己的自我感。这种概括在浪漫关系、为人父母，或与我们年幼自我的关系中同样适用。与受创伤或被遗弃的年幼部分融合或纠缠的倾向是自然的：我们感受到一种感受或身体反应，自然地给它冠以"我"字开头的名称。"我累了——我焦虑——我感到非常孤独——我很愤怒。"感受状态越强烈，体验越频繁，我们就越有可能用"我"来开头，它就越有可能具有传染性，我们就越有可能与之融合——这是幼儿父母每天面临的挑战。同样有问题的是否认或拒绝某些部分（例如脆弱的部分），和/或认同敌意（例如控制性、评判性、攻击性部分）或绝望、退行、孩子气的部分。无论哪种情况发生，系统中的平衡都会丧失——以及现实检验、视角和慈悲的丧失。如果我们的来访者认同羞耻、顺从、顺应的部分，他或她就有未能感知到健康愤怒或防御反应迹象的风险；如果来访者认同愤怒或自杀的部分，他或她就有愤怒管理问题、自我毁灭行为，或在内心重建早期敌意环境的风险。

Helping clients to attune to parts they loathe or feel intimidated by is just as important as bringing secure attachment experiences to young child parts for whom empathy is easy. It is more challenging to foster empathy for judgmental or scathingly critical parts and harder for clients to want to reach out to an angry part whose sharp tongue and intimidating manner costs them jobs, friendships, and neighborly relationships. Because earned secure attachment is dependent upon acceptance and compassion for all of our "selves," the therapist must insist that clients at the very least thank those "harder to love" parts for their protection. The therapist, like a parent or coach, must often be creative in brokering attachment relationships between the normal life self and more dysregulated or disowned parts.

帮助来访者与他们厌恶或感到被其恐吓的部分协调，与为那些容易产生共情的年幼孩子部分带来安全依恋体验同样重要。培养对评判性或尖刻批评性部分的共情更具挑战性，来访者也更难愿意与尖锐的言辞和令人生畏的方式使他们失去工作、友谊和邻里关系的愤怒部分接触。因为习得的安全依恋依赖于对我们所有"自我"的接纳和慈悲，治疗师必须坚持要求来访者至少感谢那些"更难去爱"的部分对其保护。治疗师，就像父母或教练一样，在调解正常生活的持续自我与更失调或被否认的部分之间的依恋关系时，往往必须富有创造力。

Linda had come a long way—from suicidal despair to stabilization, from accepting her traumatic childhood to realizing what happened thanks to the parts who finally told her about the events she had not remembered. What was missing in her life was the ability to have needs: she could be generous, but she could not accept generosity; she could be kind, but she couldn't accept kindness. Her 11-year-old parentified child part wanted nothing for herself: kindness was for those who deserved it. The other "missing person" was an angry part. She knew about her suicidal part and had thanked it for its offers of help during the darkest of days, but she insisted repeatedly that there was no angry part, no feelings of anger, and she was glad! Her stance was: anger is destructive; I am not a destructive person; therefore, I have no anger. Ironically, this was the only stand she had ever taken in opposition to me over many years of therapy! "No," she said, "I am never angry." Then, one day, as we were talking about the issue of anger, she heard a rough, scathing voice inside, saying, "Oh, isn't she [referring to me] so 'nice'?—this bitch is just too nice! I want to puke!" Linda startled.
"What are you noticing?" I asked.
"Some part just called you a bitch!"
"Hooray! That's cause for celebration—the angry part is in the house! [Laughing] You were wondering if you really had an angry part—I think it just showed up. But before you dismiss it, hear me out: some part of you has to be cynical; some part has to keep an eye on the people who act "so nice" and then knife you when you're not looking. Who else is going to have your back? And furthermore, that part is right—I can sound too sickly sweet sometimes."
The next week, Linda came back, excited to tell me something. She had recently been promoted to CFO of a large corporation, a mixed blessing because the job came with the challenge of dealing with the competitive behavior of male colleagues who repeatedly sabotaged her efforts to work with them as a collaborator. "Do you remember I told you that they schedule meetings and deliberately don't include me in the email announcements?" "I do." "Well, luckily, the secretaries are on my side, so they're letting me know when it happens. This week, something amazing happened. As the time for the mystery meeting came up, I suddenly felt powerful—like I didn't have to let them get away with this shit! So I marched myself down to the conference room, walked in, sat down at the table with all the confidence in the world, and said ever so sweetly, 'I knew you'd want me in on this.' What could they say?! I won!"

Linda走过了漫长的路程——从自杀性绝望到稳定，从接受她的创伤性童年到认识到发生了什么，这要感谢那些终于告诉她她所不记得的事件的部分。她生活中缺失的是拥有需求的能力：她可以慷慨，但她无法接受慷慨；她可以友善，但她无法接受友善。她那个11岁被父母化的孩子部分不为自己想要任何东西：友善是给那些值得的人的。另一个"失踪者"是一个愤怒的部分。她知道自己的自杀部分，并在最黑暗的日子里感谢它提供的帮助，但她反复坚持没有愤怒部分、没有愤怒的感受，而且她为此高兴！她的立场是：愤怒是有破坏性的；我不是一个有破坏性的人；因此，我没有愤怒。具有讽刺意味的是，这是她多年治疗中对我唯一一次采取的反对立场！"不，"她说，"我从不愤怒。"然后，有一天，当我们谈论愤怒的问题时，她听到内心一个粗糙、尖刻的声音说："哦，她（指我）不是'非常好'吗？——这个婊子太好了！我想吐！"Linda吓了一跳。
"你注意到了什么？"我问道。
"某个部分刚刚叫你婊子！"
"万岁！这是值得庆祝的——愤怒部分出现了！〔笑〕你在想你是否真的有一个愤怒部分——我认为它刚刚出现了。但在你否定它之前，听我说：你的某个部分必须保持愤世嫉俗；某个部分必须盯着那些表现得'这么好'然后在你不注意时捅你刀子的人。还有谁会支持你？而且，那个部分是对的——我有时可能听起来甜得发腻。"
下周，Linda回来了，兴奋地要告诉我一件事。她最近被提升为一家大公司的首席财务官，这是一种喜忧参半的晋升，因为这份工作带来了应对男同事竞争行为的挑战，这些人反复破坏她作为合作者与他们共事的努力。"你还记得我告诉你他们安排会议时故意不把我包括在电子邮件通知中吗？""记得。""嗯，幸运的是，秘书们站在我这边，所以当这种情况发生时她们会通知我。这周，发生了一件了不起的事。当那个神秘会议的时间到来时，我突然感到强大——就像我不必让他们这样逍遥法外！所以我径直走下去到会议室，走进去，满怀自信地坐在桌子旁，非常甜蜜地说：'我知道你们会想让我参与这个。'他们能说什么？！我赢了！"

ME: "And are you having the same thought I am?"

我：「你和我有同样的想法吗？」

LINDA: "You mean, was that the angry part? You better believe it was! I felt so calm, powerful, determined, and clear-headed. I could be fake-sweet, but I felt like I had steel inside me. That was definitely not me!"

LINDA：「你是说，那是愤怒部分吗？你最好相信就是！我感到如此平静、强大、坚定和头脑清晰。我可以假装甜蜜，但我感觉内心有钢铁。那绝对不是我！」

ME: "Then a high five to the angry part …"

我：「那就给愤怒部分击个掌……」

LINDA: "No, not enough. The angry part gets an Olympic gold medal!"

LINDA：「不，还不够。愤怒部分应该获得奥运金牌！」

In the weeks and months following, Linda matter-of-factly challenged her male colleagues by simply taking her place among them, no matter how hard they tried to prevent it. Simultaneously, she began to feel more deserving of the life she had worked so hard to achieve, better able to take pleasure in its perks rather than blending with the 11-year-old submit part who felt worthless and undeserving. The angry part of her had brought to the system a much-needed sense of having rights and boundaries. Linda had always gotten ahead by working harder than everyone else. The fight part helped her learn to get ahead by standing her ground, holding her head high, and refusing to take responsibility for others who were not doing their jobs. While the angry part contributed "backbone," the sweetness of her attach part and the collaborative willingness of submit made it hard for her peers to react angrily. By accepting the angry part and trusting it, despite her wish to disown it, Linda created safety for herself and her parts even in the corporate "jungle."

在随后的数周和数月里，Linda平静地挑战了她的男同事，只是简单地占据她在他们中间的位置，无论他们多么努力地阻止。同时，她开始感到自己更值得拥有她如此努力实现的生活，更能享受其中的好处，而不是与那个感到毫无价值、不配拥有的11岁顺从部分融合。她的愤怒部分为这个系统带来了一种非常需要的拥有权利和边界的感觉。Linda一直通过比其他人更努力工作来取得进步。战斗部分帮助她学会通过坚守阵地、昂首挺胸，以及拒绝为那些没有尽职的其他人承担责任来取得进步。虽然愤怒部分提供了"脊梁"，她的依附部分的甜蜜和顺从部分的协作意愿使她的同事很难做出愤怒的反应。通过接受愤怒部分并信任它，尽管她想否认它，Linda即使在企业"丛林"中也为自己和各部分创造了安全。

Earned Secure Attachment and the Resolution of Trauma

习得的安全依恋与创伤的解决

"The fact that these adults [with earned secure attachment status] are capable of sensitive, attuned caregiving of their children, even under stress, suggests that this 'earned' status is more than just being able to 'talk the talk'; they can also 'walk the walk' of being emotionally connected with their own children, despite not having such experiences in their own childhoods. We may serve a vital role for this and future generations in enabling each other to achieve the more reflective, integrated functioning that facilitates secure attachments."

"这些〔获得了'习得性安全依恋'状态的〕成年人即便在压力之下，也能够对自己的孩子给予敏感、协调的照料，这一事实表明，这种'习得'的状态远不止是能够'说得头头是道'；尽管他们自己的童年并无这样的体验，他们也能够'身体力行'地与自己的孩子建立情感连接。在使彼此得以达成那种促进安全依恋的、更具反思性与整合性的功能方面，我们或许对这一代以及未来世代都发挥着至关重要的作用。"

(Siegel, 1999, p. 11)

If helping traumatized clients "earn" secure attachment by forging bonds of affection and connection to their young selves can help prevent attachment failure in the next generation, then the work described here will also serve a preventive function. Therapist and client can take pride in knowing that they are not only healing old wounds but also protecting their children from another generation of parenting by dysregulated, attachment-disordered adults.

如果帮助受创伤的来访者通过与年幼自我建立情感和连结纽带来"赢得"安全依恋，可以帮助预防下一代的依恋失败，那么这里描述的工作也将具有预防功能。治疗师和来访者可以自豪地知道，他们不仅在治愈旧创伤，还在保护他们的孩子免受另一代由失调的、依恋障碍的成年人所造成的养育问题。

Whereas disorganized attachment is associated with autonomic dysegulation, controlling attachment strategies, internal conflicts between distance and closeness, and difficulties with identity formation, both earned and continuous secure attachment are associated with resilience. Studies report an association between secure attachment and greater affect tolerance, as well as increased ability to bounce back from hurt, stress, rejection, or disappointment, tolerate both closeness and distance, and internalize positive attachment figures. In studies of earned secure attachment, two findings are particularly relevant to a parts approach: first, although earned secure attachment was associated with depressive symptoms and emotional distress in some parents studied, they nonetheless evidenced an ability to provide good attachment to their children, suggesting that their earned secure attachment status allowed them to tolerate higher levels of internal discomfort without their parenting ability being compromised. The second finding was that the benefits of earned secure attachment were virtually indistinguishable from the benefits of what researchers called "continuous secure attachment" (Roisman et al., 2002), that is, childhood secure attachment. These findings fit well with the model presented in this book. Long after internal attachment bonds have been established, clients and their trauma-related parts may still periodically suffer distress, still be vulnerable to depression and anxiety, and even have destructive impulses. But earned secure attachment provides a stable base that enables individuals to tolerate grief, loss, betrayal, and other stressful normal life experiences—without loss of their capacity to parent the next generation or to soothe and reassure themselves—or their "selves."

虽然无序化依恋与自主失调、控制性依恋策略、距离和亲密之间的内部冲突，以及身份形成困难相关，但习得的和持续的安全依恋都与韧性相关。研究报告了安全依恋与更大的情感耐受性之间的关联，以及从伤害、压力、拒绝或失望中恢复的能力增强、同时耐受亲密和距离，以及内化积极依恋人物的能力增强。在习得的安全依恋研究中，两个发现与部分取向特别相关：首先，虽然习得的安全依恋在一些被研究的父母中与抑郁症状和情感痛苦相关，但他们仍然表现出为孩子提供良好依恋的能力，表明他们的习得安全依恋状态允许他们耐受更高水平的内部不适，而不会损害其养育能力。第二个发现是，习得的安全依恋的益处几乎与研究人员称之为"持续安全依恋"（Roisman等人，2002年）的益处无法区分，即童年安全依恋。这些发现与本书中提出的模型非常吻合。在建立内部依恋纽带后很久，来访者及其创伤相关部分可能仍然会定期遭受痛苦，仍然容易受到抑郁和焦虑的影响，甚至有破坏性冲动。但习得的安全依恋提供了一个稳定的基础，使个体能够忍受悲伤、失去、背叛和其他压力性正常生活体验——而不失去养育下一代的能力，也不失去安抚和让自己放心——或让他们的"自我"放心的能力。

This is very good news for trauma survivors who have struggled with the painful effects of disrupted, disorganized attachment. As they overcome trauma-related self-alienation, their internal sense of safety and well-being will be equal to that of adults born to securely attached parents. So often, clients fear that they have been irreparably damaged by the abuse and attachment failure. The research says otherwise. If trauma survivors are willing to overcome trauma-related tendencies to fear and loathe some parts and over-identify with others, if they can welcome all the "children" without having favorites or scapegoats, the ending can be different. If traumatized individuals are willing to embrace intimidating judgmental parts, frightening suicidal parts, and parts who wound the body or "pour whiskey in the baby bottle" to silence the little parts, the seeds of earned secure attachment are sown. There need be no pressure to love or nurture hostile or aggressive parts because that would be to fail them empathically. An adopted teenager would need different kinds of experiences to feel safely attached than a 3-year-old. Attunement arises from a sensitivity to each part and to the "missing experiences" necessary for each to transform and heal wounded or broken places. The "missing experience" (Ogden & Fisher, 2015) for a fight part, as Linda demonstrates, is not being held and soothed; it is the experience of control over threat, the feeling of being respected for its strength and its need for clear boundaries that ensure safety. When the normal life self of the client overcomes the tendency to ignore the fight part's injunctions against vulnerability or caretaking of others and instead works to develop increasing ability to set boundaries and insist on fairness in relationships, the relationship between the two begins to shift. When the safety concerns of the fight parts are heard, when they are treated as heroes rather than perpetrators, they become committed, loyal, and bonded. Being ignored or engaged in a power struggle inflames them; being heard and taken seriously tames them. The same is true for the flight parts: attempting to force closeness or commitment on them pushes them away; acceptance of their needs for control over interpersonal distance relaxes their guard.

对于那些一直在与无序化、混乱依恋的痛苦影响作斗争的创伤幸存者来说，这是非常好的消息。随着他们克服与创伤相关的自我疏离，他们内心的安全感和幸福感将与那些由安全依恋父母所生的成年人相同。来访者常常害怕他们已经被虐待和依恋失败不可挽回地损害了。研究结果却并非如此。如果创伤幸存者愿意克服与创伤相关的倾向——对某些部分感到恐惧和厌恶，以及与其他部分过度认同——如果他们能够欢迎所有的"孩子"而不偏心或设立替罪羊，结局可以不同。如果受创伤的个体愿意拥抱令人生畏的评判性部分、令人恐惧的自杀部分，以及伤害身体或"往婴儿奶瓶里倒威士忌"来压制小部分的部分，习得安全依恋的种子就被播下了。不必有爱或滋养敌意或攻击性部分的压力，因为那样做将是在共情上辜负它们。一个被收养的青少年需要与3岁孩子不同的体验来感到安全依恋。协调来自对每个部分及其转变和治愈受伤或破损之处所必需的"缺失体验"的敏感性。正如Linda所展示的，战斗部分的"缺失体验"（Ogden与Fisher，2015年）不是被抱持和安抚；而是控制威胁的体验，因其力量和对确保安全的清晰边界的需求而被尊重的感觉。当来访者的正常生活的持续自我克服了忽视战斗部分对脆弱性或照顾他人的禁令的倾向，转而致力于发展越来越强的设立边界和坚持关系公平的能力时，两者之间的关系开始转变。当战斗部分的安全关切被倾听，当它们被视为英雄而非施害者时，它们变得投入、忠诚和有纽带感。被忽视或被卷入权力斗争会激怒它们；被倾听和被认真对待会驯服它们。逃跑部分也是如此：试图强迫亲密或承诺会把它们推开；接受它们对人际距离控制的需求会放松它们的警惕。

No matter how their implicit memories and animal defenses manifest, all parts, like all human beings, desire acceptance and attunement. Even though a mother might find one child temperamentally easier to parent than another, her job is to forge an attachment bond to both the "easy" and the "hard" babies equally. For individuals to experience the internal stability and well-being endowed by earned secure attachment, all parts must be embraced—from the grouchy, distancing adolescent flight part to the endearing and innocent attach part to the always depressed and hopeless submit part to the silent, terrified freeze part and the "take no prisoners" fight part. When the client can find something to love about each and every part, the internal world begins to transform. Just as therapists are not trained to ask clients, "How did you survive? How did you do it?" they are also rarely trained to ask, "What could you love about that part that won't let you sleep? That won't let you eat? That won't let anyone get close to you?"

无论其内隐记忆和动物防御如何表现，所有部分，像所有人类一样，都渴望被接纳和协调。即使一位母亲可能发现一个孩子在气质上比另一个更容易养育，她的工作是对"容易"和"难"的婴儿都同等地建立依恋纽带。为了让个体体验到习得安全依恋所赋予的内部稳定性和幸福感，所有部分都必须被接纳——从暴躁、疏离的青少年逃跑部分，到可爱而无辜的依附部分，到总是抑郁和绝望的顺从部分，到沉默、恐惧的冻结部分，以及"不留俘虏"的战斗部分。当来访者能够在每一个部分中找到值得爱的东西时，内心世界就开始转化。就像治疗师没有被训练去问来访者"你是怎么活下来的？你是怎么做到的？"一样，他们也很少被训练去问："你能爱那个不让你睡觉的部分的什么？不让你吃饭的部分？不让任何人靠近你的部分？"

Earned secure attachment, according to researchers, is most often built through healthy, meaningful relationships in adulthood (such as that with a spouse or therapist) or through the vicarious experience of secure attachment available through parenting one's own children. To add to that list, earned secure attachment can also be cultivated through healthy, attuned relationships to our "selves." The ingredients are the same: the willingness to prioritize the needs of the other, the ability to communicate welcome and acceptance, attunement and coregulation, emotional closeness, compassion, loving presence, and the ability to maintain a felt connection to the other even when one is dysregulated, frustrated, or overwhelmed. Whether we bring these capacities to a newborn baby of our own, or to an infant or child self, they have neurobiological effects. The cornerstone of infant attachment is what Allan Schore (2001) calls "adaptive projective identification." That term refers to the way in which the infant's distress, projected via dysregulation, is experienced by parents as their own distress. The baby cries; the parent is dysregulated by the cries. She feels uncomfortable, so much so that she is driven to pick the baby up, soothe, comfort, and distract, until the repair effort hits on the infant's unmet need and the baby calms and settles into the parent's arms. Only then does the parental nervous system calm and settle. All is well now—both are regulated and soothed. Sometimes, the infant's unmet need might be for up-regulation made possible by the parent's making funny faces and sounds, eliciting infant smiles and laughter, until the point at which the parent also feels an uplift in mood. Parent and child feel a shared, reciprocal pleasure hard to capture in words other than to call it "attunement bliss."

根据研究人员的说法，习得的安全依恋最常通过成年期健康、有意义的关系（例如与配偶或治疗师的关系）建立，或通过养育自己孩子所获得的代理安全依恋体验建立。除此之外，习得的安全依恋也可以通过与我们"自我"的健康、协调的关系来培养。要素是相同的：愿意优先考虑他人的需求、传达欢迎和接纳的能力、协调和共同调节、情感亲密、慈悲、充满爱的临在，以及即使在自己失调、沮丧或不堪重负时也能维持与他人感知连结的能力。无论我们将这些能力带给自己的新生婴儿，还是带给婴儿或孩子的自我，它们都具有神经生物学效应。婴儿依恋的基石是Allan Schore（2001年）所称的"适应性投射性认同"。这个术语指的是婴儿的痛苦——通过失调来投射——被父母体验为他们自己的痛苦的方式。婴儿哭泣；父母被哭声搞得失调。她感到不舒服，以至于她被迫抱起婴儿、安抚、安慰和转移注意力，直到修复努力触及婴儿未满足的需求，婴儿平静下来，安定在父母的怀抱里。只有那时，父母的神经系统才平静下来并安定。现在一切都好了——两者都被调节和安抚了。有时，婴儿未满足的需求可能是父母通过做鬼脸和发出声音来实现的上调，引发婴儿的微笑和笑声，直到父母也感到情绪的提振。父母和孩子感受到一种共同的、相互的快乐，难以用其他词语来描述，只能称之为"协调的幸福"。

Hearing the Child's Cry

听见孩子的哭声

Child parts, too, feel distress, and they too "project" their discomfort to signal for help. In a two-person system in one biological body, it is more difficult for child parts to be heard, other than via blending and/or reciprocal dysregulation. For that reason, practice of the skills described in Chapters 4 and 5 is the crux of the treatment. Having mastered these skills in the therapist's office, the normal life self can hear the child's cry as a signal to unblend from the distress, recognizing that "she" or "he" is upset. Curious because of the discomfort of her own state, the client is motivated to be interested in this child self who is so unhappy, rather than avoidant. Curiosity helps regulate the mutual dysregulation and distress and keeps adult and child in contact, challenging habitual self-alienation tendencies to ignore, disown or reblend with the part's feelings.

孩子部分也感到痛苦，它们也"投射"自己的不适来发出求助信号。在一个生物身体中的双人系统中，孩子部分很难被听到，除非通过融合和/或相互失调。因此，练习第4章和第5章描述的技能是治疗的关键。在治疗师办公室掌握了这些技能之后，正常生活的持续自我可以将孩子的哭声听作从痛苦中脱离融合的信号，认识到"她"或"他"感到痛苦。出于对自己状态不适的好奇，来访者被激励对这个如此不快乐的孩子自我感到兴趣，而不是回避。好奇心有助于调节相互的失调和痛苦，使成人和孩子保持接触，挑战习惯性自我疏离倾向——忽视、否认或重新与部分的感受融合。

Then the normal life self learns to do what any good secure attachment-promoting parent would do when a small child is crying: he or she experiments to find a repair for the child's distressed state. The measure of a successful repair lies in the body: if a repair is successfully made, the little boy or girl will take a breath, heart rate will slow, the nervous system will settle, and there will be a sense of relief in the body. If the therapist allows the client to identify that state of relief as "I feel better now," the opportunity to build secure attachment will be lost, at least for the moment. Only by staying "present" in relationship to the child can the client foster a secure attachment experience. Soothing distress or evoking positive feelings does not build resilience in young children or parts when it is followed by a quick, "OK, that's done. Now I have other things more important to do." Even securely attached children need to feel "held in mind" by their parents, even when they are not physically present.

然后，正常生活的持续自我学会做任何一个良好地促进安全依恋的父母在小孩哭泣时会做的事：他或她尝试为孩子的痛苦状态找到修复方案。成功修复的衡量标准在于身体：如果修复成功，小男孩或小女孩会深吸一口气，心率会减慢，神经系统会平静，身体中会有一种解脱感。如果治疗师允许来访者将那种解脱状态认定为"我现在感觉好多了"，建立安全依恋的机会将会丧失，至少在那一刻是如此。只有通过在与孩子的关系中保持"临在"，来访者才能培养安全依恋体验。安抚痛苦或唤起积极感受并不能在年幼孩子或部分中建立韧性，如果这之后紧随着一个快速的"好了，这完成了。现在我有其他更重要的事情要做。"即使是安全依恋的孩子也需要感到被父母"放在心上"，即使他们没有身体上的在场。

To heal the fragmented selves of traumatized clients entails a therapist willing to "see" the parts in an individual's whole physical body, able to be "relentless" in helping clients learn to interpret distress as "theirs," and skilled in gently and non-coercively insisting on a focus on the needs of wounded children. Just as therapists do in treating traumatic attachment in children, clients have to be helped to consistently provide reparative interventions to parts whose presence is felt "now" because some stimulus has activated their implicit memories, causing pain. Each repair reclaims a part that was once left behind, "retrieves" a lost "soul," no longer disowned and phobically avoided. There is no need for parts whose job was to loathe and fear the vulnerable parts to ensure the self-alienation. There is no need to fear the vulnerability and no need for self-loathing as a protection. Better yet, by helping clients identify the somatic signs that "the little one feels better," sharing in the felt sense of "better," communicating the shared enjoyment of "better" back to the child, and continuing to deepen the mutually felt sense of safety, closeness, and welcome, there is an unexpected reward. There is an experience of relaxation, safety, and "attunement bliss" that pulls not for avoidance but for embracing the child, making her welcome, finding a place for him at the table of the client's life.

治愈受创伤来访者的碎裂自我，需要一位治疗师愿意在个体的整个身体中"看见"各部分，能够在帮助来访者学习将痛苦解读为"他们的"方面保持"不懈"，并善于温和而非强制地坚持聚焦于受伤孩子的需求。就像治疗师在治疗儿童的创伤性依恋时所做的那样，来访者必须被帮助持续地为那些存在感在"现在"被感受到的部分提供修复性干预，因为某些刺激激活了它们的内隐记忆，引起了痛苦。每次修复都找回了一个曾经被遗留在后的部分，"取回"了一个失去的"灵魂"，不再被否认和恐惧性地回避。不再需要那些工作是厌恶和恐惧脆弱部分的部分来确保自我疏离。不再需要恐惧脆弱性，也不再需要自我厌恶作为保护。更好的是，通过帮助来访者识别"小家伙感觉好多了"的躯体迹象、分享"好转"的感知感觉、将"好转"的共同享受传达回孩子，并继续加深相互感知到的安全、亲密和受欢迎的感觉，有一个意想不到的奖励。有一种放松、安全和"协调幸福"的体验，它不是引向回避，而是引向拥抱孩子、让她感到受欢迎、在来访者生活的餐桌上为他找到一席之地。

Healing the fragmented selves of traumatized clients requires only that the positivity-oriented left brain-related normal life self befriend right brain-related parts, both "owned" and disowned, and become curious about their ages, stages, fears, and strengths, and learn to be in relation to them. This is an apparently small, non-threatening step but it challenges trauma-related conditioned learning by increasing communication and collaboration between the two hemispheres, the opposite of splitting. Healing our broken places and fragmented parts happens naturally as an organic process—much like plants grow toward the light. All that is needed is the willingness to "see" the parts, hear their fears and feelings, and be curious even if not yet compassionate. Guided by a therapist who can speak for all the parts and for the system as a whole, the normal life self's conditioned avoidance of the parts is challenged. Mindful dual awareness decreases the automatic tendency to disown the parts by regulating autonomic arousal and facilitating being able to "see" each other.

治愈受创伤来访者的碎裂自我，只需要以积极性为导向的左脑相关的正常生活的持续自我与右脑相关的部分结交朋友——无论是"自认"的还是被否认的——并对它们的年龄、阶段、恐惧和力量感到好奇，学会与它们建立关系。这是一个看似微小、不具威胁性的步骤，但它通过增加两个大脑半球之间的沟通和协作——分裂的对立面——来挑战创伤相关的条件学习。治愈我们破损的地方和碎裂的部分作为一种有机过程自然发生——很像植物向光生长。所需要的只是愿意"看见"各部分、倾听它们的恐惧和感受，并保持好奇，即使还没有达到慈悲。在一位能够为所有部分和整个系统发声的治疗师的引导下，正常生活的持续自我对各部分的条件性回避受到挑战。正念双重觉察通过调节自主唤起和促进能够"看见"彼此，减少了自动否认各部分的倾向。

Like nations at war, like families in conflict, sitting down together elicits the commonalities and prevents "demonizing" each other. With a therapist who facilitates dual awareness, who is determined to repair the fault lines between the emotionally driven parts and logic-driven normal lfe part, who is willing to see each side as worthy and deserving of a place at the table, and whose own compassion and attunement is palpable, there is a softening toward not-me parts. When both client and therapist can appreciate the ways in which every part has supported the survival of the whole, how the internal struggles that still occur are simply a reflection of parts trying to defend against the threats "then," there is more softening. Much like planting and tending a garden, internal attachment-building involves patience, repetition, and a deep conviction that healing is normal, natural, and cannot be rushed. It requires only the right "soil" and patient, compassionate "gardeners" to evoke innate healing tendencies in even the most wounded of living beings.

就像交战的国家，就像冲突中的家庭，坐在一起能唤起共同点并防止彼此"妖魔化"。有一位促进双重觉察的治疗师——他决心修复情绪驱动的部分与逻辑驱动的正常生活部分之间的断层线，愿意将每一方都视为有价值的、值得在桌上占有一席之地，其自身的慈悲和协调显而易见——对于"非我"部分，会有一种软化。当来访者和治疗师都能欣赏每个部分支持整体生存的方式，认识到仍在发生的内部斗争只是部分试图抵御"那时"威胁的反映时，会有更多的软化。很像种植和打理花园，内部依恋建设涉及耐心、重复，以及对治愈是正常的、自然的、不能被催促的深信。它只需要合适的"土壤"和耐心、慈悲的"园丁"，就能在即使是最受伤的生命体中唤起固有的治愈倾向。

"I am still every age that I have been. Because I was once a child, I am always a child. Because I was once an adolescent, given to moods and ecstasies, these are still part of me, and always will be. … This does not mean that I ought to be trapped or enclosed in any of these ages, … but that they are in me to be drawn on … my past is part of what makes the present … and must not be denied or rejected."

"我依然是我曾经历过的每一个年纪。因为我曾经是个孩子，所以我永远是个孩子。因为我曾经是个易陷入情绪与狂喜的青少年，这些至今仍是我的一部分，并将永远如此。……这并不意味着我就应当被困在或封闭于这些年纪中的任何一个，……而是说它们存在于我之中，可供汲取……我的过去是构成当下的一部分……绝不可被否认或拒斥。"

(L'Engle, 1972, pp. 199–200)

References

Friedman, W.J. (2012). Resonance: welcoming you in me—a core therapeutic competency. Undivided, the Online Journal of Unduality and Psychology, 1(3).

L'Engle, M. (1972). A circle of quiet. New York: Harper Collins.

Ogden, P. & Fisher, J. (2015). Sensorimotor Psychotherapy: interventions for trauma and attachment. New York: W.W. Norton.

Roisman, G. I., Padron, E., Sroufe, L.A., & Egeland, B. (2002). Earned-secure attachment status in retrospect and prospect. Child Development, 73(4), 1204–1219.

Schore, A. N. (2001). Neurobiology, developmental psychology, and psychoanalysis: convergent findings on the subject of projective identification. In Edwards, J. (Ed.). Being alive: building on the work of Anne Alvarez. New York: Brunner-Routledge.

Siegel, D. J. (2010a). The neurobiology of 'we.' Keynote address, Psychotherapy Networker Symposium, Washington, D.C., March 2010.

Siegel, D. J. (2010b). The mindful therapist: a clinician's guide to mindsight and neural integration. New York: W.W. Norton.

APPENDIX A
Five Steps to "Unblending"

附录A：解融合的五个步骤

When we are triggered by something and our traumatized parts get activated, their feelings flood the body with intense and overwhelming feelings and impulses to act or react in ways that are not "us" or who we intend to be. That experience is called "blending." To find our adult selves again, we need to "unblend," to mindfully separate from the intense reactions of the parts until we have a felt sense of "I'm here" and also "he or she is still here, too." Here are the five steps to unblending:

当我们被某些事物触发，创伤相关部分被激活时，它们的情绪会以强烈而难以承受的感受淹没身体，并产生以不属于"我们"或我们本意的方式行动或反应的冲动。这种体验被称为"融合"。为了重新找回成人自我，我们需要"解融合"——用正念将自己与各部分的强烈反应分离，直到我们感受到"我在这里"，同时也感受到"他/她也依然在这里"。以下是解融合的五个步骤：

1 First, assume that any and all upsetting or overwhelming feelings and thoughts are a communication from parts—and try to make that assumption even if you are not sure it is true.

1 首先，假定所有令你不安或难以承受的感受和想法，都是各部分发出的信息——即使你不确定这是否属实，也请尽量保持这种假设。

2 Describe the feelings and thoughts as "their" reaction: "They are upset—they are having a hard time—they are overwhelmed." See what happens when you speak for the parts by talking about "their" feelings.

2 将这些感受和想法描述为"它们"的反应："它们很难受——它们正在经历艰难时刻——它们被淹没了。"看看当你代表各部分、谈论"它们"的感受时，会发生什么变化。

3 Create a little more separation from them, just enough so you can feel their feelings less intensely and you can feel yourself, too. Change your position, lengthen your spine, engage your core, or sit back. Keep repeating, "They are feeling ___________________________________."

3 与它们创造更多一点的距离，刚好足以让你对它们的感受不那么强烈，同时也能感受到你自己的存在。改变姿势、伸展脊柱、收紧核心肌群，或者向后坐一坐。持续重复："它们感到___________________________________。"

4 Use your wise grownup mind, the part of you that is a compassionate friend or organized professional, to have a reassuring conversation with whomever is upset. Acknowledge that the part or parts are afraid, overwhelmed, ashamed, or sad. Imagine: if these were the fears of your colleagues, clients, or friends, how would you respond? What would you tell them? Ask them what they need from you to be a little less afraid.

4 运用你智慧的成人心智——你内心那个充满慈悲的朋友或沉着的专业人士——与那些感到不安的部分进行安抚性对话。承认这些部分正处于恐惧、不知所措、羞耻或悲伤之中。想象一下：如果这些是你同事、来访者或朋友的恐惧，你会如何回应？你会对他们说什么？询问它们需要你做什么，才能让它们少一点恐惧。

5 Get their feedback and opinions: Is what you are doing helping even a little? What do they need right in this moment to feel a little less alone, a little less afraid, a little less angry? Do they like it when you listen and show concern? Promise them that you will check in with them, make more of an effort to remember they are in distress, or be more protective.

5 征求它们的反馈和意见：你所做的有没有哪怕一点点帮助？此刻它们需要什么，才能感到少一点孤独、少一点恐惧、少一点愤怒？当你倾听并表达关怀时，它们是否感到满意？向它们承诺你会定期与它们沟通，更加用心地记住它们正处于痛苦之中，或者给予更多保护。

The key to the success of this technique is consistency, repetition, and a willingness to keep using it even if you have days when it does not work.

这一技术成功的关键在于：持续性、反复练习，以及即便在某些时候它似乎无效时，也愿意坚持使用它的意愿。

APPENDIX B
Meditation Circle for Parts

附录B：各部分冥想圈

This intervention can help in a number of ways: it encourages daily or almost daily mindfulness meditation (a good treatment for a traumatized nervous system). It promotes internal awareness of parts that might otherwise disrupt or destabilize your normal life part, and it increases self-compassion and compassion for the traumatized parts.

这一干预方法可以在多个层面发挥帮助：它鼓励每天或几乎每天进行正念冥想（这对受创伤的神经系统是一种有效的调节方式）；它促进对各部分的内在觉察，而这些部分若不加关注可能会干扰或破坏你的正常生活自我；同时，它也能增强自我慈悲以及对创伤相关部分的慈悲心。

All it takes is willingness to trust that any pain, loneliness, shame, overwhelm, or threat you feel is a communication from dissociated child parts. Rather than wait until they get triggered or until you are overwhelmed by their feelings, the meditation circle practice helps to build internal dialogue, create trust, and reassure the parts that someone cares and prevent problems from escalating.

你所需要的只是愿意相信：你感受到的任何痛苦、孤独、羞耻、不知所措或威胁感，都是来自解离的孩子部分的信息。与其等到它们被触发，或等到你被它们的情绪淹没，冥想圈的练习可以帮助建立内部对话、创造信任，并让这些部分确信有人在乎它们，从而防止问题不断升级。

Once a day, preferably at the same time each day, find a comfortable quiet place to sit. Relax or close your eyes, take a breath, and then make an internal announcement, for example: "I want to ask every part of me to come into the meditation circle … this is not to criticize or judge or control you. I want to get to know you—I want to know when you're having a hard time—I want to know what's bothering you so I can learn to help you more." Then pause and visualize the meditation circle, communicate welcome to the parts, and be curious about the children and teenagers who slowly join it. Do you recognize the parts that slowly gather together? Are you surprised at who shows up or how they communicate who they are through their body language and facial expression?

每天一次，最好在同一时间，找一个舒适安静的地方坐下。放松身体或闭上眼睛，深呼吸，然后向内宣告，例如："我想邀请我的每一个部分进入冥想圈……这不是为了批评、评判或控制你。我想了解你——我想知道你什么时候正在经历艰难——我想了解困扰你的事情，这样我才能学会更好地帮助你。"然后暂停，想象冥想圈，向各部分传递欢迎之意，并对那些缓缓加入的孩子和青少年保持好奇。你认出那些慢慢聚集过来的部分吗？谁出现了，或者它们通过肢体语言和面部表情传达了什么，是否让你感到惊讶？

Many people are surprised by what they see: more parts than they expected, more obvious pain and vulnerability, younger or older ages. Assume that everything you notice (ages, facial expressions, dress, even body language) will tell you more about them. Your job is to welcome them, to be curious about what they need, hope, or fear.

许多人对所看到的感到惊讶：比预期中更多的部分、更明显的痛苦与脆弱、更年幼或更年长的年龄。请假定你注意到的一切（年龄、面部表情、衣着，乃至肢体语言）都在告诉你关于它们的更多信息。你的任务是欢迎它们，对它们的需求、希望或恐惧保持好奇。

Sometimes there is no clear image, just a sensation of the parts joining you, or no one shows up at all. This is not a problem. You can still validate them and what they have endured: "I bet some or all of you don't trust this—maybe you are worried that it's a trap—or that you will have to let your guard down."

有时并没有清晰的画面，只是一种各部分前来陪伴你的感觉，或者根本没有任何部分出现。这都不是问题。你仍然可以确认它们及其所承受的一切："我猜你们中的一些或所有人都不信任这件事——也许你们担心这是个圈套——或者你们害怕必须放下戒备。"

Once you have an image or sense of parts gathered in the circle, invite them to tell you what they are worried about—is there anything they want you to know about their worries?

一旦你在圈中看到或感受到各部分聚集，邀请它们告诉你它们在担忧什么——它们有没有什么想让你知道的忧虑？

Try to be a good listener: try to really "get" what they're telling you about themselves. Take their fears and feelings seriously. If they express feelings of abandonment or hurt that you haven't been there, try to "own" it if you recognize some truth to their perception. Try to take responsibility: "I should have been there—I can see why that was hard for you." Be an "equal opportunity" welcomer: even if you are "turned off" by a particular part's shame, vulnerability, or anger, try to accept all feelings and beliefs expressed by the parts as a natural and normal emotion any traumatized child might be likely to have.

尽量做一个好的倾听者：真正"理解"它们向你诉说的关于自己的一切。认真对待它们的恐惧和感受。如果它们表达了被遗弃的感受，或者因你不在而受伤，如果你能认识到它们的感知有几分真实，请尽量"承认"这一点。尝试承担责任："我本应在那里——我能理解那对你来说为何如此艰难。"做一个"机会均等"的欢迎者：即便某个部分的羞耻、脆弱或愤怒让你感到抵触，也请尝试接纳各部分所表达的一切感受和信念，将它们视为任何受过创伤的孩子都可能有的自然而正常的情绪。

To the extent that you can, try to come up with the support and validation the parts need to assuage their fears and frustrations: "I will remember how scared it makes you when people get angry—maybe you can stand behind me so you don't have to worry about someone blaming you." "Maybe I can help you look out for bad things—maybe I can promise to protect you from …" "You've been alone a long time—I won't forget that." Try to keep the focus on today or right now: "Notice that right here, right now, I am here and I'm not leaving." Traumatized children have many fears, and it doesn't help them to open them all up at once or try to solve them all at once. Equally, it is natural that some parts won't trust you at first, will hesitate to hear you, or even be angry. You can tell them, "Every day we will meet, and you can tell me more about your worries and what I can do each day to help or understand or be there. Maybe over time, you will trust me. … There is no rush—take all the time you need."

尽你所能，为各部分提供它们所需要的支持与确认，以安抚它们的恐惧和挫败感："我会记住，当别人发怒时你有多害怕——也许你可以站在我身后，这样就不必担心有人责怪你。""也许我可以帮你留意危险——也许我可以承诺保护你不受……的伤害。""你已经独自一人很长时间了——我不会忘记这一点。"尽量将焦点保持在今天或此刻："注意，就在这里，就在此刻，我在这里，我不会离开。"受过创伤的孩子有很多恐惧，一次性将所有恐惧都打开或试图同时解决所有问题，对它们并没有帮助。同样，有些部分起初不信任你、犹豫是否要倾听你，甚至感到愤怒，这都是自然的。你可以告诉它们："每天我们都会相聚，你可以告诉我更多你的忧虑，以及我每天可以做什么来帮助你、理解你或陪伴你。也许随着时间的推移，你会信任我。……不急——慢慢来，按你自己的节奏。"

APPENDIX C
Internal Dialogue Technique

附录C：内部对话技术

Step 1: Focus on the thoughts and feelings that are causing you distress right this minute, and assume that they belong to a part. Tune into that part for a few moments and see what you notice about it: it is speaking to you right now through the thoughts, feelings, beliefs, and gut responses that you are experiencing. What kind of part would feel or think this way? A very young one? A middle-sized child? A teenager? Connect to that part by letting it know you are there.

第一步： 专注于此刻正令你痛苦的想法和感受，并假定它们属于某个部分。用几分钟的时间调频到那个部分，观察你注意到了什么：它正通过你正在经历的想法、感受、信念和直觉反应向你说话。什么样的部分会这样感受或思考？一个很幼小的部分？一个中等年龄的孩子？还是一个青少年？通过让它知道你在这里，与那个部分建立连接。

Step 2: If you are feeling too blended with that part to have a conversation, then create a little bit more space by asking the part to "sit back" or "relax a little bit," and make room for you, the adult, to listen to what this part has to say. This step can be repeated whenever you get too "blended" or start to get confusion or overwhelm. Confusion, overwhelm, and anxiety always mean that parts are confused or overwhelmed. They are talking to you by communicating their feelings. The same is true when you feel depression, shame, anger, or self-criticism. If ashamed, depressed, angry, or judgmental parts jump up at any time, just repeat Step 1.

第二步： 如果你感到与那个部分过度融合而无法展开对话，那么请通过要求该部分"退后一些"或"稍微放松一下"来创造更多空间，为作为成人的你腾出位置，去倾听这个部分想说的话。每当你过度"融合"，或开始感到困惑或不堪重负时，都可以重复这一步骤。困惑、不堪重负和焦虑，始终意味着各部分正处于困惑或压倒状态。它们通过传递自己的感受来与你沟通。当你感到抑郁、羞耻、愤怒或自我批判时，情况也同样如此。如果感到羞耻、抑郁、愤怒或具有评判性的部分在任何时候跳出来，只需重复第一步。

Step 3: Be curious. Ask the part what she or he is worried about. The assumption is that parts are activated because they are triggered and experiencing past-related fears. Children need to know that people hear their worries and take them seriously, or they don't feel safe. Listen to the words that come up, even if they don't make sense to you, and then reflect the words back to the part: "It sounds as if you feel really worthless and unlovable." Make sure to ask: "Is that right? Am I getting it?" That lets the part know that you are really listening and really trying to connect and help. Sometimes, parts worry that they will have no place in the adult's current life, and those fears must be reassured for Step II to be effective. Sometimes when you have parts that are very young, they don't speak in words: they speak through feelings and body sensations. For example, you might ask, "What are you worried about if I go to my friend's birthday celebration?" and then get no verbal response but instead a physical response, like fear or shame. Assume the feeling or tension is a communication, and reflect it back, "It sounds like you're afraid that people will see you … Is that right?"

第三步： 保持好奇心。询问这个部分它在担忧什么。我们的假定是：各部分之所以被激活，是因为它们被触发并正在经历与过去相关的恐惧。孩子需要知道有人听到了它们的担忧并认真对待，否则它们不会感到安全。倾听出现的词语，即便这些话对你来说没有意义，然后将这些话反映给那个部分："听起来你感到自己真的毫无价值、不值得被爱。"一定要问："是这样吗？我理解对了吗？"这让那个部分知道你真的在倾听，真的在尝试连接并给予帮助。有时，各部分会担心它们在成人当下的生活中没有容身之处，这些恐惧必须得到安抚，第二步才能有效发挥作用。有时，当你内在的部分非常年幼时，它们不用语言说话：它们通过感受和身体感觉来表达。例如，你可能会问："如果我去参加朋友的生日庆典，你在担心什么？"然后没有得到语言回应，而是身体反应，例如恐惧或羞耻。请将这种感受或紧张视为一种沟通，并将其反映回去："听起来你害怕别人会看到你……是这样吗？"

Step 4: Explore the underlying fears. Usually, the underlying fear is a variant on the theme of "something bad will happen" which has gotten projected onto current triggers. Often we have to explore several levels of fear to get to the core fear. Ask the part again:
"What are you worried about?" No matter what feeling or words come up (anger, sadness, shame, guilt, fear), assume that this part is not comfortable with the feeling and is worried about something.
Then, once you have that next layer of worry, ask: "And if that were to come true, what would you be worried about?" (The questions should be as concrete as possible and tied to the expressed fear of the part, even if the fear doesn't make sense.) Usually, the answer is "safety," which then requires another question: "How would he or she be unsafe if this happened?"
It usually takes 2 to 4 questions along these lines to get to the core fear, usually a fear connected to the trauma in some way: "I'll be alone," "I would be trapped," "It would be too much—I would just shatter."

第四步： 探索潜在的恐惧。通常，潜在的恐惧是"某些坏事会发生"这一主题的变体，并已被投射到当下的触发因素上。我们往往需要探索几个层次的恐惧，才能抵达核心恐惧。再次询问那个部分：
"你在担忧什么？"无论出现什么感受或词语（愤怒、悲伤、羞耻、内疚、恐惧），都请假定这个部分对该感受感到不舒适，并且正在担忧某件事。
然后，一旦掌握了下一层担忧，就问："如果那真的发生了，你会担忧什么？"（问题应尽可能具体，并与该部分所表达的恐惧相关联，即便这种恐惧看起来没有道理。）通常，答案是"安全"，这时需要再追问："如果这发生了，他/她会面临什么危险？"
通常需要2到4个这样的问题，才能抵达核心恐惧，而这种恐惧往往以某种方式与创伤相连："我会孤独一人"，"我会被困住"，"那会太难承受——我会彻底崩碎"。

Step 5: Identify some type of corrective experience that can be provided by the adult self directly to the part, something that the part didn't get back then, like validation, support, comfort, care, reassurance, or protection. These fears come from long ago, even though they feel connected to right now because they are happening in the present moment. They are the fears of child parts who don't know that you are an adult with strengths and resources and who has safety under your control most of the time, certainly compared to when you were a child. Ask the worried part, "What do you need from me right here, right now, to not be so afraid of _________?" In most cases, the answer the part gives is: "I need to feel that you, the adult, are there with me and not as scared as I am."

第五步： 识别成人自我可以直接提供给那个部分的某种矫正性体验——那个部分当年没有得到的东西，例如确认、支持、安慰、关爱、安抚或保护。这些恐惧源自久远的过去，尽管它们感觉上与此刻相连，因为它们正在当下发生。这些是孩子部分的恐惧，它们不知道你已经是一个拥有力量和资源的成年人，也是一个大多数时候掌控着自身安全的人——相比你童年时期，更是如此。询问那个忧虑的部分："就在这里、就在此刻，你需要我做什么，才能让你不那么害怕_________？"在大多数情况下，该部分的回答是："我需要感受到你，那个成年人，与我同在，并且没有我那么害怕。"

Step 6: Focus on how the adult you are today can provide a corrective experience for the child you once were. Child parts can be afraid that if the adult is scared, too, or overwhelmed, there really will be danger, and no one will be there to help the child part. I stress to my clients that an adult would only be afraid of a real danger, not afraid of past dangers happening again exactly the same way. The adult can reassure the child parts that right now they are not alone—they're with you. Or reassure them that nothing bad is happening—they're just remembering how scary it was then. If words don't calm the body or the emotions, you can do something physical to communicate safety: for example, put a hand over the part of the body where the anxiety is felt (the chest, stomach) or lengthen your spine by gently stretching it from the middle of the back upward or stand up and walk around to demonstrate how tall and strong you are. You can also reassure the part through imagining being there with her … What would you want to do if you saw him feeling this way? Take his hand? Pick her up? Take her away from that place?

第六步： 专注于今天的你作为成年人，如何为曾经的那个孩子提供矫正性体验。孩子部分可能会担心：如果成年人也感到害怕或不堪重负，那真的就会有危险，届时没有人能帮助孩子部分。我向来访者强调：成年人只会对真实的危险感到害怕，而不会害怕过去的危险以完全相同的方式再次发生。成年人可以安抚孩子部分：此刻它们并不孤单——它们与你同在。或者安抚它们：现在没有什么坏事在发生——它们只是在回忆当时有多可怕。如果语言无法平静身体或情绪，你可以通过身体动作来传达安全感：例如，将手放在感受到焦虑的身体部位（胸口、腹部），或者从背部中段向上轻柔地拉伸脊柱，或者站起来走动，以展示你是多么高大和强壮。你也可以通过想象与那个部分同在来给予安抚……如果你看到他/她有这种感受，你会想做什么？握住他的手？抱起她？把她从那个地方带走？

Step 7: Practice! The more you practice these skills, the easier it will be to recover from crises and avoid them. Remember every crisis results from some part getting triggered and reacting out of fear or shame or anger.
The key is communicating a real commitment to the parts that, from now on, you will listen to them, take their fears seriously, connect to them with compassion, and try to provide the protection and support they have been waiting for.

第七步： 练习！你越多地练习这些技能，就越容易从危机中恢复，也越容易避免危机的发生。请记住，每一次危机都源于某个部分被触发，并出于恐惧、羞耻或愤怒做出反应。
关键在于向各部分传达一个真实的承诺：从现在起，你会倾听它们，认真对待它们的恐惧，带着自我慈悲与它们连接，并努力提供它们一直等待的保护和支持。

APPENDIX D
Treatment Paradigm for Internal Attachment Repair

附录D：内部依恋修复的治疗范式

The premise of this paradigm or protocol is that dissociative disorder clients, borderline clients with dissociative features, and structurally dissociated complex PTSD clients all come to therapy because their parts are intruding upon the consciousness of their going on with normal life selves. The presenting problem described to the therapist by the client will in some way reflect the activation of a part holding trauma-related implicit memories: depression might be a sign that a depressed child has been triggered by a loss; anxiety might be the communication from an anxious part whose implicit memories have been activated by the birth of a child; relationship difficulties may be an indication of conflict between parts about trust/mistrust, closeness/distance. Whatever implicit memories underlie the presenting problem, therapy is apt to further activate the parts because it is a promise of help from an authority figure, something for which they have been waiting many years. By its very nature, therapy will evoke impulses to disclose but also exacerbate procedurally learned secrecy. It will stimulate the yearning to trust and connect but also trigger hesitancy and hypervigilance. Closeness to the therapist and the invitation to "open up" will trigger implicit memories, and separation or distance will also be triggering.

这一范式或方案的前提是：解离障碍来访者、具有解离特征的边缘性人格障碍来访者，以及结构性解离的复杂创伤后应激障碍（PTSD）来访者，都因其各部分侵入了正常生活自我的意识而前来接受治疗。来访者向治疗师描述的主诉问题，将以某种方式反映出持有创伤相关内隐记忆的某个部分被激活的状态：抑郁可能是一个抑郁的孩子部分因某次失去而被触发的迹象；焦虑可能是某个焦虑部分的内隐记忆被孩子的出生所激活后发出的信号；人际关系困难则可能表明各部分之间在信任/不信任、亲密/疏离问题上存在冲突。无论主诉问题背后隐藏着什么样的内隐记忆，治疗都很可能进一步激活各部分，因为治疗意味着来自权威人物的帮助承诺——这是它们等待了多年的事情。从本质上说，治疗会唤起倾诉的冲动，但同时也会加剧程序性习得的保密倾向。它会激发对信任与连接的渴望，但同时也会触发犹豫和过度警觉。与治疗师的亲近以及被邀请"敞开心扉"会触发内隐记忆，而分离或距离感同样也会构成触发。

The therapist's job is to give both sides "a voice":

治疗师的工作是让双方都拥有"发言权"：

1 At each session, as the client arrives with a presenting problem or distress of the day, the therapist's job is first to tie that distress to a part, that is, if the client is feeling more anxious, the therapist reframes the anxiety as the child part's nervousness or fear and expresses empathy for the part rather than empathy for the "client." Although it may be important to spend some time listening to what the clients are feeling, it is also important to avoid reinforcing their procedurally learned "stories" about themselves and to help them become more mindful and curious about the part in distress.

1 在每次会谈中，当来访者带着当日的主诉问题或痛苦前来时，治疗师的首要任务是将那份痛苦与某个部分联系起来，也就是说，如果来访者感到更加焦虑，治疗师应将这种焦虑重新框架为孩子部分的紧张或恐惧，并对那个部分表达共情，而非对"来访者"表达共情。虽然花一些时间倾听来访者的感受可能很重要，但避免强化他们程序性习得的关于自身的"叙事"也同样重要，治疗师需要帮助他们变得更加正念，对处于困境中的部分更加好奇。

2 Next, switch pronouns so that "you" now describes the adult self of the client and "he" or "she" describes the part: "Yes, she's really scared, isn't she? Do you know what triggered her? Or did you just wake up to find her in this state?"

2 接下来，切换代词，使"你"指代来访者的成人自我，而"他"或"她"指代那个部分："是的，她真的很害怕，不是吗？你知道是什么触发了她吗？还是你醒来就发现她处于这种状态？"

3 Evoke curiosity about the part that is in distress: Is he or she very young? Are his or her feelings familiar? What is going on in the client's life that might trigger these emotions? [Notice that there is no attempt to place the part in childhood history or in the traumatic context. The emphasis is on the part's experience now in the context of the client's daily life and the relationship between the normal life self and the part.]

3 唤起对处于痛苦中的部分的好奇心：他或她是否非常年幼？他或她的感受是否让你感到熟悉？来访者生活中正在发生什么，可能触发了这些情绪？【请注意，这里并不试图将该部分置于童年历史或创伤情境中。重点在于该部分此刻在来访者日常生活情境中的体验，以及正常生活自我与该部分之间的关系。】

4 Use language and tones of voice that speak to not only the adult but also to the age of that part, whether a young child, teenager, or latency-aged child.

4 使用的语言和语气要同时面向成人，也要适应那个部分的年龄，无论它是一个幼小的孩子、青少年，还是潜伏期年龄的孩子。

5 Be prepared for other parts to get triggered by the attention to vulnerability: A skeptical part that questions the use of parts language, an angry part that feels condescended to, a "shutdown" part that stops talking and goes mute.

5 做好准备，其他部分可能会因关注脆弱性而被触发：一个质疑使用"各部分"语言的怀疑部分；一个感到被俯视的愤怒部分；一个停止说话、陷入沉默的"关闭"部分。

6 Notice and name parts that distract or shut down the conversation with or about a vulnerable part: "Interesting—there's a part that thinks I'm condescending, huh? I wonder what in my tone of voice or words gave her that message …" "I appreciate the skeptical part's questioning of what we're doing here … that's important." "Notice how protective these parts are of the anxious part—they don't want us to get too close to her."

6 注意并命名那些干扰或关闭与脆弱部分有关的对话的部分："有意思——有一个部分认为我在居高临下，是吗？我想知道我的语气或措辞中哪里给了她这样的信息……""我欣赏那个怀疑部分对我们在这里所做事情的质疑……这很重要。""注意这些部分对焦虑部分的保护性有多强——它们不想让我们离她太近。"

7 Be the voice or spokesperson for all the parts: "Remember that all parts are welcome here …" "Keep in mind this is a child—no wonder she is so upset …"

7 成为所有部分的声音或代言人："请记住，所有部分在这里都是受欢迎的……""请记住这是一个孩子——难怪她如此难过……"

8 As the client expresses feelings and thoughts or describes physical reactions, images, or impulses (whether in parts language or not), keep reminding him or her that all of these sources of information can be communications from parts: "If this belief/feeling/impulse/image were a communication from a part, what would that part be trying to tell you?"

8 当来访者表达感受和想法，或描述身体反应、意象或冲动时（无论是否使用"各部分"的语言），不断提醒他/她：所有这些信息来源都可能是各部分发出的沟通："如果这个信念/感受/冲动/意象是来自某个部分的信息，那个部分想告诉你什么？"

9 Then have the client check with the parts by asking to him or herself: "Is that right? Is that true?" If the answer is "no," then have client invite the part to correct the statement until it is "right."

9 然后让来访者向内与各部分核查，问自己："是这样吗？这是真的吗？"如果答案是"不"，则让来访者邀请那个部分修正这一表述，直到它"正确"为止。

10 Invite the client to ask inside, "Are you tired of feeling this way?" or "Are you tired of being in the past?"

10 邀请来访者向内询问："你是否厌倦了这样的感受？"或"你是否厌倦了停留在过去？"

11 If the answer is "yes," then whatever interventions are offered should be framed as an attempt to help the parts. Often, especially when clients shut down or refuse to speak, our interventions are framed as attempts to get the adult back in control of the body. But that approach sends a negative message to parts that they are not welcome. The same intervention (e.g., grounding) done on behalf of the parts will be much more successful.

11 如果答案是"是的"，那么无论提供什么干预措施，都应将其框架为帮助各部分的尝试。通常，尤其是当来访者关闭或拒绝说话时，我们的干预措施被框架为让成人重新控制身体的尝试。但这种方式向各部分传递了一个负面信息：它们不受欢迎。同样的干预（例如落地技术），若以帮助各部分为名来实施，将会更加成功。

12 After each intervention tried, ask the client to check inside with the parts: "Does that help?" "Does this feel better or worse?" If the answer is positive, repeat the intervention or affirm the part's feelings: "Yes, it feels good to me, too—I like holding your hand." Or "I want to protect you."

12 每次尝试干预之后，请来访者向内与各部分核查："这有帮助吗？""这感觉更好还是更糟？"如果答案是肯定的，重复该干预，或确认那个部分的感受："是的，我也感觉很好——我喜欢握住你的手。"或者"我想保护你。"

APPENDIX F
The Four Befriending Questions

附录F：四个结友问题

Step 1: The client is asked to identify a part that is in some kind of distress. Then the therapist initiates the dialogue by inviting the client to: "Ask this distressed part what she's worried about if you ________________________________? [e.g., go to the party, say "No," get angry, stand up to your boss, etc.]

第一步： 请来访者找出一个处于某种痛苦之中的部分。然后治疗师通过邀请来访者来启动对话："询问这个处于痛苦中的部分，如果你________________________________，她担心什么？"【例如，去参加聚会、说"不"、发怒、向老板据理力争，等等。】

Step 2: "Ask her what she's worried will happen next if her worry [repeat the part's exact description of it] really does come true."

第二步： "询问她，如果她的担忧【重复该部分对担忧的原话描述】真的成为现实，她担心接下来会发生什么。"

Step 3: "Ask her: if those worries that [repeat the part's exact description] really do happen, what is she worried will happen next?"Keep repeating Step 3 until a core fear is reached: usually either the fear of annihilation or the fear of abandonment.

第三步： "询问她：如果那些【重复该部分的原话描述】真的发生了，她担心接下来会发生什么？"持续重复第三步，直到触及核心恐惧：通常是消亡的恐惧或被遗弃的恐惧之一。

Step 4: "Acknowledge her fear by mirroring it back to her, then ask the part: what does she need from you right here, right now to not be so afraid of ________________?" "Right here, right now" is the operative word: the need must be small enough and sufficiently concrete that it can be met by the normal life part with coaching as appropriate from the therapist.

第四步： "通过将她的恐惧反映回给她来确认这份恐惧，然后询问这个部分：就在这里、就在此刻，她需要你做什么，才能不那么害怕________________？""就在这里、就在此刻"是关键所在：这个需求必须足够小、足够具体，使正常生活自我能够在治疗师适当引导下加以满足。